<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3a56a98-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125"><num value="1125">§ 1125.</num><heading> Postpetition disclosure and solicitation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56a99-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56a9a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “adequate information” means information of a kind, and in sufficient detail, as far as is reasonably practicable in light of the nature and history of the debtor and the condition of the debtor’s books and records, including a discussion of the potential material Federal tax consequences of the plan to the debtor, any successor to the debtor, and a hypothetical investor typical of the holders of claims or interests in the case, that would enable such a hypothetical investor of the relevant class to make an informed judgment about the plan, but adequate information need not include such information about any other possible or proposed plan and in determining whether a disclosure statement provides adequate information, the court shall consider the complexity of the case, the benefit of additional information to creditors and other parties in interest, and the cost of providing additional information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56a9b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> “investor typical of holders of claims or interests of the relevant class” means investor having—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a56a9c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a claim or interest of the relevant class;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a56a9d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such a relationship with the debtor as the holders of other claims or interests of such class generally have; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a56a9e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such ability to obtain such information from sources other than the disclosure required by this section as holders of claims or interests in such class generally have.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56a9f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> An acceptance or rejection of a plan may not be solicited after the commencement of the case under this title from a holder of a claim or interest with respect to such claim or interest, unless, at the time of or before such solicitation, there is transmitted to such holder the plan or a summary of the plan, and a written disclosure statement approved, after notice and a hearing, by the court as containing adequate information. The court may approve a disclosure statement without a valuation of the debtor or an appraisal of the debtor’s assets.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56aa0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The same disclosure statement shall be transmitted to each holder of a claim or interest of a particular class, but there may be transmitted different disclosure statements, differing in amount, detail, or kind of information, as between classes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56aa1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Whether a disclosure statement required under subsection (b) of this section contains adequate information is not governed by any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, rule, or regulation, but an agency or official whose duty is to administer or enforce such a law, rule, or regulation may be heard on the issue of whether a disclosure statement contains adequate information. Such an agency or official may not appeal from, or otherwise seek review of, an order approving a disclosure statement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56aa2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> A person that solicits acceptance or rejection of a plan, in good faith and in compliance with the applicable provisions of this title, or that participates, in good faith and in compliance with the applicable provisions of this title, in the offer, issuance, sale, or purchase of a security, offered or sold under the plan, of the debtor, of an affiliate participating in a joint plan with the debtor, or of a newly organized successor to the debtor under the plan, is not liable, on account of such solicitation or participation, for violation of any applicable law, rule, or regulation governing solicitation of acceptance or rejection of a plan or the offer, issuance, sale, or purchase of securities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56aa3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (b), in a small business case—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the court may determine that the plan itself provides adequate information and that a separate disclosure statement is not necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the court may approve a disclosure statement submitted on standard forms approved by the court or adopted under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2075">section 2075 of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the court may conditionally approve a disclosure statement subject to final approval after notice and a hearing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> acceptances and rejections of a plan may be solicited based on a conditionally approved disclosure statement if the debtor provides adequate information to each holder of a claim or interest that is solicited, but a conditionally approved disclosure statement shall be mailed not later than 25 days before the date of the hearing on confirmation of the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a56aa9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the hearing on the disclosure statement may be combined with the hearing on confirmation of a plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a56aaa-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1125/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (b), an acceptance or rejection of the plan may be solicited from a holder of a claim or interest if such solicitation complies with applicable nonbankruptcy law and if such holder was solicited before the commencement of the case in a manner complying with applicable nonbankruptcy law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd3a56aab-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2633">92 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s509">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 509</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/385">98 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tII/s217/e">Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 217(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4127">108 Stat. 4127</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tIV">Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 408, 431, title VII, § 717, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/106">119 Stat. 106</ref>, 109, 131.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3a56aac-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd3a56aad-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a56aae-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1125 of the House amendment is derived from section 1125 of the House bill and Senate amendment except with respect to section 1125(f) of the Senate amendment. It will not be necessary for the court to consider the report of the examiner prior to approval of a disclosure statement. The investigation of the examiner is to proceed on an independent basis from the procedure of the reorganization under chapter 11. In order to ensure that the examiner’s report will be expeditious and fair, the examiner is precluded from serving as a trustee in the case or from representing a trustee if a trustee is appointed, whether the case remains in chapter 11 or is converted to chapter 7 or 13.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a7dbaf-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section extends disclosure requirements in connection with solicitations to all cases under chapter 11. Heretofore this subject was dealt with by the Bankruptcy Act [former title 11] mainly in the special contexts of railroad reorganizations and chapter X [chapter 10 of former title 11] cases.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) defines (1) the subject matter of disclosure as “adequate information” and relates the standard of adequacy to an (2) “investor typical of holders or claims or interests of the relevant class.” “Investor” is used broadly here, for it will almost always include a trade creditor or other creditors who originally had no investment intent or interest. It refers to the investment-type decision by those called upon to accept a plan to modify their claims or interests, which typically will involve acceptance of new securities or of a cash payment in lieu thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Both the kind and form of information are left essentially to the judicial discretion of the court, guided by the specification in subparagraph (a)(1) that it be of a kind and in sufficient detail that a reasonable and typical investor can make an informed judgment about the plan. The information required will necessarily be governed by the circumstances of the case.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reporting and audit standards devised for solvent and continuing businesses do not necessarily fit a debtor in reorganization. Subsection (a)(1) expressly incorporates consideration of the nature and history of the debtor and the condition of its books and rec­ords into the determination of what is reasonably practicable to supply. These factors are particularly pertinent to historical data and to discontinued operations of no future relevance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A plan is necessarily predicated on knowledge of the assets and liabilities being dealt with and on factually supported expectations as to the future course of the business sufficient to meet the feasibility standard in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1130/a/11">section 1130(a)(11) of this title</ref>. It may thus be necessary to provide estimates or judgments for that purpose. Yet it remains practicable to describe, in such detail as may be relevant and needed, the basis for the plan and the data on which supporters of the plan rely.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) establishes the jurisdiction of the court over this subject by prohibiting solicitation of acceptance or rejection of a plan after the commencement of the case, unless the person solicited receives, before or at the time of the solicitation, a written disclosure statement approved by the court, after notice and hearing, as containing adequate information. As under present law, determinations of value, by appraisal or otherwise, are not required if not needed to accomplish the purpose specified in subsection (a)(1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) requires that the same disclosure statement be transmitted to each member of a class. It recognizes that the information needed for an informed judgment about the plan may differ among classes. A class whose rights under the plan center on a particular fund or asset would have no use for an extensive description of other matters that could not affect them.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (d) relieves the court of the need to follow any otherwise applicable Federal or state law in determining the adequacy of the information contained in the disclosure statement submitted for its approval. It authorizes an agency or official, Federal or state, charged with administering cognate laws so preempted to advise the court on the adequacy of proposed disclosure statement. But they are not authorized to appeal the court’s decision.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Solicitations with respect to a plan do not involve just mere requests for opinions. Acceptance of the plan vitally affects creditors and shareholders, and most frequently the solicitation involves an offering of securities in exchange for claims or interests. The present bankruptcy statute [former title 11] has exempted such offerings under each of its chapters from the registration and disclosure requirements of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.], an exemption also continued by <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1145/a/2">section 1145(a)(2) of this title</ref>. The extension of the disclosure requirements to all chapter 11 cases justifies the coordinate extension of these exemptions. By the same token, no valid purpose is served not to exempt from the requirements of similar state laws in a matter under the exclusive jurisdiction of the Federal bankruptcy laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e) exonerates any person who, in good faith and in compliance with this title, solicits or participates in the offer, issuance, sale or purchase, under the plan, of a security from any liability, on account of such solicitation or participation, for violation of any law, rule, or regulation governing the offer, issuance, sale, or purchase of securities. This exoneration is coordinate with the exemption from Federal or State registration or licensing requirements provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1145">section 1145 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In the nonpublic case, the court, when approving the disclosure statement, has before it the texts of the plan, a proposed disclosure document, and such other information the plan proponents and other interested parties may present at the hearing. In the final analysis the exoneration which subsection (e) grants must depend on the good faith of the plan proponents and of those who participate in the preparation of the disclosure statement and in the solicitation. Subsection (e) does not affect civil or criminal liability for defects and inadequacies that are beyond the limits of the exoneration that good faith provides.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1125 applies to public companies as well, subject to the qualifications of subsection (f). In case of a public company no solicitations of acceptance is permitted unless authorized by the court upon or after approval of the plan pursuant to section 1128(c). In addition to the documents specified in subsection (b), subsection (f) requires transmission of the opinion and order of the court approving the plan and, if filed, the advisory report of the Securities and Exchange Commission or a summary thereof prepared by the Commission.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a7dbb0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is new. It is the heart of the consolidation of the various reorganization chapters found in current law. It requires disclosure before solicitation of acceptances of a plan or reorganization.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) contains two definitions. First, “adequate information” is defined to mean information of a kind, and insufficient detail, as far as is reasonably practical in light of the nature and history of the debtor and the condition of the debtor’s books and records, that would enable a hypothetical reasonable investor typical of holders of claims or interests of the relevant class to make an informed judgment about the plan. Second, “investor typical of holders of claims or interests of the relevant class” is defined to mean an investor having a claim or interest of the relevant class, having such a relationship with the debtor as the holders of other claims or interests of the relevant class have, and having such ability to obtain information from sources other than the disclosure statement as holders of claims or interests of the relevant class have, and having such ability to obtain information from sources other than the disclosure statement as holders of claims or interests of the relevant class have. That is, the hypothetical investor against which the disclosure is measured must not be an insider if other members of the class are not insiders, and so on. In other words, the adequacy of disclosure is measured against the typical investor, not an extraordinary one.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Supreme Court’s rulemaking power will not extend to rulemaking that will prescribe what constitutes adequate information. That standard is a substantive standard. Precisely what constitutes adequate information in any particular instance will develop on a case-by-case basis. Courts will take a practical approach as to what is necessary under the circumstances of each case, such as the cost of preparation of the statements, the need for relative speed in solicitation and confirmation, and, of course, the need for investor protection. There will be a balancing of interests in each case. In reorganization cases, there is frequently great uncertainty. Therefore the need for flexibility is greatest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) is the operative subsection. It prohibits solicitation of acceptances or rejections of a plan after the commencement of the case unless, at the time of the solicitation or before, there is transmitted to the solicitee the plan or a summary of the plan, and a written disclosure statement approved by the court as containing adequate information. The subsection permits approval of the statement without the necessity of a valuation of the debtor or an appraisal of the debtor’s assets. However, in some cases, a valuation or appraisal will be necessary to develop adequate information. The court will be able to determine what is necessary in light of the facts and circumstances of each particular case.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) requires that the same disclosure statement go to all members of a particular class, but permits different disclosure to different classes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (d) excepts the disclosure statements from the requirements of the securities laws (such as section 14 of the 1934 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78n">15 U.S.C. 78n</ref>] and section 5 of the 1933 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77e">15 U.S.C. 77e</ref>]), and from similar State securities laws (blue sky laws, for example). The subsection permits an agency or official whose duty is to administer or enforce such laws (such as the Securities and Exchange Commission or State Corporation Commissioners) to appear and be heard on the issue of whether a disclosure statement contains adequate information, but the agencies and officials are not granted the right of appeal from an adverse determination in any capacity. They may join in an appeal by a true party in interest, however.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e) is a safe harbor provision, and is necessary to make the exemption provided by subsection (d) effective. Without it, a creditor that solicited an acceptance or rejection in reliance on the court’s approval of a disclosure statement would be potentially liable under antifraud sections designed to enforce the very sections of the securities laws from which subsection (d) excuses compliance. The subsection protects only persons that solicit in good faith and in compliance with the applicable provisions of the reorganization chapter. It provides protection from legal liability as well as from equitable liability based on an injunctive action by the SEC or other agency or official.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3a7dbb1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd3a7dbb2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s717">Pub. L. 109–8, § 717</ref>, inserted “including a discussion of the potential material Federal tax consequences of the plan to the debtor, any successor to the debtor, and a hypothetical investor typical of the holders of claims or interests in the case,” after “records,” and substituted “such a hypothetical investor” for “a hypothetical reasonable investor typical of holders of claims or interests”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s431/1">Pub. L. 109–8, § 431(1)</ref>, inserted before semicolon “and in determining whether a disclosure statement provides adequate information, the court shall consider the complexity of the case, the benefit of additional information to creditors and other parties in interest, and the cost of providing additional information”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s431/2">Pub. L. 109–8, § 431(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which read as follows: “Notwithstanding subsection (b), in a case in which the debtor has elected under section 1121(e) to be considered a small business—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the court may conditionally approve a disclosure statement subject to final approval after notice and a hearing;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) acceptances and rejections of a plan may be solicited based on a conditionally approved disclosure statement as long as the debtor provides adequate information to each holder of a claim or interest that is solicited, but a conditionally approved disclosure statement shall be mailed at least 10 days prior to the date of the hearing on confirmation of the plan; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) a hearing on the disclosure statement may be combined with a hearing on confirmation of a plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s408">Pub. L. 109–8, § 408</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s509/a/1">Pub. L. 98–353, § 509(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “, but adequate information need not include such information about any other possible or proposed plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s509/a/2">Pub. L. 98–353, § 509(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “the” after “with”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s509/a/3">Pub. L. 98–353, § 509(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “of” after “holders”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s509/b">Pub. L. 98–353, § 509(b)</ref>, inserted “required under subsection (b) of this section” and “, or otherwise seek review of,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s509/c">Pub. L. 98–353, § 509(c)</ref>, inserted “acceptance or rejection of a plan” after “solicits”, and “solicitation of acceptance or rejection of a plan or” after “governing”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3a7dbb3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a7dbb4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a7dbb5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a7dbb6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
