<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3af07c9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1166"><num value="1166">§ 1166.</num><heading> Effect of subtitle IV of title 49 and of Federal, State, or local regulations</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except with respect to abandonment under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1170">section 1170 of this title</ref>, or merger, modification of the financial structure of the debtor, or issuance or sale of securities under a plan, the trustee and the debtor are subject to the provisions of subtitle IV of title 49 that are applicable to railroads, and the trustee is subject to orders of any Federal, State, or local regulatory body to the same extent as the debtor would be if a petition commencing the case under this chapter had not been filed, but—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3af07ca-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1166/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any such order that would require the expenditure, or the incurring of an obligation for the expenditure, of money from the estate is not effective unless approved by the court; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3af07cb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1166/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the provisions of this chapter are subject to section 601(b) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idd3af07cc-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2642">92 Stat. 2642</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/449/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 97–449, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2442">96 Stat. 2442</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s518">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 518</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/388">98 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tV/s501/d/34">Pub. L. 103–394, title V, § 501(d)(34)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4146">108 Stat. 4146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3af07cd-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd3af07ce-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3af07cf-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1166 of the House amendment is derived from sections 1164 and 1165 of the House bill. An alternative proposal contained in section 1168(1) of the Senate bill is rejected as violative of the principle of equal treatment of all creditors under title 11.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3af07d0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1168 [enacted as section 1166] makes the trustee subject to the Interstate Commerce Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s10101">49 U.S.C. 10101</ref> et seq.] and to lawful orders of the Interstate Commerce Commission, the U.S. Department of Transportation, and State and regulatory bodies. The approval of the court is required, however, if the order requires the expenditure of money or the incurring of an expenditure other than the payment of certain interline accounts. The limitation of “lawful orders” of State commissions to those involving “safety, location of tracks, and terminal facilities,” which is contained in present section 77(c)(2) [section 205(c)(2) of former title 11], is eliminated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (1) further provides that the debtor must pay in cash all amounts owed other carriers for current balances owed for interline freight, passenger and per diem, including incentive per diem, for periods both prior and subsequent to the filing of the petition, without the necessity of court approval.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (2) makes the provisions of the chapter subject to section 601(b) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791/b">45 U.S.C. 791(b)</ref>], which excludes the Interstate Commerce Commission from any participation in the reorganization of certain northeast railroads that have transferred their rail properties to Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3af07d1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1164 [enacted as section 1166] makes the debtor railroad subject to the provisions of the Interstate Commerce Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s10101">49 U.S.C. 10101</ref> et seq.] that are applicable to railroads, and the trustee subject to the orders of the Interstate Commerce Commission to the same extent as the debtor would have been if the case had not been commenced. There are several exceptions. The section does not apply with respect to abandonment of rail lines, which is provided for under section 1169, or with respect to merger under a plan, modification of the financial structure of the debtor by reason of the plan, or the issuance or sale of securities under a plan. Further, the orders of the ICC are not effective if the order would require the expenditure or the incurring of an obligation for the expenditure of money from the estate, unless approved by the court, and the provisions of this chapter are subject to section 601(b) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791/b">45 U.S.C. 791(b)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Section 1165 (enacted as section 1166)] The same rules apply with respect to Federal, State, or local regulations. The trustee is subject to the orders of a Federal, State, or local regulatory body to the same extent as the debtor would be if the case had not been commenced. However, any order that would require the expenditure, or the incurring of an obligation for the expenditure, of money is not effective under [until] approved by the court.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3af07d2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd3af07d3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 601(b) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973, referred to in par. (2), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791/b">section 791(b) of Title 45</ref>, Railroads.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd3af07d4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> struck out “(<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791/b">45 U.S.C. 791(b)</ref>)” after “Act of 1973”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> directed substitution of “subtitle IV of title 49” for “the Interstate Commerce Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1">49 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.)”, which substitution had previously been made by <ref href="/us/pl/97/449">Pub. L. 97–449</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/449">Pub. L. 97–449</ref> substituted “subtitle IV of title 49” for “Interstate Commerce Act” in section catchline, and “subtitle IV of title 49” for “the Interstate Commerce Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1">49 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.)” in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3af07d5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3af07d6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
