<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3b1784c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173"><num value="1173">§ 1173.</num><heading> Confirmation of plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3b1784d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The court shall confirm a plan if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3b1784e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the applicable requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1129">section 1129 of this title</ref> have been met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3b1784f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> each creditor or equity security holder will receive or retain under the plan property of a value, as of the effective date of the plan, that is not less than the value of property that each such creditor or equity security holder would so receive or retain if all of the operating railroad lines of the debtor were sold, and the proceeds of such sale, and the other property of the estate, were distributed under chapter 7 of this title on such date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3b17850-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in light of the debtor’s past earnings and the probable prospective earnings of the reorganized debtor, there will be adequate coverage by such prospective earnings of any fixed charges, such as interest on debt, amortization of funded debt, and rent for leased railroads, provided for by the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3b17851-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the plan is consistent with the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3b17852-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1173/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If the requirements of subsection (a) of this section are met with respect to more than one plan, the court shall confirm the plan that is most likely to maintain adequate rail service in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd3b17853-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2644">92 Stat. 2644</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s523">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 523</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/388">98 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3b17854-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd3b17855-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3b17856-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1173 of the House amendment concerns confirmation of a plan of railroad reorganization and is derived from section 1172 of the House bill as modified. In particular, section 1173(a)(3) of the House amendment is derived from section 1170(3) of the Senate amendment. Section 1173(b) is derived from section 1173(a)(8) of the Senate amendment.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3b17857-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1173 adapts the provisions dealing with reorganization plans generally contained in section 1130 to the particular requirements of railroad reorganization plans, as set out in present section 77(e) [section 205(e) of former title 11]. Subsection (a) specifies the findings which the court must make before approving a plan: (1) The plan complies with the applicable provisions of the chapter; (2) the proponent of the plan complies with the applicable provisions of the chapter; (3) the plan has been proposed in good faith; (4) any payments for services or for costs or expenses in connection with the case or the plan are disclosed to the court and are reasonable, or, if to be paid later, are subject to the approval of the court as reasonable; (5) the proponent of the plan has disclosed the identity and affiliations of the individuals who will serve as directors, officers, or voting trustees, such appointments or continuations in office are consistent with the interests of creditors, equity security holders, and the proponent the public, and has disclosed the identity and compensation of any insider who will be employed or retained under the plan; (6) that rate changes proposed in the plan have been approved by the appropriate regulatory commission, or that the plan is contingent on such approval; (7) that confirmation of the plan is not likely to be followed by further reorganization or liquidation, unless it is contemplated by the plan; (8) that the plan, if there is more than one, is the one most likely to maintain adequate rail service and (9) that the plan provides the priority traditionally accorded by section 77(b) [section 205(b) of former title 11] to claims by rail creditors for necessary services rendered during the 6 months preceding the filing of the petition in bankruptcy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) continues the present power of the court in section 77(e) [section 205(e) of former title 11] to confirm a plan over the objections of creditors or equity security holders who are materially and adversely affected. The subsection also confirms the authority of the court to approve a transfer of all or part of a debtor’s property or its merger over the objections of equity security holders if it finds (1) that the “public interest” in continued rail transportation outweighs any adverse effect on creditors and equity security holders, and (2) that the plan is fair and equitable, affords due recognition to the rights of each class, and does not discriminate unfairly against any class.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) permits modification of a plan confirmed by a final order only for fraud.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3b17858-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Section 1172] This section [enacted as section 1173] requires the court to confirm a plan if the applicable requirements of section 1129 (relating to confirmation of reorganization plans generally) are met, if the best interest test is met, and if the plan is compatible with the public interest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The test in this paragraph is similar to the test prescribed for ordinary corporate reorganizations. However, since a railroad cannot liquidate its assets and sell them for scrap to satisfy its creditors, the test focuses on the value of the railroad as a going concern. That is, the test is based on what the assets, sold as operating rail lines, would bring.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The public interest requirement, found in current law, will now be decided by the court, with the ICC representing the public interest before the court, rather than in the first instance by the ICC. Liquidation of the debtor is not, per se, contrary to the public interest.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3b17859-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd3b1785a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> substituted “consistent” for “compatible”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3b1785b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3b1785c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
