<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd34fa967-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327"><num value="327">§ 327.</num><heading> Employment of professional persons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa968-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the trustee, with the court’s approval, may employ one or more attorneys, accountants, appraisers, auctioneers, or other professional persons, that do not hold or represent an interest adverse to the estate, and that are disinterested persons, to represent or assist the trustee in carrying out the trustee’s duties under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa969-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If the trustee is authorized to operate the business of the debtor under section 721, 1202, or 1108 of this title, and if the debtor has regularly employed attorneys, accountants, or other professional persons on salary, the trustee may retain or replace such professional persons if necessary in the operation of such business.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa96a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> In a case under chapter 7, 12, or 11 of this title, a person is not disqualified for employment under this section solely because of such person’s employment by or representation of a creditor, unless there is objection by another creditor or the United States trustee, in which case the court shall disapprove such employment if there is an actual conflict of interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa96b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The court may authorize the trustee to act as attorney or accountant for the estate if such authorization is in the best interest of the estate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa96c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The trustee, with the court’s approval, may employ, for a specified special purpose, other than to represent the trustee in conducting the case, an attorney that has represented the debtor, if in the best interest of the estate, and if such attorney does not represent or hold any interest adverse to the debtor or to the estate with respect to the matter on which such attorney is to be employed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd34fa96d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s327/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The trustee may not employ a person that has served as an examiner in the case.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd34fa96e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2563">92 Stat. 2563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s430/c">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 430(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/370">98 Stat. 370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/tII">Pub. L. 99–554, title II</ref>, §§ 210, 257(e), <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3099">100 Stat. 3099</ref>, 3114.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd34fa96f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd34fa970-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd34fa971-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 327(a) of the House amendment contains a technical amendment indicating that attorneys, and perhaps other officers enumerated therein, represent, rather than assist, the trustee in carrying out the trustee’s duties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 327(c) represents a compromise between H.R. 8200 as passed by the House and the Senate amendment. The provision states that former representation of a creditor, whether secured or unsecured, will not automatically disqualify a person from being employed by a trustee, but if such person is employed by the trustee, the person may no longer represent the creditor in connection with the case.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 327(f) prevents an examiner from being employed by the trustee.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd34fa972-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section authorizes the trustee, subject to the court’s approval, to employ professional persons, such as attorneys, accountants, appraisers, and auctioneers, to represent or perform services for the estate. The trustee may employ only disinterested persons that do not hold or represent an interest adverse to the estate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) is an exception, and authorizes the trustee to retain or replace professional persons that the debtor has employed if necessary in the operation of the debtor’s business.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) provides a professional person is not disqualified for employment solely because of the person’s prior employment by or representation of a secured or unsecured creditor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (d) permits the court to authorize the trustee, if qualified to act as his own counsel or accountant.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e) permits the trustee, subject to the court’s approval, to employ for a specified special purpose an attorney that has represented the debtor, if such employment is in the best interest of the estate and if the attorney does not hold or represent an interest adverse to the debtor of the estate with respect to the matter on which he is to be employed. This subsection does not authorize the employment of the debtor’s attorney to represent the estate generally or to represent the trustee in the conduct of the bankruptcy case. The subsection will most likely be used when the debtor is involved in complex litigation, and changing attorneys in the middle of the case after the bankruptcy case has commenced would be detrimental to the progress of that other litigation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd34fa973-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) is an additional exception. The trustee may employ as his counsel a nondisinterested person if the only reason that the attorney is not disinterested is because of his representation of an unsecured creditor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd34fa974-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd34fa975-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s257/e/1">Pub. L. 99–554, § 257(e)(1)</ref>, which directed the insertion of “, 1202,” after “section 721,” was executed by making the insertion after “section 721” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s257/e/2">Pub. L. 99–554, § 257(e)(2)</ref>, which directed the insertion of “, 12,” after “section 7,” was executed by making the insertion after “chapter 7” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s210">Pub. L. 99–554, § 210</ref>, inserted “or the United States trustee” after “another creditor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> substituted “In a case under chapter 7 or 11 of this title, a person is not disqualified for employment under this section solely because of such person’s employment by or representation of a creditor, unless there is objection by another creditor, in which case the court shall disapprove such employment if there is an actual conflict of interest.” for “In a case under chapter 7 or 11 of this title, a person is not disqualified for employment under this section solely because of such person’s employment by or representation of a creditor, but may not, while employed by the trustee, represent, in connection with the case, a creditor.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd34fa976-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd34fa977-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective date and applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s210">section 210 of Pub. L. 99–554</ref> dependent upon the judicial district involved, see section 302(d), (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s581">section 581 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s257">section 257 of Pub. L. 99–554</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, but not applicable to cases commenced under this title before that date, see section 302(a), (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f368-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
