<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd351f387-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330"><num value="330">§ 330.</num><heading> Compensation of officers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f388-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f389-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> After notice to the parties in interest and the United States Trustee and a hearing, and subject to sections 326, 328, and 329, the court may award to a trustee, a consumer privacy ombudsman appointed under section 332, an examiner, an ombudsman appointed under section 333, or a professional person employed under section 327 or 1103—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f38a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reasonable compensation for actual, necessary services rendered by the trustee, examiner, ombudsman, professional person, or attorney and by any paraprofessional person employed by any such person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f38b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reimbursement for actual, necessary expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f38c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The court may, on its own motion or on the motion of the United States Trustee, the United States Trustee for the District or Region, the trustee for the estate, or any other party in interest, award compensation that is less than the amount of compensation that is requested.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f38d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In determining the amount of reasonable compensation to be awarded to an examiner, trustee under chapter 11, or professional person, the court shall consider the nature, the extent, and the value of such services, taking into account all relevant factors, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f38e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the time spent on such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f38f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the rates charged for such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f390-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whether the services were necessary to the administration of, or beneficial at the time at which the service was rendered toward the completion of, a case under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f391-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> whether the services were performed within a reasonable amount of time commensurate with the complexity, importance, and nature of the problem, issue, or task addressed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f392-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> with respect to a professional person, whether the person is board certified or otherwise has demonstrated skill and experience in the bankruptcy field; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f393-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> whether the compensation is reasonable based on the customary compensation charged by comparably skilled practitioners in cases other than cases under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f394-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f395-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the court shall not allow compensation for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f396-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> unnecessary duplication of services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f397-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> services that were not—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd351f398-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> reasonably likely to benefit the debtor’s estate; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd351f399-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> necessary to the administration of the case.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In a chapter 12 or chapter 13 case in which the debtor is an individual, the court may allow reasonable compensation to the debtor’s attorney for representing the interests of the debtor in connection with the bankruptcy case based on a consideration of the benefit and necessity of such services to the debtor and the other factors set forth in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The court shall reduce the amount of compensation awarded under this section by the amount of any interim compensation awarded under section 331, and, if the amount of such interim compensation exceeds the amount of compensation awarded under this section, may order the return of the excess to the estate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Any compensation awarded for the preparation of a fee application shall be based on the level and skill reasonably required to prepare the application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> In determining the amount of reasonable compensation to be awarded to a trustee, the court shall treat such compensation as a commission, based on section 326.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f39f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There shall be paid from the filing fee in a case under chapter 7 of this title $105 to the trustee serving in such case, after such trustee’s services are rendered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3a0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Judicial Conference of the United States—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f3a1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall prescribe additional fees of the same kind as prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1914/b">section 1914(b) of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f3a2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may prescribe notice of appearance fees and fees charged against distributions in cases under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">to pay $15 to trustees serving in cases after such trustees’ services are rendered. Beginning 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Bankruptcy Reform Act of 1994, such $15 shall be paid in addition to the amount paid under paragraph (1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3a3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Unless the court orders otherwise, in a case under chapter 12 or 13 of this title the compensation paid to the trustee serving in the case shall not be less than $5 per month from any distribution under the plan during the administration of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3a4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s330/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> In a case in which the United States trustee serves as trustee, the compensation of the trustee under this section shall be paid to the clerk of the bankruptcy court and deposited by the clerk into the United States Trustee System Fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s589a">section 589a of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd351f3a5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2564">92 Stat. 2564</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII">Pub. L. 98–353, title III</ref>, §§ 433, 434, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/370">98 Stat. 370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/tII">Pub. L. 99–554, title II</ref>, §§ 211, 257(f), <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3099">100 Stat. 3099</ref>, 3114; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tI/s117">Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 117</ref>, title II, § 224(b), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4119">108 Stat. 4119</ref>, 4130; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tII/s232/b">Pub. L. 109–8, title II, § 232(b)</ref>, title IV, §§ 407, 415, title XI, § 1104(b), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/74">119 Stat. 74</ref>, 106, 107, 192; <ref href="/us/pl/116/325/s3/c">Pub. L. 116–325, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-12">Jan. 12, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5087">134 Stat. 5087</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/43/dA/s131">Pub. L. 117–43, div. A, § 131</ref>, <date date="2021-09-30">Sept. 30, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/351">135 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s3/a">Pub. L. 119–76, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2026-02-06">Feb. 6, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/741">140 Stat. 741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd351f3a6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idd351f3a7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Delayed Applicability of Amendment</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd351f3a8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">For delayed applicability of amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 119–76</ref>, see Effective Date of 2026 Amendment note below.</heading>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd351f3a9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd351f3aa-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330(a) contains the standard of compensation adopted in H.R. 8200 as passed by the House rather than the contrary standard contained in the Senate amendment. Attorneys’ fees in bankruptcy cases can be quite large and should be closely examined by the court. However bankruptcy legal services are entitled to command the same competency of counsel as other cases. In that light, the policy of this section is to compensate attorneys and other professionals serving in a case under title 11 at the same rate as the attorney or other professional would be compensated for performing comparable services other than in a case under title 11. Contrary language in the Senate report accompanying S. 2266 is rejected, and <i>Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Company v. Brock</i>, 405 F.2d 429, 432 (5th Cir. 1968) is overruled. Notions of economy of the estate in fixing fees are outdated and have no place in a bankruptcy code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330(a)(2) of the Senate amendment is deleted although the Securities and Exchange Commission retains a right to file an advisory report under section 1109.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330(b) of the Senate amendment is deleted as unnecessary, as the limitations contained therein are covered by section 328(c) of H.R. 8200 as passed by the House and contained in the House amendment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330(c) of the Senate amendment providing for a trustee to receive a fee of $20 for each estate from the filing fee paid to the clerk is retained as section 330(b) of the House amendment. The section will encourage private trustees to serve in cases under title 11 and in pilot districts will place less of a burden on the U.S. trustee to serve in no-asset cases.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330(b) of H.R. 8200 as passed by the House is retained by the House amendment as section 330(c) [section 15330].</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd351f3ab-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330 authorizes the court to award compensation for services and reimbursement of expenses of officers of the estate, and other professionals. The compensation is to be reasonable, for economy in administration is the basic objective. Compensation is to be for actual necessary services, based on the time spent, the nature, the extent and the value of the services rendered, and the cost of comparable services in nonbankruptcy cases. There are the criteria that have been applied by the courts as analytic aids in defining “reasonable” compensation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reference to “the cost of comparable services” in a nonbankruptcy case is not intended as a change of existing law. In a bankruptcy case fees are not a matter for private agreement. There is inherent a “public interest” that “must be considered in awarding fees,” <i>Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Co. v. Brock</i>, 405 F.2d 429, 432 (C.A.5, 1968), cert. denied, 395 U.S. 906 (1969). An allowance is the result of a balance struck between moderation in the interest of the estate and its security holders and the need to be “generous enough to encourage” lawyers and others to render the necessary and exacting services that bankruptcy cases often require. <i>In re Yale Express System, Inc</i>., 366 F.Supp. 1376, 1381 (S.D.N.Y. 1973). The rates for similar kinds of services in private employment is one element, among others, in that balance. Compensation in private employment noted in subsection (a) is a point of reference, not a controlling determinant of what shall be allowed in bankruptcy cases.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">One of the major reforms in 1938, especially for reorganization cases, was centralized control over fees in the bankruptcy courts. See <i>Brown v. Gerdes</i>, 321 U.S. 178, 182–184 (1944); <i>Leiman v. Guttman</i>, 336 U.S. 1, 4–9 (1949). It was intended to guard against a recurrence of “the many sordid chapters” in “the history of fees in corporate reorganizations.” <i>Dickinson Industrial Site, Inc. v. Cowan</i>, 309 U.S. 382, 388 (1940). In the years since then the bankruptcy bar has flourished and prospered, and persons of merit and quality have not eschewed public service in bankruptcy cases merely because bankruptcy courts, in the interest of economy in administration, have not allowed them compensation that may be earned in the private economy of business or the professions. There is no reason to believe that, in generations to come, their successors will be less persuaded by the need to serve in the public interest because of stronger allures of private gain elsewhere.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) provides for compensation of paraprofessionals in order to reduce the cost of administering bankruptcy cases. Paraprofessionals can be employed to perform duties which do not require the full range of skills of a qualified professional. Some courts have not hesitated to recognize paraprofessional services as compensable under existing law. An explicit provision to that effect is useful and constructive.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The last sentence of subsection (a) provides that in the case of a public company—defined in section 1101(3)—the court shall refer, after a hearing, all applications to the Securities and Exchange Commission for a report, which shall be advisory only. In Chapter X cases in which the Commission has appeared, it generally filed reports on fee applications. Usually, courts have accorded the SEC’s views substantial weight, as representing the opinion of a disinterested agency skilled and experienced in reorganization affairs. The last sentence intends for the advisory assistance of the Commission to be sought only in case of a public company in reorganization under chapter 11.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) reenacts section 249 of Chapter X of the Bankruptcy Act ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s649">11 U.S.C. 649</ref>). It is a codification of equitable principles designed to prevent fiduciaries in the case from engaging in the specified transactions since they are in a position to gain inside information or to shape or influence the course of the reorganization. <i>Wolf v. Weinstein</i>, 372 U.S. 633 (1963). The statutory bar of compensation and reimbursement is based on the principle that such transactions involve conflicts of interest. Private gain undoubtedly prompts the purchase or sale of claims or stock interests, while the fiduciary’s obligation is to render loyal and disinterested service which his position of trust has imposed upon him. Subsection (b) extends to a trustee, his attorney, committees and their attorneys, or any other persons “acting in the case in a representative or fiduciary capacity.” It bars compensation to any of the foregoing, who after assuming to act in such capacity has purchased or sold, directly or indirectly, claims against, or stock in the debtor. The bar is absolute. It makes no difference whether the transaction brought a gain or loss, or neither, and the court is not authorized to approve a purchase or sale, before or after the transaction. The exception is for an acquisition or transfer “otherwise” than by a voluntary purchase or sale, such as an acquisition by bequest. See <i>Otis &amp; Co. v. Insurance Bldg. Corp</i>., 110 F.2d 333, 335 (C.A.1, 1940).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) [enacted as (b)] is intended for no asset liquidation cases where minimal compensation for trustees is needed. The sum of $20 will be allowed in each case, which is double the amount provided under current law.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd351f3ac-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 330 authorizes compensation for services and reimbursement of expenses of officers of the estate. It also prescribes the standards on which the amount of compensation is to be determined. As noted above, the compensation allowable under this section is subject to the maxima set out in sections 326, 328, and 329. The compensation is to be reasonable, for actual necessary services rendered, based on the time, the nature, the extent, and the value of the services rendered, and on the cost of comparable services other than in a case under the bankruptcy code. The effect of the last provision is to overrule <i>In re Beverly Crest Convalescent Hospital, Inc</i>., 548 F.2d 817 (9th Cir. 1976, as amended 1977), which set an arbitrary limit on fees payable based on the amount of a district judge’s salary, and other, similar cases that require fees to be determined based on notions of conservation of the estate and economy of administration. If that case were allowed to stand, attorneys that could earn much higher incomes in other fields would leave the bankruptcy arena. Bankruptcy specialists, who enable the system to operate smoothly, efficiently, and expeditiously, would be driven elsewhere, and the bankruptcy field would be occupied by those who could not find other work and those who practice bankruptcy law only occasionally almost as a public service. Bankruptcy fees that are lower than fees in other areas of the legal profession may operate properly when the attorneys appearing in bankruptcy cases do so intermittently, because a low fee in a small segment of a practice can be absorbed by other work. Bankruptcy specialists, however, if required to accept fees in all of their cases that are consistently lower than fees they could receive elsewhere, will not remain in the bankruptcy field.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subsection provides for reimbursement of actual, necessary expenses. It further provides for compensation of paraprofessionals employed by professional persons employed by the estate of the debtor. The provision is included to reduce the cost of administering bankruptcy cases. In nonbankruptcy areas, attorneys are able to charge for a paraprofessional’s time on an hourly basis, and not include it in overhead. If a similar practice does not pertain in bankruptcy cases then the attorney will be less inclined to use paraprofessionals even where the work involved could easily be handled by an attorney’s assistant, at much lower cost to the estate. This provision is designed to encourage attorneys to use paraprofessional assistance where possible, and to insure that the estate, not the attorney, will bear the cost, to the benefit of both the estate and the attorneys involved.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd351f3ad-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd351f3ae-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Bankruptcy Reform Act of 1994, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, which was approved <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd351f3af-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2026—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 119–76, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “$105” for “$45”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 119–76, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which created the Chapter 7 Trustee Fund and explained its usage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/325">Pub. L. 116–325</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/43">Pub. L. 117–43</ref> struck out “in that fiscal year” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1104/b/1">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1104(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “an ombudsman appointed under section 333, or” before “a professional person” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s232/b">Pub. L. 109–8, § 232(b)</ref>, inserted “a consumer privacy ombudsman appointed under section 332,” before “an examiner” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1104/b/2">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1104(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “ombudsman,” before “professional person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s407/1">Pub. L. 109–8, § 407(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “In” for “(A) In” and inserted “to an examiner, trustee under chapter 11, or professional person” after “awarded”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s415">Pub. L. 109–8, § 415</ref>, added subpar. (E) and redesignated former subpar. (E) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s407/2">Pub. L. 109–8, § 407(2)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s224/b">Pub. L. 103–394, § 224(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “After notice to any parties in interest and to the United States trustee and a hearing, and subject to sections 326, 328, and 329 of this title, the court may award to a trustee, to an examiner, to a professional person employed under section 327 or 1103 of this title, or to the debtor’s attorney—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) reasonable compensation for actual, necessary services rendered by such trustee, examiner, professional person, or attorney, as the case may be, and by any paraprofessional persons employed by such trustee, professional person, or attorney, as the case may be, based on the nature, the extent, and the value of such services, the time spent on such services, and the cost of comparable services other than in a case under this title; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) reimbursement for actual, necessary expenses.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s117">Pub. L. 103–394, § 117</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s211/1">Pub. L. 99–554, § 211(1)</ref>, inserted “to any parties in interest and to the United States trustee” after “notice”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s257/f">Pub. L. 99–554, § 257(f)</ref>, inserted reference to chapter 12.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s211/2">Pub. L. 99–554, § 211(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s433/1">Pub. L. 98–353, § 433(1)</ref>, struck out “to any parties in interest and to the United States trustee” after “After notice”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s433/2">Pub. L. 98–353, § 433(2)</ref>, substituted “nature, the extent, and the value of such services, the time spent on such services” for “time, the nature, the extent, and the value of such services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s434/a">Pub. L. 98–353, § 434(a)</ref>, substituted “$45” for “$20”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s434/b">Pub. L. 98–353, § 434(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd351f3b0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2026 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s6">Pub. L. 119–76, § 6</ref>, <date date="2026-02-06">Feb. 6, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/743">140 Stat. 743</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dI/s5018/b/1">Pub. L. 119–75, div. I, § 5018(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/632">140 Stat. 632</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/75/dI/s5018/b/1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the amendments made by this Act [amending this section and sections 589a and 1930 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, and amending provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s152">section 152 of Title 28</ref>] shall take effect on the first day of the calendar quarter that first occurs on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2026-02-06">Feb. 6, 2026</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compensation of officers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Section 3 [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s589a">section 589a of Title 28</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1930">section 1930 of Title 28</ref>] and the amendments made by section 3 shall apply to any case under title 11, United States Code, commenced on or after October 1 that first occurs after the date of enactment of this Act—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> under chapter 7 of title 11, United States Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> under chapter 11, 12, or 13 of title 11, United States Code, that is converted to a case under chapter 7 of title 11, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bankruptcy fees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Section 4 [amending sections 589a and 1930 of Title 28 and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s589a">section 589a of Title 28</ref>] and the amendments made by section 4 shall apply to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any case commenced or pending under chapter 11 of title 11, United States Code, on or after the first day of the calendar quarter that first occurs on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2026-02-06">Feb. 6, 2026</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> quarterly fees payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1930/a/6">section 1930(a)(6) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, as amended by section 4, for disbursements made in any calendar quarter that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dI/s5018/b/2">Pub. L. 119–75, div. I, § 5018(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/632">140 Stat. 632</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/75/dI/s5018/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/119/76/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 119–76</ref>, set out above] shall take effect as though enacted immediately after the enactment of the Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act of 2025 [<ref href="/us/pl/119/76">Pub. L. 119–76</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/325/s3/e">Pub. L. 116–325, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-12">Jan. 12, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5088">134 Stat. 5088</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/325/s3/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 589a and 1930 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-12">Jan. 12, 2021</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compensation of officers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by subsection (c) [amending this section] shall apply to any case filed on or after the date of enactment of this Act—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> under chapter 7 of title 11, United States Code; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> under chapter 11, 12, or 13 of that title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> converted to a chapter 7 case under that title.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bankruptcy fees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by subsection (d) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1930">section 1930 of Title 28</ref>] shall apply to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> any case pending under chapter 11 of title 11, United States Code, on or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> quarterly fees payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1930/a/6">section 1930(a)(6) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, as amended by subsection (d), for disbursements made in any calendar quarter that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s117">section 117 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before, on, and after <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s224/b">section 224(b) of Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective date and applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s211">section 211 of Pub. L. 99–554</ref> dependent upon the judicial district involved, see section 302(d), (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s581">section 581 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s257">section 257 of Pub. L. 99–554</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, but not applicable to cases commenced under this title before that date, see section 302(a), (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd351f3b6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
