<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd351f3cb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333"><num value="333">§ 333.</num><heading> Appointment of patient care ombudsman</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3cc-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3cd-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the debtor in a case under chapter 7, 9, or 11 is a health care business, the court shall order, not later than 30 days after the commencement of the case, the appointment of an ombudsman to monitor the quality of patient care and to represent the interests of the patients of the health care business unless the court finds that the appointment of such ombudsman is not necessary for the protection of patients under the specific facts of the case.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3ce-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3cf-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If the court orders the appointment of an ombudsman under paragraph (1), the United States trustee shall appoint 1 disinterested person (other than the United States trustee) to serve as such ombudsman.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the debtor is a health care business that provides long-term care, then the United States trustee may appoint the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman appointed under the Older Americans Act of 1965 for the State in which the case is pending to serve as the ombudsman required by paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If the United States trustee does not appoint a State Long-Term Care Ombudsman under subparagraph (B), the court shall notify the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman appointed under the Older Americans Act of 1965 for the State in which the case is pending, of the name and address of the person who is appointed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> An ombudsman appointed under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f3d3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> monitor the quality of patient care provided to patients of the debtor, to the extent necessary under the circumstances, including interviewing patients and physicians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f3d4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than 60 days after the date of appointment, and not less frequently than at 60-day intervals thereafter, report to the court after notice to the parties in interest, at a hearing or in writing, regarding the quality of patient care provided to patients of the debtor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd351f3d5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if such ombudsman determines that the quality of patient care provided to patients of the debtor is declining significantly or is otherwise being materially compromised, file with the court a motion or a written report, with notice to the parties in interest immediately upon making such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An ombudsman appointed under subsection (a) shall maintain any information obtained by such ombudsman under this section that relates to patients (including information relating to patient records) as confidential information. Such ombudsman may not review confidential patient records unless the court approves such review in advance and imposes restrictions on such ombudsman to protect the confidentiality of such records.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd351f3d8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s333/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An ombudsman appointed under subsection (a)(2)(B) shall have access to patient records consistent with authority of such ombudsman under the Older Americans Act of 1965 and under non-Federal laws governing the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd351f3d9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tXI/s1104/a/1">Pub. L. 109–8, title XI, § 1104(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/191">119 Stat. 191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd351f3da-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd351f3db-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd351f3dc-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Older Americans Act of 1965, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2)(B), (C) and (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/73">Pub. L. 89–73</ref>, <date date="1965-07-14">July 14, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/218">79 Stat. 218</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 3001 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd35463dd-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd35463de-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2005 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
