<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd35463e0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341"><num value="341">§ 341.</num><heading> Meetings of creditors and equity security holders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd35463e1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Within a reasonable time after the order for relief in a case under this title, the United States trustee shall convene and preside at a meeting of creditors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd35463e2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The United States trustee may convene a meeting of any equity security holders.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd35463e3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The court may not preside at, and may not attend, any meeting under this section including any final meeting of creditors. Notwithstanding any local court rule, provision of a State constitution, any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, or any other requirement that representation at the meeting of creditors under subsection (a) be by an attorney, a creditor holding a consumer debt or any representative of the creditor (which may include an entity or an employee of an entity and may be a representative for more than 1 creditor) shall be permitted to appear at and participate in the meeting of creditors in a case under chapter 7 or 13, either alone or in conjunction with an attorney for the creditor. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require any creditor to be represented by an attorney at any meeting of creditors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd35463e4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> Prior to the conclusion of the meeting of creditors or equity security holders, the trustee shall orally examine the debtor to ensure that the debtor in a case under chapter 7 of this title is aware of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd35463e5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the potential consequences of seeking a discharge in bankruptcy, including the effects on credit history;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd35463e6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the debtor’s ability to file a petition under a different chapter of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd35463e7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the effect of receiving a discharge of debts under this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd35463e8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the effect of reaffirming a debt, including the debtor’s knowledge of the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s524/d">section 524(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd35463e9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s341/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), the court, on the request of a party in interest and after notice and a hearing, for cause may order that the United States trustee not convene a meeting of creditors or equity security holders if the debtor has filed a plan as to which the debtor solicited acceptances prior to the commencement of the case.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd35463ea-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2564">92 Stat. 2564</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/tII/s212">Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3099">100 Stat. 3099</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tI/s115">Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4118">108 Stat. 4118</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tIV">Pub. L. 109–8, title IV</ref>, §§ 402, 413, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/104">119 Stat. 104</ref>, 107.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd35463eb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd35463ec-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd35463ed-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 341(c) of the Senate amendment is deleted and a contrary provision is added indicating that the bankruptcy judge will not preside at or attend the first meeting of creditors or equity security holders but a discharge hearing for all individuals will be held at which the judge will preside.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd35463ee-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section [Subsection] (a) of this section requires that there be a meeting of creditors within a reasonable time after the order for relief in the case. The Bankruptcy Act [former title 11] and the current Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure provide for a meeting of creditors, and specify the time and manner of the meeting, and the business to be conducted. This bill leaves those matters to the rules. Under section 405(d) of the bill, the present rules will continue to govern until new rules are promulgated. Thus, pending the adoption of different rules, the present procedure for the meeting will continue.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) authorizes the court to order a meeting of equity security holders in cases where such a meeting would be beneficial or useful, for example, in a chapter 11 reorganization case where it may be necessary for the equity security holders to organize in order to be able to participate in the negotiation of a plan of reorganization.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) makes clear that the bankruptcy judge is to preside at the meeting of creditors.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd35463ef-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd35463f0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s413">Pub. L. 109–8, § 413</ref>, inserted at end “Notwithstanding any local court rule, provision of a State constitution, any otherwise applicable nonbankruptcy law, or any other requirement that representation at the meeting of creditors under subsection (a) be by an attorney, a creditor holding a consumer debt or any representative of the creditor (which may include an entity or an employee of an entity and may be a representative for more than 1 creditor) shall be permitted to appear at and participate in the meeting of creditors in a case under chapter 7 or 13, either alone or in conjunction with an attorney for the creditor. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require any creditor to be represented by an attorney at any meeting of creditors.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s402">Pub. L. 109–8, § 402</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s212/1">Pub. L. 99–554, § 212(1)</ref>, substituted “the United States trustee shall convene and preside at a meeting of creditors” for “there shall be a meeting of creditors”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s212/2">Pub. L. 99–554, § 212(2)</ref>, substituted “United States trustee may convene” for “court may order”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s212/3">Pub. L. 99–554, § 212(3)</ref>, inserted “including any final meeting of creditors”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd35463f1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd35463f2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd35463f3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd35463f4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective date and applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref> dependent upon the judicial district involved, see section 302(d), (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s581">section 581 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd35463f5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Participation by Bankruptcy Administrator at Meetings of Creditors and Equity Security Holders</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tI/s105">Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4111">108 Stat. 4111</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/394/tI/s105">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presiding Officer</inline>.—</heading><content>A bankruptcy administrator appointed under section 302(d)(3)(I) of the Bankruptcy Judges, United States Trustees, and Family Farmer Bankruptcy Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t28/s581">28 U.S.C. 581</ref> note; <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Public Law 99–554</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/100/3123">100 Stat. 3123</ref>), as amended by section 317(a) of the Federal Courts Study Committee Implementation Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/650">Public Law 101–650</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/104/5115">104 Stat. 5115</ref>), or the bankruptcy administrator’s designee may preside at the meeting of creditors convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s341/a">section 341(a) of title 11</ref>, United States Code. The bankruptcy administrator or the bankruptcy administrator’s designee may preside at any meeting of equity security holders convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s341/b">section 341(b) of title 11</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Examination of the Debtor</inline>.—</heading><content>The bankruptcy administrator or the bankruptcy administrator’s designee may examine the debtor at the meeting of creditors and may administer the oath required under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s343">section 343 of title 11</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
