<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd369e7a4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503"><num value="503">§ 503.</num><heading> Allowance of administrative expenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd369e7a5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> An entity may timely file a request for payment of an administrative expense, or may tardily file such request if permitted by the court for cause.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd369e7a6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> After notice and a hearing, there shall be allowed administrative expenses, other than claims allowed under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s502/f">section 502(f) of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7a7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7a8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the actual, necessary costs and expenses of preserving the estate including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7a9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> wages, salaries, and commissions for services rendered after the commencement of the case; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7aa-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> wages and benefits awarded pursuant to a judicial proceeding or a proceeding of the National Labor Relations Board as back pay attributable to any period of time occurring after commencement of the case under this title, as a result of a violation of Federal or State law by the debtor, without regard to the time of the occurrence of unlawful conduct on which such award is based or to whether any services were rendered, if the court determines that payment of wages and benefits by reason of the operation of this clause will not substantially increase the probability of layoff or termination of current employees, or of nonpayment of domestic support obligations, during the case under this title;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7ab-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any tax—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7ac-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> incurred by the estate, whether secured or unsecured, including property taxes for which liability is in rem, in personam, or both, except a tax of a kind specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s507/a/8">section 507(a)(8) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7ad-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> attributable to an excessive allowance of a tentative carryback adjustment that the estate received, whether the taxable year to which such adjustment relates ended before or after the commencement of the case;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7ae-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any fine, penalty, or reduction in credit relating to a tax of a kind specified in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7af-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> notwithstanding the requirements of subsection (a), a governmental unit shall not be required to file a request for the payment of an expense described in subparagraph (B) or (C), as a condition of its being an allowed administrative expense;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7b0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> compensation and reimbursement awarded under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s330/a">section 330(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7b1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the actual, necessary expenses, other than compensation and reimbursement specified in paragraph (4) of this subsection, incurred by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a creditor that files a petition under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s303">section 303 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a creditor that recovers, after the court’s approval, for the benefit of the estate any property transferred or concealed by the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a creditor in connection with the prosecution of a criminal offense relating to the case or to the business or property of the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a creditor, an indenture trustee, an equity security holder, or a committee representing creditors or equity security holders other than a committee appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1102">section 1102 of this title</ref>, in making a substantial contribution in a case under chapter 9 or 11 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a custodian superseded under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s543">section 543 of this title</ref>, and compensation for the services of such custodian; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7b7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> a member of a committee appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s1102">section 1102 of this title</ref>, if such expenses are incurred in the performance of the duties of such committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7b8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> reasonable compensation for professional services rendered by an attorney or an accountant of an entity whose expense is allowable under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of paragraph (3) of this subsection, based on the time, the nature, the extent, and the value of such services, and the cost of comparable services other than in a case under this title, and reimbursement for actual, necessary expenses incurred by such attorney or accountant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7b9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> reasonable compensation for services rendered by an indenture trustee in making a substantial contribution in a case under chapter 9 or 11 of this title, based on the time, the nature, the extent, and the value of such services, and the cost of comparable services other than in a case under this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7ba-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the fees and mileage payable under chapter 119 of title 28;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7bb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> with respect to a nonresidential real property lease previously assumed under section 365, and subsequently rejected, a sum equal to all monetary obligations due, excluding those arising from or relating to a failure to operate or a penalty provision, for the period of 2 years following the later of the rejection date or the date of actual turnover of the premises, without reduction or setoff for any reason whatsoever except for sums actually received or to be received from an entity other than the debtor, and the claim for remaining sums due for the balance of the term of the lease shall be a claim under section 502(b)(6);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7bc-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> the actual, necessary costs and expenses of closing a health care business incurred by a trustee or by a Federal agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551/1">section 551(1) of title 5</ref>) or a department or agency of a State or political subdivision thereof, including any cost or expense incurred—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7bd-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in disposing of patient records in accordance with section 351; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7be-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in connection with transferring patients from the health care business that is in the process of being closed to another health care business; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7bf-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the value of any goods received by the debtor within 20 days before the date of commencement of a case under this title in which the goods have been sold to the debtor in the ordinary course of such debtor’s business.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd369e7c0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (b), there shall neither be allowed, nor paid—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7c1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> a transfer made to, or an obligation incurred for the benefit of, an insider of the debtor for the purpose of inducing such person to remain with the debtor’s business, absent a finding by the court based on evidence in the record that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7c2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transfer or obligation is essential to retention of the person because the individual has a bona fide job offer from another business at the same or greater rate of compensation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7c3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the services provided by the person are essential to the survival of the business; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7c4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd369e7c5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of the transfer made to, or obligation incurred for the benefit of, the person is not greater than an amount equal to 10 times the amount of the mean transfer or obligation of a similar kind given to nonmanagement employees for any purpose during the calendar year in which the transfer is made or the obligation is incurred; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd369e7c6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if no such similar transfers were made to, or obligations were incurred for the benefit of, such nonmanagement employees during such calendar year, the amount of the transfer or obligation is not greater than an amount equal to 25 percent of the amount of any similar transfer or obligation made to or incurred for the benefit of such insider for any purpose during the calendar year before the year in which such transfer is made or obligation is incurred;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7c7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> a severance payment to an insider of the debtor, unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7c8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the payment is part of a program that is generally applicable to all full-time employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd369e7c9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the payment is not greater than 10 times the amount of the mean severance pay given to nonmanagement employees during the calendar year in which the payment is made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd369e7ca-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s503/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> other transfers or obligations that are outside the ordinary course of business and not justified by the facts and circumstances of the case, including transfers made to, or obligations incurred for the benefit of, officers, managers, or consultants hired after the date of the filing of the petition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd369e7cb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2581">92 Stat. 2581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s446">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 446</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/374">98 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/tII/s283/g">Pub. L. 99–554, title II, § 283(g)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3117">100 Stat. 3117</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tI/s110">Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 110</ref>, title II, § 213(c), title III, § 304(h)(2), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4113">108 Stat. 4113</ref>, 4126, 4134; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tIII">Pub. L. 109–8, title III</ref>, §§ 329, 331, title IV, § 445, title VII, § 712(b), (c), title XI, § 1103, title XII, §§ 1208, 1227(b), <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/101">119 Stat. 101</ref>, 102, 117, 128, 190, 194, 200; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/tIII/s320/b">Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title III, § 320(b)</ref>, (f)(2)(A)(ii), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2015">134 Stat. 2015</ref>, 2016.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd369e7cc-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd369e7cd-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd369e7ce-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 503(a) of the House amendment represents a compromise between similar provisions in the House bill and the Senate amendment by leaving to the Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure the determination of the location at which a request for payment of an administrative expense may be filed. The preamble to section 503(b) of the House bill makes a similar change with respect to the allowance of administrative expenses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 503(b)(1) adopts the approach taken in the House bill as modified by some provisions contained in the Senate amendment. The preamble to section 503(b) makes clear that none of the paragraphs of section 503(b) apply to claims or expenses of the kind specified in section 502(f) that arise in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business or financial affairs and that arise during the gap between the commencement of an involuntary case and the appointment of a trustee or the order for relief, whichever first occurs. The remainder of section 503(b) represents a compromise between H.R. 8200 as passed by the House and the Senate amendments. Section 503(b)(3)(E) codifies present law in cases such as <i>Randolph v. Scruggs</i>, 190 U.S. 533, which accords administrative expense status to services rendered by a prepetition custodian or other party to the extent such services actually benefit the estate. Section 503(b)(4) of the House amendment conforms to the provision contained in H.R. 8200 as passed by the House and deletes language contained in the Senate amendment providing a different standard of compensation under section 330 of that amendment.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd369e7cf-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) of this section permits administrative expense claimants to file with the court a request for payment of an administrative expense. The Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure will specify the time, the form, and the method of such a filing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) specifies the kinds of administrative expenses that are allowable in a case under the bankruptcy code. The subsection is derived mainly from section 64a(1) of the Bankruptcy Act [section 104(a)(1) of former title 11], with some changes. The actual, necessary costs and expenses of preserving the estate, including wages, salaries, or commissions for services rendered after the order for relief, and any taxes on, measured by, or withheld from such wages, salaries, or commissions, are allowable as administrative expenses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In general, administrative expenses include taxes which the trustee incurs in administering the debtor’s estate, including taxes on capital gains from sales of property by the trustee and taxes on income earned by the estate during the case. Interest on tax liabilities and certain tax penalties incurred by the trustee are also included in this first priority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Taxes which the Internal Revenue Service may find due after giving the trustee a so-called “quickie” tax refund and later doing an audit of the refund are also payable as administrative expenses. The tax code [title 26] permits the trustee of an estate which suffers a net operating loss to carry back the loss against an earlier profit year of the estate or of the debtor and to obtain a tentative refund for the earlier year, subject, however, to a later full audit of the loss which led to the refund. The bill, in effect, requires the Internal Revenue Service to issue a tentative refund to the trustee (whether the refund was applied for by the debtor or by the trustee), but if the refund later proves to have been erroneous in amount, the Service can request that the tax attributable to the erroneous refund be payable by the estate as an administrative expense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Postpetition payments to an individual debtor for services rendered to the estate are administrative expenses, and are not property of the estate when received by the debtor. This situation would most likely arise when the individual was a sole proprietor and was employed by the estate to run the business after the commencement of the case. An individual debtor in possession would be so employed, for example. See <i>Local Loan v. Hunt</i>, 292 U.S. 234, 243 (1943).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Compensation and reimbursement awarded officers of the estate under section 330 are allowable as administrative expenses. Actual, necessary expenses, other than compensation of a professional person, incurred by a creditor that files an involuntary petition, by a creditor that recovers property for the benefit of the estate, by a creditor that acts in connection with the prosecution of a criminal offense relating to the case, by a creditor, indenture, trustee, equity security holder, or committee of creditors or equity security holders (other than official committees) that makes a substantial contribution to a reorganization or municipal debt adjustment case, or by a superseded custodian, are all allowable administrative expenses. The phrase “substantial contribution in the case” is derived from Bankruptcy Act §§ 242 and 243 [sections 642 and 643 of former title 11]. It does not require a contribution that leads to confirmation of a plan, for in many cases, it will be a substantial contribution if the person involved uncovers facts that would lead to a denial of confirmation, such as fraud in connection with the case.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (4) permits reasonable compensation for professional services rendered by an attorney or an accountant of an equity whose expense is compensable under the previous paragraph. Paragraph (5) permits reasonable compensation for an indenture trustee in making a substantial contribution in a reorganization or municipal debt adjustment case. Finally, paragraph (6) permits witness fees and mileage as prescribed under chapter 119 [§ 2041 et seq.] of title 28.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd369e7d0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd369e7d1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s320/f/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–260, § 320(f)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, contingent on its addition by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s320/b">Pub. L. 116–260, § 320(b)</ref>, struck out par. (10) which read as follows: “any debt incurred under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s364/g/1">section 364(g)(1) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s320/b">Pub. L. 116–260, § 320(b)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s329">Pub. L. 109–8, § 329</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “the actual, necessary costs and expenses of preserving the estate, including wages, salaries, or commissions for services rendered after the commencement of the case;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s712/b">Pub. L. 109–8, § 712(b)</ref>, inserted “whether secured or unsecured, including property taxes for which liability is in rem, in personam, or both,” before “except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s712/c">Pub. L. 109–8, § 712(c)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1208">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1208</ref>, inserted “subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of” before “paragraph (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s445">Pub. L. 109–8, § 445</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1103">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1103</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1227/b">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1227(b)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s331">Pub. L. 109–8, § 331</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s213/c">Pub. L. 103–394, § 213(c)</ref>, inserted “timely” after “may” and “, or may tardily file such request if permitted by the court for cause” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s304/h/2">Pub. L. 103–394, § 304(h)(2)</ref>, substituted “507(a)(8)” for “507(a)(7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s110">Pub. L. 103–394, § 110</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s283/g/1">Pub. L. 99–554, § 283(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “507(a)(7)” for “507(a)(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s283/g/2">Pub. L. 99–554, § 283(g)(2)</ref>, inserted “and” after “title;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s283/g/3">Pub. L. 99–554, § 283(g)(3)</ref>, substituted a period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/1">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(1)</ref>, struck out the comma after “be allowed” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/2">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(2)</ref>, struck out the comma after “credit”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/3">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(3)</ref>, inserted “(a)” after “330”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/4">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(4)</ref>, inserted a comma after “paragraph (4) of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/5">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(5)</ref>, struck out the comma after “case”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/6">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(6)</ref>, struck out “and” after “title;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s446/7">Pub. L. 98–353, § 446(7)</ref>, substituted “; and” for period at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd369e7d2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd369e7d3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/s320/b">section 320(b) of div. N of Pub. L. 116–260</ref> effective on the date on which the Administrator of the Small Business Administration submits to the Director of the Executive Office for United States Trustees a written determination relating to loan eligibility under pars. (36) and (37) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">section 636(a) of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, and applicable to any case pending on or commenced on or after such date, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/s320/f/2/A/ii">section 320(f)(2)(A)(ii) of div. N of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, relating to repeal of such amendment if it became effective, effective two years after <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s320/f">section 320(f) of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s364">section 364 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">[Pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a/36/A/iii">15 U.S.C. 636(a)(36)(A)(iii)</ref>, the “covered period” for loans under the Paycheck Protection Program ended on <date date="2021-06-30">June 30, 2021</date>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd369e7d4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd369e7d5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd369e7d6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/554">Pub. L. 99–554</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/554/s302/a">section 302(a) of Pub. L. 99–554</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s581">section 581 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd369e7d7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
