<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd37cfb4b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525"><num value="525">§ 525.</num><heading> Protection against discriminatory treatment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb4c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except as provided in the Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1930, the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, and section 1 of the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the Department of Agriculture for the fiscal year ending <date date="1944-06-30">June 30, 1944</date>, and for other purposes,” approved <date date="1943-07-12">July 12, 1943</date>, a governmental unit may not deny, revoke, suspend, or refuse to renew a license, permit, charter, franchise, or other similar grant to, condition such a grant to, discriminate with respect to such a grant against, deny employment to, terminate the employment of, or discriminate with respect to employment against, a person that is or has been a debtor under this title or a bankrupt or a debtor under the Bankruptcy Act, or another person with whom such bankrupt or debtor has been associated, solely because such bankrupt or debtor is or has been a debtor under this title or a bankrupt or debtor under the Bankruptcy Act, has been insolvent before the commencement of the case under this title, or during the case but before the debtor is granted or denied a discharge, or has not paid a debt that is dischargeable in the case under this title or that was discharged under the Bankruptcy Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb4d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> No private employer may terminate the employment of, or discriminate with respect to employment against, an individual who is or has been a debtor under this title, a debtor or bankrupt under the Bankruptcy Act, or an individual associated with such debtor or bankrupt, solely because such debtor or bankrupt—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb4e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is or has been a debtor under this title or a debtor or bankrupt under the Bankruptcy Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb4f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has been insolvent before the commencement of a case under this title or during the case but before the grant or denial of a discharge; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb50-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has not paid a debt that is dischargeable in a case under this title or that was discharged under the Bankruptcy Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb51-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb52-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A governmental unit that operates a student grant or loan program and a person engaged in a business that includes the making of loans guaranteed or insured under a student loan program may not deny a student grant, loan, loan guarantee, or loan insurance to a person that is or has been a debtor under this title or a bankrupt or debtor under the Bankruptcy Act, or another person with whom the debtor or bankrupt has been associated, because the debtor or bankrupt is or has been a debtor under this title or a bankrupt or debtor under the Bankruptcy Act, has been insolvent before the commencement of a case under this title or during the pendency of the case but before the debtor is granted or denied a discharge, or has not paid a debt that is dischargeable in the case under this title or that was discharged under the Bankruptcy Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb53-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s525/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In this section, “student loan program” means any program operated under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 or a similar program operated under State or local law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd37cfb54-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2593">92 Stat. 2593</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/354">98 Stat. 354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tIII/s313">Pub. L. 103–394, title III, § 313</ref>, title V, § 501(d)(15), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4140">108 Stat. 4140</ref>, 4145; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tXII/s1211">Pub. L. 109–8, title XII, § 1211</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/194">119 Stat. 194</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tX/s1001/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title X, § 1001(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3217">134 Stat. 3217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd37cfb55-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd37cfb56-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd37cfb57-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is additional debtor protection. It codifies the result of <i>Perez v. Campbell</i>, 402 U.S. 637 (1971), which held that a State would frustrate the Congressional policy of a fresh start for a debtor if it were permitted to refuse to renew a drivers license because a tort judgment resulting from an automobile accident had been unpaid as a result of a discharge in bankruptcy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other laws, section 525 prohibits a governmental unit from denying, revoking, suspending, or refusing to renew a license, permit, charter, franchise, or other similar grant to, from conditioning such a grant to, from discrimination with respect to such a grant against, deny employment to, terminate the employment of, or discriminate with respect to employment against, a person that is or has been a debtor or that is or has been associated with a debtor. The prohibition extends only to discrimination or other action based solely on the basis of the bankruptcy, on the basis of insolvency before or during bankruptcy prior to a determination of discharge, or on the basis of nonpayment of a debt discharged in the bankruptcy case (the <i>Perez</i> situation). It does not prohibit consideration of other factors, such as future financial responsibility or ability, and does not prohibit imposition of requirements such as net capital rules, if applied nondiscriminatorily.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In addition, the section is not exhaustive. The enumeration of various forms of discrimination against former bankrupts is not intended to permit other forms of discrimination. The courts have been developing the <i>Perez</i> rule. This section permits further development to prohibit actions by governmental or quasi-governmental organizations that perform licensing functions, such as a State bar association or a medical society, or by other organizations that can seriously affect the debtors’ livelihood or fresh start, such as exclusion from a union on the basis of discharge of a debt to the union’s credit union.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effect of the section, and of further interpretations of the <i>Perez</i> rule, is to strengthen the anti-reaffirmation policy found in section 524(b). Discrimination based solely on nonpayment could encourage reaffirmations, contrary to the expressed policy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The section is not so broad as a comparable section proposed by the Bankruptcy Commission, S. 236, 94th Cong., 1st Sess. § 4–508 (1975), which would have extended the prohibition to any discrimination, even by private parties. Nevertheless, it is not limiting either, as noted. The courts will continue to mark the contours of the anti-discrimination provision in pursuit of sound bankruptcy policy.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd37cfb58-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd37cfb59-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1930, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-10/ch436">act June 10, 1930, ch. 436</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/531">46 Stat. 531</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 20A (§ 499a et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499a/a">section 499a(a) of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1921-08-15/ch64">act Aug. 15, 1921, ch. 64</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/159">42 Stat. 159</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 9 (§ 181 et seq.) of Title 7. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s181">section 181 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1 of the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the Department of Agriculture for the fiscal year ending <date date="1944-06-30">June 30, 1944</date>, and for other purposes,” approved <date date="1943-07-12">July 12, 1943</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s204">section 204 of Title 7</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Bankruptcy Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1898-07-01/ch541">act July 1, 1898, ch. 541</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/544">30 Stat. 544</ref>, which was classified generally to former Title 11.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1219">79 Stat. 1219</ref>. Title IV of the Act is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 1070 et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd37cfb5a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s1001/c/2">Pub. L. 116–260, § 1001(c)(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which read as follows: “A person may not be denied relief under sections 4022 through 4024 of the CARES Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9056">15 U.S.C. 9056</ref>, 9057, 9058) because the person is or has been a debtor under this title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s1001/c/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 1001(c)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1211/1">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1211(1)</ref>, inserted “student” before “grant, loan,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1211/2">Pub. L. 109–8, § 1211(2)</ref>, substituted “any program operated under” for “the program operated under part B, D, or E of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s501/d/15">Pub. L. 103–394, § 501(d)(15)</ref>, struck out “(<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499a–499s">7 U.S.C. 499a–499s</ref>)” after “Act, 1930”, “(<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s181–229">7 U.S.C. 181–229</ref>)” after “Act, 1921”, and “(<ref href="/us/stat/57/422">57 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s204">7 U.S.C. 204</ref>)” after “<date date="1943-07-12">July 12, 1943</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s313">Pub. L. 103–394, § 313</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted “the” before “Perishable”, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd37cfb5b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd37cfb5c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tX/s1001/c/2">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title X, § 1001(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3217">134 Stat. 3217</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1001(c)(2) is effective on the date that is 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd37cfb5d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd37cfb5e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd37cfb5f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
