<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd37cfb60-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526"><num value="526">§ 526.</num><heading> Restrictions on debt relief agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb61-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> A debt relief agency shall not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb62-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> fail to perform any service that such agency informed an assisted person or prospective assisted person it would provide in connection with a case or proceeding under this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb63-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make any statement, or counsel or advise any assisted person or prospective assisted person to make a statement in a document filed in a case or proceeding under this title, that is untrue or misleading, or that upon the exercise of reasonable care, should have been known by such agency to be untrue or misleading;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb64-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> misrepresent to any assisted person or prospective assisted person, directly or indirectly, affirmatively or by material omission, with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd37cfb65-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the services that such agency will provide to such person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd37cfb66-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the benefits and risks that may result if such person becomes a debtor in a case under this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37cfb67-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> advise an assisted person or prospective assisted person to incur more debt in contemplation of such person filing a case under this title or to pay an attorney or bankruptcy petition preparer a fee or charge for services performed as part of preparing for or representing a debtor in a case under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37cfb68-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any waiver by any assisted person of any protection or right provided under this section shall not be enforceable against the debtor by any Federal or State court or any other person, but may be enforced against a debt relief agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f4459-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f445a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any contract for bankruptcy assistance between a debt relief agency and an assisted person that does not comply with the material requirements of this section, section 527, or section 528 shall be void and may not be enforced by any Federal or State court or by any other person, other than such assisted person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f445b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any debt relief agency shall be liable to an assisted person in the amount of any fees or charges in connection with providing bankruptcy assistance to such person that such debt relief agency has received, for actual damages, and for reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs if such agency is found, after notice and a hearing, to have—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f445c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> intentionally or negligently failed to comply with any provision of this section, section 527, or section 528 with respect to a case or proceeding under this title for such assisted person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f445d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provided bankruptcy assistance to an assisted person in a case or proceeding under this title that is dismissed or converted to a case under another chapter of this title because of such agency’s intentional or negligent failure to file any required document including those specified in section 521; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f445e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> intentionally or negligently disregarded the material requirements of this title or the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure applicable to such agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f445f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In addition to such other remedies as are provided under State law, whenever the chief law enforcement officer of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating this section, the State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4460-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may bring an action to enjoin such violation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4461-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may bring an action on behalf of its residents to recover the actual damages of assisted persons arising from such violation, including any liability under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4462-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of any successful action under subparagraph (A) or (B), shall be awarded the costs of the action and reasonable attorneys’ fees as determined by the court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f4463-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The district courts of the United States for districts located in the State shall have concurrent jurisdiction of any action under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f4464-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law and in addition to any other remedy provided under Federal or State law, if the court, on its own motion or on the motion of the United States trustee or the debtor, finds that a person intentionally violated this section, or engaged in a clear and consistent pattern or practice of violating this section, the court may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4465-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enjoin the violation of such section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4466-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> impose an appropriate civil penalty against such person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd37f4467-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> No provision of this section, section 527, or section 528 shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4468-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> annul, alter, affect, or exempt any person subject to such sections from complying with any law of any State except to the extent that such law is inconsistent with those sections, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd37f4469-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> be deemed to limit or curtail the authority or ability—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd37f446a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> of a State or subdivision or instrumentality thereof, to determine and enforce qualifications for the practice of law under the laws of that State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd37f446b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s526/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> of a Federal court to determine and enforce the qualifications for the practice of law before that court.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd37f446c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tII/s227/a">Pub. L. 109–8, title II, § 227(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/67">119 Stat. 67</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/327/s2/a/20">Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3560">124 Stat. 3560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd37f446d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd37f446e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd37f446f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure, referred to in subsec. (c)(2)(C), are set out in the Appendix to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd37f4470-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/327/s2/a/20/A">Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(20)(A)</ref>, substituted “that is untrue or” for “that is untrue and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/327/s2/a/20/B">Pub. L. 111–327, § 2(a)(20)(B)</ref>, inserted “a” after “preparer”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd37f4471-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd37f4472-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2005 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
