<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd392576b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741"><num value="741">§ 741.</num><heading> Definitions for this subchapter</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd392576c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “Commission” means Securities and Exchange Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd392576d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> “customer” includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392576e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> entity with whom a person deals as principal or agent and that has a claim against such person on account of a security received, acquired, or held by such person in the ordinary course of such person’s business as a stockbroker, from or for the securities account or accounts of such entity—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392576f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for safekeeping;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925770-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with a view to sale;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925771-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to cover a consummated sale;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925772-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> pursuant to a purchase;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925773-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> as collateral under a security agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925774-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> for the purpose of effecting registration of transfer; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925775-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> entity that has a claim against a person arising out of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925776-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a sale or conversion of a security received, acquired, or held as specified in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925777-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a deposit of cash, a security, or other property with such person for the purpose of purchasing or selling a security;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3925778-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> “customer name security” means security—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925779-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> held for the account of a customer on the date of the filing of the petition by or on behalf of the debtor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392577a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> registered in such customer’s name on such date or in the process of being so registered under instructions from the debtor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392577b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> not in a form transferable by delivery on such date;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd392577c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> “customer property” means cash, security, or other property, and proceeds of such cash, security, or property, received, acquired, or held by or for the account of the debtor, from or for the securities account of a customer—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392577d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392577e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> property that was unlawfully converted from and that is the lawful property of the estate;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392577f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a security held as property of the debtor to the extent such security is necessary to meet a net equity claim of a customer based on a security of the same class and series of an issuer;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925780-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> resources provided through the use or realization of a customer’s debit cash balance or a debit item includible in the Formula for Determination of Reserve Requirement for Brokers and Dealers as promulgated by the Commission under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925781-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> other property of the debtor that any applicable law, rule, or regulation requires to be set aside or held for the benefit of a customer, unless including such property as customer property would not significantly increase customer property; but</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925782-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> not including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925783-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a customer name security delivered to or reclaimed by a customer under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s751">section 751 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925784-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> property to the extent that a customer does not have a claim against the debtor based on such property;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3925785-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “margin payment” means payment or deposit of cash, a security, or other property, that is commonly known to the securities trade as original margin, initial margin, maintenance margin, or variation margin, or as a mark-to-market payment, or that secures an obligation of a participant in a securities clearing agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3925786-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> “net equity” means, with respect to all accounts of a customer that such customer has in the same capacity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925787-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925788-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> aggregate dollar balance that would remain in such accounts after the liquidation, by sale or purchase, at the time of the filing of the petition, of all securities positions in all such accounts, except any customer name securities of such customer; minus</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925789-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any claim of the debtor against such customer in such capacity that would have been owing immediately after such liquidation; plus</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392578a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any payment by such customer to the trustee, within 60 days after notice under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s342">section 342 of this title</ref>, of any business related claim of the debtor against such customer in such capacity;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd392578b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> “securities contract”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd392578c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392578d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a contract for the purchase, sale, or loan of a security, a certificate of deposit, a mortgage loan, any interest in a mortgage loan, a group or index of securities, certificates of deposit, or mortgage loans or interests therein (including an interest therein or based on the value thereof), or option on any of the foregoing, including an option to purchase or sell any such security, certificate of deposit, mortgage loan, interest, group or index, or option, and including any repurchase or reverse repurchase transaction on any such security, certificate of deposit, mortgage loan, interest, group or index, or option (whether or not such repurchase or reverse repurchase transaction is a “repurchase agreement”, as defined in section 101);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392578e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any option entered into on a national securities exchange relating to foreign currencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd392578f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the guarantee (including by novation) by or to any securities clearing agency of a settlement of cash, securities, certificates of deposit, mortgage loans or interests therein, group or index of securities, or mortgage loans or interests therein (including any interest therein or based on the value thereof), or option on any of the foregoing, including an option to purchase or sell any such security, certificate of deposit, mortgage loan, interest, group or index, or option (whether or not such settlement is in connection with any agreement or transaction referred to in clauses (i) through (xi));</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925790-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any margin loan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925791-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> any extension of credit for the clearance or settlement of securities transactions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925792-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> any loan transaction coupled with a securities collar transaction, any prepaid forward securities transaction, or any total return swap transaction coupled with a securities sale transaction;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925793-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> any other agreement or transaction that is similar to an agreement or transaction referred to in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925794-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> any combination of the agreements or transactions referred to in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925795-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> any option to enter into any agreement or transaction referred to in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925796-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> a master agreement that provides for an agreement or transaction referred to in clause (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), (viii), or (ix), together with all supplements to any such master agreement, without regard to whether the master agreement provides for an agreement or transaction that is not a securities contract under this subparagraph, except that such master agreement shall be considered to be a securities contract under this subparagraph only with respect to each agreement or transaction under such master agreement that is referred to in clause (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), (viii), or (ix); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3925797-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/A/xi"><num value="xi">(xi)</num><content> any security agreement or arrangement or other credit enhancement related to any agreement or transaction referred to in this subparagraph, including any guarantee or reimbursement obligation by or to a stockbroker, securities clearing agency, financial institution, or financial participant in connection with any agreement or transaction referred to in this subparagraph, but not to exceed the damages in connection with any such agreement or transaction, measured in accordance with section 562; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3925798-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include any purchase, sale, or repurchase obligation under a participation in a commercial mortgage loan;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3925799-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> “settlement payment” means a preliminary settlement payment, a partial settlement payment, an interim settlement payment, a settlement payment on account, a final settlement payment, or any other similar payment commonly used in the securities trade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd392579a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s741/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “SIPC” means Securities Investor Protection Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idd392579b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2611">92 Stat. 2611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8</ref>, <date date="1982-07-27">July 27, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/237">96 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s482">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 482</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/382">98 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tV/s501/d/25">Pub. L. 103–394, title V, § 501(d)(25)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4146">108 Stat. 4146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tIX/s907/a/2">Pub. L. 109–8, title IX, § 907(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/173">119 Stat. 173</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-12">Dec. 12, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2697">120 Stat. 2697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd392579c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd392579d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd392579e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 741(6) of the House bill and Senate amendment is deleted by the House amendment since the defined term is used only in section 741(4)(A)(iii). A corresponding change is made in that section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd392579f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 741 sets forth definitions for subchapter III of chapter 7.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (1) defines “Commission” to mean the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (2) defines “customer” to include anybody that interacts with the debtor in a capacity that concerns securities transactions. The term embraces cash or margin customers of a broker or dealer in the broadest sense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (3) defines “customer name security” in a restrictive fashion to include only non-transferable securities that are registered, or in the process of being registered in a customer’s own name. The securities must not be endorsed by the customer and the stockbroker must not be able to legally transfer the securities by delivery, by a power of attorney, or otherwise.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (4) defines “customer property” to include all property of the debtor that has been segregated for customers or property that should have been segregated but was unlawfully converted. Clause (i) refers to customer property not properly segregated by the debtor or customer property converted and then recovered so as to become property of the estate. Unlawfully converted property that has been transferred to a third party is excluded until it is recovered as property of the estate by virtue of the avoiding powers. The concept excludes customer name securities that have been delivered to or reclaimed by a customer and any property properly belonging to the stockholder, such as money deposited by a customer to pay for securities that the stockholder has distributed to such customer.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (5) [enacted as (6)] defines “net equity” to establish the extent to which a customer will be entitled to share in the single and separate fund. Accounts of a customer are aggregated and offset only to the extent the accounts are held by the customer in the same capacity. Thus, a personal account is separate from an account held as trustee. In a community property state an account held for the community is distinct from an account held as separate property.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The net equity is computed by liquidating all securities positions in the accounts and crediting the account with any amount due to the customer. Regardless of the actual dates, if any, of liquidation, the customer is only entitled to the liquidation value at the time of the filing of the petition. To avoid double counting, the liquidation value of customer name securities belonging to a customer is excluded from net equity. Thus, clause (ii) includes claims against a customer resulting from the liquidation of a security under clause (i). The value of a security on which trading has been suspended at the time of the filing of the petition will be estimated. Once the net liquidation value is computed, any amount that the customer owes to the stockbroker is subtracted including any amount that would be owing after the hypothetical liquidation, such as brokerage fees. Debts owed by the customer to the debtor, other than in a securities related transaction, will not reduce the net equity of the customer. Finally, net equity is increased by any payment by the customer to the debtor actually paid within 60 days after notice. The principal reason a customer would make such a payment is to reclaim customer name securities under § 751.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (6) defines “1934 Act” to mean the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (7) [enacted as (9)] defines “SIPC” to mean the Securities Investor Protection Corporation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd39257a0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd39257a1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in par. (4)(A)(iii), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd39257a2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Par. (7)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/A">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “a mortgage loan,” for “a mortgage loan or” and inserted “(whether or not such repurchase or reverse repurchase transaction is a ‘repurchase agreement’, as defined in section 101)” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/B">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “(including by novation)” after “the guarantee” and “(whether or not such settlement is in connection with any agreement or transaction referred to in clauses (i) through (xi))” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7)(A)(v) to (vii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/D">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(D)</ref>, (E), added cls. (v) and (vi) and redesignated former cl. (v) as (vii). Former cls. (vi) and (vii) redesignated (viii) and (ix), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7)(A)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/D">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(D)</ref>, redesignated cl. (vi) as (viii). Former cl. (viii) redesignated (x).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/C">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “(vii), (viii), or (ix)” for “or (vii)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7)(A)(ix) to (xi). <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s5/a/3/D">Pub. L. 109–390, § 5(a)(3)(D)</ref>, redesignated cls. (vii) to (ix) as (ix) to (xi), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> added par. (7) and struck out former par. (7) which read as follows: “ ‘securities contract’ means contract for the purchase, sale, or loan of a security, including an option for the purchase or sale of a security, certificate of deposit, or group or index of securities (including any interest therein or based on the value thereof), or any option entered into on a national securities exchange relating to foreign currencies, or the guarantee of any settlement of cash or securities by or to a securities clearing agency;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Par. (4)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> struck out “(<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.)” after “Act of 1934”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Par. (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/1">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(1)</ref>, substituted “with whom a person deals” for “with whom the debtor deals”, “that has a claim” for “that holds a claim”, “against such person” for “against the debtor”, “held by such person” for “held by the debtor”, and “such person’s business as a stockbroker,” for “business as a stockbroker”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/2/A">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(2)(A)</ref>, (B), substituted “has a claim” for “holds a claim” and “against a person” for “against the debtor” in provisions preceding cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/2/C">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “such person” for “the debtor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/3">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(3)</ref>, substituted “from and that is the lawful” for “and that is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/4">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(4)</ref>, inserted a comma after “petition” and “any” after “except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/5">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(5)</ref>, amended par. (7) generally, inserting provisions relating to options for the purchase or sale of certificates of deposit, or a group or index of securities (including any interest therein or based on the value thereof), or any option entered into on a national securities exchange relating to foreign currencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (8). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s482/6">Pub. L. 98–353, § 482(6)</ref>, inserted “a final settlement payment,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8/1">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8(1)</ref>, struck out “at any time” after “security, or property,” in provisions preceding subpar. (A), and inserted “of a customer” after “claim” in subpar. (A)(ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8/3">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8(3)</ref>, added par. (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8/2">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8(2)</ref>, (4), redesignated former par. (5) as (6), in provisions preceding subpar. (A), substituted “all accounts of a customer that such customer has” for “the aggregate of all of a customer’s accounts that such customer holds”, in subpar. (A)(2) inserted “in such capacity”, and in subpar. (B) inserted “in such capacity”. Former par. (6) redesignated (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8/5">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8(5)</ref>, added pars. (7) and (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s8/2">Pub. L. 97–222, § 8(2)</ref>, (6), redesignated former par. (6) as (9) and substituted “Securities” for “Security”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd39257a3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd39257a4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/390">Pub. L. 109–390</ref> not applicable to any cases commenced under this title or to appointments made under any Federal or State law, before <date date="2006-12-12">Dec. 12, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/390/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 109–390</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd39257a5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd39257a6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd39257a7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
