<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd394c906-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752"><num value="752">§ 752.</num><heading> Customer property</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd394c907-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The trustee shall distribute customer property ratably to customers on the basis and to the extent of such customers’ allowed net equity claims and in priority to all other claims, except claims of the kind specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s507/a/2">section 507(a)(2) of this title</ref> that are attributable to the administration of such customer property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd394c908-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd394c909-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The trustee shall distribute customer property in excess of that distributed under subsection (a) of this section in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s726">section 726 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd394c90a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s510">section 510 of this title</ref>, if a customer is not paid the full amount of such customer’s allowed net equity claim from customer property, the unpaid portion of such claim is a claim entitled to distribution under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s726">section 726 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd394c90b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s752/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any cash or security remaining after the liquidation of a security interest created under a security agreement made by the debtor, excluding property excluded under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B">section 741(4)(B) of this title</ref>, shall be apportioned between the general estate and customer property in the same proportion as the general estate of the debtor and customer property were subject to such security interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd394c90c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2614">92 Stat. 2614</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/222/s15">Pub. L. 97–222, § 15</ref>, <date date="1982-07-27">July 27, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/238">96 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s484">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 484</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/383">98 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tXV/s1502/a/3">Pub. L. 109–8, title XV, § 1502(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/216">119 Stat. 216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd394c90d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd394c90e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd394c90f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 752(a) requires the trustee to distribute customer property to customers based on the amount of their net equity claims. Customer property is to be distributed in priority to all claims except expenses of administration entitled to priority under § 507(1). It is anticipated that the court will apportion such administrative claims on an equitable basis between the general estate and the customer property of the debtor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b)(1) indicates that in the event customer property exceeds customers net equity claims and administrative expenses, the excess pours over into the general estate. This event would occur if the value of securities increased dramatically after the order for relief but before liquidation by the trustee. Subsection (b)(2) indicates that the unpaid portion of a customer’s net equity claim is entitled to share in the general estate as an unsecured claim unless subordinated by the court under proposed <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s501">11 U.S.C. 501</ref>. A net equity claim of a customer that is subordinated under section 747 is entitled to share in distribution under section 726(a)(2) unless subordinated under section 510 independently of the subordination under section 747.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) provides for apportionment between customer property and the general estate of any equity of the debtor in property remaining after a secured creditor liquidates a security interest. This might occur if a stockbroker hypothecates securities of his own and of his customers if the value of the hypothecated securities exceeds the debt owed to the secured party. The apportionment is to be made according to the ratio of customer property and general property of the debtor that comprised the collateral. The subsection refers to cash and securities of customers to include any customer property unlawfully converted by the stockbroker in the course of such a transaction. The apportionment is made subject to section 741(4)(B) to insure that property in a customer’s account that is owed to the stockbroker will not be considered customer property. This recognizes the right of the stockbroker to withdraw money that has been erroneously placed in a customer’s account or that is otherwise owing to the stockbroker.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd394c910-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd394c911-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> substituted “507(a)(2)” for “507(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s484/a">Pub. L. 98–353, § 484(a)</ref>, substituted “customers’ allowed” for “customers allowed”, “except claims of the kind” for “except claims”, and “such customer property” for “customer property”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s484/b">Pub. L. 98–353, § 484(b)</ref>, substituted “section 726” for “section 726(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/222">Pub. L. 97–222</ref> substituted “Any cash or security remaining after the liquidation of a security interest created under a security agreement made by the debtor, excluding property excluded under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B">section 741(4)(B) of this title</ref>, shall be apportioned between the general estate and customer property in the same proportion as the general estate of the debtor and customer property were subject to such security interest” for “Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s741/4/B">section 741(4)(B) of this title</ref>, any cash or security remaining after the liquidation of a security interest created under a security agreement made by the debtor shall be apportioned between the general estate and customer property in the proportion that the general property of the debtor and the cash or securities of customers were subject to such security interest”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd394c912-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd394c913-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under this title before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd394c914-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective with respect to cases filed 90 days after <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s552/a">section 552(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
