<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id745e6f0e-3a70-11f1-9d9e-dfac6d46cab7" identifier="/us/usc/t36/s2307"><num value="2307">§ 2307.</num><heading> Gifts, bequests, and devises of property; tax treatment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Museum may solicit, and the Museum may accept, hold, administer, invest, and use gifts, bequests, and devises of property, both real and personal, and all revenues received or generated by the Museum to aid or facilitate the operation and maintenance of the memorial museum. Property may be accepted pursuant to this section, and the property and the proceeds thereof used as nearly as possible in accordance with the terms of the gift, bequest, or devise donating such property. Funds donated to and accepted by the Museum pursuant to this section or otherwise received or generated by the Museum are not to be regarded as appropriated funds and are not subject to any requirements or restrictions applicable to appropriated funds. For the purposes of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, property accepted under this section shall be considered as a gift, bequest, or devise to the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id745e6f0f-3a70-11f1-9d9e-dfac6d46cab7">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/292/s1">Pub. L. 106–292, § 1</ref>, <date date="2000-10-12">Oct. 12, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1033">114 Stat. 1033</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id745e6f10-3a70-11f1-9d9e-dfac6d46cab7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id745e6f11-3a70-11f1-9d9e-dfac6d46cab7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id745e6f12-3a70-11f1-9d9e-dfac6d46cab7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2307, <ref href="/us/pl/105/225">Pub. L. 105–225</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1279">112 Stat. 1279</ref>, provided for administrative provisions, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/106/292">Pub. L. 106–292</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
