<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb6a3f43-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j"><num value="1141j">§ 1141j.</num><heading> Miscellaneous provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f44-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> “Cooperative association” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “cooperative association” means any association in which farmers act together in processing, preparing for market, handling, and/or marketing the farm products of persons so engaged, and also means any association in which farmers act together in purchasing, testing, grading, processing, distributing, and/or furnishing farm supplies and/or farm business services: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such associations are operated for the mutual benefit of the members thereof as such producers or purchasers and conform to one or both of the following requirements:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">First. That no member of the association is allowed more than one vote because of the amount of stock or membership capital he may own therein; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Second. That the association does not pay dividends on stock or membership capital in excess of 8 per centum per annum.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">And in any case to the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Third. That the association shall not deal in farm products, farm supplies, and farm business services with or for nonmembers in an amount greater in value than the total amount of such business transacted by it with or for members. All business transacted by any cooperative association for or on behalf of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof shall be disregarded in determining the volume of member and nonmember business transacted by such association.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f45-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Speculation prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for the governor, or any officer or employee of the Farm Credit Administration to speculate directly or indirectly, in any agricultural commodity or product thereof, or in contracts relating thereto, or in the stock or membership interests of any association or corporation engaged in handling, processing, or disposing of any such commodity or product. Any person violating this subdivision shall upon conviction thereof be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f46-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidential information; disclosure prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful (1) for any cooperative association, stabilization corporation, clearing-house association, or commodity committee, or (2) for any director, officer, employee, or member or person acting on behalf of any such association, corporation, or committee, to which or to whom information has been imparted in confidence by the administration, to disclose such information in violation of any regulation of the administration. Any such association, corporation, or committee, or director, officer, employee, or member thereof, violating this subdivision, shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f47-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Separability clause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter is declared unconstitutional, or the applicability thereof to any person, circumstance, commodity, or class of transactions with respect to any commodity is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of the chapter and the applicability of such provision to other persons, circumstances, commodities, and classes of transactions shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f48-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Citation of chapter</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Agricultural Marketing Act.”</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb6a3f49-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1141j/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> “Agricultural commodity” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “agricultural commodity” includes, in addition to other agricultural commodities, crude gum (oleoresin) from a living tree, and the following products as processed by the original producer of the crude gum (oleoresin) from which derived: Gum spirits of turpentine and gum rosin, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s92">section 92 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb6a3f4a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1929-06-15/ch24/s15">June 15, 1929, ch. 24, § 15</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/18">46 Stat. 18</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1931-03-04/ch520/s3">Mar. 4, 1931, ch. 520, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1550">46 Stat. 1550</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6084, <date date="1933-03-27">Mar. 27, 1933</date>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch98">June 16, 1933, ch. 98</ref>, title V, § 55, <ref href="/us/stat/48/266">48 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-06-03/ch164/s12">June 3, 1935, ch. 164, § 12</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/317">49 Stat. 317</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tI/s1610">Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1610</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1018">122 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title I, § 1610, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1746.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb6a3f4b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb6a3f4c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb6a3f4d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s535">section 535 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb6a3f4e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsecs. (d) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s1610">Pub. L. 110–246, § 1610</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (e) to (g) as (d) to (f), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “The inclusion in any governmental report, bulletin, or other such publication hereafter issued or published of any prediction with respect to cotton prices is prohibited. Any officer or employee of the United States who authorizes or is responsible for the inclusion in any such report, bulletin, or other publication of any such prediction, or who knowingly causes the issuance or publication of any such report, bulletin, or other publication containing any such prediction, shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not less than $500 or more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than five years, or both: <i>Provided</i>, That this subdivision shall not apply to the Governor of the Farm Credit Administration when engaged in the performance of his duties herein provided.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1935-06-03">June 3, 1935</date>, amended definition of cooperative association and inserted second sentence in par. “Third”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1933—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date>, among other changes, inserted proviso and all subsequent thereto.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1931—Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1931-03-04">Mar. 4, 1931</date>, added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb6a3f4f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb6a3f50-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Governor” and “Farm Credit Administration” substituted in text for “any member” and “board”, respectively, and “Governor of the Farm Credit Administration” substituted for “members of the board”, pursuant to Ex. Ord. No. 6084, set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2241">section 2241 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb6a3f51-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddb6a3f52-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Establishment of Farm Credit Administration as an independent agency, composition of Farm Credit Administration, appointment of Governor of Farm Credit Administration, and duties thereof, including duty to perform functions, etc., of Farm Credit Administration, see section 2241 et seq of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb6a3f53-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb6a3f54-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Farm Credit Administration or any agency, officer, or entity of, under, or subject to supervision of said Administration excepted from functions of officers, agencies, and employees transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
