<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb9c4bd4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1469"><num value="1469">§ 1469.</num><heading> Authority to invest in State housing corporations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that Federal savings and loan associations and national banks should have the authority to assist in financing the organization and operation of any State housing corporation established under the laws of the State in which the corporation will carry on its operation. It is the purpose of this section to provide a means whereby private financial institutions can assist in providing housing, particularly for families of low- or moderate-income, by purchasing stock of and investing in loans to any such State housing corporation situated in the particular State in which the Federal savings and loan association or national bank involved is located.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb9c4bd5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/100/s5/a">Pub. L. 93–100, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/343">87 Stat. 343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb9c4bd6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb9c4bd7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb9c4bd8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/pl/93/100/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 93–100</ref>, which enacted this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1470">section 1470 of this title</ref> and amended sections 24 and 1464 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb9c4bd9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb9c4bda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddb9c4bdb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/100/s8">Pub. L. 93–100, § 8</ref>, <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/348">87 Stat. 348</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/100/s8">“The provisions of this Act [enacting this section and sections 1470 and 1832 of this title, amending sections 24, 461 note, 1464, 1725, 1727 and 1828 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s548">section 548 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the thirtieth day after the date of its enactment [<date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>], except that the amendments made by sections 1 and 5 [enacting this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1470">section 1470 of this title</ref> and amending sections 24, 461 note, and 1464 of this title] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
