<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddba10667-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–5a"><num value="1701g–5a">§ 1701g–5a.</num><heading> Transfer of New Communities Fund assets and liabilities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall transfer all assets and liabilities of the fund established pursuant to section 717 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4518">42 U.S.C. 4518</ref>), to the Revolving fund (liquidating programs) established pursuant to title II of the Independent Offices Appropriation Act, 1955, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–5">12 U.S.C. 1701g–5</ref>).</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddba10668-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/45/tI/s101">Pub. L. 98–45, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1983-07-12">July 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/223">97 Stat. 223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddba10669-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddba1066a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddba1066b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 717 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4518">42 U.S.C. 4518</ref>), referred to in text, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 474(e)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1239">97 Stat. 1239</ref>, but remaining in effect until completion of the transfer required in title I of the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Independent Offices Appropriation Act, 1955, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1954-06-24/ch359">act June 24, 1954, ch. 359</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/272">68 Stat. 272</ref>. Provisions of title II of this Act relating to the establishment of the revolving fund (liquidating programs) are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–5">section 1701g–5 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddba1066c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
