<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddba377ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3"><num value="1701j–3">§ 1701j–3.</num><heading> Preemption of due-on-sale prohibitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba377ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “due-on-sale clause” means a contract provision which authorizes a lender, at its option, to declare due and payable sums secured by the lender’s security instrument if all or any part of the property, or an interest therein, securing the real property loan is sold or transferred without the lender’s prior written consent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “lender” means a person or government agency making a real property loan or any assignee or transferee, in whole or in part, of such a person or agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “real property loan” means a loan, mortgage, advance, or credit sale secured by a lien on real property, the stock allocated to a dwelling unit in a cooperative housing corporation, or a residential manufactured home, whether real or personal property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “residential manufactured home” means a manufactured home as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5402/6">section 5402(6) of title 42</ref> which is used as a residence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba377f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Loan contract and terms governing execution or enforcement of due-on-sale options and rights and remedies of lenders and borrowers; assumptions of loan rates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any provision of the constitution or laws (including the judicial decisions) of any State to the contrary, a lender may, subject to subsection (c), enter into or enforce a contract containing a due-on-sale clause with respect to a real property loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), the exercise by the lender of its option pursuant to such a clause shall be exclusively governed by the terms of the loan contract, and all rights and remedies of the lender and the borrower shall be fixed and governed by the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the exercise of its option under a due-on-sale clause, a lender is encouraged to permit an assumption of a real property loan at the existing contract rate or at a rate which is at or below the average between the contract and market rates, and nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prohibit any such assumption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba377f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State prohibitions applicable for prescribed period; subsection (b) provisions applicable upon expiration of such period; loans subject to State and Federal regulation or subsection (b) provisions when authorized by State laws or Federal regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of a contract involving a real property loan which was made or assumed, including a transfer of the liened property subject to the real property loan, during the period beginning on the date a State adopted a constitutional provision or statute prohibiting the exercise of due-on-sale clauses, or the date on which the highest court of such State has rendered a decision (or if the highest court has not so decided, the date on which the next highest appellate court has rendered a decision resulting in a final judgment if such decision applies State-wide) prohibiting such exercise, and ending on <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, the provisions of subsection (b) shall apply only in the case of a transfer which occurs on or after the expiration of 3 years after <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a State, by a State law enacted by the State legislature prior to the close of such 3-year period, with respect to real property loans originated in the State by lenders other than national banks, Federal savings and loan associations, Federal savings banks, and Federal credit unions, may otherwise regulate such contracts, in which case subsection (b) shall apply only if such State law so provides; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba377fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Comptroller of the Currency with respect to real property loans originated by national banks or the National Credit Union Administration Board with respect to real property loans originated by Federal credit unions may, by regulation prescribed prior to the close of such period, otherwise regulate such contracts, in which case subsection (b) shall apply only if such regulation so provides.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For any contract to which subsection (b) does not apply pursuant to this subsection, a lender may require any successor or transferee of the borrower to meet customary credit standards applied to loans secured by similar property, and the lender may declare the loan due and payable pursuant to the terms of the contract upon transfer to any successor or transferee of the borrower who fails to meet such customary credit standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A lender may not exercise its option pursuant to a due-on-sale clause in the case of a transfer of a real property loan which is subject to this subsection where the transfer occurred prior to <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba377fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> This subsection does not apply to a loan which was originated by a Federal savings and loan association or Federal savings bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba377ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption of specified transfers or dispositions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to a real property loan secured by a lien on residential real property containing less than five dwelling units, including a lien on the stock allocated to a dwelling unit in a cooperative housing corporation, or on a residential manufactured home, a lender may not exercise its option pursuant to a due-on-sale clause upon—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37800-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the creation of a lien or other encumbrance subordinate to the lender’s security instrument which does not relate to a transfer of rights of occupancy in the property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37801-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the creation of a purchase money security interest for household appliances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37802-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a transfer by devise, descent, or operation of law on the death of a joint tenant or tenant by the entirety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37803-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the granting of a leasehold interest of three years or less not containing an option to purchase;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37804-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a transfer to a relative resulting from the death of a borrower;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37805-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a transfer where the spouse or children of the borrower become an owner of the property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37806-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a transfer resulting from a decree of a dissolution of marriage, legal separation agreement, or from an incidental property settlement agreement, by which the spouse of the borrower becomes an owner of the property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37807-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> a transfer into an inter vivos trust in which the borrower is and remains a beneficiary and which does not relate to a transfer of rights of occupancy in the property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddba37808-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> any other transfer or disposition described in regulations prescribed by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba37809-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules, regulations, and interpretations; future income bearing loans subject to due-on-sale options</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba3780a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Federal Home Loan Bank Board, in consultation with the Comptroller of the Currency and the National Credit Union Administration Board, is authorized to issue rules and regulations and to publish interpretations governing the implementation of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddba3780b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (d), the rules and regulations prescribed under this section may permit a lender to exercise its option pursuant to a due-on-sale clause with respect to a real property loan and any related agreement pursuant to which a borrower obtains the right to receive future income.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba3780c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date for enforcement of Corporation-owned loans with due-on-sale options</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (hereinafter referred to as the “Corporation”) shall not, prior to <date date="1983-07-01">July 1, 1983</date>, implement the change in its policy announced on <date date="1982-07-02">July 2, 1982</date>, with respect to enforcement of due-on-sale clauses in real property loans which are owned in whole or in part by the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddba3780d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–3/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Balloon payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Federal Home Loan Bank Board regulations restricting the use of a balloon payment shall not apply to a loan, mortgage, advance, or credit sale to which this section applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddba3780e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tIII/s341">Pub. L. 97–320, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1505">96 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 473], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1237">97 Stat. 1237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddba3780f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddba37810-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddba37811-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Thrift Institutions Restructuring Act and also as part of the Garn-St Germain Depository Institutions Act of 1982, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddba37812-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “With respect to a real property loan secured by a lien on residential real property containing less than five dwelling units, including a lien on the stock allocated to a dwelling unit in a cooperative housing corporation, or on a residential manufactured home, a lender” for “A lender”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddba37813-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddba37814-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Home Loan Bank Board abolished and functions transferred, see sections 401 to 406 of <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddba37815-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddba37816-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
