<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb9e951f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c"><num value="1701c">§ 1701c.</num><heading> Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out his functions, powers, and duties—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb9e9520-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of personnel; delegation of functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may appoint such officers and employees as he may find necessary, which appointments shall be subject to the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. The Secretary may make such expenditures as may be necessary to carry out his functions, powers, and duties, and there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to carry out such functions, powers, and duties and for administrative expenses in connection therewith. The Secretary, without in any way relieving himself from final responsibility, may delegate any of his functions and powers to such officers, agents, or employees as he may designate, may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions and powers, as he may deem desirable, and may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out his functions, powers, and duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb9e9521-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb9e9522-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional powers and duties of Secretary and Federal Home Loan Bank Board</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, respectively, may, in addition to and not in derogation of any powers and authorities conferred elsewhere in this Act—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb9e9523-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with the consent of the agency or organization concerned, accept and utilize equipment, facilities, or the services of employees of any Federal, State, or local public agency or instrumentality, educational institution, or nonprofit agency or organization and, in connection with the utilization of such services, may make payments for transportation while away from their homes or regular places of business and per diem in lieu of subsistence en route and at place of such service, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb9e9524-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> utilize, contract with and act through, without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>, any Federal, State, or local public agency or instrumentality, educational institution, or non-profit agency or organization with the consent of the agency or organization concerned, and any funds available to said officers for carrying out their respective functions, powers, and duties shall be available to reimburse or pay any such agency or organization; and, whenever in the judgment of any such officer necessary, he may make advance, progress, or other payments with respect to such contracts without regard to the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">section 3324 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb9e9525-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make expenditures for all necessary expenses, including preparation, mounting, shipping, and installation of exhibits; purchase and exchange of technical apparatus; and such other expenses as may, from time to time, be found necessary in carrying out their respective functions, powers, and duties: <i>Provided</i>, That funds made available for administrative expenses in carrying out the functions, powers, and duties imposed upon the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Federal Home Loan Bank Agency,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002108">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002108"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should refer to the Federal Housing Finance Agency.</note> respectively, by or pursuant to law may at their option be consolidated into a single administrative expense fund accounts of such officer or agency for expenditure by them, respectively, in accordance with the provisions hereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb9e9526-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds for library memberships</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may utilize funds made available to him for salaries and expenses for payment in advance for dues or fees for library memberships in organizations (or for membership of the individual librarians in organizations which will not accept library membership) whose publications are available to members only, or to members at a price lower than to the general public, and for payment in advance for publications available only upon that basis or available at a reduced price on prepublication order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddba10627-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-08-10/ch832">Aug. 10, 1948, ch. 832</ref>, title V, § 502, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1283">62 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-04-20/ch94">Apr. 20, 1950, ch. 94</ref>, title V, § 503, <ref href="/us/stat/64/80">64 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/tIX/s909">Pub. L. 87–70, title IX, § 909</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/192">75 Stat. 192</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s5/d/1">Pub. L. 90–19, § 5(d)(1)</ref>–(3), (8)–(13), <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/21">81 Stat. 21</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII">Pub. L. 98–479, title II</ref>, §§ 202(b), 203(c), <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2228">98 Stat. 2228</ref>, 2229; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tV/s570/a/1">Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 570(a)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1949">101 Stat. 1949</ref>, 1950; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 101–73, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/352">103 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII/s370">Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 370</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1565">124 Stat. 1565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddba10628-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddba10629-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddba1062a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1948-08-10/ch832">act Aug. 10, 1948, ch. 832</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1268">62 Stat. 1268</ref>, known as the Housing Act of 1948. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1948 Amendments note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddba1062b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c)(2), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b) of section 502 of act <date date="1948-08-10">Aug. 10, 1948</date>, is set out as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1404a">section 1404a of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing Act of 1948, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddba1062c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s370/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 370(1)</ref>, substituted “, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation” for “and the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s370/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 370(2)</ref>, substituted “Agency” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s306/a">Pub. L. 101–73, § 306(a)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision” for “Federal Home Loan Bank Board (which term as used in this section shall also include and refer to the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, the Home Owners Loan Corporation, and the Chairman of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board)”, was executed as directed, except that “Home Owners’ ” rather than “Home Owners” appeared in the original in the language struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s306/b">Pub. L. 101–73, § 306(b)</ref>, substituted “of any Federal, State, or local” for “of any State or local”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/s570/a/1">Pub. L. 100–242, § 570(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “The Secretary of Commerce or his designee shall hereafter be included in the membership of the National Housing Council.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/s570/a/3">Pub. L. 100–242, § 570(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/s202/b/1">Pub. L. 98–479, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/s202/b/2">Pub. L. 98–479, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–2">5 U.S.C. 73b–2</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/s203/c">Pub. L. 98–479, § 203(c)</ref>, substituted “subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">section 3324 of title 31</ref>” for “section 3648 of the Revised Statutes [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>]”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s5/d/1">Pub. L. 90–19, § 5(d)(1)</ref>–(3), substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrator” and “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing, and struck out provision for preparation of official seal and judicial notice thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s5/d/8">Pub. L. 90–19, § 5(d)(8)</ref>, (9), substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrator, the Home Loan Bank Board” where it first appears and “Federal Home Loan Bank Board” for “Home Loan Bank Board, the Federal Housing Commissioner, and the Public Housing Commissioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s5/d/10">Pub. L. 90–19, § 5(d)(10)</ref>, (11), substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board” and “such officer or agency” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrator, the Home Loan Bank Board, the Federal Housing Commissioner, and the Public Housing Commissioner” and “said officers or agencies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s5/d/12">Pub. L. 90–19, § 5(d)(12)</ref>, (13), substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may utilize funds made available to him” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrator, the Federal Housing Commissioner and the Public Housing Commissioner, respectively, may utilize funds made available to them” and struck out “of the respective agencies” after “librarians”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/s909/1">Pub. L. 87–70, § 909(1)</ref>, struck out provisions which made <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">section 5 of title 41</ref> inapplicable to any purchase or contract by officers (or their agencies) for services or supplies if the amount thereof does not exceed $300.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/s909/2">Pub. L. 87–70, § 909(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-04-20">Apr. 20, 1950</date>, amended third sentence of subsec. (a) to authorize the Administrator to permit redelegation of functions and powers which he had delegated previously to officers, agents, and employees but this does not relieve him of any final responsibility, and inserted “or pay” after “reimburse” in subsec. (c)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddba1062d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddba1062e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s351">section 351 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="iddba1062f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed (subject to a savings clause) by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, 655.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddba10630-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Home Loan Bank Board abolished and functions transferred, see sections 401 to 406 of <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddba10631-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Report on Areas of Program Administration and Management Which Require Improvement</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/90/448/s5">Pub. L. 90–448, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/477">82 Stat. 477</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/91/609/tIX/s918">Pub. L. 91–609, title IX, § 918</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1816">84 Stat. 1816</ref>, directed Secretary to report annually to Committees on Banking and Currency of House and Senate, identifying specific areas of program administration and management which require improvement, describing actions taken and proposed, and recommendations for legislation, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/93/608/s1/9">Pub. L. 93–608, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1968">88 Stat. 1968</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddba10632-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddba10633-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11196</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11196, <date date="1965-02-02">Feb. 2, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 1171, which delegated functions to Housing and Home Finance Administrator, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12553, <date date="1986-02-25">Feb. 25, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 7237.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddba10634-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Preparedness Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For assignment of certain emergency preparedness functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see Parts 1, 2, and 9 of Ex. Ord. No. 12656, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 47491, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5195">section 5195 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
