<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddba3782e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701m"><num value="1701m">§ 1701m.</num><heading> Credit and cancellation of notes transferred from Reconstruction Finance Corporation; net loss computation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed from time to time to credit and cancel the note or notes of the Housing and Home Finance Administrator executed and delivered in connection with loans transferred from the Reconstruction Finance Corporation to the Housing and Home Finance Agency pursuant to Reorganization Plan Numbered 23 of 1950 (<ref href="/us/stat/64/1279">64 Stat. 1279</ref>), to the extent of the net loss, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, sustained by said Agency in the liquidation of defaulted loans. The net loss shall be the sum of the unpaid principal and advances for care and preservation of collateral, together with accrued and unpaid interest on said principal and advances, and all expenses and costs (other than those subject to administrative expense limitations) in connection with the liquidation of defaulted loans, less the amount actually realized by the Housing and Home Finance Agency on account of such defaulted loans.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddba3782f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-07-14/ch723/s9">July 14, 1952, ch. 723, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/603">66 Stat. 603</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddba37830-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddba37831-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddba37832-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 23 of 1950, referred to in text, is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddba37833-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing Act of 1952, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddba37834-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddba37835-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions, powers, and duties of Housing and Home Finance Agency and its Administrator transferred to and vested in Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>, classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3534">section 3534 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddba37836-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination and Liquidation of Reconstruction Finance Corporation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Termination on <date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>, of Reconstruction Finance Corporation and liquidation thereof, see sections 608 and 609 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and notes thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddba37837-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddba37838-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Reconstruction Finance Corporation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6(a) of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1957, eff. <date date="1957-06-30">June 30, 1957</date>, 22 F.R. 4633, <ref href="/us/stat/71/647">71 Stat. 647</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, abolished Reconstruction Finance Corporation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
