<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddba3783f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701o"><num value="1701o">§ 1701o.</num><heading> Annual report of Secretary</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, as soon as practicable during each calendar year, make a report to the President for submission to the Congress on all operations and programs (including but not limited to the insurance, urban renewal, public housing, and rent supplement programs) under the jurisdiction of the Department of Housing and Urban Development during the previous calendar year. Such report shall contain recommendations for strengthening or improving such programs, or, when necessary to implement more effectively Congressional policies and purposes, for establishing new or alternative programs.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddba37840-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-02/ch649">Aug. 2, 1954, ch. 649</ref>, title VIII, § 802(a), <ref href="/us/stat/68/642">68 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tXI/s1101">Pub. L. 89–117, title XI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/502">79 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s10/f">Pub. L. 90–19, § 10(f)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/23">81 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tV/s570/b">Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 570(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1950">101 Stat. 1950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddba37841-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddba37842-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddba37843-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing Act of 1954, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddba37844-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> inserted section catchline “Annual report of Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> struck out “FHA” before “insurance” and substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development” and “Department of Housing and Urban Development” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrator” and “Housing and Home Finance Agency”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/117">Pub. L. 89–117</ref> specifically included FHA insurance, urban renewal, public housing, and rent supplement programs within the operation and programs of the Housing and Home Finance Agency which the report shall cover and inserted requirement that the report contain recommendations for improving programs and for new or alternative programs.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
