<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddbb41987-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4"><num value="1701z–4">§ 1701z–4.</num><heading> Abandoned properties demonstration proj­ect</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddbb41988-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants for arrest of incipient abandonment and revitalization of blighted areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–1">section 1701z–1 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may undertake programs to demonstrate the most feasible means of providing assistance to localities in which a substantial number of structures are abandoned or are threatened with abandonment for the purpose of arresting the process of housing abandonment in its incipiency or in restoring viability to blighted areas in which abandonment is pervasive. For this purpose, the Secretary is authorized to make grants, subject to the limitations of this section, to assist local public bodies in planning and implementing demonstration projects for prompt and effective action in alleviating and preventing such abandonment in designated demonstration areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddbb41989-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Preferred projects; scope of projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In administering this section, the Secretary shall give preference to those demonstration projects which in his judgment can reasonably be expected to arrest the process of abandonment in the demonstration area within a period of two years and which provide for innovative approaches to combating the problem of housing abandonment. Such projects may include, but shall not be limited to (1) acquisition by negotiated purchase, lease, receivership, tax lien proceedings, or other means authorized by law and satisfactory to the Secretary, of real property within the demonstration area or areas which is abandoned, deteriorated, or in violation of applicable code standards; (2) the repair of streets, sidewalks, parks, playgrounds, publicly owned utilities, public buildings to meet needs consistent with the revitalization and continued use of the area; (3) the demolition of structures determined to be structurally unsound or unfit for human habitation or which contribute adversely to the physical or social environment of the locality involved; (4) the establishment of recreational or community facilities including public playgrounds; (5) the improvement of garbage and trash collection, street cleaning and other essential services necessary to the revitalization and maintenance of the area; (6) the rehabilitation of privately and publicly owned real property by the locality; and (7) the establishment and operation of locally controlled, nonprofit housing management corporations and municipal repair programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddbb4198a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase or lease of project real estate at fair market value for new or rehabilitated housing use; conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, real property held as part of a project assisted under this section may be made available to (1) a limited dividend corporation, nonprofit corporation, or association, cooperative or public body or agency, or other approved purchaser or lessee, or (2) a purchaser who would be eligible for a mortgage insured under section 1715<i>l</i>(d)(3) or (d)(4), section 1715<i>l</i>(h)(1), section 1715z(i) or (j)(1), or <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–1">section 1715z–1 of this title</ref>, for purchase or lease at fair market value for use by such purchaser or lessee, as, or in the provision of, new or rehabilitated housing for occupancy by families or individuals of low or moderate income.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddbb4198b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of grants; authorization of appropriations; continuing availability of funds; locality limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Grants under this section shall be in amounts which do not exceed 90 per centum of the net project cost as determined by the Secretary. There are authorized to be appropriated for demonstration grants under this section not to exceed $20,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>. Any amounts appropriated shall remain available until expended and any amount authorized but not appropriated may be appropriated for any succeeding fiscal year commencing prior to <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>. Not more than one-third of the aggregate amount of grants made in any fiscal year under this section shall be made with respect to projects undertaken by one locality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddbb68a8c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–4/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Projects as part of urban renewal projects for purpose of application of urban renewal provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of sections 1456, 1465, and 1466 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002119"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 42, and section 1452b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref> of title 42, may apply to projects assisted under this Act as if such projects were being carried out in urban renewal areas as part of urban renewal projects within the meaning of section 1460 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref> of title 42.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddbb68a8d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/609/tV/s505">Pub. L. 91–609, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1787">84 Stat. 1787</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/386/tI/s105/a">Pub. L. 99–386, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-22">Aug. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/822">100 Stat. 822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddbb68a8e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddbb68a8f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddbb68a90-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1456, 1460, and 1466 of title 42, referred to in subsec. (e), were omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5316">section 5316 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, which terminated authority to make grants or loans under those sections after <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1465">Section 1465 of title 42</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/91/646/tII/s220/a/5">Pub. L. 91–646, title II, § 220(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1903">84 Stat. 1903</ref>. See section 4601 et seq. of Title 42.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1452b">Section 1452b of title 42</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s289/b/1">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 289(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4128">104 Stat. 4128</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddbb68a91-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddbb68a92-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/386">Pub. L. 99–386</ref> struck out subsec. (f) which related to annual reports to Congress by Secretary with respect to status of demonstration projects.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
