<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddbbb45f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1702"><num value="1702">§ 1702.</num><heading> Administrative provisions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The powers conferred by this chapter shall be exercised by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”). In order to carry out the provisions of this subchapter and subchapters II, III, V, VI, VII, VIII, IX–B, and X, the Secretary may establish such agencies, accept and utilize such voluntary and uncompensated services, utilize such Federal officers and employees, and, with the consent of the State, such State and local officers and employees, and appoint such other officers and employees as he may find necessary, and may prescribe their authorities, duties, responsibilities, and tenure and fix their compensation. The Secretary may delegate any of the functions and powers conferred upon him under this subchapter and subchapters II, III, V, VI, VII, VIII, IX–B, and X to such officers, agents, and employees as he may designate or appoint, and may make such expenditures (including expenditures for personal services and rent at the seat of government and elsewhere, for law books and books of reference, and for paper, printing, and binding) as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter and subchapters II, III, V, VI, VII, VIII, IX–B, and X, without regard to any other provisions of law governing the expenditure of public funds. All such compensation, expenses, and allowances shall be paid out of funds made available by this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That notwithstanding any other provisions of law except provisions of law hereafter enacted expressly in limitation hereof, all expenses of the Department of Housing and Urban Development in connection with the examination and insurance of loans or investments under any subchapter of this chapter all properly capitalized expenditures, and other necessary expenses not attributable to general overhead in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles shall be considered nonadministrative and payable from funds made available by this chapter, except that, unless made pursuant to specific authorization by the Congress therefor, expenditures made in any fiscal year pursuant to this proviso, other than the payment of insurance claims and other than expenditures (including services on a contract or fee basis, but not including other personal services) in connection with the acquisition, protection, completion, operation, maintenance, improvement, or disposition of real or personal property of the Department acquired under authority of this chapter, shall not exceed 35 per centum of the income received by the Department of Housing and Urban Development from premiums and fees during the preceding fiscal year. Except with respect to subchapter III, for the purposes of this section, the term “nonadministrative” shall not include contract expenses that are not capitalized or routinely deducted from the proceeds of sales, and such expenses shall not be payable from funds made available by this chapter. The Secretary shall, in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter and subchapters II, III, V, VI, VII, VIII, IX–B, and X, be authorized, in his official capacity, to sue and be sued in any court of competent jurisdiction, State or Federal.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddbbdb5fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title I, § 1, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 344(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/722">49 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1941-03-28/ch31/s2">Mar. 28, 1941, ch. 31, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/61">55 Stat. 61</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1941-06-28/ch261/s6">June 28, 1941, ch. 261, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/365">55 Stat. 365</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-08-10/ch832">Aug. 10, 1948, ch. 832</ref>, title IV, § 402, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1283">62 Stat. 1283</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-08-08/ch403/s2">Aug. 8, 1949, ch. 403, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/576">63 Stat. 576</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-25/ch729/s2">Oct. 25, 1949, ch. 729, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/905">63 Stat. 905</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-04-20/ch94">Apr. 20, 1950, ch. 94</ref>, title I, § 122, <ref href="/us/stat/64/59">64 Stat. 59</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title II, § 202, <ref href="/us/stat/65/303">65 Stat. 303</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tXI/s1108/bb">Pub. L. 89–117, title XI, § 1108(bb)</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/507">79 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/754/tX/s1020/g">Pub. L. 89–754, title X, § 1020(g)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1296">80 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 90–19, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (c), <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/17">81 Stat. 17</ref>, 18; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII/s202/a/1">Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 202(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2228">98 Stat. 2228</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tIV/s429/a">Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 429(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1918">101 Stat. 1918</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/235/tI/s133/d/1">Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 133(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2027">103 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/74/tII/s212">Pub. L. 106–74, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1073">113 Stat. 1073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddbbdb5fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddbbdb5fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddbbdb5fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 1701 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddbbdb5fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/74">Pub. L. 106–74</ref> inserted before last sentence “Except with respect to subchapter III, for the purposes of this section, the term “nonadministrative” shall not include contract expenses that are not capitalized or routinely deducted from the proceeds of sales, and such expenses shall not be payable from funds made available by this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/235">Pub. L. 101–235</ref> struck out “IX–A,” after “VIII,” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> struck out comma before period at end of second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/479">Pub. L. 98–479</ref> struck out “without regard to the provisions of other laws applicable to the employment or compensation of other officers or employees of the United States” at end of second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Department of Housing and Urban Development” and “Secretary” for “Federal Housing Administration” and “Commissioner”, respectively, wherever appearing, substituted provision for exercise of national housing powers by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for former authorization for creation of a Federal Housing Administration under a Federal Housing Commissioner appointed by the President with the consent of the Senate, and substituted “Department” for “Administration” in penultimate sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/754">Pub. L. 89–754</ref> inserted references to subchapter IX–B.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/117">Pub. L. 89–117</ref> inserted references to subchapters V and IX–A.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-09-01">Sept. 1, 1951</date>, inserted references to subchapter X.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-04-20">Apr. 20, 1950</date>, made technical amendments to section to reflect change in title of Administrator to Commissioner and to omit provisions relating to tenure and compensation of Commissioner.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Joint Res. <date date="1949-10-25">Oct. 25, 1949</date>, inserted proviso at end of fourth sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1949-08-08">Aug. 8, 1949</date>, made provisions applicable to subchapter VIII.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Act <date date="1948-08-10">Aug. 10, 1948</date>, substituted “subchapters II, III, VI, and VII” for “subchapters II, III, and VI”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1941—Act <date date="1941-06-28">June 28, 1941</date>, substituted “$12,000” for “$10,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1941-03-28">Mar. 28, 1941</date>, substituted “subchapters II, III, and VI” for “subchapters II and III”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, inserted sentence at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddbbdb5ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddbbdb600-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1941 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1941-06-28">June 28, 1941</date>, effective <date date="1941-07-01">July 1, 1941</date>, see section 6 of act <date date="1941-06-28">June 28, 1941</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="iddbbdb601-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1948-08-10/ch832/tV/s501/a">Act Aug. 10, 1948, ch. 832, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1283">62 Stat. 1283</ref>, formerly cited as a credit to this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/655">80 Stat. 655</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddbbdb602-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions, powers, and duties of Federal Housing Administration and Housing and Home Finance Agency transferred to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development who was authorized to delegate such functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of Department of Housing and Urban Development as Secretary may designate, see sections 3534 and 3535 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddbbdb603-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddbbdb604-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1947, eff. <date date="1947-07-27">July 27, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4981, <ref href="/us/stat/61/954">61 Stat. 954</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, abolished office of Federal Housing Administrator and transferred functions to Federal Housing Commissioner. It also consolidated Federal Housing Administration with other agencies into Housing and Home Finance Agency and transferred functions of Federal Loan Administrator with respect to Federal Housing Administration and its functions to Housing and Home Finance Administrator. Federal Housing Administration continued as a constituent agency within Housing and Home Finance Agency. For provisions concerning appointment and compensation of Federal Housing Commissioner, see section 3 of Reorganization Plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions, powers, and duties of National Housing Agency with respect to property, funds, and other assets which were formerly under administration of Farm Security Administration and were transferred to National Housing Agency by Ex. Ord. No. 9070, <date date="1942-02-24">Feb. 24, 1942</date>, 7 F.R. 1529, as amended, were abolished by section 2(a)(3) of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-14/ch964">act Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 964</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1063">60 Stat. 1063</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under sections 1001 to 1005d of Title 7, Agriculture, except with respect of housing projects and such other properties and assets in process of liquidation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Housing Administration consolidated with other agencies into National Housing Agency during World War II, see Ex. Ord. No. 9070.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of National Housing Agency with respect to non-farm-housing projects and other properties remaining under its jurisdiction pursuant to section 2(a)(3) of act <date date="1946-08-14">Aug. 14, 1946</date>, transferred to Public Housing Commissioner by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1947, § 4(b), eff. <date date="1947-07-27">July 27, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4983, <ref href="/us/stat/61/955">61 Stat. 955</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Housing Administration to be administered by Federal Loan Administrator within Federal Loan Agency, see Reorg. Plan No. I of 1939, § 402, eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2730, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1429">53 Stat. 1429</ref> set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddbbdb605-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 7058</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 7058, <date date="1935-05-29">May 29, 1935</date>, authorized Federal Housing Administrator to adopt a seal for Federal Housing Administration, provided that copies of any books, records, papers, documents, agreements, orders, rules, or regulations of Administration were admissible in evidence equally with originals thereof, and empowered Administrator or his designee to certify or exemplify copies of any books, records, papers, or documents of Administration.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddbbdb606-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 7280</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 7280, <date date="1936-01-28">Jan. 28, 1936</date>, was issued as evidence of creation of Federal Housing Administration and validated and confirmed creation thereof.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
