<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddbdef976-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715d"><num value="1715d">§ 1715d.</num><heading> Insurance of mortgages on property in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, and Virgin Islands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development finds that, because of higher costs prevailing in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands, it is not feasible to construct dwellings or manufactured home courts or parks on property located in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands without sacrifice of sound standards of construction, design, or livability, within the limitations as to maximum or maxima mortgage amounts provided in this chapter, the Secretary may, by regulations or otherwise, prescribe, with respect to dollar amount, a higher maximum or maxima for the principal obligation of mortgages insured under this chapter covering property located in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands in such amounts as he shall find necessary to compensate for such higher costs but not to exceed, in any event, the maximum or maxima otherwise applicable (including increased mortgage amounts in geographical areas where cost levels so require) by more than one-half thereof. No mortgage with respect to a project or property in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands shall be accepted for insurance under this chapter unless the Secretary finds that the project or property is an acceptable risk giving consideration to the acute housing shortage in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands: <i>Provided</i>, That any such mortgage may be insured or accepted for insurance without regard to any requirement in any other section of this chapter that the Secretary find the project or property to be economically sound or an acceptable risk. Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this chapter or any other law, the Alaska Housing Authority or the Government of Guam, the Virgin Islands, or Hawaii or any agency or instrumentality thereof shall be eligible as mortgagor or mortgagee, as the case may be, for any of the purposes of mortgage insurance under the provisions of this chapter. Upon application by the mortgagee (1) where the mortgagor is regulated or restricted pursuant to the last sentence of this section or (2) where the Alaska Housing Authority or the Government of Guam, the Virgin Islands, or Hawaii or any agency or instrumentality thereof is the mortgagor or mortgagee, for the insurance of a mortgage under any provisions of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized to insure the mortgage (including advances thereon where otherwise authorized), and to make commitments for the insuring of any such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon, under such provision (and this section) without regard to any requirement that the mortgagor shall have paid a prescribed amount on account of such property. Without limiting the authority of the Secretary under any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized, with respect to any mortgagor in such case (except where the Alaska Housing Authority is the mortgagor or mortgagee), to require the mortgagor to be regulated or restricted as to rents or sales, charges, capital structure, rate of return, and methods of operation to such an extent and in such manner as the Secretary determines advisable to provide reasonable rentals and sales prices and a reasonable return on the investment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddbdef977-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title II, § 214, as added <ref href="/us/act/1949-04-23/ch89/s2/a">Apr. 23, 1949, ch. 89, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/57">63 Stat. 57</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title VI, § 606, <ref href="/us/stat/65/315">65 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-14/ch723/s10/a/3">July 14, 1952, ch. 723, § 10(a)(3)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/603">66 Stat. 603</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-06-30/ch170/s25/a">June 30, 1953, ch. 170, § 25(a)</ref>, (c), <ref href="/us/stat/67/128">67 Stat. 128</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/70/s10/c">Pub. L. 86–70, § 10(c)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/142">73 Stat. 142</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/372/tI/s106">Pub. L. 86–372, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1959-09-23">Sept. 23, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/657">73 Stat. 657</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s1/a/2">Pub. L. 90–19, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/17">81 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/152/tIV/s418/e">Pub. L. 91–152, title IV, § 418(e)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/402">83 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/399/tIII/s308/c/1">Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 308(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1640">94 Stat. 1640</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII/s204/a/4">Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 204(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2232">98 Stat. 2232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tIV/s406/b/7">Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 406(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1901">101 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tIII/s333">Pub. L. 101–625, title III, § 333</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4141">104 Stat. 4141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddbdef978-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddbdef979-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddbdef97a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 1701 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddbdef97b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of section 214 of act <date date="1934-06-27">June 27, 1934</date>, as added by section 2(a) of act <date date="1949-04-23">Apr. 23, 1949</date>, which insofar as Alaska, Hawaii, and Guam individually are concerned, was, formerly, also set out as sections 484d, 723, and 1425 of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions. Section 2(b) of act <date date="1949-04-23">Apr. 23, 1949</date>, which was formerly classified to sections 484e, 724 and 1426 of Title 48, was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-02/ch649/tII/s205">act Aug. 2, 1954, ch. 649, title II, § 205</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/622">68 Stat. 622</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddbdef97c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/625">Pub. L. 101–625</ref> amended section catchline generally, inserting reference to Virgin Islands, substituted “Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands,” for “Alaska, Guam, or Hawaii,” after “costs prevailing in”, “Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands” for “Alaska or in Guam or Hawaii” wherever appearing, and inserted “, the Virgin Islands,” after “Government of Guam” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> struck out “shall be the owner and occupant of the property or” before “shall have paid a prescribed amount” in fourth sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/479">Pub. L. 98–479</ref> substituted “Insurance of mortgages on property in Alaska, Guam, and Hawaii” for “Construction of dwellings or mobile home courts or parks in Alaska, Guam, and Hawaii; increased maximum for mortgage insurance; conditions and limitations” in section catchline, and substituted “Notwithstanding” for “Nowithstanding” at beginning of third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/399">Pub. L. 96–399</ref> substituted “manufactured” for “mobile”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—<ref href="/us/pl/91/152">Pub. L. 91–152</ref> extended to mobile home courts or parks the special provisions applicable to properties located in Alaska, Guam, or Hawaii.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development” for “Federal Housing Commissioner” and “Secretary” for “Commissioner”, respectively, wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/372">Pub. L. 86–372</ref> inserted “(including increased mortgage amounts in geographical areas where cost levels so require)” after “maximum or maxima otherwise applicable”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/70">Pub. L. 86–70</ref> substituted “Alaska, Guam,” for “the Territory of Alaska or in Guam”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, § 25(a), inserted “or Hawaii” after “Guam” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, § 25(c), substituted in fourth sentence “Upon application by the mortgagee (1) where the mortgagor is regulated or restricted pursuant to the last sentence of this section or (2)” for “Upon application by the mortgagee,”; and inserted sentence beginning “Without limiting the authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Act <date date="1952-07-14">July 14, 1952</date>, inserted “or in Guam” after “Alaska” wherever appearing, inserted “or maxima” after “maximum,” and inserted “or the Government of Guam or any agency or instrumentality thereof” after “Alaska Housing Authority” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-09-01">Sept. 1, 1951</date>, substituted “one-half” for “one-third” in first sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddbdef97d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddbdef97e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> applicable only with respect to mortgages insured pursuant to conditional commitment issued on or after <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, or in accordance with direct endorsement program (24 CFR 200.163), if approved underwriter of mortgagee signs appraisal report for property on or after <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1709">section 1709 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddbdef97f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Report Respecting Utilization of Factory-Built and Other Appropriate Types of Housing for Indian, etc., Housing Programs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/399/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1647">94 Stat. 1647</ref>, directed Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to study feasibility of utilizing factory-built and other appropriate types of housing (other than the traditional type of site-built housing), to the extent practicable, in carrying out housing programs for Indians and Alaskan Natives, and not later than eighteen months after <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, to transmit a report to Congress containing the findings and conclusions of such study, including a comparison of costs and benefits of utilizing the traditional type of site-built housing and of utilizing other types of housing in situations in which either type of housing could be used.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddbdef980-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Purchases of Obligations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">No additional notes or obligations to be purchased after <date date="1954-06-24">June 24, 1954</date>, from funds appropriated pursuant to the Alaska Housing Act, as amended, which is classified, in part, to this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–5">section 1701g–5 of this title</ref>, and References in Text note thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddbdef981-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Revolving Fund</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Establishment of revolving fund under which to account for assets and liabilities in connection with notes and other obligations purchased pursuant to the Alaska Housing Act, as amended, which is classified, in part, to this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–5">section 1701g–5 of this title</ref>, and References in Text note thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddbdef982-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddbdef983-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Admission of Alaska and Hawaii to Statehood</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Alaska was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3269, <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 81, 73 Stat. c16, and Hawaii was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3309, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 6868. 73 Stat. c74. For Alaska Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. For Hawaii Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/4">73 Stat. 4</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s491">section 491 of Title 48</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
