<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc0a0161-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a"><num value="1715z–11a">§ 1715z–11a.</num><heading> Disposition of HUD-owned properties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0a0162-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Flexible authority for multifamily projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During fiscal year 1997 and fiscal years thereafter, the Secretary may manage and dispose of multifamily properties owned by the Secretary, including, for fiscal years 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and thereafter, the provision of grants and loans from the General Insurance Fund (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735c">12 U.S.C. 1735c</ref>) for the necessary costs of rehabilitation, demolition, or construction on the properties (which shall be eligible whether vacant or occupied), and multifamily mortgages held by the Secretary on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine, notwithstanding any other provision of law. A grant provided under this subsection during fiscal years 2006 through 2010 shall be available only to the extent that appropriations are made in advance for such purposes and shall not be derived from the General Insurance Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0a0163-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of unoccupied and substandard housing to local governments and community development corporations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0a0164-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding the authority under subsection (a) and the last sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710/g">section 1710(g) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall transfer ownership of any qualified HUD property, subject to the requirements of this section, to a unit of general local government having jurisdiction for the area in which the property is located or to a community development corporation which operates within such a unit of general local government in accordance with this subsection, but only to the extent that units of general local government and community development corporations consent to transfer and the Secretary determines that such transfer is practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0a0165-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified HUD properties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified HUD property” means any property for which, as of the date that notification of the property is first made under paragraph (3)(B), not less than 6 months have elapsed since the later of the date that the property was acquired by the Secretary or the date that the property was determined to be unoccupied or substandard, that is owned by the Secretary and is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an unoccupied multifamily housing project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a substandard multifamily housing project; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> an unoccupied single family property that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has been determined by the Secretary not to be an eligible asset under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710/h">section 1710(h) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> is an eligible asset under such <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710/h">section 1710(h) of this title</ref>, but—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc0c4b5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is not subject to a specific sale agreement under such section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc0c4b5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has been determined by the Secretary to be inappropriate for continued inclusion in the program under such <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710/h">section 1710(h) of this title</ref> pursuant to paragraph (10) of such section.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish procedures that provide for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> time deadlines for transfers under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> notification to units of general local government and community development corporations of qualified HUD properties in their jurisdictions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b60-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such units and corporations to express interest in the transfer under this subsection of such properties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b61-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> a right of first refusal for transfer of qualified HUD properties to units of general local government and community development corporations, under which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b62-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary shall establish a period during which the Secretary may not transfer such properties except to such units and corporations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b63-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Secretary shall offer qualified HUD properties that are single family properties for purchase by units of general local government at a cost of $1 for each property, but only to the extent that the costs to the Federal Government of disposal at such price do not exceed the costs to the Federal Government of disposing of property subject to the procedures for single family property established by the Secretary pursuant to the authority under the last sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710/g">section 1710(g) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b64-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the Secretary may accept an offer to purchase a property made by a community development corporation only if the offer provides for purchase on a cost recovery basis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b65-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the Secretary shall accept an offer to purchase such a property that is made during such period by such a unit or corporation and that complies with the requirements of this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4b66-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a written explanation, to any unit of general local government or community development corporation making an offer to purchase a qualified HUD property under this subsection that is not accepted, of the reason that such offer was not acceptable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b67-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Other disposition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to any qualified HUD property, if the Secretary does not receive an acceptable offer to purchase the property pursuant to the procedure established under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall dispose of the property to the unit of general local government in which property is located or to community development corporations located in such unit of general local government on a negotiated, competitive bid, or other basis, on such terms as the Secretary deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b68-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Satisfaction of indebtedness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before transferring ownership of any qualified HUD property pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall satisfy any indebtedness incurred in connection with the property to be transferred, by canceling the indebtedness.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b69-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of status of properties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To ensure compliance with the requirements of this subsection, the Secretary shall take the following actions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Upon enactment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon the enactment of this subsection [<date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>], the Secretary shall promptly assess each residential property owned by the Secretary to determine whether such property is a qualified HUD property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Upon acquisition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon acquiring any residential property, the Secretary shall promptly determine whether the property is a qualified HUD property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall periodically reassess the residential properties owned by the Secretary to determine whether any such properties have become qualified HUD properties.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Tenant leases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall not affect the terms or the enforceability of any contract or lease entered into with respect to any residential property before the date that such property becomes a qualified HUD property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Property transferred under this subsection shall be used only for appropriate neighborhood revitalization efforts, including homeownership, rental units, commercial space, and parks, consistent with local zoning regulations, local building codes, and subdivision regulations and restrictions of record.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b6f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability to properties made available for homeless</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, this subsection shall not apply to any properties that the Secretary determines are to be made available for use by the homeless pursuant to subpart E of part 291 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, during the period that the properties are so available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b70-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of existing contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection may not be construed to alter, affect, or annul any legally binding obligations entered into with respect to a qualified HUD property before the property becomes a qualified HUD property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b71-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b72-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Community development corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “community development corporation” means a nonprofit organization whose primary purpose is to promote community development by providing housing opportunities for low-income families.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b73-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost recovery basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “cost recovery basis” means, with respect to any sale of a residential property by the Secretary, that the purchase price paid by the purchaser is equal to or greater than the sum of: (i) the appraised value of the property, as determined in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary shall establish; and (ii) the costs incurred by the Secretary in connection with such property during the period beginning on the date on which the Secretary acquires title to the property and ending on the date on which the sale is consummated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b74-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Multifamily housing project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “multifamily housing project” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–11">section 1701z–11 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b75-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Residential property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “residential property” means a property that is a multifamily housing project or a single family property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b76-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b77-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Severe physical problems</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “severe physical problems” means, with respect to a dwelling unit, that the unit—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b78-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> lacks hot or cold piped water, a flush toilet, or both a bathtub and a shower in the unit, for the exclusive use of that unit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b79-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> on not less than three separate occasions during the preceding winter months, was uncomfortably cold for a period of more than 6 consecutive hours due to a malfunction of the heating system for the unit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b7a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> has no functioning electrical service, exposed wiring, any room in which there is not a functioning electrical outlet, or has experienced three or more blown fuses or tripped circuit breakers during the preceding 90-day period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b7b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> is accessible through a public hallway in which there are no working light fixtures, loose or missing steps or railings, and no elevator; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4b7c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> has severe maintenance problems, including water leaks involving the roof, windows, doors, basement, or pipes or plumbing fixtures, holes or open cracks in walls or ceilings, severe paint peeling or broken plaster, and signs of rodent infestation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b7d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Single family property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “single family property” means a 1- to 4-family residence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b7e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Substandard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “substandard” means, with respect to a multifamily housing project, that 25 percent or more of the dwelling units in the project have severe physical problems.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b7f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Unit of general local government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “unit of general local government” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5302/a">section 5302(a) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b80-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/11/J"><num value="J" class="bold">(J)</num><heading class="bold"> Unoccupied</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “unoccupied” means, with respect to a residential property, that the unit of general local government having jurisdiction over the area in which the project is located has certified in writing that the property is not inhabited.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b81-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b82-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/12/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall issue such interim regulations as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4b83-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–11a/b/12/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Final</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall issue such final regulations as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc0c4b84-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/204/tII/s204">Pub. L. 104–204, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1996-09-26">Sept. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2894">110 Stat. 2894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tII/s213">Pub. L. 105–65, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1366">111 Stat. 1366</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tII/s206">Pub. L. 105–276, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2484">112 Stat. 2484</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/74/tV/s537">Pub. L. 106–74, title V, § 537</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1122">113 Stat. 1122</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/377/s1/a/1/tII/s204">Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(a)(1) [title II, § 204]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1441">114 Stat. 1441</ref>, 1441A–24; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/7/tI/s141">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title I, § 141]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–614; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tII/s2003/a">Pub. L. 109–171, title II, § 2003(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/9">120 Stat. 9</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc0c4b85-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc0c4b86-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc0c4b87-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc0c4b88-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> inserted at end “A grant provided under this subsection during fiscal years 2006 through 2010 shall be available only to the extent that appropriations are made in advance for such purposes and shall not be derived from the General Insurance Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> substituted “Disposition of HUD-owned properties” for “Flexible authority” in section catchline, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/377">Pub. L. 106–377</ref> substituted “2000, and thereafter” for “and 2000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/74">Pub. L. 106–74</ref> substituted “1999, and 2000” for “and 1999” and “, demolition, or construction on the properties (which shall be eligible whether vacant or occupied)” for “or demolition”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/276">Pub. L. 105–276</ref> substituted “fiscal years 1997, 1998, and 1999” for “fiscal years 1997 and 1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/65">Pub. L. 105–65</ref> inserted “, including, for fiscal years 1997 and 1998, the provision of grants and loans from the General Insurance Fund (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735c">12 U.S.C. 1735c</ref>) for the necessary costs of rehabilitation or demolition,” after “owned by the Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc0c4b89-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc0c4b8a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> not applicable to any transaction that formally commences within one year prior to <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s2003/c">section 2003(c) of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–11">section 1701z–11 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
