<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc051fa0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a"><num value="1715z–4a">§ 1715z–4a.</num><heading> Double damages remedy for unauthorized use of multifamily housing project assets and income</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc051fa1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Action to recover assets or income</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc051fa2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may request the Attorney General to bring an action in a United States district court to recover any assets or income used by any person in violation of (A) a regulatory agreement that applies to a multifamily project, nursing home, intermediate care facility, board and care home, assisted living facility, or hospital whose mortgage is or, at the time of the violations, was insured or held by the Secretary under title II of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1707">12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.]; (B) a regulatory agreement that applies to a multifamily project whose mortgage is or, at the time of the violations, was insured or held by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including property subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>); (C) a regulatory agreement or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary that applies to mortgages insured or held or, at the time of the violations, was <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002170">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002170"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> insured or held by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–22">section 1715z–22 of this title</ref>, but not reinsured under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–22">section 1715z–22 of this title</ref>; or (D) any applicable regulation. For purposes of this section, a use of assets or income in violation of the regulatory agreement, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary, or any applicable regulation shall include any use for which the documentation in the books and accounts does not establish that the use was made for a reasonable operating expense or necessary repair of the property and has not been maintained in accordance with the requirements of the Secretary and in reasonable condition for proper audit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc051fa3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of a mortgage insured or held by the Secretary under title II of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1707">12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.], under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>) and under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–22">section 1715z–22 of this title</ref>, the term “any person” shall mean any person or entity that owns or operates a property, as identified in the regulatory agreement, including but not limited to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any stockholder holding 25 percent or more interest of a corporation that owns that property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any beneficial owner of the property under any business or trust;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any officer, director, or partner of an entity owning or controlling the property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any nursing home lessee or operator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> any hospital lessee or operator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051fa9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any other person or entity that controls the property regardless of that person or entity’s official relationship to the property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc051faa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> any heir, assignee, successor in interest, or agent of any person or entity described in the preceding subparagraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc051fab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiation of proceedings and temporary relief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General, upon request of the Secretary, shall have the exclusive authority to authorize the initiation of proceedings under this section. Pending final resolution of any action under this section, the court may grant appropriate temporary or preliminary relief, including restraining orders, injunctions, and acceptance of satisfactory performance bonds, to protect the interests of the Secretary and to prevent use of assets or income in violation of the regulatory agreement, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary, and any applicable regulation and to prevent loss of value of the realty and personalty involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc051fac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount recoverable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any judgment favorable to the United States entered under this section, the Attorney General may recover double the value of the assets and income of the property that the court determines to have been used in violation of the regulatory agreement, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary, or any applicable regulation, plus all costs relating to the action, including but not limited to reasonable attorney and auditing fees. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may apply the recovery, or any portion of the recovery, to the property or to the applicable insurance fund under the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">12 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.] or, in the case of any project for which the mortgage is held by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including property subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>), to the project or to the Department for use by the appropriate office within the Department for administrative costs related to enforcement of the requirements of the various programs administered by the Secretary, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc051fad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Time limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other statute of limitations, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to bring an action under this section at any time up to and including 6 years after the latest date that the Secretary discovers any use of a property’s assets and income in violation of the regulatory agreement, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary, or any applicable regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc051fae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–4a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued availability of other remedies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The remedy provided by this section is in addition to any other remedies available to the Secretary or the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc051faf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1913">101 Stat. 1913</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tV/s563">Pub. L. 105–65, title V, § 563</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1419">111 Stat. 1419</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dI/tII/s220">Pub. L. 108–447, div. I, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3319">118 Stat. 3319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/115/dA/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 109–115, div. A, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="2005-11-30">Nov. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2466">119 Stat. 2466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc051fb0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc051fb1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc051fb2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Housing Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 1701 et seq.). Title II of the National Housing Act is classified generally to this subchapter (§ 1707 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc051fb3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc051fb4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/115/s324/1">Pub. L. 109–115, § 324(1)</ref>, inserted “or, at the time of the violations, was” after “is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/115/s324/2">Pub. L. 109–115, § 324(2)</ref>, inserted “or, at the time of the violations, was insured or held” after “held”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/3">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(3)</ref>, substituted “property” for “project” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/1">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(1)</ref>, inserted “, nursing home, intermediate care facility, board and care home, assisted living facility, or hospital” after “project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(2)</ref>, inserted “or, at the time of the violations, was” after “whose mortgage is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/4">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(4)</ref>, substituted “that owns or operates a property, as identified in the regulatory agreement, including but not limited to—” and subpars. (A) to (G) for “which owns a project, as identified in the regulatory agreement, including but not limited to any stockholder holding 25 percent or more interest of a corporation that owns the project; any beneficial owner under any business or trust; any officer, director, or partner of an entity owning the project; and any heir, assignee, successor in interest, or agent of any owner.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/5">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(5)</ref>, substituted “property that the court determines” for “project that the court determines” and “property or to the applicable insurance fund” for “project or to the applicable insurance fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s220/6">Pub. L. 108–447, § 220(6)</ref>, substituted “a property’s” for “project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s563/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 563(1)</ref>, substituted “(B) a regulatory agreement that applies to a multifamily project whose mortgage is insured or held by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including property subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>); (C) a regulatory agreement or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary that applies to mortgages insured or held by the Secretary under section 542 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, but not reinsured under section 542 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992; or (D)” for “or (B)” in first sentence and inserted “, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary,” after “regulatory agreement” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s563/2">Pub. L. 105–65, § 563(2)</ref>, inserted “under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>) and under section 542 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992,” after “title II of National Housing Act,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s563/3">Pub. L. 105–65, § 563(3)</ref>, inserted “, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary,” after “regulatory agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s563/4">Pub. L. 105–65, § 563(4)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted “, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary,” after “regulatory agreement” and inserted before period at end of second sentence “or, in the case of any project for which the mortgage is held by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> (including property subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of this title</ref> as it existed before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>), to the project or to the Department for use by the appropriate office within the Department for administrative costs related to enforcement of the requirements of the various programs administered by the Secretary, as appropriate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s563/5">Pub. L. 105–65, § 563(5)</ref>, inserted “, or such other form of regulatory control as may be imposed by the Secretary,” after “regulatory agreement”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
