<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc0c4bb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a"><num value="1715z–13a">§ 1715z–13a.</num><heading> Loan guarantees for Indian housing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To provide access to sources of private financing to Indian families, Indian housing authorities, and Indian tribes, who otherwise could not acquire housing financing because of the unique legal status of Indian lands, the Secretary may guarantee not to exceed 100 percent of the unpaid principal and interest due on any loan eligible under subsection (b) made to an Indian family, Indian housing authority, or Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible loans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Loans guaranteed pursuant to this section shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bbb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible borrowers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The loans shall be made only to borrowers who are Indian families, Indian housing authorities, or Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bbc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible housing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The loan shall be used to construct, acquire, refinance, or rehabilitate 1- to 4-family dwellings that are standard housing and are located on trust land or land located in an Indian or Alaska Native area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bbd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Security</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The loan may be secured by any collateral authorized under existing Federal law or applicable State or tribal law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bbe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Lenders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The loan shall be made only by a lender approved by and meeting qualifications established by the Secretary, except that loans otherwise insured or guaranteed by an agency of the Federal Government or made by an organization of Indians from amounts borrowed from the United States shall not be eligible for guarantee under this section. The following lenders are deemed to be approved under this paragraph:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bbf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any mortgagee approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for participation in the single family mortgage insurance program under title II of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1707">12 U.S.C. 1707</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any lender whose housing loans under chapter 37 of title 38 are automatically guaranteed pursuant to section 1802(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002174">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002174"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be section “3702(d)”.</note> of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any lender approved by the Secretary of Agriculture to make guaranteed loans for single family housing under the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">42 U.S.C. 1441</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any other lender that is supervised, approved, regulated, or insured by any agency of the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bc3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The loan shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be made for a term not exceeding 30 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> bear interest (exclusive of the guarantee fee under section 404 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002175">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002175"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection (d)”.</note> and service charges, if any) at a rate agreed upon by the borrower and the lender and determined by the Secretary to be reasonable, which may not exceed the rate generally charged in the area (as determined by the Secretary) for home mortgage loans not guaranteed or insured by any agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> involve a principal obligation not exceeding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4bc7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 97.75 percent of the appraised value of the property as of the date the loan is accepted for guarantee (or 98.75 percent if the value of the property is $50,000 or less); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4bc8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount approved by the Secretary under this section; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bc9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> involve a payment on account of the property (i) in cash or its equivalent, or (ii) through the value of any improvements to the property made through the skilled or unskilled labor of the borrower, as the Secretary shall provide.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certificate of guarantee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bcb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before the Secretary approves any loan for guarantee under this section, the lender shall submit the application for the loan to the Secretary for examination. If the Secretary approves the loan for guarantee, the Secretary shall issue a certificate under this paragraph as evidence of the guarantee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bcc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard for approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may approve a loan for guarantee under this section and issue a certificate under this paragraph only if the Secretary determines there is a reasonable prospect of repayment of the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bcd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A certificate of guarantee issued under this paragraph by the Secretary shall be conclusive evidence of the eligibility of the loan for guarantee under the provisions of this section and the amount of such guarantee. Such evidence shall be incontestable in the hands of the bearer and the full faith and credit of the United States is pledged to the payment of all amounts agreed to be paid by the Secretary as security for such obligations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Fraud and misrepresentation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection may not be construed to preclude the Secretary from establishing defenses against the original lender based on fraud or material misrepresentation or to bar the Secretary from establishing by regulations in effect on the date of issuance or disbursement, whichever is earlier, partial defenses to the amount payable on the guarantee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bcf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Trailing documents</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may issue a certificate of guarantee under this subsection for a loan involving a security interest in Indian trust land before the Secretary receives the trailing documents required by the Secretary from the Bureau of Indian Affairs, including the final certified title status report showing the recordation by the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the mortgage relating to the loan, if the originating lender agrees to indemnify the Secretary for any losses that may result when—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4bd1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a claim payment is presented to the Secretary due to the default of the borrower on the loan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0c4bd2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the required trailing documents are outstanding.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of indemnification agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An indemnification agreement between an originating lender and the Secretary described in subparagraph (A) shall only terminate upon receipt by the Secretary of the trailing documents described in that subparagraph in a form and manner that is acceptable to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/c/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as authorizing the Bureau of Indian Affairs to delay the issuance of a final certified title status report and recorded mortgage relating to a loan closed on Indian trust land.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Guarantee fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish and collect, at the time of issuance of the guarantee, a fee for the guarantee of loans under this section, in an amount not exceeding 3 percent of the principal obligation of the loan. The Secretary may also establish and collect annual premium payments in an amount not exceeding 1 percent of the remaining guaranteed balance (excluding the portion of the remaining balance attributable to the fee collected at the time of issuance of the guarantee). The Secretary shall establish the amount of the fees and premiums by publishing a notice in the Federal Register. The Secretary shall deposit any fees and premiums collected under this subsection in the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund established under subsection (i).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability under guarantee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The liability under a guarantee provided under this section shall decrease or increase on a pro rata basis according to any decrease or increase in the amount of the unpaid obligation under the provisions of the loan agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer and assumption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any loan guaranteed under this section, including the security given for the loan, may be sold or assigned by the lender to any financial institution subject to examination and supervision by an agency of the Federal Government or of any State or the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Disqualification of lenders and civil money penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bd9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that any lender or holder of a guarantee certificate under subsection (c) has failed to maintain adequate accounting records, to adequately service loans guaranteed under this section, to exercise proper credit or underwriting judgment, or has engaged in practices otherwise detrimental to the interest of a borrower or the United States, the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> refuse, either temporarily or permanently, to guarantee any further loans made by such lender or holder;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bdb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> bar such lender or holder from acquiring additional loans guaranteed under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bdc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> require that such lender or holder assume not less than 10 percent of any loss on further loans made or held by the lender or holder that are guaranteed under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bdd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil money penalties for intentional violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that any lender or holder of a guarantee certificate under subsection (c) has intentionally failed to maintain adequate accounting records, to adequately service loans guaranteed under this section, or to exercise proper credit or underwriting judgment, the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on such lender or holder in the manner and amount provided under section 536 of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14">12 U.S.C. 1735f–14</ref>] with respect to mortgagees and lenders under such Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bde-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment on loans made in good faith</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), the Secretary may not refuse to pay pursuant to a valid guarantee on loans of a lender or holder barred under this subsection if the loans were previously made in good faith.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bdf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment under guarantee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Lender options</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the event of default by the borrower on a loan guaranteed under this section, the holder of the guarantee certificate shall provide written notice of the default to the Secretary. Upon providing such notice, the holder of the guarantee certificate shall be entitled to payment under the guarantee (subject to the provisions of this section) and may proceed to obtain payment in one of the following manners:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/1/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The holder of the certificate may initiate foreclosure proceedings (after providing written notice of such action to the Secretary) and upon a final order by the court authorizing foreclosure and submission to the Secretary of a claim for payment under the guarantee, the Secretary shall pay to the holder of the certificate the pro rata portion of the amount guaranteed (as determined pursuant to subsection (e)) plus reasonable fees and expenses as approved by the Secretary. The Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the holder of the guarantee and the lender holder shall assign the obligation and security to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/1/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> No foreclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Without seeking foreclosure (or in any case in which a foreclosure proceeding initiated under clause (i) continues for a period in excess of 1 year), the holder of the guarantee may submit to the Secretary a request to assign the obligation and security interest to the Secretary in return for payment of the claim under the guarantee. The Secretary may accept assignment of the loan if the Secretary determines that the assignment is in the best interests of the United States. Upon assignment, the Secretary shall pay to the holder of the guarantee the pro rata portion of the amount guaranteed (as determined under subsection (e)). The Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the holder of the guarantee and the holder shall assign the obligation and security to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before any payment under a guarantee is made under subparagraph (A), the holder of the guarantee shall exhaust all reasonable possibilities of collection. Exhausting all reasonable possibilities of collection by the holder of the guarantee shall include a good faith consideration of loan modification as well as meeting standards for servicing loans in default, as determined by the Secretary. Upon payment, in whole or in part, to the holder, the note or judgment evidencing the debt shall be assigned to the United States and the holder shall have no further claim against the borrower or the United States. The Secretary shall then take such action to collect as the Secretary determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on liquidation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the event of a default by the borrower on a loan guaranteed under this section involving a security interest in restricted Indian land, the mortgagee or the Secretary shall only pursue liquidation after offering to transfer the account to an eligible tribal member, the tribe, or the Indian housing authority serving the tribe or tribes. If the mortgagee or the Secretary subsequently proceeds to liquidate the account, the mortgagee or the Secretary shall not sell, transfer, or otherwise dispose of or alienate the property except to one of the entities described in the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund for the purpose of providing loan guarantees under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4be8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Credits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Guarantee Fund shall be credited with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4be9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any amounts, claims, notes, mortgages, contracts, and property acquired by the Secretary under this section, and any collections and proceeds therefrom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any amounts appropriated under paragraph (7);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4beb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any guarantee fees collected under subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any interest or earnings on amounts invested under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Use</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts in the Guarantee Fund shall be available, to the extent provided in appropriation Acts, for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> fulfilling any obligations of the Secretary with respect to loans guaranteed under this section, including the costs (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661a">section 661a of title 2</ref>) of such loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> paying taxes, insurance, prior liens, expenses necessary to make fiscal adjustment in connection with the application and transmittal of collections, and other expenses and advances to protect the Secretary for loans which are guaranteed under this section or held by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bf0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> acquiring such security property at foreclosure sales or otherwise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bf1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> paying administrative expenses in connection with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0c4bf2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> reasonable and necessary costs of rehabilitation and repair to properties that the Secretary holds or owns pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any amounts in the Guarantee Fund determined by the Secretary to be in excess of amounts currently required to carry out this section may be invested in obligations of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on commitments to guarantee loans and mortgages</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The authority of the Secretary to enter into commitments to guarantee loans under this section shall be effective for any fiscal year to the extent or in such amounts as are or have been provided in appropriations Acts, without regard to the fiscal year for which such amounts were appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on costs of guarantees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The authority of the Secretary to enter into commitments to guarantee loans under this section shall be effective for any fiscal year only to the extent that amounts in the Guarantee Fund are or have been made available in appropriation Acts to cover the costs (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661a">section 661a of title 2</ref>) of such loan guarantees for such fiscal year. Any amounts appropriated pursuant to this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on outstanding aggregate principal amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to the limitations in subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary may enter into commitments to guarantee loans under this section in each of fiscal years 2008 through 2012 with an aggregate outstanding principal amount not exceeding such amount as may be provided in appropriation Acts for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0c4bf8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Liabilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All liabilities and obligations of the assets credited to the Guarantee Fund under paragraph (2)(A) shall be liabilities and obligations of the Guarantee Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0ebbf9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/i/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Guarantee Fund to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2012.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0ebbfa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for standard housing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish housing safety and quality standards for use under this section. Such standards shall provide sufficient flexibility to permit the use of various designs and materials in housing acquired with loans guaranteed under this section. The standards shall require each dwelling unit in any housing so acquired to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebbfb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be decent, safe, sanitary, and modest in size and design;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebbfc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> conform with applicable general construction standards for the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebbfd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> contain a heating system that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebbfe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has the capacity to maintain a minimum temperature in the dwelling of 65 degrees Fahrenheit during the coldest weather in the area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebbff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is safe to operate and maintain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc00-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> delivers a uniform distribution of heat; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc01-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> conforms to any applicable tribal heating code or, if there is no applicable tribal code, an appropriate county, State, or National code;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc02-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> contain a plumbing system that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc03-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> uses a properly installed system of piping;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc04-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes a kitchen sink and a partitional bathroom with lavatory, toilet, and bath or shower; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc05-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> uses water supply, plumbing, and sewage disposal systems that conform to any applicable tribal code or, if there is no applicable tribal code, the minimum standards established by the applicable county or State;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc06-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> contain an electrical system using wiring and equipment properly installed to safely supply electrical energy for adequate lighting and for operation of appliances that conforms to any applicable tribal code or, if there is no applicable tribal code, an appropriate county, State, or National code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc07-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> be not less than—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc08-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc09-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 570 square feet in size, if designed for a family of not more than 4 persons;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc0a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 850 square feet in size, if designed for a family of not less than 5 and not more than 7 persons; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc0b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> 1020 square feet in size, if designed for a family of not less than 8 persons, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc0c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the size provided under the applicable locally adopted standards for size of dwelling units;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that the Secretary, upon the request of a tribe or Indian housing authority, may waive the size requirements under this paragraph; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc0d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/j/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> conform with the energy performance requirements for new construction established by the Secretary under section 526(a) of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–4/a">12 U.S.C. 1735f–4(a)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0ebc0e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of environmental,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002176">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002176"><num>3</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> review, decisionmaking, and action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) and any other law that furthers the purposes of that Act, a loan guarantee under this section shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc0f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be treated as a grant under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4101">25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc10-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be subject to the regulations promulgated by the Secretary to carry out section 105 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4115">25 U.S.C. 4115</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc0ebc11-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc12-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “family” means 1 or more persons maintaining a household, as the Secretary shall by regulation provide.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc13-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Guarantee Fund” means the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund established under subsection (i).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc14-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “Indian” means person recognized as being Indian or Alaska Native by an Indian tribe, the Federal Government, or any State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc15-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “Indian area” means the area within which an Indian housing authority or Indian tribe is authorized to provide housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc16-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “Indian housing authority” means any entity that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc17-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> is authorized to engage in or assist in the development or operation of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0ebc18-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> low-income housing for Indians; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0ebc19-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> housing subject to the provisions of this section; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc0ebc1a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> is established—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0ebc1b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> by exercise of the power of self-government of an Indian tribe independent of State law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc0ebc1c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> by operation of State law providing specifically for housing authorities for Indians, including regional housing authorities in the State of Alaska.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The term includes tribally designated housing entities under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4101">25 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.].</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc1d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc1e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “standard housing” means a dwelling unit or housing that complies with the requirements established under subsection (j).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc1f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribe; indian tribe</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “tribe” or “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community of Indians, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act of 1975 [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc0ebc20-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a/l/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “trust land” means land title to which is held by the United States for the benefit of an Indian or Indian tribe or title to which is held by an Indian tribe subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc0ebc21-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tI/s184">Pub. L. 102–550, title I, § 184</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3739">106 Stat. 3739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 104–330, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>–(j), <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4048-4050">110 Stat. 4048–4050</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s595/e/11">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 595(e)(11)</ref>–(13), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2658">112 Stat. 2658</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/377/s1/a/1/tII/s227">Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(a)(1) [title II, § 227]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1441">114 Stat. 1441</ref>, 1441A–30; <ref href="/us/pl/106/568/tX/s1002">Pub. L. 106–568, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2925">114 Stat. 2925</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tV/s502">Pub. L. 106–569, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2961">114 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/292/s2/d">Pub. L. 107–292, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-13">Nov. 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2053">116 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/37/s2">Pub. L. 110–37, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-06-18">June 18, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/229">121 Stat. 229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/6/dF/tVIII/s1806">Pub. L. 113–6, div. F, title VIII, § 1806</ref>, <date date="2013-03-26">Mar. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/433">127 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dK/tII/s241">Pub. L. 113–235, div. K, title II, § 241</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2759">128 Stat. 2759</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Q, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2171">134 Stat. 2171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc0ebc22-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc0ebc23-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc0ebc24-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Housing Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(4)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1707 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (b)(4)(C), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">act July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/413">63 Stat. 413</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 8A (§ 1441 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">section 1441 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (k), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996, referred to in subsecs. (k)(1) and (<i>l</i>)(5), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/330">Pub. L. 104–330</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4016">110 Stat. 4016</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 43 (§ 4101 et seq.) of Title 25, Indians. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4101">section 4101 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>)(8), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>)(8), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 46 (§ 5301 et seq.) of Title 25, Indians. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc0ebc25-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and not as part of the National Housing Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc0ebc26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (h)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/235">Pub. L. 113–235</ref> inserted after first sentence “Exhausting all reasonable possibilities of collection by the holder of the guarantee shall include a good faith consideration of loan modification as well as meeting standards for servicing loans in default, as determined by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/113/6">Pub. L. 113–6</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary shall fix and collect a guarantee fee for the guarantee of loans under this section, which may not exceed the amount equal to 1 percent of the principal obligation of the loan. The fee shall be paid by the lender at time of issuance of the guarantee and shall be adequate, in the determination of the Secretary, to cover expenses and probable losses. The Secretary shall deposit any fees collected under this subsection in the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund established under subsection (i) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (i)(5)(C),(7). <ref href="/us/pl/110/37">Pub. L. 110–37</ref> substituted “fiscal years 2008 through 2012” for “fiscal years 1997 through 2007”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (i)(5)(C), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/107/292">Pub. L. 107–292</ref> substituted “each of fiscal years 1997 through 2007” for “each fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/377/s1/a/1/tII/s227/1">Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(a)(1) [title II, § 227(1)]</ref>, struck out “or as a result of a lack of access to private financial markets” after “legal status of Indian lands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/377/s1/a/1/tII/s227/2">Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(a)(1) [title II, § 227(2)]</ref>, inserted “refinance,” after “acquire,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/106/568/s1002/1">Pub. L. 106–568, § 1002(1)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s502/1">Pub. L. 106–569, § 502(1)</ref>, amended par. (5) identically, adding subpar. (C) and striking out heading and text of former subpar. (C). Text read as follows: “Subject to the limitations in subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary may enter into commitments to guarantee loans under this section in each of fiscal years 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001 with an aggregate outstanding principal amount not exceeding $400,000,000 for each such fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/106/568/s1002/2">Pub. L. 106–568, § 1002(2)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s502/2">Pub. L. 106–569, § 502(2)</ref>, amended par. (7) identically, substituting “each fiscal year” for “each of fiscal years 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s595/e/11">Pub. L. 105–276, § 595(e)(11)</ref>, struck out before period at end “that is under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe for which an Indian housing plan has been submitted and approved pursuant to sections 102 and 103 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 that provides for the use of loan guarantees under this section to provide affordable homeownership housing in such areas.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s595/e/12">Pub. L. 105–276, § 595(e)(12)</ref>, substituted “not” for “note”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s595/e/13">Pub. L. 105–276, § 595(e)(13)</ref>, added subsec. (k) and redesignated former subsec. (k) as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/a/1">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, (b), substituted “, Indian housing authorities, and Indian tribes,” for “and Indian housing authorities”, “lands or as a result of a lack of access to private financial markets” for “trust land”, and “, Indian housing authority, or Indian tribe” for “or Indian housing authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/a/2">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “, Indian housing authorities, or Indian tribes” for “or Indian housing authorities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/c">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(c)</ref>, inserted before period at end “that is under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe for which an Indian housing plan has been submitted and approved pursuant to sections 102 and 103 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 that provides for the use of loan guarantees under this section to provide affordable homeownership housing in such areas”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/i">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(i)</ref>, added cl. (i) and struck out former cl. (i) which read as follows: “an amount equal to the sum of (I) 97 percent of $25,000 of the appraised value of the property, as of the date the loan is accepted for guarantee, and (II) 95 percent of such value in excess of $25,000; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(d)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “in a court of competent jurisdiction” after “foreclosure proceedings” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/d/1/B">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(d)(1)(B)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out heading and text of former cl. (ii). Text read as follows: “Without seeking a judicial foreclosure (or in any case in which a foreclosure proceeding initiated under clause (i) continues for a period in excess of 1 year), the holder of the guarantee may submit to the Secretary a claim for payment under the guarantee and the Secretary shall only pay to such holder for a loss on any single loan an amount equal to 90 percent of the pro rata portion of the amount guaranteed (as determined under subsection (e) of this section). The Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the holder of the guarantee and the holder shall assign the obligation and security to the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/d/2">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(d)(2)</ref>, (3), (e), redesignated par. (3) as (2), in first sentence substituted “restricted Indian land, the mortgagee or” for “tribal allotted or trust land,”, in second sentence substituted “mortgagee or the Secretary” for “Secretary” in two places, and struck out heading and text of former par. (2). Text read as follows: “Notwithstanding paragraph (1), upon receiving notice of default on a loan guaranteed under this section from the holder of the guarantee, the Secretary may accept assignment of the loan if the Secretary determines that the assignment is in the best interests of the United States. Upon assignment the Secretary shall pay to the holder of the guarantee the pro rata portion of the amount guaranteed (as determined under subsection (e) of this section). The Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the holder of the guarantee and the holder shall assign the obligation and security to the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/j/1">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(j)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out heading and text of former subpar. (A). Text read as follows: “The authority of the Secretary to enter into commitments to guarantee loans under this section shall be effective for any fiscal year only to the extent or in such amounts as are or have been provided in appropriations Acts for such fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/j/2">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(j)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “Any amounts appropriated pursuant to this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/f">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(f)</ref>, substituted “1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001 with an aggregate outstanding principal amount note exceeding $400,000,000 for each such fiscal year” for “1993 and 1994 with an aggregate outstanding principal amount not exceeding such amount as may be provided in appropriation Acts for each such year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/g">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(g)</ref>, substituted “such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001” for “such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 1993 and $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1994”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/h/1">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(h)(1)</ref>, inserted “or Indian tribe” after “authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/h/2">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(h)(2)</ref>, inserted concluding provisions, added subpar. (A), and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “is authorized to engage in or assist in the development or operation of low-income housing for Indians; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s701/h/3">Pub. L. 104–330, § 701(h)(3)</ref>, added par. (8) and struck out former par. (8) which read as follows: “The term ‘tribe’ means any tribe, band, pueblo, group, community, or nation of Indians or Alaska Natives.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc0ebc27-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc0ebc28-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s595/f">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 595(f)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2659">112 Stat. 2659</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s595/f">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4168">section 4168 of Title 25</ref>, Indians, amending this section, sections 4103, 4111 to 4113, 4131, 4135 to 4139 of Title 25, and sections 1437e and 12899h–1 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and repealing provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of Title 42</ref>] are made and shall apply beginning upon the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc0ebc29-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings Related to Improvements to Loan Guarantees for Indian Housing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tI/s105/a">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Q, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2170">134 Stat. 2170</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tI/s105/a">
<inline>“Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the extended timelines for approving lenders’ applications to participate in the program established under section 184 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a">12 U.S.C. 1715z–13a</ref>) are unacceptably long;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> those extended timelines inhibit the ability of lenders to provide needed mortgage loans on Native American reservations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> it can take a significant amount of time for certain Bureau of Indian Affairs Land Title and Records Offices to issue final certified title status reports for mortgages issued on Indian trust land under section 184 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a">12 U.S.C. 1715z–13a</ref>), which delays the guarantee of the loan by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc0ebc2a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports on Acceleration of Processing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tI/s105/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Q, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2171">134 Stat. 2171</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tI/s105/c">
<inline>“The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on a semi-annual basis on the progress that the Secretary is making to accelerate the processing of loan applications on fee simple and Indian trust land under section 184 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–13a">12 U.S.C. 1715z–13a</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if there is no improvement in accelerating those processing timelines, submit to the committees described in paragraph (1) a report explaining the lack of improvement.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
