<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc244040-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1731a"><num value="1731a">§ 1731a.</num><heading> Penalties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to refuse the benefits of participation (either directly as an insured lender or as a borrower, or indirectly as a builder, contractor, or dealer, or salesman or sales agent for a builder, contractor or dealer) under subchapter I, II, VI, VII, VIII, IX–B, or X of this chapter to any person or firm (including but not limited to any individual, partnership, association, trust, or corporation) if the Secretary has determined that such person or firm (1) has knowingly or willfully violated any provision of this chapter or of title III of the Servicemen’s Readjustment Act of 1944, as amended, or of chapter 37 of title 38, or of any regulation issued by the Secretary under this chapter or by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under said title III, or chapter 37, or (2) has, in connection with any construction, alteration, repair or improvement work financed with assistance under this chapter or under said title III, or chapter 37, or in connection with contracts or financing relating to such work, violated any Federal or State penal statute, or (3) has failed materially to properly carry out contractual obligations with respect to the completion of construction, alteration, repair, or improvement work financed with assistance under this chapter or under title III of the Servicemen’s Readjustment Act of 1944, as amended, or of chapter 37 of title 38. Before any such determination is made any person or firm with respect to whom such a determination is proposed shall be notified in writing by the Secretary and shall be entitled, upon making a written request to the Secretary, to a written notice specifying charges in reasonable detail and an opportunity to be heard and to be represented by counsel. Determinations made by the Secretary under this section shall be based on the preponderance of the evidence. For the purposes of compliance with this section the Secretary’s notice of a proposed determination under this section shall be considered to have been received by the interested person or firm if the notice is properly mailed to the last known address of such person or firm.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddc244041-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title V, § 512, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-02/ch649">Aug. 2, 1954, ch. 649</ref>, title I, § 132, <ref href="/us/stat/68/610">68 Stat. 610</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/85/857/s13/h">Pub. L. 85–857, § 13(h)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1265">72 Stat. 1265</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/372/tI/s119">Pub. L. 86–372, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1959-09-23">Sept. 23, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/665">73 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/754/tX/s1020/e">Pub. L. 89–754, title X, § 1020(e)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1296">80 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s1/a/3">Pub. L. 90–19, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/17">81 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII/s204/a/17">Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 204(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2232">98 Stat. 2232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/235/tI/s133/d/3">Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 133(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2027">103 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/54/s13/d/2/B">Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(d)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/274">105 Stat. 274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc244042-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc244043-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc244044-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Servicemen’s Readjustment Act of 1944, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1944-06-22/ch268">act June 22, 1944, ch. 268</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/284">58 Stat. 284</ref>. Title III of the Servicemen’s Readjustment Act of 1944 was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 694 et seq.) of chapter 11C of former Title 38, Pensions, Bonuses, and Veterans’ Relief, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/85/857/s14/87">section 14(87) of Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1273">72 Stat. 1273</ref>, the first section of which reenacted title III of such Act as chapter 37 (§ 1801 [now 3701] et seq.) of Title 38, Veterans’ Benefits.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddc244045-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 512 of act of <date date="1934-06-27">June 27, 1934</date>, related to offenses and penalties, and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1731">section 1731 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645/s21">act June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/862">62 Stat. 862</ref>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>. See note under section 1731.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc244046-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/54">Pub. L. 102–54</ref> substituted “Secretary of Veterans Affairs” for “Administrator of Veterans’ Affairs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/235">Pub. L. 101–235</ref> struck out reference to subchapter IX–A after reference to subchapter VIII.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/479">Pub. L. 98–479</ref> substituted “Penalties” for “Denial of benefits in cases of abuses; determination by Secretary; notice and hearing” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/16">Pub. L. 90–16</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Commissioner” wherever appearing, and “Secretary’s” for “Commissioner’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/754">Pub. L. 89–754</ref> inserted references to subchapters IX–A and IX–B of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/372">Pub. L. 86–372</ref> provided that for purposes of compliance with this section the Commissioner’s notice of a proposed determination under this section shall be considered to have been received by the interested person or firm if the notice is properly mailed to the last known address of such person or firm.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref> inserted references to chapter 37 of title 38.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc244047-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc244048-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref> effective <date date="1959-01-01">Jan. 1, 1959</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/857/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note preceding part I of Title 38, Veterans’ Benefits.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
