<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc28fb2e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14"><num value="1735f–14">§ 1735f–14.</num><heading> Civil money penalties against mortgagees, lenders, and other participants in FHA programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb2f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb30-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a mortgagee approved under the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002198">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002198"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “this”.</note> chapter, a lender holding a contract of insurance under subchapter I, or a principal, officer, or employee of such mortgagee or lender, or other person or entity participating in either an insured mortgage or subchapter I loan transaction under this chapter or providing assistance to the borrower in connection with any such loan, including sellers of the real estate involved, borrowers, closing agents, title companies, real estate agents, mortgage brokers, appraisers, loan correspondents and dealers, knowingly and materially violates any applicable provision of subsection (b), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the mortgagee or lender, or such other person or entity, in accordance with this section. The penalty under this paragraph shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions. The penalty shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb31-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount of the penalty, as determined by the Secretary, may not exceed $5,000 for each violation, except that the maximum penalty for all violations by any particular mortgagee or lender or such other person or entity during any 1-year period shall not exceed $1,000,000. Each violation of a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002199">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002199"><num>2</num> So in original. The word “a” probably should not appear.</note> the provisions of subsection (b)(1) shall constitute a separate violation with respect to each mortgage or loan application. In the case of a continuing violation, as determined by the Secretary, each day shall constitute a separate violation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of the mortgagee’s failure to engage in loss mitigation activities, as provided in subsection (b)(1)(I), the penalty shall be in the amount of three times the amount of any insurance benefits claimed by the mortgagee with respect to any mortgage for which the mortgagee failed to engage in such loss mitigation actions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb32-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations for which a penalty may be imposed</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb33-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty under subsection (a) for any knowing and material violation by a mortgagee or lender or any of its owners, officers, or directors, as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb34-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except where expressly permitted by statute, regulation, or contract approved by the Secretary, transfer of a mortgage insured under this chapter to a mortgagee not approved by the Secretary, or transfer of a loan to a transferee that is not holding a contract of insurance under subchapter I of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb35-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Failure of a nonsupervised mortgagee, as defined by the Secretary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb36-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to segregate all escrow funds received from a mortgagor for ground rents, taxes, assessments, and insurance premiums; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb37-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to deposit these funds in a special account with a depository institution whose accounts are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation through the Deposit Insurance Fund, or by the National Credit Union Administration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb38-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Use of escrow funds for any purpose other than that for which they were received.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb39-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Submission to the Secretary of information that was false, in connection with any mortgage insured under this chapter, or any loan that is covered by a contract of insurance under subchapter I of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb3a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> With respect to an officer, director, principal, or employee—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb3b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> hiring such an individual whose duties will involve, directly or indirectly, programs administered by the Secretary, while that person was under suspension or withdrawal by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb3c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> retaining in employment such an individual who continues to be involved, directly or indirectly, in programs administered by the Secretary, while that person was under suspension or withdrawal by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb3d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Falsely certifying to the Secretary or submitting to the Secretary a false certification by another person or entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb3e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> Failure to comply with an agreement, certification, or condition of approval set forth on, or applicable to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb3f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the application of a mortgagee or lender for approval by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc28fb40-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the notification by a mortgagee or lender to the Secretary concerning establishment of a branch office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb41-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Violation of any provisions of subchapter I or II of this chapter, or any implementing regulation, handbook, or mortgagee letter that is issued under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb42-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Failure to engage in loss mitigation actions as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715u/a">section 1715u(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb43-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> Failure to perform a required physical inspection of the mortgaged property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb44-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> Violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1708/d">section 1708(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb45-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> Use of “Federal Housing Administration”, “Department of Housing and Urban Development”, “Government National Mortgage Association”, “Ginnie Mae”, the acronyms “HUD”, “FHA”, or “GNMA”, or any official seal or logo of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, except as authorized by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb46-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional violations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty under subsection (a) for any knowing and material violation by a principal, officer, or employee of a mortgagee or lender, or other participants in either an insured mortgage or subchapter I loan transaction under this chapter or provision of assistance to the borrower in connection with any such loan, including sellers of the real estate involved, borrowers, closing agents, title companies, real estate agents, mortgage brokers, appraisers, loan correspondents, and dealers for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb47-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> submission to the Secretary of information that was false, in connection with any mortgage insured under this chapter, or any loan that is covered by a contract of insurance under subchapter I of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb48-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> falsely certifying to the Secretary or submitting to the Secretary a false certification by another person or entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb49-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> failure by a loan correspondent or dealer to submit to the Secretary information which is required by regulations or directives in connection with any loan that is covered by a contract of insurance under subchapter I; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb4a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> causing or participating in any of the violations set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb4b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against misleading use of Federal entity designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty, as adjusted from time to time, under subsection (a) for any use of “Federal Housing Administration”, “Department of Housing and Urban Development”, “Government National Mortgage Association”, “Ginnie Mae”, the acronyms “HUD”, “FHA”, or “GNMA”, or any official seal or logo of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, by any person, party, company, firm, partnership, or business, including sellers of real estate, closing agents, title companies, real estate agents, mortgage brokers, appraisers, loan correspondents, and dealers, except as authorized by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb4c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb4d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under subsection (a). These standards and procedures—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb4e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall provide for the Secretary to make the determination to impose the penalty or to use an administrative entity (such as the Mortgagee Review Board, established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1708/c">section 1708(c) of this title</ref>) to make the determination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb4f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall provide for the imposition of a penalty only after the mortgagee or lender or such other person or entity has been given an opportunity for a hearing on the record; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc28fb50-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> may provide for review by the Secretary of any determination or order, or interlocutory ruling, arising from a hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb51-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Final orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If no hearing is requested within 15 days of receipt of the notice of opportunity for hearing, the imposition of the penalty shall constitute a final and unappealable determination. If the Secretary reviews the determination or order, the Secretary may affirm, modify, or reverse that determination or order. If the Secretary does not review the determination or order within 90 days of the issuance of the determination or order, the determination or order shall be final.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb52-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors in determining amount of penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In determining the amount of a penalty under subsection (a), consideration shall be given to such factors as the gravity of the offense, any history of prior offenses (including those before <date date="1989-12-15">December 15, 1989</date>), ability to pay the penalty, injury to the public, benefits received, deterrence of future violations, and such other factors as the Secretary may determine in regulations to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb53-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reviewability of imposition of penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary’s determination or order imposing a penalty under subsection (a) shall not be subject to review, except as provided in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb54-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review of agency determination</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb55-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After exhausting all administrative remedies established by the Secretary under subsection (c)(1), a mortgagee or lender or such other person or entity against whom the Secretary has imposed a civil money penalty under subsection (a) may obtain a review of the penalty and such ancillary issues (such as any administrative sanctions under 24 C.F.R. parts 24 and 25) as may be addressed in the notice of determination to impose a penalty under subsection (c)(1)(A) in the appropriate court of appeals of the United States, by filing in such court, within 20 days after the entry of such order or determination, a written petition praying that the Secretary’s determination or order be modified or be set aside in whole or in part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Objections not raised in hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The court shall not consider any objection that was not raised in the hearing conducted pursuant to subsection (c)(1) unless a demonstration is made of extraordinary circumstances causing the failure to raise the objection. If any party demonstrates to the satisfaction of the court that additional evidence not presented at the hearing is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to present such evidence at the hearing, the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary for consideration of the additional evidence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The decisions, findings, and determinations of the Secretary shall be reviewed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s706">section 706 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Order to pay penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any such review, the court shall have the power to order payment of the penalty imposed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Action to collect penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any mortgagee or lender or such other person or entity fails to comply with the Secretary’s determination or order imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (a), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by subsections (c)(1) and (d), the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in an appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the mortgagee or lender or such other person or entity and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the court’s discretion, include the attorneys fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Settlement by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> “Knowingly” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a person acts knowingly when a person has actual knowledge of acts or should have known of the acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc28fb5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–14/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit of penalties in insurance funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all civil money penalties collected under this section shall be deposited in the appropriate insurance fund or funds established under this chapter, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc28fb5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title V, § 536, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/235/tI/s107/a">Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2000">103 Stat. 2000</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tII/s2704/d/13/B">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2704(d)(13)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-490">110 Stat. 3009–490</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tV/s553">Pub. L. 105–65, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1413">111 Stat. 1413</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tVI/s601/g">Pub. L. 105–276, title VI, § 601(g)</ref>, (h), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2674">112 Stat. 2674</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dI/tII/s219/a">Pub. L. 108–447, div. I, title II, § 219(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3319">118 Stat. 3319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tII/s2102/b">Pub. L. 109–171, title II, § 2102(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/9">120 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s9/f/2">Pub. L. 109–173, § 9(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-15">Feb. 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3618">119 Stat. 3618</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/dA/tII/s203/f">Pub. L. 111–22, div. A, title II, § 203(f)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-20">May 20, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1647">123 Stat. 1647</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc28fb5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc28fb60-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc28fb61-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/1/A/i">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “or any of its owners, officers, or directors” after “mortgagee or lender” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “subchapter I or II of this chapter, or any implementing regulation, handbook, or mortgagee letter that is issued under this chapter.” for “subchapter I, II, or IX–A (as such subchapter existed immediately before <date date="1989-12-15">December 15, 1989</date>) of this chapter or any implementing regulation or handbook that is issued under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(K), (L). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, added subpars. (K) and (L).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/1/B">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(1)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/1/C">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(1)(C)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Before taking action to impose a civil money penalty for a violation under paragraph (1)(D) or (F), or paragraph (2)(A), (B), or (C), the Secretary shall inform the Attorney General of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s203/f/2">Pub. L. 111–22, § 203(f)(2)</ref>, substituted “For purposes of this section, a person acts knowingly when a person has actual knowledge of acts or should have known of the acts.” for “The term ‘knowingly’ means having actual knowledge of or acting with deliberate ignorance of or reckless disregard for the prohibitions under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173">Pub. L. 109–173</ref> substituted “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Bank Insurance Fund for banks and through the Savings Association Insurance Fund for savings associations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/13/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(13)(B)</ref>. See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(1)(J). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref> added subpar. (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s601/g">Pub. L. 105–276, § 601(g)</ref>, inserted second paragraph.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s601/h">Pub. L. 105–276, § 601(h)</ref>, which directed the addition of subpar. (I) after subpar. “(h)”, was executed by adding subpar. (I) after subpar. (H), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/a">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(a)</ref>, amended section catchline generally, substituting “mortgagees, lenders, and other participants in FHA programs” for “mortgagees and lenders”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/b/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “If a mortgagee approved under the chapter, a lender holding a contract of insurance under subchapter I, or a principal, officer, or employee of such mortgagee or lender, or other person or entity participating in either an insured mortgage or subchapter I loan transaction under this chapter or providing assistance to the borrower in connection with any such loan, including sellers of the real estate involved, borrowers, closing agents, title companies, real estate agents, mortgage brokers, appraisers, loan correspondents and dealers, knowingly and materially violates any applicable provision of subsection (b), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the mortgagee or lender, or such other person or entity, in accordance with this section. The penalty under this paragraph shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions.” for “Whenever a mortgagee approved under this chapter, or a lender holding a contract of insurance under subchapter I of this chapter, knowingly and materially violates any of the provisions of subsection (b), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the mortgagee or lender in accordance with the provisions of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/b/2">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “or such other person or entity” after “lender” in first sentence and substituted “the provisions of subsection (b)(1)” for “provision of subsection (b)(1)” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/c/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(c)(1)</ref>, (2), added par. (2) and redesignated former par. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/c/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(c)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (2) as (3) and substituted “or (F), or paragraph (2)(A), (B), or (C)” for “or paragraph (1)(F)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/d/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “or such other person or entity” after “lender”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/d/2">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(d)(2)</ref>, inserted “or such other person or entity” after “lender” and substituted “parts 24 and 25” for “part 25”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s553/d/3">Pub. L. 105–65, § 553(d)(3)</ref>, inserted “or such other person or entity” after “lender” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/13/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(13)(B)</ref>, which directed the amendment of section 526(b)(1)(B)(ii) of the National Housing Act by substituting “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Bank Insurance Fund for banks and through the Savings Association Insurance Fund for savings associations” and which substitution was probably intended by Congress to be made in subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii) of this section, section 536 of the National Housing Act, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc28fb62-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc28fb63-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/173">Pub. L. 109–173</ref> effective <date date="2006-03-31">Mar. 31, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s9/j">section 9(j) of Pub. L. 109–173</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> effective no later than the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the end of the 90-day period beginning <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s2102/c">section 2102(c) of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, set out as a Merger of BIF and SAIF note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc28fb64-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1999-01-01">Jan. 1, 1999</date>, if no insured depository institution is a savings association on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/c">section 2704(c) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddc28fb65-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/235/tI/s107/b">Pub. L. 101–235, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2003">103 Stat. 2003</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/235/tI/s107/b">
<inline>“The amendment made by subsection (a) [enacting this section] shall apply only with respect to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> violations referred to in the amendment that occur on or after the effective date of this section [<date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of a continuing violation (as determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development), any portion of a violation referred to in the amendment that occurs on or after such date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc28fb66-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tV/s541">Pub. L. 105–65, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1412">111 Stat. 1412</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/65/tV/s541">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance of Necessary Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 7(<i>o</i>) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3535">42 U.S.C. 3535</ref>(<i>o</i>)] or part 10 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations (as in existence on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>]), the Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary determines to be necessary to implement this subtitle [subtitle C (§§ 541–564) of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/105/65">Pub. L. 105–65</ref>, enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437z–1">section 1437z–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, amending this section, sections 1708, 1715z–4a, 1715z–19, and 1735f–15 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1516">section 1516 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, and sections 503 and 1437z of Title 42, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–15">section 1735f–15 of this title</ref> and sections 503 and 1437z–1 of Title 42] and the amendments made by this subtitle in accordance with section 552 or 553 of title 5, United States Code, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Existing Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>In implementing any provision of this subtitle, the Secretary may, in the discretion of the Secretary, provide for the use of existing regulations to the extent appropriate, without rulemaking.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
