<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc2b45b8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19"><num value="1735f–19">§ 1735f–19.</num><heading> Partial payment of claims on defaulted mortgages and in connection with mortgage restructuring</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc2b45b9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Defaulted mortgages</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Secretary is requested to accept assignment of a mortgage insured by the Secretary that covers a multifamily housing project (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–11/b">section 1701z–11(b) of this title</ref>) or a health care facility (including a nursing home, intermediate care facility, or board and care home (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715w">section 1715w of this title</ref>), a hospital (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–7">section 1715z–7 of this title</ref>), or a group practice facility (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1749aaa–5">section 1749aaa–5 of this title</ref>)) and the Secretary determines that partial payment would be less costly to the Federal Government than other reasonable alternatives for maintaining the low-income character of the project, or for keeping the health care facility operational to serve community needs, the Secretary may request the mortgagee, in lieu of assignment, to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc2b45ba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> accept partial payment of the claim under the mortgage insurance contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc2b45bb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> recast the mortgage, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc2b45bc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing mortgages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, in connection with a mortgage restructuring under section 514 of the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997, may make a one time, nondefault partial or full payment of claim under one or more mortgage insurance contracts, which shall include a determination by the Secretary or the participating administrative entity, in accordance with the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997, of the market value of the project and a restructuring of the mortgage, under such terms and conditions as are permitted by section 517(a) of such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc2b45bd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–19/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Repayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a condition to a partial claim payment under this section, the mortgagor shall agree to repay to the Secretary the amount of such payment and such obligation shall be secured by a second mortgage on the property on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc2b45be-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title V, § 541, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/tI/s101/e">Pub. L. 103–233, title I, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/357">108 Stat. 357</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tII/s210">Pub. L. 105–65, title II, § 210</ref>, title V, § 523(b), <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1366">111 Stat. 1366</ref>, 1406; <ref href="/us/pl/106/74/tII/s213/a">Pub. L. 106–74, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1073">113 Stat. 1073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc2b45bf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc2b45c0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc2b45c1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997, referred to in subsec. (b), is title V of <ref href="/us/pl/105/65">Pub. L. 105–65</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1384">111 Stat. 1384</ref>. Sections 514 and 517(a) of the Act are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1997 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc2b45c2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/74/s213/a/1">Pub. L. 106–74, § 213(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “defaulted mortgages and in connection with mortgage restructuring” for “multifamily housing projects and health care facilities” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/74/s213/a/2">Pub. L. 106–74, § 213(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “partial or full payment of claim under one or more mortgage insurance contracts” for “partial payment of the claim under the mortgage insurance contract”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s210/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 210(1)</ref>, inserted “and health care facilities” after “housing projects” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s523/b/1">Pub. L. 105–65, § 523(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Defaulted mortgages” for “Authority” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s210/2/B">Pub. L. 105–65, § 210(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “or for keeping the health care facility operational to serve community needs,” after “character of the project,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s210/2/A">Pub. L. 105–65, § 210(2)(A)</ref>, which directed the insertion, in introductory provisions, of “or a health care facility (including a nursing home, intermediate care facility, or board and care home (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715w">section 1715w of this title</ref>), a hospital (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715z–7">section 1715z–7 of this title</ref>), or a group practice facility (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1749aaa–5">section 1749aaa–5 of this title</ref>))” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–11/b">section 1701z–11(b) of this title</ref>”, was executed by inserting the language after “<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–11/b">section 1701z–11(b) of this title</ref>)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/s523/b/2">Pub. L. 105–65, § 523(b)(2)</ref>, (3), added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
