<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc3027ae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1747f"><num value="1747f">§ 1747f.</num><heading> Payment of claims; assignment of benefits by investors</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If in any operating year the net income of a project insured under this subchapter is less than the aggregate of the minimum annual amortization charge and the insured annual return, the Secretary, upon submission by the investor of a claim for the payment of the amount of the difference between such net income and the aggregate of the minimum annual amortization charge and the insured annual return and after proof of the validity of such claim, shall pay to the investor, in cash from the General Insurance Fund, the amount of such difference, as determined by the Secretary, but not exceeding, in any event, an amount equal to the aggregate of the minimum annual amortization charge and the insured annual return. Nothing contained in this subchapter or any other provision of law shall be construed as preventing or restricting an investor from assigning, pledging, or otherwise transferring or disposing of, subject to rules and regulations of the Secretary, any or all rights, claims, or other benefits under any insurance contract made pursuant to this subchapter to an assignee, pledgee, or other transferee, including the holders (or the trustee for such holders) of any debentures issued by the investor in connection with the project to which such insurance contract relates, and the Secretary is authorized to pay claims or issue debentures in accordance with the provisions of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1747g">section 1747g of this title</ref> to any such assignee, pledgee, or other transferee.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddc3027af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title VII, § 707, as added <ref href="/us/act/1948-08-10/ch832">Aug. 10, 1948, ch. 832</ref>, title IV, § 401, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1278">62 Stat. 1278</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1950-04-20/ch94">Apr. 20, 1950, ch. 94</ref>, title I, § 122, <ref href="/us/stat/64/59">64 Stat. 59</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title VI, § 609(b), <ref href="/us/stat/65/316">65 Stat. 316</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tXI/s1108/s">Pub. L. 89–117, title XI, § 1108(s)</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/506">79 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s1/a/3">Pub. L. 90–19, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/17">81 Stat. 17</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc3027b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc3027b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc3027b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Insurance Fund, referred to in text, was established by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735c">section 1735c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc3027b3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Commissioner” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/117">Pub. L. 89–117</ref> substituted “General Insurance Fund” for “Housing Investment Insurance Fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-09-01">Sept. 1, 1951</date>, inserted second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-04-20">Apr. 20, 1950</date>, substituted “Commissioner” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
