<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc34e243-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2"><num value="1748h–2">§ 1748h–2.</num><heading> Insurance of mortgages for defense housing for impacted areas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e244-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary may insure and make commitments to insure any mortgage under this section which meets the eligibility requirements hereinafter set forth.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e245-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No mortgage shall be insured under this section unless (1) the housing which is covered by the insured mortgage is necessary in the interest of national security in order to provide adequate housing for (A) military personnel and essential civilian personnel serving or employed in connection with any installation of one of the armed services of the United States, or (B) essential personnel employed or assigned to duty at or in connection with any research or development installation of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration or of the Atomic Energy Commission, (2) there is no present intention to curtail substantially the number of such personnel assigned or to be assigned to the installation, (3) adequate housing is not available for such personnel at reasonable rentals within reasonable commuting distances of such installation, and (4) the mortgaged property will not so far as can be reasonably foreseen substantially curtail occupancy in any existing housing in the vicinity of the installation which is covered by mortgages insured under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e246-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Economical soundness of property or project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may accept any mortgage for insurance under this section without regard to any requirement in any other section of this chapter that the property or project be economically sound.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e247-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rental conditions; preferences and priorities in the sale or rental of dwellings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall require each project covered by a mortgage insured under this section to be held for rental for a period of not less than five years after the project or dwelling is made available for initial occupancy or until he finds that the housing may be released from such rental condition. The Secretary shall prescribe such procedures as in his judgment are necessary to secure reasonable preference or priority in the sale or rental of dwellings covered by a mortgage insured under this section for military personnel and essential civilian employees of the armed services, employees of contractors for the armed services, and persons described in clause (1)(B) of subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e248-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Property held by mortgagor approved by Secretary; acquisition of stock or interest; redemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of providing multifamily rental housing projects or housing projects consisting of individual single-family dwellings for sale, the Secretary is authorized to insure mortgages (including advances on such mortgages during construction) which cover property held by a mortgagor approved by the Secretary. Any such mortgagor shall possess powers necessary therefor and incidental thereto and shall until the termination of all obligations of the Secretary under such insurance be regulated or restricted as to rents or sales, charges, capital structure, rate of return, and methods of operation to such extent and in such manner as to provide reasonable rentals to tenants and a reasonable return on the investment. The Secretary may make such contracts with, and acquire for not to exceed $100 such stock or interest in, any such mortgagor as he may deem necessary to render effective such restriction or regulation. Such stock or interest shall be paid for out of the General Insurance Fund, and shall be redeemed by the mortgagor at par upon the termination of all obligations of the Secretary under the insurance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e249-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Mortgage limitations for multifamily rental property or project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible for insurance under this section, a mortgage on any multifamily rental property or project shall involve a principal obligation in an amount not to exceed, for such part of such property or project as may be attributable to dwelling use, $9,000 per family unit without a bedroom, $12,500 per family unit with one bedroom, $15,000 per family unit with two bedrooms, and $18,500 per family unit with three or more bedrooms, and not to exceed 90 per centum of the estimated value of the property or project when the proposed physical improvements are completed. The Secretary may, by regulation, increase any of the foregoing dollar amount limitations contained in this paragraph by not to exceed 45 per centum in any geographical area where he finds that cost levels so require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e24a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Mortgage limitation for property or project constructed for eventual sale of single-family dwellings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible for insurance under this section a mortgage on any property or project constructed for eventual sale of single-family dwellings shall involve a principal obligation in an amount not to exceed a sum computed on the basis of a separate mortgage for each single-family dwelling (irrespective of whether such dwelling has a party wall or is otherwise physically connected with another dwelling or dwellings) comprising the property or project equal to the total of each of the maximum principal obligations of such mortgages which would meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1709/b/2">section 1709(b)(2) of this title</ref> if the mortgagor were the owner and occupant who had made the required payment on account of the property prescribed in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e24b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Amortization; interest; release of part of mortgaged property from lien; replacement of certain mortgages by individual mortgages; commercial and community facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any mortgage insured under this section shall provide for complete amortization by periodic payments within such terms as the Secretary may prescribe but not to exceed the maximum term applicable to mortgages under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref> and shall bear interest at such rate as may be agreed upon by the mortgagor and the mortgagee, except that individual mortgages of the character described in subsection (g) covering the individual dwellings in the project may have a term not in excess of the maximum term applicable to mortgages insured under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1709">section 1709 of this title</ref> or the unexpired term of the project mortgage at the time of the release of the mortgaged property from such project mortgage, whichever is the greater, and shall bear interest at such rate as may be agreed upon by the mortgagor and the mortgagee. The Secretary may consent to the release of a part or parts of the mortgaged property from the lien of the mortgage upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe and the mortgage may provide for such release, and a mortgage of the character described in subsection (g) of this section may provide that, at any time after the release of the project from the rental period prescribed by subsection (d), such mortgage may be replaced, in whole or in part, by individual mortgages covering each individual dwelling in the project in amounts not to exceed the unpaid balance of the blanket mortgage allocable to the individual property. Each such individual mortgage may be insured under this section. Property covered by a mortgage insured under this section may include eight or more family units and may include such commercial and community facilities as the Secretary deems adequate to serve the occupants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e24c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on aggregate number of dwelling units</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The aggregate number of dwelling units (including all units in multifamily projects or individual dwellings) covered by outstanding commitments to insure and mortgages insured under this section shall at no time exceed five thousand dwelling units.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e24d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsections (d), (e), (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), (<i>l</i>), and (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref> shall be applicable to mortgages insured under this section except individual mortgages of the character described in subsection (g) of this section covering the individual dwellings in the project, and as to such individual mortgages the provisions of subsections (a), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002204">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002204"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (j), and (k) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002204">1</ref> of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710">section 1710 of this title</ref> shall be applicable: <i>Provided</i>, That wherever the words “Fund” or “Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund” appear in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710">section 1710 of this title</ref>, such reference shall refer to the General Insurance Fund with respect to mortgages insured under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc34e24e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1748h–2/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Aggregate amount of mortgages insured; termination date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of sections 1748, 1748a,<sup>1</sup> 1748b(c), 1748b(i), 1748b(j), 1748c(a), 1748c(b),<sup>1</sup> and 1748f of this title and the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1748b/a">section 1748b(a) of this title</ref> relating to the aggregate amount of all mortgages insured under this subchapter shall be applicable to mortgages insured under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc34e24f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, title VIII, § 810, as added <ref href="/us/pl/86/372/tVII/s704/a">Pub. L. 86–372, title VII, § 704(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-23">Sept. 23, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/683">73 Stat. 683</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/tVI/s611/a">Pub. L. 87–70, title VI, § 611(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/180">75 Stat. 180</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/623/s3">Pub. L. 87–623, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-08-31">Aug. 31, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/418">76 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/127/s2">Pub. L. 88–127, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-09-23">Sept. 23, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/163">77 Stat. 163</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/560/tI/s107/f">Pub. L. 88–560, title I, § 107(f)</ref>, <date date="1964-09-02">Sept. 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/776">78 Stat. 776</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tII/s202/c">Pub. L. 89–117, title II, § 202(c)</ref>, title XI, § 1108(w), <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/466">79 Stat. 466</ref>, 506; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s1/a/3">Pub. L. 90–19, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/17">81 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tXVII/s1722/f">Pub. L. 90–448, title XVII, § 1722(f)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/611">82 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/78/s2/e">Pub. L. 91–78, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1969-09-30">Sept. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/125">83 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/152/tI/s101/g">Pub. L. 91–152, title I, § 101(g)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/379">83 Stat. 379</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/432/s1/e">Pub. L. 91–432, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-02">Oct. 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/887">84 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/473/s1/e">Pub. L. 91–473, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-21">Oct. 21, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1065">84 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/525/s1/e">Pub. L. 91–525, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-01">Dec. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1384">84 Stat. 1384</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/609/tI/s101/g">Pub. L. 91–609, title I, § 101(g)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1770">84 Stat. 1770</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/503/s1/g">Pub. L. 92–503, § 1(g)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/906">86 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/85/s1/g">Pub. L. 93–85, § 1(g)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/220">87 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/117/s1/g">Pub. L. 93–117, § 1(g)</ref>, <date date="1973-10-02">Oct. 2, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/421">87 Stat. 421</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tIII">Pub. L. 93–383, title III</ref>, §§ 304(j), 316(e), <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/678">88 Stat. 678</ref>, 685; <ref href="/us/pl/95/60/s1/f">Pub. L. 95–60, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/257">91 Stat. 257</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/80/s1/f">Pub. L. 95–80, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1977-07-31">July 31, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/339">91 Stat. 339</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/128/tIII/s301/i">Pub. L. 95–128, title III, § 301(i)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1131">91 Stat. 1131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/406/s1/i">Pub. L. 95–406, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/879">92 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/557/tIII/s301/i">Pub. L. 95–557, title III, § 301(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-31">Oct. 31, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2096">92 Stat. 2096</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/71/s1/i">Pub. L. 96–71, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-28">Sept. 28, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/501">93 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/105/s1/i">Pub. L. 96–105, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-08">Nov. 8, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/794">93 Stat. 794</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/153/tIII/s301/i">Pub. L. 96–153, title III, § 301(i)</ref>, <date date="1979-12-21">Dec. 21, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1112">93 Stat. 1112</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/372/s1/i">Pub. L. 96–372, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1363">94 Stat. 1363</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/399/tIII/s301/i">Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 301(i)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1639">94 Stat. 1639</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s331/h/2">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 331(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/413">95 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/289/s1/i">Pub. L. 97–289, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-06">Oct. 6, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1230">96 Stat. 1230</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/35/s1/i">Pub. L. 98–35, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1983-05-26">May 26, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/197">97 Stat. 197</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/109/s1/i">Pub. L. 98–109, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="1983-10-01">Oct. 1, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/745">97 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 401(h)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1208">97 Stat. 1208</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/120/s1/h/2">Pub. L. 99–120, § 1(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-08">Oct. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/503">99 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/156/s1/h/2">Pub. L. 99–156, § 1(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-15">Nov. 15, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/816">99 Stat. 816</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/219/s1/h/2">Pub. L. 99–219, § 1(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-26">Dec. 26, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1731">99 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/267/s1/i/2">Pub. L. 99–267, § 1(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-03-27">Mar. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/74">100 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tIII/s3007/h/2">Pub. L. 99–272, title III, § 3007(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/105">100 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/289/s1/b">Pub. L. 99–289, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-05-02">May 2, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/412">100 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/345/s1">Pub. L. 99–345, § 1</ref>, <date date="1986-06-24">June 24, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/673">100 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/430">Pub. L. 99–430</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/986">100 Stat. 986</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/122/s1">Pub. L. 100–122, § 1</ref>, <date date="1987-09-30">Sept. 30, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/793">101 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/154">Pub. L. 100–154</ref>, <date date="1987-11-05">Nov. 5, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/890">101 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/170">Pub. L. 100–170</ref>, <date date="1987-11-17">Nov. 17, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/914">101 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/179">Pub. L. 100–179</ref>, <date date="1987-12-03">Dec. 3, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1018">101 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/200">Pub. L. 100–200</ref>, <date date="1987-12-21">Dec. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1327">101 Stat. 1327</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tIV">Pub. L. 100–242, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(a)(6), 429(k), <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1898">101 Stat. 1898</ref>, 1919.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc34e250-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc34e251-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc34e252-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Insurance Fund, referred to in text, was established by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735c">section 1735c of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710">section 1710 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (j), was redesignated subsec. (i) by <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tVI/s602/1">Pub. L. 105–276, title VI, § 602(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2674">112 Stat. 2674</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1710">section 1710 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (j), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tVI/s601/c">Pub. L. 105–276, title VI, § 601(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2673">112 Stat. 2673</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1748a and 1748c of this title, referred to in subsec. (k), were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tXI/s1108">Pub. L. 89–117, title XI, § 1108</ref> (aa), <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/507">79 Stat. 507</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddc34e253-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 810 of title VIII of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title VI, § 601(d), <ref href="/us/stat/65/313">65 Stat. 313</ref>, which related to mortgage on housing constructed for personnel of the Atomic Energy Commission, was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1748g–1">section 1748g–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc34e254-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/s429/k">Pub. L. 100–242, § 429(k)</ref>, substituted “at such rate as may be agreed upon by the mortgagor and the mortgagee” for “(exclusive of premium charges for insurance) at not to exceed the rate applicable to mortgages insured under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref>” and “such rate as may be agreed upon by the mortgagor and the mortgagee” for “not to exceed the rate applicable to mortgages insured under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1709">section 1709 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/s401/a/6">Pub. L. 100–242, § 401(a)(6)</ref>, struck out “No more mortgages shall be insured under this section after <date date="1988-03-15">March 15, 1988</date>, except pursuant to a commitment to insure before such date.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/200">Pub. L. 100–200</ref> substituted “<date date="1988-03-15">March 15, 1988</date>” for “<date date="1987-12-16">December 16, 1987</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/179">Pub. L. 100–179</ref> substituted “<date date="1987-12-16">December 16, 1987</date>” for “<date date="1987-12-02">December 2, 1987</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/170">Pub. L. 100–170</ref> substituted “<date date="1987-12-02">December 2, 1987</date>” for “<date date="1987-11-15">November 15, 1987</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/154">Pub. L. 100–154</ref> substituted “<date date="1987-11-15">November 15, 1987</date>” for “<date date="1987-10-31">October 31, 1987</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/122">Pub. L. 100–122</ref> substituted “<date date="1987-10-31">October 31, 1987</date>” for “<date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/99/430">Pub. L. 99–430</ref> substituted “<date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>” for “<date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/345">Pub. L. 99–345</ref> substituted “<date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>” for “<date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/289">Pub. L. 99–289</ref> substituted “<date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>” for “<date date="1986-04-30">April 30, 1986</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> made amendment identical to <ref href="/us/pl/99/219">Pub. L. 99–219</ref>. See 1985 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/267">Pub. L. 99–267</ref> substituted “<date date="1986-04-30">April 30, 1986</date>” for “<date date="1986-03-17">March 17, 1986</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/99/219">Pub. L. 99–219</ref> substituted “<date date="1986-03-17">March 17, 1986</date>” for “<date date="1985-12-15">December 15, 1985</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/156">Pub. L. 99–156</ref> substituted “<date date="1985-12-15">December 15, 1985</date>” for “<date date="1985-11-14">November 14, 1985</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/120">Pub. L. 99–120</ref> substituted “<date date="1985-11-14">November 14, 1985</date>” for “<date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “<date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>” for “<date date="1983-11-30">November 30, 1983</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/109">Pub. L. 98–109</ref> substituted “<date date="1983-11-30">November 30, 1983</date>” for “<date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/35">Pub. L. 98–35</ref> substituted “<date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>” for “<date date="1983-05-20">May 20, 1983</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/97/289">Pub. L. 97–289</ref> substituted “<date date="1983-05-20">May 20, 1983</date>” for “<date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted “1982” for “1981”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/96/399">Pub. L. 96–399</ref> substituted “<date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>” for “<date date="1980-10-15">October 15, 1980</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/372">Pub. L. 96–372</ref> substituted “<date date="1980-10-15">October 15, 1980</date>” for “<date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/96/153">Pub. L. 96–153</ref> substituted “<date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>” for “<date date="1979-11-30">November 30, 1979</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/105">Pub. L. 96–105</ref> substituted “<date date="1979-11-30">November 30, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1979-10-31">October 31, 1979</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/71">Pub. L. 96–71</ref> substituted “<date date="1979-10-31">October 31, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/95/557">Pub. L. 95–557</ref> substituted “<date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1978-10-31">October 31, 1978</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/406">Pub. L. 95–406</ref> substituted “<date date="1978-10-31">October 31, 1978</date>” for “<date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/95/128">Pub. L. 95–128</ref> substituted “<date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>” for “<date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/80">Pub. L. 95–80</ref> substituted “<date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>” for “<date date="1977-07-31">July 31, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/60">Pub. L. 95–60</ref> substituted “<date date="1977-07-31">July 31, 1977</date>” for “<date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/s304/j/1">Pub. L. 93–383, § 304(j)(1)</ref>, struck out “(1) not to exceed $5,000,000 or (2)” after “in an amount”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/s304/j/2">Pub. L. 93–383, § 304(j)(2)</ref>, struck out “not to exceed $5,000,000 and” after “in an amount”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/s316/e">Pub. L. 93–383, § 316(e)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>” for “<date date="1974-10-01">October 1, 1974</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/93/117">Pub. L. 93–117</ref> substituted “<date date="1974-10-01">October 1, 1974</date>” for “<date date="1973-10-01">October 1, 1973</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/85">Pub. L. 93–85</ref> substituted “<date date="1973-10-01">October 1, 1973</date>” for “<date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/92/503">Pub. L. 92–503</ref> substituted “<date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>” for “<date date="1972-10-01">October 1, 1972</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/91/609">Pub. L. 91–609</ref> substituted “<date date="1972-10-01">October 1, 1972</date>” for “<date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/525">Pub. L. 91–525</ref> substituted “<date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>” for “<date date="1970-12-01">December 1, 1970</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/473">Pub. L. 91–473</ref> substituted “<date date="1970-12-01">December 1, 1970</date>” for “<date date="1970-11-01">November 1, 1970</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/432">Pub. L. 91–432</ref> substituted “<date date="1970-11-01">November 1, 1970</date>” for “<date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/91/152">Pub. L. 91–152</ref> substituted “<date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>” for “<date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/78">Pub. L. 91–78</ref> substituted “<date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>” for “<date date="1969-10-01">October 1, 1969</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> substituted “mortgagor approved by the Secretary” for “private corporation, association, cooperative society, or trust” in first sentence, and “mortgagor” for “corporation, association, cooperative society, or trust” in third and fourth sentences.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Commissioner” wherever appearing in subsecs. (a), (c) to (f), and (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/s1108/w/1">Pub. L. 89–117, § 1108(w)(1)</ref>, substituted “General Insurance Fund” for “Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/s1108/w/2">Pub. L. 89–117, § 1108(w)(2)</ref>, (3), struck out reference to subsecs. (m) and (p) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref> and, in proviso, substituted “General Insurance Fund” for “Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Fund” and struck out reference to the appearance of “Housing Insurance Fund” in sections 1710 and 1713 of this title and the appearance of “Fund” or “Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund” in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/89/117/s202/c">Pub. L. 89–117, § 202(c)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1969-10-01">October 1, 1969</date>” for “<date date="1965-10-01">October 1, 1965</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/88/560">Pub. L. 88–560</ref> changed limits on mortgages for multifamily rental property or project, in cl. (2) of the first sentence from “$2,500 per room (or $9,000 per family unit if the number of rooms in such property or project is less than four per family unit)” to “$9,000 per family unit without a bedroom, $12,500 per family unit with one bedroom, $15,000 per family unit with two bedrooms, and $18,500 per family unit with three or more bedrooms”; and, in the second sentence, inserted “, by regulation,” and substituted provisions authorizing an increase “by not to exceed 45 per centum” of any of such limits because of cost levels for former provision authorizing such an increase “by not to exceed $1,000 per room”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/88/127/s2/1">Pub. L. 88–127, § 2(1)</ref>, included essential personnel employed or assigned to duty at or in connection with any research or development installation of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration or of the Atomic Energy Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/88/127/s2/2">Pub. L. 88–127, § 2(2)</ref>, included persons described in cl. (1)(B) of subsec. (b) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/88/127/s2/3">Pub. L. 88–127, § 2(3)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1965-10-01">October 1, 1965</date>” for “<date date="1963-10-01">October 1, 1963</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/87/623">Pub. L. 87–623</ref> provided that no mortgages shall be insured under this section after <date date="1963-10-01">October 1, 1963</date>, except pursuant to a commitment before such date, and struck out “and the expiration date of the Commissioner’s authority to insure” after “amount of all mortgages insured”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/s611/a/1">Pub. L. 87–70, § 611(a)(1)</ref>, struck out provisions which required certification by Secretary of Defense or his designee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/s611/a/2">Pub. L. 87–70, § 611(a)(2)</ref>, struck out provisions which related to certification and advice of Secretary of Defense or his designee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/s611/a/3">Pub. L. 87–70, § 611(a)(3)</ref>, repealed subsec. (<i>l</i>) which required Secretary of Defense to guarantee Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Fund from loss.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc34e255-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc34e256-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s371">section 371 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3701">section 3701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddc34e257-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. See, also, Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc34e258-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments to Provisions for Family Unit Limits on Rental Housing; Equitable Application of Such Amendments or Pre-Amendment Provisions to Projects Submitted for Consideration Prior to <date date="1964-09-02">September 2, 1964</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Equitable application of amendment to subsec. (f) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/88/560/s107/f">section 107(f) of Pub. L. 88–560</ref> or pre-amendment provisions to projects submitted for consideration prior to <date date="1964-09-02">Sept. 2, 1964</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/560/s107/g">section 107(g) of Pub. L. 88–560</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1713">section 1713 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
