<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc40c92c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1761"><num value="1761">§ 1761.</num><heading> Management</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc40c92d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1761/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of directors, credit committee, and supervisory committee; election to board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The management of a Federal credit union shall be by a board of directors, a supervisory committee, and where the bylaws so provide, a credit committee. The board shall consist of an odd number of directors, at least five in number, to be elected annually by and from the members as the bylaws provide. Any vacancy occurring on the board shall be filled until the next annual election by appointment by the remainder of the directors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc40c92e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1761/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership on supervisory committee; names and addresses of officers and committee members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The supervisory committee shall be appointed by the board of directors and shall consist of not less than three members nor more than five members, one of whom may be a director other than the compensated officer of the board. A record of the names and addresses of the executive officers, members of the supervisory committee, credit committee, and loan officers, shall be filed with the Administration within ten days after their election or appointment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc40c92f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1761/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No member of the board or of any other committee shall, as such, be compensated, except that reasonable health, accident, similar insurance protection, and the reimbursement of reasonable expenses incurred in the execution of the duties of the position shall not be considered compensation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc40c930-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, title I, § 111, formerly § 11, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1219">48 Stat. 1219</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-06-15/ch366">June 15, 1940, ch. 366</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/398">54 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-31/ch711">July 31, 1946, ch. 711</ref>, §§ 3–6, <ref href="/us/stat/60/745">60 Stat. 745</ref>; 1947 Reorg. Plan No. 1, § 401, eff. <date date="1947-07-01">July 1, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4534, <ref href="/us/stat/61/952">61 Stat. 952</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-29/ch711">June 29, 1948, ch. 711</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1091">62 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-25/ch713/s2">Oct. 25, 1949, ch. 713, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/890">63 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-06-30/ch426/s1">June 30, 1954, ch. 426, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/335">68 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-24/ch905">Aug. 24, 1954, ch. 905</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/68/792">68 Stat. 792</ref>; renumbered § 12 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/86/354/s1">Pub. L. 86–354, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/632">73 Stat. 632</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/353/s2">Pub. L. 88–353, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/269">78 Stat. 269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/206/s2/3">Pub. L. 91–206, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-03-10">Mar. 10, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/49">84 Stat. 49</ref>; renumbered title I, § 111, <ref href="/us/pl/91/468/s1/2">Pub. L. 91–468, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-19">Oct. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/994">84 Stat. 994</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tI/s116">Pub. L. 93–495, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1507">88 Stat. 1507</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 95–630, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3681">92 Stat. 3681</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tV/s520">Pub. L. 97–320, title V, § 520</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1531">96 Stat. 1531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc40c931-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc40c932-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc40c933-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> substituted provisions divided into subsecs. (a), (b), and (c) relating to the management of a Federal credit union, including the board of directors, credit and supervisory committees, and the matter of their compensation, for provisions which read as follows: “The business affairs of a Federal credit union shall be managed by a board of not less than five directors, and a credit committee of not less than three members, all to be elected at the annual members’ meeting by and from the members, and by a supervisory committee of not less than three members nor more than five members, one of whom may be a director other than the treasurer, to be appointed by the board. Any vacancy occurring in the supervisory committee shall be filled in the same manner as original appointments to such committee. All members of the board and of such committees shall hold office for such terms, respectively, as the bylaws may provide. A record of the names and addresses of the members of the board and such committees and of the officers of the credit union shall be filed with the Administration within ten days after their election or appointment. No member of the board or of either such committee shall, as such, be compensated: <i>Provided, however</i>, That reasonable health, accident, and similar insurance protection shall not be considered compensation under regulations promulgated by the Board.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> substituted “Board” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/495">Pub. L. 93–495</ref> inserted proviso relating to compensation in the form of health, accident, and similar insurance protection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/206">Pub. L. 91–206</ref> substituted “Administration” for “Bureau”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/353">Pub. L. 88–353</ref> increased size of supervisory committee from three members to not less than three members nor more than five members.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/354">Pub. L. 86–354</ref> provided for appointment instead of election of members of supervisory committee and for filling of vacancies in such committee, and struck out former subsecs. (b) to (e) relating to officers, directors, credit committee and supervisory committee. See sections 1761a to 1761d of this title, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsecs. (b), (c). Act <date date="1954-08-24">Aug. 24, 1954</date>, provided express authority for the Director of the Bureau of Federal Credit Unions to regulate the minimum amount and character of surety bonds for officers and employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>, inserted provision with respect to interest refunds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1949-10-25">Oct. 25, 1949</date>, substituted “$400” for “$300” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, struck out “fix the amount and character of the surety bond required of any officer having custody of funds” and inserted “require any officer or employee having custody of or handling funds to give bond with good and sufficient surety in an amount and character to be determined, from time to time, by the board and authorize the payment of the premium or premiums therefor from the funds of the Federal credit union”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, struck out requirement that notice of meeting of the credit committee must be given by the treasurer and increased the maximum amount of an unsecured loan to a member from $100 to $300.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, inserted last sentence defining “passbook”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1940-06-15">June 15, 1940</date>, substituted “$100” for “$50” in fourth sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc40c934-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc40c935-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> effective on expiration of 120 days after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, and transitional provisions, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s509">section 509 of Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752">section 1752 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddc40c936-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddc40c937-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions of Farm Credit Administration and Governor thereof, generally, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1751">section 1751 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Governor of Farm Credit Administration under this section transferred to Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1947.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
