<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc40c968-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1761d"><num value="1761d">§ 1761d.</num><heading> Supervisory committee; powers and duties; suspension of members; passbook</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The supervisory committee shall make or cause to be made an annual audit and shall submit a report of that audit to the board of directors and a summary of the report to the members at the next annual meeting of the credit union; shall make or cause to be made such supplementary audits as it deems necessary or as may be ordered by the Board, and submit reports of the supplementary audits to the board of directors; may by a unanimous vote suspend any officer of the credit union or any member of the credit committee or of the board of directors, until the next members’ meeting, which shall be held not less than seven or more than fourteen days after any such suspension, at which meeting any such suspension shall be acted upon by the members; and may call by a majority vote a special meeting of the members to consider any violations of this chapter, the charter, or the bylaws, or any practice of the credit union deemed by the supervisory committee to be unsafe or unauthorized. Any member of the supervisory committee may be suspended by a majority vote of the board of directors. The members shall decide, at a meeting held not less than seven nor more than fourteen days after any such suspension, whether the suspended committee member shall be removed from or restored to the supervisory committee. The supervisory committee shall cause the passbooks and accounts of the members to be verified with the records of the treasurer from time to time, and not less frequently than once every two years. As used in this section, the term “passbook” shall include any book, statement of account, or other record approved by the Board for use by Federal credit unions.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddc40c969-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, title I, § 115, formerly § 16, as added <ref href="/us/pl/86/354/s1">Pub. L. 86–354, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/633">73 Stat. 633</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/375/s1/6">Pub. L. 90–375, § 1(6)</ref>, (7), <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/284">82 Stat. 284</ref>, 285; <ref href="/us/pl/91/206/s2/1">Pub. L. 91–206, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-03-10">Mar. 10, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/49">84 Stat. 49</ref>; renumbered title I, § 115, <ref href="/us/pl/91/468/s1/2">Pub. L. 91–468, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-19">Oct. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/994">84 Stat. 994</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tVII/s724">Pub. L. 93–383, title VII, § 724</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/719">88 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 95–630, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3681">92 Stat. 3681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc40c96a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc40c96b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddc40c96c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising this section were contained in section 11(e) of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">act June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1219">48 Stat. 1219</ref> (formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1761/e">section 1761(e) of this title</ref>), prior to the amendment and renumbering of act <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date> by <ref href="/us/pl/86/354">Pub. L. 86–354</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc40c96d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> substituted “Board” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/383">Pub. L. 93–383</ref> substituted “an annual” for “a semiannual”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/206">Pub. L. 91–206</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Director” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/375">Pub. L. 90–375</ref> substituted provisions which required a semiannual audit for provisions which required a quarterly examination of the affairs of a Federal credit union, including an audit of the books, authorized the making of such supplementary audits as deemed necessary by the supervisory committee or as ordered by the Director, eliminated the requirement of an annual audit, and provided that the suspension of any member of the supervisory committee be pursuant to a majority vote of the board of directors.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc40c96e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc40c96f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> effective on expiration of 120 days after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, and transitional provisions, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s509">section 509 of Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752">section 1752 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
