<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc4339e2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771"><num value="1771">§ 1771.</num><heading> Conversion from Federal to State credit union and from State to Federal credit union</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc4339e3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> A Federal credit union may be converted into a State credit union under the laws of any State, the District of Columbia, the several Territories and possessions of the United States, the Panama Canal Zone, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by complying with the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc4339e4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The proposition for such conversion shall first be approved, and a date set for a vote thereon by the members (either at a meeting to be held on such date or by written ballot to be filed on or before such date), by a majority of the directors of the Federal credit union. Written notice of the proposition and of the date set for the vote shall then be delivered in person to each member, or mailed to each member at the address for such member appearing on the records of the credit union, not more than thirty nor less than seven days prior to such date. Approval of the proposition for conversion shall be by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the credit union who vote on the proposal. The written notice of the proposition shall in boldface type state that the issue will be decided by a majority of the members who vote.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc4339e5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A statement of the results of the vote, verified by the affidavits of the president or vice president and the secretary, shall be filed with the Administration within ten days after the vote is taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc4339e6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Promptly after the vote is taken and in no event later than ninety days thereafter, if the proposition for conversion was approved by such vote, the credit union shall take such action as may be necessary under the applicable State law to make it a State credit union, and within ten days after receipt of the State credit union charter there shall be filed with the Administration a copy of the charter thus issued. Upon such filing the credit union shall cease to be a Federal credit union.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc4339e7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Upon ceasing to be a Federal credit union, such credit union shall no longer be subject to any of the provisions of this chapter. The successor State credit union shall be vested with all of the assets and shall continue responsible for all of the obligations of the Federal credit union to the same extent as though the conversion had not taken place.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc4339e8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc4339e9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A State credit union, organized under the laws of any State, the District of Columbia, the several Territories and possessions of the United States, the Panama Canal Zone, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, may be converted into a Federal credit union by (A) complying with all State requirements requisite to enabling it to convert to a Federal credit union or to cease being a State credit union, (B) filing with the Administration proof of such compliance, satisfactory to the Board, and (C) filing with the Administration an organization certificate as required by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc4339ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1771/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> When the Board has been satisfied that all of such requirements, and all other requirements of this chapter, have been complied with, the Board shall approve the organization certificate. Upon such approval, the State credit union shall become a Federal credit union as of the date it ceases to be a State credit union. The Federal credit union shall be vested with all of the assets and shall continue responsible for all of the obligations of the State credit union to the same extent as though the conversion had not taken place.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc4339eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, title I, § 125, formerly § 26, as added <ref href="/us/pl/86/354/s1">Pub. L. 86–354, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/638">73 Stat. 638</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/206/s2/1">Pub. L. 91–206, § 2(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1970-03-10">Mar. 10, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/49">84 Stat. 49</ref>; renumbered title I, § 125, <ref href="/us/pl/91/468/s1/2">Pub. L. 91–468, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-19">Oct. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/994">84 Stat. 994</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 95–630, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3681">92 Stat. 3681</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tV/s527">Pub. L. 97–320, title V, § 527</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1535">96 Stat. 1535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc4339ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc4339ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc4339ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in text, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddc4339ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1771, <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750/s21">act June 26, 1934, ch. 750, § 21</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1937-07-09/ch471">July 9, 1937, ch. 471</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/487">50 Stat. 487</ref>, related to allotment of space in Federal buildings, prior to the amendment of act <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/86/354">Pub. L. 86–354</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1770">section 1770 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc4339f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> substituted “of the credit union who vote on the proposal” for “, in person or in writing”, and inserted provision that the written notice of the proposition shall in boldface type state that the issue will be decided by a majority of the members who vote.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> substituted “Board” for “Administrator” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/206">Pub. L. 91–206</ref> substituted “Administration” for “Bureau” and “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc4339f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc4339f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> effective on expiration of 120 days after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, and transitional provisions, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s509">section 509 of Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752">section 1752 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
