<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc62341f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815"><num value="1815">§ 1815.</num><heading> Deposit insurance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623420-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to Corporation required</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623421-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), any depository institution which is engaged in the business of receiving deposits other than trust funds (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/p">section 1813(p) of this title</ref>), upon application to and examination by the Corporation and approval by the Board of Directors, may become an insured depository institution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623422-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim depository institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any interim Federal depository institution that is chartered by the appropriate Federal banking agency and will not open for business, the depository institution shall be an insured depository institution upon the issuance of the institution’s charter by the agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623423-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application and approval not required in cases of continued insurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of any depository institution whose insured status is continued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1814">section 1814 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623424-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Review requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In reviewing any application under this subsection, the Board of Directors shall consider the factors described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1816">section 1816 of this title</ref> in determining whether to approve the application for insurance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623425-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of denial of application for insurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Board of Directors votes to deny any application for insurance by any depository institution, the Board of Directors shall promptly notify the appropriate Federal banking agency and, in the case of any State depository institution, the appropriate State banking supervisor of the denial of such application, giving specific reasons in writing for the Board of Directors’ determination with reference to the factors described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1816">section 1816 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623426-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Nondelegation requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The authority of the Board of Directors to make any determination to deny any application under this subsection may not be delegated by the Board of Directors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623427-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreign branch nonmember banks; matters considered</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of this chapter and to such terms and conditions as the Board of Directors may impose, any branch of a foreign bank, upon application by the bank to the Corporation, and examination by the Corporation of the branch, and approval by the Board of Directors, may become an insured branch. Before approving any such application, the Board of Directors shall give consideration to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc623428-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the financial history and condition of the bank,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc623429-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the adequacy of its capital structure,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> its future earnings prospects,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the general character and fitness of its management, including but not limited to the management of the branch proposed to be insured,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the risk presented to the Deposit Insurance Fund,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the convenience and needs of the community to be served by the branch,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> whether or not its corporate powers, insofar as they will be exercised through the proposed insured branch, are consistent with the purposes of this chapter, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc62342f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the probable adequacy and reliability of information supplied and to be supplied by the bank to the Corporation to enable it to carry out its functions under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623430-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection to Deposit Insurance Fund; surety bond, pledge of assets, etc.; injunction</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc623431-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before any branch of a foreign bank becomes an insured branch, the bank shall deliver to the Corporation or as the Corporation may direct a surety bond, a pledge of assets, or both, in such amounts and of such types as the Corporation may require or approve, for the purpose set forth in paragraph (4) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc623432-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> After any branch of a foreign bank becomes an insured branch, the bank shall maintain on deposit with the Corporation, or as the Corporation may direct, surety bonds or assets or both, in such amounts and of such types as shall be determined from time to time in accordance with such regulations as the Board of Directors may prescribe. Such regulations may impose differing requirements on the basis of any factors which in the judgment of the Board of Directors are reasonably related to the purpose set forth in paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc623433-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Corporation may require of any given bank larger deposits of bonds and assets than required under paragraph (2) of this subsection if, in the judgment of the Corporation, the situation of that bank or any branch thereof is or becomes such that the deposits of bonds and assets otherwise required under this section would not adequately fulfill the purpose set forth in paragraph (4). The imposition of any such additional requirements may be without notice or opportunity for hearing, but the Corporation shall afford an opportunity to any such bank to apply for a reduction or removal of any such additional requirements so imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc623434-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The purpose of the surety bonds and pledges of assets required under this subsection is to provide protection to the Deposit Insurance Fund against the risks entailed in insuring the domestic deposits of a foreign bank whose activities, assets, and personnel are in large part outside the jurisdiction of the United States. In the implementation of its authority under this subsection, however, the Corporation shall endeavor to avoid imposing requirements on such banks which would unnecessarily place them at a competitive disadvantage in relation to domestically incorporated banks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc623435-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In the case of any failure or threatened failure of a foreign bank to comply with any requirement imposed under this subsection (c), the Corporation, in addition to all other administrative and judicial remedies, may apply to any United States district court, or United States court of any territory, within the jurisdiction of which any branch of the bank is located, for an injunction to compel such bank and any officer, employee, or agent thereof, or any other person having custody or control of any of its assets, to deliver to the Corporation such assets as may be necessary to meet such requirement, and to take any other action necessary to vest the Corporation with control of assets so delivered. If the court shall determine that there has been any such failure or threatened failure to comply with any such requirement, it shall be the duty of the court to issue such injunction. The propriety of the requirement may be litigated only as provided in chapter 7 of title 5, and may not be made an issue in an action for an injunction under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623436-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623437-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any institution that becomes insured by the Corporation, and any noninsured branch that becomes insured by the Corporation, shall pay the Corporation any fee which the Corporation may by regulation prescribe, after giving due consideration to the need to establish and maintain the reserve ratio of the Deposit Insurance Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623438-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee credited to the Deposit Insurance Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The fee paid by the depository institution under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the Deposit Insurance Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623439-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for certain depository institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any depository institution that becomes an insured depository institution by operation of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1814/a">section 1814(a) of this title</ref> shall not pay any fee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62343a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of commonly controlled depository institutions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62343b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62343c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability established</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any insured depository institution shall be liable for any loss incurred by the Corporation, or any loss which the Corporation reasonably anticipates incurring, after <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>, in connection with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc62343d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the default of a commonly controlled insured depository institution; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc62343e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any assistance provided by the Corporation to any commonly controlled insured depository institution in danger of default.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62343f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment upon notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An insured depository institution shall pay the amount of any liability to the Corporation under subparagraph (A) upon receipt of written notice by the Corporation in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623440-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice required to be provided within 2 years of loss</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No insured depository institution shall be liable to the Corporation under subparagraph (A) if written notice with respect to such liability is not received by such institution before the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date the Corporation incurred the loss.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623441-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of compensation; procedures</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623442-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of estimates</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">When an insured depository institution is in default or requires assistance to prevent default, the Corporation shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623443-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in good faith, estimate the amount of the loss the Corporation will incur from such default or assistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623444-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if, with respect to such insured depository institution, there is more than 1 commonly controlled insured depository institution, estimate the amount of each such commonly controlled depository institution’s share of such liability; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623445-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> advise each commonly controlled depository institution of the Corporation’s estimate of the amount of such institution’s liability for such losses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623446-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures; immediate payment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Corporation, after consultation with the appropriate Federal banking agency and the appropriate State chartering agency, shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623447-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> on a case-by-case basis, establish the procedures and schedule under which any insured depository institution shall reimburse the Corporation for such institution’s liability under paragraph (1) in connection with any commonly controlled insured depository institution; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623448-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> require any insured depository institution to make immediate payment of the amount of such institution’s liability under paragraph (1) in connection with any commonly controlled insured depository institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623449-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The liability of any insured depository institution under this subsection shall have priority with respect to other obligations and liabilities as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62344a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Superiority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The liability shall be superior to the following obligations and liabilities of the depository institution:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc62344b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Any obligation to shareholders arising as a result of their status as shareholders (including any depository institution holding company or any shareholder or creditor of such company).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc62344c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Any obligation or liability owed to any affiliate of the depository institution (including any other insured depository institution), other than any secured obligation which was secured as of <date date="1989-05-01">May 1, 1989</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62344d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Subordination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The liability shall be subordinate in right and payment to the following obligations and liabilities of the depository institution:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc62344e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Any deposit liability (which is not a liability described in clause (i)(II)).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc62344f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Any secured obligation, other than any obligation owed to any affiliate of the depository institution (including any other insured depository institution) which was secured after <date date="1989-05-01">May 1, 1989</date>.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc623450-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Any other general or senior liability (which is not a liability described in clause (i)).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddc623451-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> Any obligation subordinated to depositors or other general creditors (which is not an obligation described in clause (i)).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623452-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment of estimated payment</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623453-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Overpayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the amount of compensation estimated by and paid to the Corporation by 1 or more such commonly controlled depository institutions is greater than the actual loss incurred by the Corporation, the Corporation shall reimburse each such commonly controlled depository institution its pro rata share of any overpayment.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623454-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/2/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Underpayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the amount of compensation estimated by and paid to the Corporation by 1 or more such commonly controlled depository institutions is less than the actual loss incurred by the Corporation, the Corporation shall redetermine in its discretion the liability of each such commonly controlled depository institution to the Corporation and shall require each such commonly controlled depository institution to make payment of any additional liability to the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623455-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623456-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Actions of the Corporation shall be reviewable pursuant to chapter 7 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623457-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Corporation shall prescribe regulations and establish administrative procedures which provide for a hearing on the record for the review of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623458-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of any loss incurred by the Corporation in connection with any insured depository institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc623459-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the liability of individual commonly controlled depository institutions for the amount of such loss; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc62345a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the schedule of payments to be made by such commonly controlled depository institutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62345b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on rights of private parties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To the extent the exercise of any right or power of any person would impair the ability of any insured depository institution to perform such institution’s obligations under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc62345c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the obligations of such insured depository institution shall supersede such right or power; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc62345d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> no court may give effect to such right or power with respect to such insured depository institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62345e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver authority</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62345f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Corporation, in its discretion, may exempt any insured depository institution from the provisions of this subsection if the Corporation determines that such exemption is in the best interests of the Deposit Insurance Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623460-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Condition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">During the period any exemption granted to any insured depository institution under subparagraph (A) or (C) is in effect, such insured depository institution and all other insured depository institution affiliates of such depository institution shall comply fully with the restrictions of sections 371c and 371c–1 of this title without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s371c/d/1">section 371c(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623461-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limited partnerships</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623462-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Corporation may, in its discretion, exempt any limited partnership and any affiliate of any limited partnership (other than any insured depository institution which is a majority owned subsidiary of such partnership) from the provisions of this subsection if such limited partnership or affiliate has filed a registration statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission on or before <date date="1989-04-10">April 10, 1989</date>, indicating that as of the date of such filing such partnership intended to acquire 1 or more insured depository institutions.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623463-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Within 10 business days after the date of submission of any request for an exemption under this subparagraph together with such information as shall be reasonably requested by the Corporation, the Corporation shall make a determination on the request and shall so advise the applicant.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623464-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusion for institutions acquired in debt collections</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any depository institution shall not be treated as commonly controlled, for purposes of this subsection, during the 5-year period beginning on the date of an acquisition described in subparagraph (A) or such longer period as the Corporation may determine after written application by the acquirer, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc623465-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 1 depository institution controls another by virtue of ownership of voting shares acquired in securing or collecting a debt previously contracted in good faith; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc623466-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> during the period beginning on <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>, and ending upon the expiration of the exclusion, the controlling bank and all other insured depository institution affiliates of such controlling bank comply fully with the restrictions of sections 371c and 371c–1 of this title, without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s371c/d/1">section 371c(d)(1) of this title</ref>, in transactions with the acquired insured depository institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc623467-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for certain FSLIC assisted institutions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No depository institution shall have any liability to the Corporation under this subsection as the result of the default of, or assistance provided with respect to, an insured depository institution which is an affiliate of such depository institution if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc623468-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such affiliate was receiving cash payments from the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation under an assistance agreement or note entered into before <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc623469-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, or such other entity which has succeeded to the payment obligations of such Corporation with respect to such assistance agreement or note, is unable to continue such payments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc62346a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> such affiliate—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc62346b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is in default or in need of assistance solely as a result of the failure to meet the payment obligations referred to in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc62346c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is not otherwise in breach of the terms of any assistance agreement or note which would authorize the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or such other successor entity, pursuant to the terms of such assistance agreement or note, to refuse to make such payments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc62346d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Commonly controlled defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, depository institutions are commonly controlled if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc62346e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such institutions are controlled by the same company; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc62346f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1815/e/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 1 depository institution is controlled by another depository institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc623470-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-21/ch967/s2">Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2</ref>[5], <ref href="/us/stat/64/876">64 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/369/s6/c/7">Pub. L. 95–369, § 6(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-17">Sept. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/616">92 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tVII/s703/c">Pub. L. 97–320, title VII, § 703(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1539">96 Stat. 1539</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tII">Pub. L. 101–73, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), 206(a), <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/187">103 Stat. 187</ref>, 195; <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tI/s115/a">Pub. L. 102–242, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, title III, § 302(e)(1), (2), title V, § 501(a), <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2249">105 Stat. 2249</ref>, 2349, 2388; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXVI">Pub. L. 102–550, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1605(a)(5)(B), 1607(a), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4085">106 Stat. 4085</ref>, 4089; <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/tIII">Pub. L. 102–558, title III</ref>, §§ 303(b)(6)(B), 305, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4225">106 Stat. 4225</ref>, 4226; <ref href="/us/pl/103/204/s9">Pub. L. 103–204, § 9</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2388">107 Stat. 2388</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tIII/s319/b">Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 319(b)</ref>, title VI, § 602(a)(2), (3), <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2225">108 Stat. 2225</ref>, 2288; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 2201(a), 2702(i), 2704(d)(14)(B)–(E), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-403">110 Stat. 3009–403</ref>, 3009–483, 3009–491; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tII/s2102/b">Pub. L. 109–171, title II, § 2102(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/9">120 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/2">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(2)</ref>–(6), <date date="2006-02-15">Feb. 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3610">119 Stat. 3610</ref>, 3611; <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 109–351, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1986">120 Stat. 1986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc623471-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc623472-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddc623473-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is derived from subsec. (f)(2) of former <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s264">section 264 of this title</ref>. See Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc623474-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/2">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Deposit Insurance Fund,” for “the Bank Insurance Fund or the Savings Association Insurance Fund,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(B)</ref>. See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/3">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “deposit insurance fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/C">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(C)</ref>, (D). See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/5">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(5)</ref> substituted, “the reserve ratio of the Deposit Insurance Fund” for “reserve ratios in the Bank Insurance Fund and the Savings Association Insurance Fund as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref>” in subpar. (A), struck out par. (1) designation and heading, redesignated subpar. (A) as par. (1) and realigned margin, and struck out subpar. (B), the text of which read as follows: “The fee paid by the depository institution shall be credited to the Bank Insurance Fund if the depository institution becomes a Bank Insurance Fund member, and to the Savings Association Insurance Fund if the depository institution becomes a Savings Association Insurance Fund member.” Former subpar. (C) redesignated par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/4">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(4)</ref>, (5)(B), added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which related to conversion transactions by insured depository institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/4">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(4)</ref>, (5)(D), redesignated par. (1)(C) of subsec. (d) as (3), realigned margin, and struck out former par. (3) which related to optional conversions by insured depository institutions subject to special rules on deposit insurance payments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/6/A">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Bank Insurance Fund or the Savings Association Insurance Fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/E/i">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(E)(i)</ref>. See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/6/B">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(6)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated pars. (7) to (9) as (6) to (8), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former par. (6). Text read as follows: “During the 5-year period beginning on <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) no Savings Association Insurance Fund member shall have any liability to the Corporation under this subsection arising out of assistance provided by the Corporation or any loss incurred by the Corporation as a result of the default of a Bank Insurance Fund member which was acquired by such Savings Association Insurance Fund member or any affiliate of such member before <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) no Bank Insurance Fund member shall have such liability with respect to assistance provided by or loss incurred by the Corporation as a result of the default of a Savings Association Insurance Fund member which was acquired by such Bank Insurance Fund member or any affiliate of such member before <date date="1989-08-09">August 9, 1989</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/E/ii">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(E)(ii)</ref>, (iii). See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(8)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s703">Pub. L. 109–351, § 703</ref>, which directed general amendment of par. (9)(A) of subsec. (e), was executed by making the amendment to par. (8)(A) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and amendment by 109–173, § 8(a)(6)(B), (C). Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “such institutions are controlled by the same depository institution holding company (including any company required to file reports pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/f/6">section 1843(f)(6) of this title</ref>); or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(B)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Deposit Insurance Fund,” for “the Bank Insurance Fund or the Savings Association Insurance Fund;”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/C">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(C)</ref> and (D), which directed the amendment of subsec. (d) by striking out par. (1) designation and heading, redesignating subpar. (A) of par. (1) as par. (1), realigning margin, and substituting “the reserve ratio of the Deposit Insurance Fund” for “reserve ratios in the Bank Insurance Fund and the Savings Association Insurance Fund”, striking out subpar. (B) of par. (1) and pars. (2) and (3) and adding new par. (2), and redesignating subpar. (C) of par. (1) as par. (3) and realigning margin, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2201/a/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2201(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “if the transaction is approved by” for “with the prior written approval of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2702/i/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2702(i)(1)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (K), the adjusted attributable deposit amount” for “The adjusted attributable deposit amount” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2201/a/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2201(a)(2)</ref>, added cl. (iii), redesignated former cls. (ii) and (iii) as (i) and (ii), respectively, and struck out former cls. (i) and (iv), which directed review of any application under the procedures and factors set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1828/c">section 1828(c) of this title</ref> and disapproval of any application unless depository institution met all applicable capital requirements, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(G) to (J). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2201/a/3">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2201(a)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subpars. (H) to (J) as (G) to (I), respectively and struck out former subpar. (G) which related to expedited approval of acquisitions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2702/i/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2702(i)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (K).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/E/i">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(E)(i)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Bank Insurance Fund or the Savings Association Insurance Fund”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/14/E/ii">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(14)(E)(ii)</ref>, (iii), which directed striking out par. (6) and redesignating pars. (7) to (9) as (6) to (8), respectively, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s602/a/2">Pub. L. 103–325, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, substituted comma for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/1">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated cl. (i) formerly entitled “In general” as subpar. (A), inserted comma after “Notwithstanding paragraph (2)(A)”, and struck out heading and text of cl. (ii). Text read as follows: “If, in connection with any transaction referred to in clause (i), the acquiring, assuming, or resulting depository institution is a Bank Insurance Fund member which is a subsidiary of a bank holding company, the prior written approval of the Board shall be required for such transaction in addition to the approval of any agency referred to in clause (i).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(E)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/2/A">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “(and, in the event the acquiring, assuming, or resulting depository institution is a Bank Insurance Fund member which is a subsidiary of a bank holding company, the Board)” after “responsible agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(E)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/2/B">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out “or Board” after “responsible agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(E)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/2/C">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(2)(C)</ref>, struck out “, and the appropriate Federal banking agency for any depository institution holding company,” after “responsible agency”, “each” before “such agency determines”, and “, and any depository institution holding company which controls such institution,” after “resulting depository institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/3">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “A Bank” for “The Board may not approve any transaction under subparagraph (A) in which the acquiring, assuming, or resulting depository institution is a Bank” and “may not be the acquiring, assuming, or resulting depository institution in a transaction under subparagraph (A) unless” for “unless the Board determines that”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s319/b/4">Pub. L. 103–325, § 319(b)(4)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subpar. (K). Text read as follows: “For purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘Board’ (other than when such term appears in connection with a reference to the Board of Directors) means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s602/a/3">Pub. L. 103–325, § 602(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated cls. (i) and (ii) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, and realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (d)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/204/s9/a">Pub. L. 103–204, § 9(a)</ref>, substituted “before the later of the end” for “before the end” and inserted before period at end “or the date on which the Savings Association Insurance Fund first meets or exceeds the designated reserve ratio for such fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/103/204/s9/b">Pub. L. 103–204, § 9(b)</ref>, added cl. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C)(ii), (iii), (3)(I)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/204/s9/c">Pub. L. 103–204, § 9(c)</ref>, substituted “moratorium period established by” for “5-year period referred to in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (d)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s303/b/6/B">Pub. L. 102–558, § 303(b)(6)(B)</ref>, amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s302/e">Pub. L. 102–242, § 302(e)</ref>. See 1991 amendment note below. <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1605/a/5/B">Pub. L. 102–550, § 1605(a)(5)(B)</ref>, which contained an identical amendment, was repealed, effective <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s305">Pub. L. 102–558, § 305</ref>, set out as a Repeal of Duplicative Provisions note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1607/a">Pub. L. 102–550, § 1607(a)</ref>, added subpar. (K).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s115/a">Pub. L. 102–242, § 115(a)</ref>, amended section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s115/a">Pub. L. 102–242, § 115(a)</ref>, added subsec. (a) consisting of pars. (1) to (6) and struck out former subsec. (a) relating to application for insurance, which consisted of pars. (1) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s501/a">Pub. L. 102–242, § 501(a)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally, substituting present provisions consisting of subpars. (A) to (J) for provisions related to optional conversion through merger, which consisted of subpars. (A) to (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s302/e/1">Pub. L. 102–242, § 302(e)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s303/b/6/B">Pub. L. 102–558, § 303(b)(6)(B)</ref>, substituted “deposits” for “average assessment base” and “shall be treated as deposits which are insured by the Savings Association Insurance Fund.” for “shall—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) be subject to assessment at the assessment rate applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref> for Savings Association Insurance Fund members;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) not be taken into account for purposes of any assessment under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref> for Bank Insurance Fund members; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(III) be treated as deposits which are insured by the Savings Association Insurance Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s302/e/2">Pub. L. 102–242, § 302(e)(2)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s303/b/6/B">Pub. L. 102–558, § 303(b)(6)(B)</ref>, substituted “deposits” for “average assessment base” and “shall be treated as deposits which are insured by the Bank Insurance Fund.” for “shall—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) be subject to assessment at the assessment rate applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref> for Bank Insurance Fund members;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) not be taken into account for purposes of any assessment under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref> for Savings Association Insurance Fund members; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(III) be treated as deposits which are insured by the Bank Insurance Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s201/a">Pub. L. 101–73, § 201(a)</ref>, substituted references to insured depository institutions for references to insured banks wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s206/a/1">Pub. L. 101–73, § 206(a)(1)</ref>–(4), inserted heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. (1) heading, and substituted “Any” for “Subject to the provisions of this chapter, any”, inserted “and State savings association” after “any State nonmember bank” and after “such State nonmember bank”, “or savings association” after “such bank”, and “or savings association, and in the case of an application by a State savings association, the Corporation shall notify the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision of the Corporation’s approval of such application” after “books of the bank”, and added pars. (2) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s206/a/5">Pub. L. 101–73, § 206(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “and fitness” after “character”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s206/a/6">Pub. L. 101–73, § 206(a)(6)</ref>, added par. (5) and redesignated former pars. (5) to (7) as (6) to (8), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s206/a/7">Pub. L. 101–73, § 206(a)(7)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> inserted provision relating to the determination before the application of an industrial bank or similar institution is approved that it is chartered and operating under provisions substantially comparable to those applicable to banks operating in the same State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/369">Pub. L. 95–369</ref> designated existing provision as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc647d65-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc647d66-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/173">Pub. L. 109–173</ref> effective <date date="2006-03-31">Mar. 31, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/b">section 8(b) of Pub. L. 109–173</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> effective no later than the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the end of the 90-day period beginning <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s2102/c">section 2102(c) of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, set out as a Merger of BIF and SAIF note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc647d67-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2704(d)(14)(B)–(E) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1999-01-01">Jan. 1, 1999</date>, if no insured depository institution is a savings association on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/c">section 2704(c) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc647d68-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s303/b/6/B">section 303(b)(6)(B) of Pub. L. 102–558</ref> deemed to have become effective <date date="1992-03-01">Mar. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/558/s304">section 304 of Pub. L. 102–558</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4502">section 4502 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> effective as if included in the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991, <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, as of <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, except that where amendment is to any provision of law added or amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref> effective after <date date="1992-12-19">Dec. 19, 1992</date>, then amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> effective on effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1609">section 1609 of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s191">section 191 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc647d69-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 302(e)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref> effective on earlier of 180 days after date on which final regulations promulgated in accordance with <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s302/c">section 302(c) of Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref>, become effective or <date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s302/g">section 302(g) of Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 102–242, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2391">105 Stat. 2391</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/242/tV/s501/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) to section 5(d)(3)(C) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d/3/C">12 U.S.C. 1815(d)(3)(C)</ref>] shall apply with respect to semiannual periods beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc647d6a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeal of Duplicative Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/558/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 102–558, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4226">106 Stat. 4226</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/558/tIII/s305">
<inline>“In the event of the enactment of H.R. 5334 (An Act to amend and extend certain laws relating to housing and community development, and for other purposes) [enacted as <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref>], the following provisions of that Act, and the amendments made by such provisions, are repealed, effective on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>]:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Section 1603(a)(3) of such Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">section 1817 of this title</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Section 1604(a)(11) of such Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3104">section 3104 of this title</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 1604(b) of such Act [amending sections 1817, 1834, and 1834a of this title].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> [sic] Paragraphs (2) through (7) of section 1605(a) of such Act [amending sections 1815, 1817, 1818, 1820, 1834, and 1834a of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 1817, 1834, and 1834a of this title].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc647d6b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Moratorium on Treatment of Credit Card Banks, Industrial Loan Companies, and Certain Other Companies Under the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVI/s603/a">Pub. L. 111–203, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1597">124 Stat. 1597</ref>, provided that, effective until 3 years after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation would not approve an application for deposit insurance received after <date date="2009-11-23">Nov. 23, 2009</date>, for an industrial bank, a credit card bank, or a trust bank owned by a commercial firm and would disapprove, with certain exceptions, a change in control of such a bank that would result in control of the industrial bank, credit card bank, or trust bank by a commercial firm.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc647d6c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deposit of Funds Into Deposit Insurance Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/4">Pub. L. 109–173, § 8(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-15">Feb. 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3610">119 Stat. 3610</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/173/s8/a/4">“any funds resulting from the application of such paragraph (2) [of subsec. (d) of this section] prior to its repeal [see 2006 Amendment note above] shall be deposited into the general fund of the Deposit Insurance Fund”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc647d6d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Newly Insured Thrift Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tII/s206/b">Pub. L. 101–73, title II, § 206(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/205">103 Stat. 205</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/73/tII/s206/b">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“Any insured depository institution (as defined in section 3(c)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/c/2">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)(2)</ref>], as added by section 204(c) of this Act)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> which was an insured institution (as defined in section 401(a) of the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1724/a">12 U.S.C. 1724(a)</ref>], as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>]) on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the board of directors of which determined, before <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>, to terminate such association’s status as an insured institution (as so defined) as evidenced in sworn minutes of the board of directors meeting held before such date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> had insured deposits of less than $11,000,000 on <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> was an insured institution (as so defined) for less than 1 year as of <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may cease to be a Savings Association Insurance Fund member and become a Bank Insurance Fund member at any time during the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act without the approval of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation under section 5(d)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1815/d/2">12 U.S.C. 1815(d)(2)</ref>] (as added by subsection (a) of this section) and without incurring any liability for any exit or entrance fee imposed under such section 5(d)(2).”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="iddc647d6e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definition of “Commercial Firm”</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 111–203, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1596">124 Stat. 1596</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tVI/s602">“For purposes of this title [see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref>], a company is a ‘commercial firm’ if the annual gross revenues derived by the company and all of its affiliates from activities that are financial in nature (as defined in section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/k">12 U.S.C. 1843(k)</ref>)) and, if applicable, from the ownership or control of one or more insured depository institutions, represent less than 15 percent of the consolidated annual gross revenues of the company.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s602">section 602 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
