<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc96b181-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1"><num value="1831m–1">§ 1831m–1.</num><heading> Reports of information regarding safety and soundness of depository institutions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b182-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to appropriate Federal banking agencies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b183-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the head of any other agency or instrumentality of the United States shall, unless otherwise prohibited by law, disclose to the appropriate Federal banking agency any information that the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, or such agency head believes raises significant concerns regarding the safety or soundness of any depository institution doing business in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b184-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b185-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Intelligence information</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b186-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Director of Central Intelligence shall disclose to the Attorney General or the Secretary of the Treasury any intelligence information that would otherwise be reported to an appropriate Federal banking agency pursuant to paragraph (1). After consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence, the Attorney General or the Secretary of the Treasury, shall disclose the intelligence information to the appropriate Federal banking agency.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b187-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for receipt of intelligence information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Each appropriate Federal banking agency, in consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence, shall establish procedures for receipt of intelligence information that are adequate to protect the intelligence information.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b188-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal investigations, safety of Government investigators, informants, and witnesses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury or their respective designees determines that the disclosure of information pursuant to paragraph (1) may jeopardize a pending civil investigation or litigation, or a pending criminal investigation or prosecution, may result in serious bodily injury or death to Government employees, informants, witnesses or their respective families, or may disclose sensitive investigative techniques and methods, the Attorney General or the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc96b189-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> provide the appropriate Federal banking agency a description of the information that is as specific as possible without jeopardizing the investigation, litigation, or prosecution, threatening serious bodily injury or death to Government employees, informants, or witnesses or their respective families, or disclosing sensitive investigation techniques and methods; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc96b18a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> permit a full review of the information by the Federal banking agency at a location and under procedures that the Attorney General determines will ensure the effective protection of the information while permitting the Federal banking agency to ensure the safety and soundness of any depository institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b18b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Grand jury investigations; criminal procedure</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Paragraph (1) shall not—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc96b18c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> apply to the receipt of information by an agency or instrumentality in connection with a pending grand jury investigation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddc96b18d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be construed to require disclosure of information prohibited by rule 6 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b18e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for receipt of disclosure reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b18f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 90 days after <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, each appropriate Federal banking agency shall establish procedures for receipt of a disclosure report by an agency or instrumentality made in accordance with subsection (a)(1). The procedures established in accordance with this subsection shall ensure adequate protection of information disclosed, including access control and information accountability.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b190-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures related to each disclosure report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receipt of a report in accordance with subsection (a)(1), the appropriate Federal banking agency shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc96b191-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> consult with the agency or instrumentality that made the disclosure regarding the adequacy of the procedures established pursuant to paragraph (1), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc96b192-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> adjust the procedures to ensure adequate protection of the information disclosed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b193-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section does not impose an affirmative duty on the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the head of any agency or instrumentality of the United States to collect new or to review existing information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc96b194-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1831m–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the terms “appropriate Federal banking agency” and “depository institution” have the same meanings as in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc96b195-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXV/s1542">Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1542</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4067">106 Stat. 4067</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tX/s1001/f">Pub. L. 105–362, title X, § 1001(f)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3292">112 Stat. 3292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc96b196-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc96b197-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc96b198-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Rule 6 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(C)(ii), is set out in the Appendix to Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc96b199-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Annunzio-Wylie Anti-Money Laundering Act and also as part of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and not as part of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc96b19a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out heading and text of subsec. (e). Text read as follows: “The Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury shall report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives, not later than 90 days after the end of each calendar year on their utilization of the exceptions provided in subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc96b19b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddc96b19c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
