<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddca753cb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841"><num value="1841">§ 1841.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753cc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753cd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, “bank holding company” means any company which has control over any bank or over any company that is or becomes a bank holding company by virtue of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753ce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any company has control over a bank or over any company if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753cf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the company directly or indirectly or acting through one or more other persons owns, controls, or has power to vote 25 per centum or more of any class of voting securities of the bank or company;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the company controls in any manner the election of a majority of the directors or trustees of the bank or company; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Board determines, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that the company directly or indirectly exercises a controlling influence over the management or policies of the bank or company.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753d2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For the purposes of any proceeding under paragraph (2)(C) of this subsection, there is a presumption that any company which directly or indirectly owns, controls, or has power to vote less than 5 per centum of any class of voting securities of a given bank or company does not have control over that bank or company.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753d3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any administrative or judicial proceeding under this chapter, other than a proceeding under paragraph (2)(C) of this subsection, a company may not be held to have had control over any given bank or company at any given time unless that company, at the time in question, directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or had power to vote 5 per centum or more of any class of voting securities of the bank or company, or had already been found to have control in a proceeding under paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753d4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No bank and no company owning or controlling voting shares of a bank is a bank holding company by virtue of its ownership or control of shares in a fiduciary capacity, except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (g) of this section. For the purpose of the preceding sentence, bank shares shall not be deemed to have been acquired in a fiduciary capacity if the acquiring bank or company has sole discretionary authority to exercise voting rights with respect thereto; except that this limitation is applicable in the case of a bank or company acquiring such shares prior to <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, only if the bank or company has the right consistent with its obligations under the instrument, agreement, or other arrangement establishing the fiduciary relationship to divest itself of such voting rights and fails to exercise that right to divest within a reasonable period not to exceed one year after <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No company is a bank holding company by virtue of its ownership or control of shares acquired by it in connection with its underwriting of securities if such shares are held only for such period of time as will permit the sale thereof on a reasonable basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> No company formed for the sole purpose of participating in a proxy solicitation is a bank holding company by virtue of its control of voting rights of shares acquired in the course of such solicitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> No company is a bank holding company by virtue of its ownership or control of shares acquired in securing or collecting a debt previously contracted in good faith, until two years after the date of acquisition. The Board is authorized upon application by a company to extend, from time to time for not more than one year at a time, the two-year period referred to herein for disposing of any shares acquired by a company in the regular course of securing or collecting a debt previously contracted in good faith, if, in the Board’s judgment, such an extension would not be detrimental to the public interest, but no such extension shall in the aggregate exceed three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753d9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> No company is a bank holding company by virtue of its ownership or control of any State-chartered bank or trust company which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753da-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is wholly owned by 1 or more thrift institutions or savings banks; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753db-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> is restricted to accepting—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753dc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> deposits from thrift institutions or savings banks;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753dd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> deposits arising out of the corporate business of the thrift institutions or savings banks that own the bank or trust company; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753de-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/E/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> deposits of public moneys.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753df-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> No trust company or mutual savings bank which is an insured bank under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.] is a bank holding company by virtue of its direct or indirect ownership or control of one bank located in the same State, if (i) such ownership or control existed on <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, and is specifically authorized by applicable State law, and (ii) the trust company or mutual savings bank does not after that date acquire an interest in any company that, together with any other interest it holds in that company, will exceed 5 per centum of any class of the voting shares of that company, except that this limitation shall not be applicable to investments of the trust company or mutual savings bank, direct and indirect, which are otherwise in accordance with the limitations applicable to national banks under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753e0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> For the purposes of this chapter, any successor to a bank holding company shall be deemed to be a bank holding company from the date on which the predecessor company became a bank holding company.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753e1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> “Company” means any corporation, partnership, business trust, association, or similar organization, or any other trust unless by its terms it must terminate within twenty-five years or not later than twenty-one years and ten months after the death of individuals living on the effective date of the trust but shall not include any corporation the majority of the shares of which are owned by the United States or by any State, and shall not include a qualified family partnership. “Company covered in 1970” means a company which becomes a bank holding company as a result of the enactment of the Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970 and which would have been a bank holding company on <date date="1968-06-30">June 30, 1968</date>, if those amendments had been enacted on that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca753e2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bank Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753e3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term “bank” means any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753e4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An insured bank as defined in section 3(h) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/h">12 U.S.C. 1813(h)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753e5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> An institution organized under the laws of the United States, any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands which both—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753e6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> accepts demand deposits or deposits that the depositor may withdraw by check or similar means for payment to third parties or others; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753e7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is engaged in the business of making commercial loans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca753e8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “bank” does not include any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753e9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A foreign bank which would be a bank within the meaning of paragraph (1) solely because such bank has an insured or uninsured branch in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An insured institution (as defined in subsection (j)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An organization that does not do business in the United States except as an incident to its activities outside the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> An institution that functions solely in a trust or fiduciary capacity, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> all or substantially all of the deposits of such institution are in trust funds and are received in a bona fide fiduciary capacity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> no deposits of such institution which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation are offered or marketed by or through an affiliate of such institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such institution does not accept demand deposits or deposits that the depositor may withdraw by check or similar means for payment to third parties or others or make commercial loans; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> such institution does not—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca753f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> obtain payment or payment related services from any Federal Reserve bank, including any service referred to in section 11A of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248a">12 U.S.C. 248a</ref>]; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca753f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/D/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> exercise discount or borrowing privileges pursuant to section 19(b)(7) of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/7">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(7)</ref>].</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A credit union (as described in section 19(b)(1)(A)(iv) of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/iv">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(A)(iv)</ref>]).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> An institution, including an institution that accepts collateral for extensions of credit by holding deposits under $100,000, and by other means which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> engages only in credit card operations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> does not accept demand deposits or deposits that the depositor may withdraw by check or similar means for payment to third parties or others;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> does not accept any savings or time deposit of less than $100,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> maintains only one office that accepts deposits; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> does not engage in the business of making commercial loans, other than credit card loans that are made to businesses that meet the criteria for a small business concern to be eligible for business loans under regulations established by the Small Business Administration under part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> An organization operating under section 25 or section 25(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002280">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002280"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Federal Reserve Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca753fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> An industrial loan company, industrial bank, or other similar institution which is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca753fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> an institution organized under the laws of a State which, on <date date="1987-03-05">March 5, 1987</date>, had in effect or had under consideration in such State’s legislature a statute which required or would require such institution to obtain insurance under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.]—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca753fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> which does not accept demand deposits that the depositor may withdraw by check or similar means for payment to third parties;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca753fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> which has total assets of less than $100,000,000; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca753ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the control of which is not acquired by any company after <date date="1987-08-10">August 10, 1987</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca75400-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an institution which does not, directly, indirectly, or through an affiliate, engage in any activity in which it was not lawfully engaged as of <date date="1987-03-05">March 5, 1987</date>,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">except that this subparagraph shall cease to apply to any institution which permits any overdraft (including any intraday overdraft), or which incurs any such overdraft in such institution’s account at a Federal Reserve bank, on behalf of an affiliate if such overdraft is not the result of an inadvertent computer or accounting error that is beyond the control of both the institution and the affiliate, or that is otherwise permissible for a bank controlled by a company described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/f/1">section 1843(f)(1) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75401-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> “Subsidiary”, with respect to a specified bank holding company, means (1) any company 25 per centum or more of whose voting shares (excluding shares owned by the United States or by any company wholly owned by the United States) is directly or indirectly owned or controlled by such bank holding company, or is held by it with power to vote; (2) any company the election of a majority of whose directors is controlled in any manner by such bank holding company; or (3) any company with respect to the management of policies of which such bank holding company has the power, directly or indirectly, to exercise a controlling influence, as determined by the Board, after notice and opportunity for hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75402-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The term “successor” shall include any company which acquires directly or indirectly from a bank holding company shares of any bank, when and if the relationship between such company and the bank holding company is such that the transaction effects no substantial change in the control of the bank or beneficial ownership of such shares of such bank. The Board may, by regulation, further define the term “successor” to the extent necessary to prevent evasion of the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75403-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> “Board” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75404-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75405-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shares owned or controlled by any subsidiary of a bank holding company shall be deemed to be indirectly owned or controlled by such bank holding company; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75406-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shares held or controlled directly or indirectly by trustees for the benefit of (A) a company, (B) the shareholders or members of a company, or (C) the employees (whether exclusively or not) of a company, shall be deemed to be controlled by such company, unless the Board determines that such treatment is not appropriate in light of the facts and circumstances of the case and the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75407-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75408-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided by paragraph (2), the application of this chapter and of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s371c">section 371c of this title</ref> shall not be affected by the fact that a transaction takes place wholly or partly outside the United States or that a company is organized or operates outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75409-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the prohibitions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843">section 1843 of this title</ref> shall not apply to shares of any company organized under the laws of a foreign country (or to shares held by such company in any company engaged in the same general line of business as the investor company or in a business related to the business of the investor company) that is principally engaged in business outside the United States if such shares are held or acquired by a bank holding company organized under the laws of a foreign country that is principally engaged in the banking business outside the United States. For the purpose of this subsection, the term “section 2(h)(2) company” means any company whose shares are held pursuant to this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca7540a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in paragraph (2) authorizes a section 2(h)(2) company to engage in (or acquire or hold more than 5 percent of the outstanding shares of any class of voting securities of a company engaged in) any banking, securities, insurance, or other financial activities, as defined by the Board, in the United States. This paragraph does not prohibit a section 2(h)(2) company from holding shares that were lawfully acquired before <date date="1987-08-10">August 10, 1987</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca7540b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> No domestic office or subsidiary of a bank holding company or subsidiary thereof holding shares of a section 2(h)(2) company may extend credit to a domestic office or subsidiary of such section 2(h)(2) company on terms more favorable than those afforded similar borrowers in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca7540c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> No domestic banking office or bank subsidiary of a bank holding company that controls a section 2(h)(2) company may offer or market products or services of such section 2(h)(2) company, or permit its products or services to be offered or marketed by or through such section 2(h)(2) company, unless such products or services were being so offered or marketed as of <date date="1987-03-05">March 5, 1987</date>, and then only in the same manner in which they were being offered or marketed as of that date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca7540d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Thrift Institution</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this chapter, the term “thrift institution” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca7540e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any domestic building and loan or savings and loan association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca7540f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any cooperative bank without capital stock organized and operated for mutual purposes and without profit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75410-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any Federal savings bank; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75411-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any State-chartered savings bank the holding company of which is registered pursuant to section 1730a <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75412-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Savings Associations and Related Term</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “savings association” or “insured institution” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75413-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any Federal savings association or Federal savings bank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75414-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any building and loan association, savings and loan association, homestead association, or cooperative bank if such association or cooperative bank is a member of the Deposit Insurance Fund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca75415-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any savings bank or cooperative bank which is deemed by the appropriate Federal banking agency to be a savings association under section 1467a(<i>l</i>) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75416-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affiliate</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this chapter, the term “affiliate” means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another company.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75417-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Bank Holding Company</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this chapter, the term “savings bank holding company” means any company which controls one or more qualified savings banks if the aggregate total assets of such savings banks constitute, upon formation of the holding company and at all times thereafter, at least 70 percent of the total assets of such company.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca75418-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><note topic="miscellaneous" id="iddca75419-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<p> [Repealed]</p></note>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca7541a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Incorporated Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this chapter, the terms “depository institution”, “insured depository institution”, “appropriate Federal banking agency”, “default”, “in danger of default”, and “State bank supervisor” have the same meanings as in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9c41b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c41c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Capital terms.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c41d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Insured depository institutions</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to insured depository institutions, the terms “well capitalized”, “adequately capitalized”, and “undercapitalized” have the same meanings as in section 38 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1831">12 U.S.C. 1831</ref><i>o</i>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c41e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bank holding company.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c41f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adequately capitalized</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to a bank holding company, the term “adequately capitalized” means a level of capitalization which meets or exceeds all applicable Federal regulatory capital standards.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c420-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Well capitalized</inline>.—</heading><content>A bank holding company is “well capitalized” if it meets the required capital levels for well capitalized bank holding companies established by the Board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c421-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other capital terms</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms “Tier 1” and “risk-weighted assets” have the meanings given those terms in the capital guidelines or regulations established by the Board for bank holding companies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c422-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Antitrust laws</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1849">section 1849 of this title</ref>, the term “antitrust laws”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c423-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has the same meaning as in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c424-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">section 45 of title 15</ref> to the extent that such section 45 relates to unfair methods of competition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c425-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Branch</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “branch” means a domestic branch (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c426-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Home state</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “home State” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c427-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to a national bank, the State in which the main office of the bank is located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c428-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to a State bank, the State by which the bank is chartered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c429-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> with respect to a bank holding company, the State in which the total deposits of all banking subsidiaries of such company are the largest on the later of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c42a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> <date date="1966-07-01">July 1, 1966</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c42b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the date on which the company becomes a bank holding company under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c42c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> with respect to a State savings association, the State by which the savings association is chartered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c42d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> with respect to a Federal savings association, the State in which the home office (as defined by the regulations of the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, or, on and after the transfer date,<sup>1</sup> the Comptroller of the Currency) of the Federal savings association is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c42e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Host state</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “host State” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c42f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to a bank, a State, other than the home State of the bank, in which the bank maintains, or seeks to establish and maintain, a branch; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c430-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to a bank holding company, a State, other than the home State of the company, in which the company controls, or seeks to control, a bank subsidiary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c431-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Out-of-state bank</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “out-of-State bank” means, with respect to any State, a bank whose home State is another State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c432-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Out-of-state bank holding company</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “out-of-State bank holding company” means, with respect to any State, a bank holding company whose home State is another State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c433-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lead insured depository institutions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c434-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “lead insured depository institution” means the largest insured depository institution controlled by the subject bank holding company at any time, based on a comparison of the average total risk-weighted assets controlled by each insured depository institution during the previous 12-month period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c435-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Branch or agency</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/j/4">section 1843(j)(4) of this title</ref>, the term “insured depository institution” includes any branch or agency operated in the United States by a foreign bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c436-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Well managed</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “well managed” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c437-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> in the case of any company or depository institution which receives examinations, the achievement of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c438-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/9/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a CAMEL composite rating of 1 or 2 (or an equivalent rating under an equivalent rating system) in connection with the most recent examination or subsequent review of such company or institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c439-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/9/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at least a satisfactory rating for management, if such rating is given; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c43a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a company or depository institution that has not received an examination rating, the existence and use of managerial resources which the Board determines are satisfactory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9c43b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified family partnership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “qualified family partnership” means a general or limited partnership that the Board determines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c43c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> does not directly control any bank, except through a registered bank holding company;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c43d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not control more than 1 registered bank holding company;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c43e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not engage in any business activity, except indirectly through ownership of other business entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c43f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> has no investments other than those permitted for a bank holding company pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/c">section 1843(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c440-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> is not obligated on any debt, either directly or as a guarantor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c441-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> has partners, all of whom are either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c442-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> individuals related to each other by blood, marriage (including former marriage), or adoption; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c443-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> trusts for the primary benefit of individuals related as described in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9c444-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> has filed with the Board a statement that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c445-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the basis for the eligibility of the partnership under subparagraph (F);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c446-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a list of the existing activities and investments of the partnership;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c447-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a commitment to comply with this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c448-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a commitment to comply with section 7 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">12 U.S.C. 1817</ref>] with respect to any acquisition of control of an insured depository institution occurring after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddca9c449-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><chapeau> a commitment to be subject, to the same extent as if the qualified family partnership were a bank holding company—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca9c44a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/v/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> to examination by the Board to assure compliance with this paragraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddca9c44b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/o/10/G/v/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> to section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</ref>].</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9c44c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financial Holding Company</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this chapter, the term “financial holding company” means a bank holding company that meets the requirements of section 1843(<i>l</i>)(1) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9c44d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1841/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Insurance Company</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of sections 1843 and 1844 of this title, the term “insurance company” includes any person engaged in the business of insurance to the extent of such activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddca9c44e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s2">May 9, 1956, ch. 240, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/133">70 Stat. 133</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/485">Pub. L. 89–485</ref>, §§ 1–6, <date date="1966-07-01">July 1, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/236">80 Stat. 236</ref>, 237; <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/tI/s101">Pub. L. 91–607, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1760">84 Stat. 1760</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/188/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 95–188, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1389">91 Stat. 1389</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/369/s8/e">Pub. L. 95–369, § 8(e)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-17">Sept. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/623">92 Stat. 623</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tI/s118/b">Pub. L. 97–320, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, title III, § 333, title IV, § 404(d)(1), <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1479">96 Stat. 1479</ref>, 1504, 1512; <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 100–86, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, (e), title II, § 205(a), <date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/554">101 Stat. 554</ref>, 562, 584; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tVI/s602/a">Pub. L. 101–73, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/409">103 Stat. 409</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/328/tI/s101/c">Pub. L. 103–328, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-29">Sept. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2341">108 Stat. 2341</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 2207, 2208(b), 2304(b), 2610, 2704(d)(17), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-406">110 Stat. 3009–406</ref>, 3009–408, 3009–425, 3009–475, 3009–495; <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tI">Pub. L. 106–102, title I</ref>, §§ 103(c)(1), 107(c), 119, title VII, § 724, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1351">113 Stat. 1351</ref>, 1359, 1373, 1471; <ref href="/us/pl/108/386/s8/c/1">Pub. L. 108–386, § 8(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2231">118 Stat. 2231</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tII/s2102/b">Pub. L. 109–171, title II, § 2102(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/9">120 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s9/h/1">Pub. L. 109–173, § 9(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-15">Feb. 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3618">119 Stat. 3618</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tVII">Pub. L. 109–351, title VII</ref>, §§ 706, 727(a), <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1987">120 Stat. 1987</ref>, 2003; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII/s354/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 354(1)</ref>, title VI, §§ 623(b)(2), 628, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1546">124 Stat. 1546</ref>, 1635, 1640.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddca9c44f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddca9c450-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddca9c451-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (4), (c), and (g) to (p), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240">act May 9, 1956, ch. 240</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/133">70 Stat. 133</ref>, known as the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, which enacted this chapter and sections 1101 to 1103 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code, and enacted provisions set out as notes under this section. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Deposit Insurance Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(5)(F) and (c)(2)(H)(i), is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-21/ch967/s2">act Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/873">64 Stat. 873</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1811 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enactment of the Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970, referred to in subsec. (b), means enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/91/607">Pub. L. 91–607</ref>, on <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>. For classification of <ref href="/us/pl/91/607">Pub. L. 91–607</ref>, see Short Title of 1970 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 25 of the Federal Reserve Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(2)(G), is classified to subchapter I (§ 601 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title. Section 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act, which is classified to subchapter II (§ 611 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title, was renumbered section 25A of that act by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tI/s142/e/2">Pub. L. 102–242, title I, § 142(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2281">105 Stat. 2281</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1727 and 1730a of this title, referred to in subsec. (i)(4), were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 101–73, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/363">103 Stat. 363</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A section 2(h)(2) company, referred to in subsec. (h)(3) to (5), is defined in subsec. (h)(2) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The transfer date, referred to in subsec. (<i>o</i>)(4)(E), probably means the transfer date defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddca9c452-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(2)(F)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s628">Pub. L. 111–203, § 628</ref>, inserted “, other than credit card loans that are made to businesses that meet the criteria for a small business concern to be eligible for business loans under regulations established by the Small Business Administration under part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations” before the period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s354/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 354(1)</ref>, substituted “appropriate Federal banking agency” for “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(4)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s623/b/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 623(b)(2)</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c)(2)(I), (J). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s727/a/1">Pub. L. 109–351, § 727(a)(1)</ref>, struck out subpars. (I) and (J), which related to the Investors Fiduciary Trust Company, located in Kansas City, Missouri, and certain savings banks as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1831/g">section 1831(g) of this title</ref>, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s706">Pub. L. 109–351, § 706</ref>, inserted before period at end “, unless the Board determines that such treatment is not appropriate in light of the facts and circumstances of the case and the purposes of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/173">Pub. L. 109–173</ref> substituted “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Savings Association Insurance Fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/17">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(17)</ref>. See 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s727/a/2">Pub. L. 109–351, § 727(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “(m) [Repealed]” for subsec. (m), which defined “qualified savings bank”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/386">Pub. L. 108–386</ref> struck out heading and text of par. (3). Text read as follows: “The term ‘District bank’ means any bank operating under the Code of Law for the District of Columbia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(5)(E)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s724">Pub. L. 106–102, § 724</ref>, inserted “1 or more” before “thrift institutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s107/c">Pub. L. 106–102, § 107(c)</ref>, inserted “, or that is otherwise permissible for a bank controlled by a company described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/f/1">section 1843(f)(1) of this title</ref>” before period at end of concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s103/c/1/A">Pub. L. 106–102, § 103(c)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “ ‘depository institution’,” after “the terms”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s119">Pub. L. 106–102, § 119</ref>, substituted “section 38” for “section 38(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (p), (q). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s103/c/1/B">Pub. L. 106–102, § 103(c)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsecs. (p) and (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2610/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2610(1)</ref>, inserted “, and shall not include a qualified family partnership” after “by any State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2304/b">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2304(b)</ref>, inserted “, including an institution that accepts collateral for extensions of credit by holding deposits under $100,000, and by other means” after “An institution” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2207">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2207</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “shares transferred after <date date="1966-01-01">January 1, 1966</date>, by any bank holding company (or by any company which, but for such transfer, would be a bank holding company) directly or indirectly to any transferee that is indebted to the transferor, or has one or more officers, directors, trustees, or beneficiaries in common with or subject to control by the transferor, shall be deemed to be indirectly owned or controlled by the transferor unless the Board, after opportunity for hearing, determines that the transferor is not in fact capable of controlling the transferee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/17">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2704(d)(17)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Deposit Insurance Fund” for “Savings Association Insurance Fund”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref>. See Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below and 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2208/b/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2208(b)(1)</ref>, added heading and text of par. (1) and struck out heading and text of former par. (1). Text read as follows: “The term ‘adequately capitalized’ means a level of capitalization which meets or exceeds all applicable Federal regulatory capital standards.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2208/b/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2208(b)(2)</ref>, added pars. (8) and (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2610/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2610(2)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (n), (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/103/328">Pub. L. 103–328</ref> added subsecs. (n) and (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> amended subsec. (j) generally, substituting provisions defining “saving association” or “insured institution” for provisions defining “insured institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(5)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s101/e">Pub. L. 100–86, § 101(e)</ref>, amended subpar. (E) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (E) read as follows: “No company is a bank holding company by virtue of its ownership or control of any State chartered bank or trust company which is wholly owned by thrift institutions and which restricts itself to the acceptance of deposits from thrift institutions, deposits arising out of the corporate business of its owners, and deposits of public moneys.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 100–86, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “ ‘Bank’ means any institution organized under the laws of the United States, any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands, except an institution the accounts of which are insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or an institution chartered by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, which (1) accepts deposits that the depositor has a legal right to withdraw on demand, and (2) engages in the business of making commercial loans. Such term does not include any organization operating under section 25 or section 25 (a) of the Federal Reserve Act, or any organization which does not do business within the United States except as an incident to its activities outside the United States. ‘District bank’ means any bank organized or operating under the Code of Law for the District of Columbia. The term ‘bank’ also includes a State chartered bank or a national banking association which is owned exclusively (except to the extent directors’ qualifying shares are required by law) by other depository institutions or by a bank holding company which is owned exclusively by other depository institutions and is organized to engage exclusively in providing services for other depository institutions and their officers, directors, and employees.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s205/a">Pub. L. 100–86, § 205(a)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The prohibitions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843">section 1843 of this title</ref> shall not apply to shares of any company organized under the laws of a foreign country (or to shares held by such company in any company engaged in the same general line of business as the investor company or in a business related to the business of the investor company) that is principally engaged in business outside the United States if such shares are held or acquired by a bank holding company organized under the laws of a foreign country that is principally engaged in the banking business outside the United States, except that (1) such exempt foreign company (A) may engage in or hold shares of a company engaged in the business of underwriting, selling or distributing securities in the United States only to the extent that a bank holding company may do so under this chapter and under regulations or orders issued by the Board under this chapter, and (B) may engage in the United States in any banking or financial operations or types of activities permitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/c/8">section 1843(c)(8) of this title</ref> or in any order or regulation issued by the Board under such section only with the Board’s prior approval under that section, and (2) no domestic office or subsidiary of a bank holding company or subsidiary thereof holding shares of such company may extend credit to a domestic office or subsidiary of such exempt company on terms more favorable than those afforded similar borrowers in the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s205/a">Pub. L. 100–86, § 205(a)</ref>, added pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 100–86, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (i) read as follows: “The term ‘thrift institution’ means (1) a domestic building and loan or savings and loan association, (2) a cooperative bank without capital stock organized and operated for mutual purposes and without profit, (3) a mutual savings bank not having capital stock represented by shares or (4) a Federal savings bank.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/100/86/s101/a/3">Pub. L. 100–86, § 101(a)(3)</ref>, added subsecs. (j) to (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s404/d/1">Pub. L. 97–320, § 404(d)(1)</ref>, inserted references to State chartered banks and national banking associations as being included in definition of “bank”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s333">Pub. L. 97–320, § 333</ref>, excepted from term “bank” an institution the accounts of which are insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or an institution chartered by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s118/b">Pub. L. 97–320, § 118(b)</ref>, added cl. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/369">Pub. L. 95–369</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided by paragraph (2), the application” for “The application”; struck out a proviso holding the prohibitions of section 1843 not applicable to shares of any company organized under the laws of a foreign country not doing business within the United States, if such shares are held or acquired by a bank holding company principally engaged in banking business outside the United States; and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/188">Pub. L. 95–188</ref> authorized the Board to extend the time for disposition of acquired shares for not more than one year at a time and three years in the aggregate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s101/a">Pub. L. 91–607, § 101(a)</ref>, in revising the provisions, added par. (1) definition of bank holding company; incorporated provisions of former cl. (1) in provisions designated as par. (2)(A), inserting text respecting company acting through one or more other persons, substituting “power to vote” for “holds with power to vote” and provision for voting of any class of voting securities of the bank or company for prior provision for voting of voting shares of each of two or more banks; incorporated former provisions of former cl. (2) in provisions designated as par. (2)(B), providing for election of trustees and substituting bank or company for directors of each of two or more banks designated cl. (A) as par. (5)(A), inserting provision that acquisition of shares shall not be deemed acquisition of shares in a fiduciary capacity if the banks or company has sole discretionary authority to exercise voting rights with respect thereto, and making such limitation applicable to bank or company acquiring the shares prior to <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, where there is right of divestiture of voting rights and there is a failure to exercise that right within reasonable time not exceeding one year after <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>; incorporated former cls. (B) and (C) in provisions designated as pars. (5)(B) and (C); added par. (5)(D) to (F); and designated concluding part of first sentence as par. (6), substituting “from the date on which” for “from the date as of which”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s101/b">Pub. L. 91–607, § 101(b)</ref>, redefined term “company” to include “partnership”, which has been expressly excluded, and inserted definition of “company covered in 1970”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s101/c">Pub. L. 91–607, § 101(c)</ref>, redefined term “bank” to mean any institution organized under Federal, State, District of Columbia, etc., laws, designated existing provisions as cl. (1), added cl. (2), and excepted from exclusion from such term an organization which does business within the United States as an incident to its activities outside the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s101/d">Pub. L. 91–607, § 101(d)</ref>, added cl. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s101/e">Pub. L. 91–607, § 101(e)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s1">Pub. L. 89–485, § 1</ref>, struck out provision placing within the classification of bank holding company any company for the benefit of whose shareholders or members 25 per centum or more of the voting shares of each of two or more banks or a bank holding company is held by trustees, struck out provision exempting from classification as bank holding companies any companies that are registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, and were so registered prior to <date date="1955-05-15">May 15, 1955</date> (or which is affiliated with any such company in such manner as to constitute an affiliated company within the meaning of that Act), unless that company (or affiliated company), as the case may be, directly owns 25 per centum or more of the voting shares of each of two or more banks, struck out provision exempting from classification as bank holding companies any companies having 80 per centum or more of their total assets composed of holdings in the field of agriculture, substituted voting shares for shares in the description of the securities the ownership or control of which, in a fiduciary capacity, would be exempted from causing the formation of a bank holding company, added “company” to “bank” as the business entities eligible for the fiduciary ownership exemption, and inserted reference in the fiduciary ownership exemption to pars. (2) and (3) of subsec. (g) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s2">Pub. L. 89–485, § 2</ref>, exempted from definition of “company” any trust which by its terms must terminate within twenty-five years or not later than twenty-one years and ten months after the death of individuals living on the effective date of the trust, and struck out the exemption formerly granted to nonprofit religious, charitable, and educational organizations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s3">Pub. L. 89–485, § 3</ref>, substituted “any institution that accepts deposits that the depositor has a legal right to withdraw on demand” for “any national banking institution or any state bank, savings bank, or trust company” in the definition of “bank” and extended the exemption for foreign banking corporations to include “agreement” foreign banking corporations under section 25 of the Federal Reserve Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s4">Pub. L. 89–485, § 4</ref>, inserted provision relating to indirect ownership or control and the holding of power to vote to direct ownership or control as the methods by which the holding of 25 per centum or more of voting shares in a company will qualify that company as a subsidiary, and struck out provisions under which any company 25 per centum or more of whose voting shares are held by trustees for the benefit of the shareholders or members of a bank holding company qualifies as a subsidiary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485">Pub. L. 89–485</ref>, §§ 5, 6, substituted provisions setting out treatment to be accorded shares owned or controlled by subsidiaries of bank holding companies, shares held or controlled by trustees for the benefit of companies, shareholders or members of companies, and employees of companies, and shares transferred after <date date="1966-01-01">January 1, 1966</date>, by bank holding companies to transferees that are indebted to the transferor or have one or more officers, directors, trustees, or beneficiaries in common with the transferor for provisions defining “agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s6">Pub. L. 89–485, § 6</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddca9c453-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c454-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s354/1">section 354(1) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s351">section 351 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 623(b)(2) and 628 of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c455-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/173">Pub. L. 109–173</ref> effective <date date="2006-03-31">Mar. 31, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/173/s9/j">section 9(j) of Pub. L. 109–173</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> effective no later than the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the end of the 90-day period beginning <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s2102/c">section 2102(c) of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, set out as a Merger of BIF and SAIF note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c456-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/386">Pub. L. 108–386</ref> effective <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, and, except as otherwise provided, applicable with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year, see sections 8(i) and 9 of <ref href="/us/pl/108/386">Pub. L. 108–386</ref>, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c457-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 103(c)(1), 107(c), and 119 of <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s161">section 161 of Pub. L. 106–102</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c458-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/d/17">section 2704(d)(17) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1999-01-01">Jan. 1, 1999</date>, if no insured depository institution is a savings association on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2704/c">section 2704(c) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821">section 1821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddca9c459-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/328">Pub. L. 103–328</ref> effective at end of 1-year period beginning on <date date="1994-09-29">Sept. 29, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/328/s101/e">section 101(e) of Pub. L. 103–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1828">section 1828 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddca9c45a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3401">Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3401</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1384">102 Stat. 1384</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3401">“This subtitle [subtitle E (§§ 3401, 3402) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843">section 1843 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Export Trading Company Act Amendments of 1988’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddca9c45b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/290/tII/s201">Pub. L. 97–290, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1982-10-08">Oct. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1235">96 Stat. 1235</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/290/tII/s201">“This title [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a–4">section 635a–4 of this title</ref>, amending sections 372 and 1843 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843">section 1843 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Bank Export Services Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddca9c45c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1970 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/607/s1">Pub. L. 91–607, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1760">84 Stat. 1760</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/607/s1">“That this Act [enacting chapter 22 (§ 1971 et seq.) and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1850">section 1850 of this title</ref> and sections 324b and 324c of former Title 31, Money and Finance, amending sections 1841 to 1843 and 1849 of this title and sections 324, 391 of former Title 31, repealing sections 316 and 458 of former Title 31, enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 317e and 391 of former Title 31, and amending provisions set out as a note under section 405a–1 of former Title 31] may be cited as the ‘Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="iddca9c45d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s1">Act May 9, 1956, ch. 240, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/133">70 Stat. 133</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s1">“That this Act [enacting this chapter and sections 1101 to 1103 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code] may be cited as the ‘Bank Holding Company Act of 1956’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="iddca9c45e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s12">Act May 9, 1956, ch. 240, § 12</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/146">70 Stat. 146</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s12">“If any provision of this Act [enacting this chapter and sections 1101 to 1103 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code], or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, shall be held invalid, the remainder of the Act, and the application of such provision to persons or circumstances other than those to which it is held invalid, shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddca9c45f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation abolished and functions transferred, see sections 401 to 406 of <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddca9c460-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transitional Rule for 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/86/tI/s101/h">Pub. L. 100–86, title I, § 101(h)</ref>, <date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/563">101 Stat. 563</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/86/tI/s101/h">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delay in application of amendment to certain institutions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> on <date date="1987-03-05">March 5, 1987</date>, an institution was not a bank (as defined in section 2(c) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841/c">12 U.S.C. 1841(c)</ref>]), as in effect on such date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any person which had a controlling interest in such institution on <date date="1987-03-05">March 5, 1987</date>, made a public announcement before such date that the transfer or other disposition of such person’s controlling interest in such institution was being considered,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the institution shall not become a bank (for purposes of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</ref> et seq.]) due to the amendment made to such section 2(c) by this section before the date on which such institution fails to meet any requirement of paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for application of subsection</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subsection shall not apply with respect to any institution described in paragraph (1) unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the transfer or other disposition of the controlling interest referred to in such paragraph is completed, or an agreement to make such transfer or other disposition is in effect (or is subject only to final approval by the appropriate Federal and State regulatory agencies), before the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this title [<date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a written notice by the person acquiring a controlling interest in such institution (pursuant to the transfer or other disposition described in subparagraph (A)) of such person’s intention to operate such institution as an institution described in section 2(c)(2)(F) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, as in effect after the enactment of this title is filed with the Board before the end of the 7-day period beginning on the later of the date of such transfer (or other disposition) or the date of the enactment of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the operation of such institution as an institution described in such section 2(c)(2)(F) begins before the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the transfer (or other disposition) described in subparagraph (A) is completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Controlling interest</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, a person has a controlling interest in any institution if such person controls—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such institution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any company which controls such institution,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">as determined in accordance with the provisions of subsections (b) and (g) of section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956.”</continuation>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddca9c461-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Moratorium on Certain Nonbanking Activities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/86/tII">Pub. L. 100–86, title II</ref>, §§ 201–203, <date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/581-584">101 Stat. 581–584</ref>, provided for the period of <date date="1987-03-06">Mar. 6, 1987</date>, to <date date="1988-03-01">Mar. 1, 1988</date>, a moratorium on certain nonbanking activities, including expansion of activities of foreign banks and authority of Federal banking agencies to authorize or allow certain security, insurance, or real estate activities.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
