<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb33a55-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1848"><num value="1848">§ 1848.</num><heading> Judicial review</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any party aggrieved by an order of the Board under this chapter may obtain a review of such order in the United States Court of Appeals within any circuit wherein such party has its principal place of business or in the Court of Appeals in the District of Columbia, by filing in the court, within thirty days after the entry of the Board’s order, a petition praying that the order of the Board be set aside. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted to the Board by the clerk of the court, and thereupon the Board shall file in the court the record made before the Board, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>. Upon the filing of such petition the court shall have the jurisdiction to affirm, set aside, or modify the order of the Board and to require the Board to take such action with regard to the matter under review as the court deems proper. The findings of the Board as to the facts, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddcb33a56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-05-09/ch240/s9">May 9, 1956, ch. 240, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/138">70 Stat. 138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/791/s34">Pub. L. 85–791, § 34</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/951">72 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s10">Pub. L. 89–485, § 10</ref>, <date date="1966-07-01">July 1, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/240">80 Stat. 240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb33a57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb33a58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcb33a59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/485">Pub. L. 89–485</ref> reduced from 60 to 30 days the period allowed for the filing of a petition to obtain judicial review of a Board order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/791">Pub. L. 85–791</ref> substituted, in second sentence, “transmitted to the Board by the clerk of the court, and thereupon the Board shall file in the court the record made before the Board, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>” for “served upon the Board, and thereupon the Board shall certify and file in the court a transcript of the record made before the Board”, and in third sentence, “such petition” for “the transcript”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
