<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb5ab87-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864"><num value="1864">§ 1864.</num><heading> Permissible bank service company activities for other persons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab88-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Services permissible other than taking deposits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A bank service company may provide to any person any service authorized by this section, except that a bank service company shall not take deposits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab89-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Services to be performed in State where shareholders or members are located</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as permissible under subsection (c), (d), or (e) or with the prior approval of the Board under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1865/b">section 1865(b) of this title</ref> in accordance with subsection (f) of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5ab8a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a bank service company shall not perform the services authorized by this section in any State other than that State in which its shareholders or members are located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5ab8b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all insured bank shareholders or members of a bank service company shall be located in the same State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab8c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance where State bank or savings association is shareholder or member</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A bank service company in which a State bank or State savings association is a shareholder or member shall perform only those services that such State bank or State savings association shareholder or member is authorized to perform under the law of the State in which such State bank or State savings association operates and shall perform such services only at locations in the State in which such State bank or State savings association shareholder or member could be authorized to perform such services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab8d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance where national bank or Federal savings association is shareholder or member</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A bank service company in which a national bank or Federal savings association is a shareholder or member shall perform only those services that such national bank or Federal savings association shareholder or member is authorized to perform under the law of the United States and shall perform such services only at locations in the State at which such national bank or Federal savings association shareholder or member could be authorized to perform such services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab8e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance where State bank and national bank are shareholders or members</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A bank service company may perform—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5ab8f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> only those services that each depository institution shareholder or member is otherwise authorized to perform under any applicable Federal or State law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5ab90-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such services only at locations in a State in which each such shareholder or member is authorized to perform such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5ab91-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s1864/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographic location</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section or any other provision of law, other than the provisions of Federal and State branching law regulating the geographic location of banks or savings associations to the extent that those laws are applicable to an activity authorized by this subsection, a bank service company may perform at any geographic location any service, other than deposit taking, that the Board has determined, by regulation, to be permissible for a bank holding company under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843/c/8">section 1843(c)(8) of this title</ref> as of the day before <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb5ab92-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/856/s4">Pub. L. 87–856, § 4</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1132">76 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tVII/s709">Pub. L. 97–320, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1542">96 Stat. 1542</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/457/s32/b/2">Pub. L. 97–457, § 32(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2511">96 Stat. 2511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tII/s2613/e">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2613(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-477">110 Stat. 3009–477</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tI/s102/b/2">Pub. L. 106–102, title I, § 102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1342">113 Stat. 1342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tVI/s602/b/3">Pub. L. 109–351, title VI, § 602(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1979">120 Stat. 1979</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb5ab93-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb5ab94-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcb5ab95-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s602/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–351, § 602(b)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “as permissible under subsection (c), (d), or (e) or” after “Except” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s602/b/3/B">Pub. L. 109–351, § 602(b)(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “or State savings association” after “State bank” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s602/b/3/C">Pub. L. 109–351, § 602(b)(3)(C)</ref>, inserted “or Federal savings association” after “national bank” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s602/b/3/D">Pub. L. 109–351, § 602(b)(3)(D)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A bank service company that has both national bank and State bank shareholders or members shall perform only those services that may lawfully be performed by both any shareholder or member of the company which is a national bank under the law of the United States and any shareholder or member of the company which is a State bank under the law of the State in which any such State bank operate and shall perform such services only at locations in the State at which both its State bank and national bank shareholders or members could be authorized to perform such services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s602/b/3/E">Pub. L. 109–351, § 602(b)(3)(E)</ref>, inserted “or savings associations” after “location of banks”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> inserted before period at end “as of the day before <date date="1999-11-12">November 12, 1999</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/5">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(5)</ref>, substituted “company” for “corporation” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “company” for “corporation” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “or members” after “shareholders” wherever appearing in text and substituted “company” for “corporation” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(1)</ref>, (3), inserted “or member” after “shareholder” wherever appearing and substituted “company” for “corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(1)</ref>, (4), substituted “company” for “corporation”, “any shareholder or member of the company which is a national bank” for “its national bank shareholder or shareholders”, “any shareholder or member of the company which is a State bank” for “its State bank shareholder or shareholders”, and “any such State bank” for “such State bank or banks”, and inserted “or members” after “national bank and State bank shareholders” and after “State bank and national bank shareholders”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s2613/e/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 2613(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “company” for “corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/457">Pub. L. 97–457</ref> substituted “under the law of the United States” for “under this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> substituted provisions relating to bank service corporation activities for other persons for provisions which read: “No bank service corporation may engage in any activity other than the performance of bank services for banks.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcb5ab96-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcb5ab97-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s161">section 161 of Pub. L. 106–102</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
