<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcc19275-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2121"><num value="2121">§ 2121.</num><heading> Establishment; titles; branches</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The banks for cooperatives established pursuant to sections 2 and 30 of the Farm Credit Act of 1933, as amended, shall continue as federally chartered instrumentalities of the United States. The Farm Credit Administration shall approve amendments consistent with this chapter to charters and organizational certificates of banks for cooperatives. Unless an existing bank for cooperatives is merged with another bank, there shall be a bank for cooperatives in each farm credit district. A bank for cooperatives may include in its title the name of the city in which it is located or other geographical designation. When authorized by the Farm Credit Administration each bank for cooperatives may establish such branches or other offices as may be appropriate for the effective operation of its business.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddcc19276-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tIII/s3">Pub. L. 92–181, title III, § 3</ref>.0, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/602">85 Stat. 602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tIV/s414/b">Pub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 414(b)</ref>, title VIII, § 802(m), <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1641">101 Stat. 1641</ref>, 1711; <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s406/b">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 406(b)</ref>, title IX, § 901(c), <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1000">102 Stat. 1000</ref>, 1007; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tV/s5411/4">Pub. L. 115–334, title V, § 5411(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4679">132 Stat. 4679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcc19277-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcc19278-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcc19279-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 2 and 30 of the Farm Credit Act of 1933, as amended, referred to in text, were classified to sections 1134 and 1134f, respectively, of this title prior to their repeal by section 5.26 of <ref href="/us/pl/92/181">Pub. L. 92–181</ref>, which enacted this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcc1927a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> struck out “and a Central Bank for Cooperatives” after “each farm credit district” and “The Central Bank for Cooperatives may be located in such place as its board of directors may determine with the approval of the Farm Credit Administration.” after “other geographical designation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s901/c">Pub. L. 100–399, § 901(c)</ref>, substituted “merged with another bank” for “merged with one or more other such banks under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2181">section 2181 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s802/m">Pub. L. 100–233, § 802(m)</ref>, substituted “The Farm Credit Administration shall approve amendments consistent with this chapter to charters and organizational certificates of banks for cooperatives” for “Their charters or organization certificates may be modified from time to time by the Farm Credit Administration, not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, as may be necessary or expedient to implement this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s414/b">Pub. L. 100–233, § 414(b)</ref>, which designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), and added subsec. (b) reading “Each bank for cooperatives shall elect from its voting stockholders a board of directors of such number, for such term, in such manner, and with such qualifications as may be required in its bylaws, except that, at least one member shall be elected by the other directors, which member shall not be a director, officer, employee, or stockholder of a System institution.”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 100–399</ref>. See Construction of 1988 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcc1927b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc1927c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> effective as if enacted immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/100/233">Pub. L. 100–233</ref>, which was approved <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 100–399</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcc1927d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s406/b">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 406(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1000">102 Stat. 1000</ref>, provided that <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s414/b">section 414(b) of Pub. L. 100–233</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, is repealed and that the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/233">Pub. L. 100–233</ref>) and this chapter shall be applied and administered as if such section had not been enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcc1927e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Voluntary Merger of Banks for Cooperatives</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1639">101 Stat. 1639</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1000">102 Stat. 1000</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s405">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of Proposal.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special committee.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>], a special committee shall be selected pursuant to subparagraph (B), for the purpose of developing a proposal for the voluntary merger of the banks for cooperatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The special committee selected under subparagraph (A) shall be composed of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> one member of each district board elected by the voting stockholders of the bank for cooperatives in the district; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> one member chosen from the board of directors of the Central Bank for Cooperatives by the board of such Bank.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 75 days after the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>], the special committee shall develop a plan of merger for all such banks and the Central Bank for Cooperatives into a National Bank for Cooperatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prerequisites to merger.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission to fca</inline>.—</heading><content>On completion of the plan of merger pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), the special committee shall submit the proposed plan, together with all information that is to be distributed to the stockholders concerning such plan, to the Farm Credit Administration for approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited review</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the Farm Credit Administration receives the plan of merger, the Administration shall promptly review such plan and advise the special committee concerning any required changes that are necessary to the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission to stockholders</inline>.—</heading><content>On approval of the plan by the Farm Credit Administration, the special committee shall, under such procedures as may be established by the committee, submit the plan and recommendations to all voting stockholders of the district banks for cooperatives and the Central Bank for Cooperatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Voting Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Majority vote required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An approval of the plan of merger developed and submitted under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> require a majority vote of the stockholders of each district bank for cooperatives voting, in person or by proxy, at a duly authorized stockholders’ meeting, computed both—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> in accordance with the requirement that, except as provided in section 3.3(d) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2124/d">12 U.S.C. 2124(d)</ref>], each cooperative that is the holder of voting stock in the bank for cooperatives shall be entitled to cast one vote; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> on the basis of the total equity interests in the bank (including allocated, but not unallocated, surplus and reserves) held by such stockholders;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> require a majority vote of the voting stockholders of the Central Bank for Cooperatives voting on a one-bank-one-vote basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> take place not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> take place prior to any other merger vote involving a bank for cooperatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approval by all banks for cooperatives</inline>.—</heading><content>If the stockholders of all of the banks for cooperatives approve the merger, the merger shall take place.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of lesser vote</inline>.—</heading><content>If the stockholders of more than one but fewer than all of the banks approve the plan, each such bank whose stockholders voted to approve the merger shall be merged into a single bank for cooperatives, as provided in paragraphs (4) or (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National bank for cooperatives.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Creation</inline>.—</heading><content>If the stockholders of eight or more of the district banks for cooperatives approve the merger, such banks, and the Central Bank for Cooperatives, shall be merged into a single bank, which shall be referred to as the ‘National Bank for Cooperatives’.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Services provided</inline>.—</heading><content>The National Bank for Cooperatives may offer credit and related services to eligible borrowers located within any territory that may be served by Farm Credit System institutions under section 5.0 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2221">12 U.S.C. 2221</ref>], or to any borrower otherwise eligible under section 3.7(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b">12 U.S.C. 2128(b)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United Bank for Cooperatives.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Creation</inline>.—</heading><content>If the stockholders of more than one but fewer than eight of the district banks approve the plan, each such bank, and the Central Bank for Cooperatives (if approved by a numerical majority of its stockholders), shall be merged into a single bank, which shall be referred to as the ‘United Bank for Cooperatives’.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Services provided</inline>.—</heading><content>The United Bank for Cooperatives shall offer credit and related services only in the territory included, as of the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>], within the boundaries of the districts that had been served by the constituent banks of the United Bank for Cooperatives, and to any borrower otherwise eligible under section 3.7(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b">12 U.S.C. 2128(b)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonconsenting banks.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National bank for cooperatives</inline>.—</heading><content>Any of the district banks whose stockholders did not approve the plan of merger may offer credit and related services to any eligible borrowers within any territory or area that may be served by the National Bank.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United bank for cooperatives</inline>.—</heading><content>Any of the district banks whose stockholders did not approve the plan of merger shall continue as district banks for cooperatives and shall continue to serve only the territory within the boundaries of the district that such banks served as of the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nondiscrimination</inline>.—</heading><content>Any district bank whose stockholders did not approve the plan of merger shall be entitled to the availability, from the National Bank for Cooperatives or the United Bank for Cooperatives, as the case may be, of the same credit and related services now provided by the Central Bank for Cooperatives as of the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>], regardless of the decision not to merge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsequent mergers</inline>.—</heading><content>Any district bank referred to in subparagraph (A) may subsequently merge with the National Bank for Cooperatives or the United Bank for Cooperatives, as the case may be, on the approval of the voting stockholders of both banks proposing to merge based on the voting requirement of subsection (b)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">References</inline>.—</heading><content>References in this section to voting stockholders shall include subscribers to the guaranty fund.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcc1927f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Bank for Cooperatives Initial Board of Directors</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tIV/s414/a">Pub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 414(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1641">101 Stat. 1641</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s406/a">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1000">102 Stat. 1000</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s406/a">“Notwithstanding section 3.2 [probably means section 3.2 of <ref href="/us/pl/92/181">Pub. L. 92–181</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2123">12 U.S.C. 2123</ref>], the initial board of each district bank for cooperatives shall be composed of the members of the district board (which is dissolved upon the creation of the district Farm Credit Bank) elected by the stockholders of the bank for cooperatives and one member elected by the other two members, which member shall not be a director, officer, employee, or stockholder of a System institution. The initial board shall operate for such term as is agreed to by the members of the board, except that such period shall not exceed two years. Thereafter, the board shall be elected and serve in accordance with section 3.0 of the Farm Credit Act of 1971 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2121">12 U.S.C. 2121</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
