<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcc402d4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128"><num value="2128">§ 2128.</num><heading> Loans, commitments, and technical and financial assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402d5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The banks for cooperatives are authorized to make loans and commitments to eligible cooperative associations and to extend to them other technical and financial assistance at any time (whether or not they have a loan from the bank outstanding), including but not limited to discounting notes and other obligations, guarantees, currency exchange necessary to service individual transactions that may be financed under subsection (b) of this section, collateral custody, or participation with other banks for cooperatives and commercial banks or other financial institutions in loans to eligible cooperatives, under such terms and conditions as may be determined to be feasible by the board of directors of each bank for cooperatives under regulations of the Farm Credit Administration. Each bank may own and lease, or lease with option to purchase, to stockholders eligible to borrow from the bank equipment needed in the operations of the stockholder and may make or participate in loans or commitments and extend other technical and financial assistance to other domestic parties for the acquisition of equipment and facilities to be leased to such stockholders for use in their operations in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402d6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional authorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402d7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A bank for cooperatives is authorized to make or participate in loans and commitments to, and to extend other technical and financial assistance to a domestic or foreign party with respect to its transactions with an association that is a voting stockholder of the bank for the import of agricultural commodities or products thereof, agricultural supplies, or aquatic products through purchases, sales or exchanges, if the bank for cooperatives determines, under regulations of the Farm Credit Administration, that the voting stockholder will benefit substantially as a result of such loan, commitment, or assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402d8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402d9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A bank for cooperatives may make or participate in loans and commitments to, and extend other technical and financial assistance to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402da-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> any domestic or foreign party for the export, including (where applicable) the cost of freight, of agricultural commodities or products thereof, agricultural supplies, or aquatic products from the United States under policies and procedures established by the bank to ensure that the commodities, products, or supplies are originally sourced, where reasonably available, from one or more eligible cooperative associations described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a">section 2129(a) of this title</ref> on a priority basis, except that if the total amount of the balances outstanding on loans made by a bank under this clause that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402db-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> are made to finance the export of commodities, products, or supplies that are not originally sourced from a cooperative, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402dc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> are not guaranteed or insured, in an amount equal to at least 95 percent of the amount loaned, by a department, agency, bureau, board, commission, or establishment of the United States or a corporation wholly-owned directly or indirectly by the United States,</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">exceeds an amount that is equal to 50 percent of the bank’s capital, then a sufficient interest in the loans shall be sold by the bank for cooperatives to commercial banks and other non-System lenders to reduce the total amount of such outstanding balances to an amount not greater than an amount equal to 50 percent of the bank’s capital; and</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402dd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), any domestic or foreign party in which an eligible cooperative association described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a">section 2129(a) of this title</ref> (including, for the purpose of facilitating its domestic business operations only, a cooperative or other entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1/A">section 2129(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>) has an ownership interest, for the purpose of facilitating the domestic or foreign business operations of the association, except that if the ownership interest by an eligible cooperative association, or associations, is less than 50 percent, the financing shall be limited to the percentage held in the party by the association or associations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402de-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A bank for cooperatives shall not use the authority provided in subparagraph (A)(ii) to provide financial assistance to a party for the purpose of financing the relocation of a plant or facility from the United States to another country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402df-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A bank for cooperatives is authorized to provide such services as may be customary and normal in maintaining relationships with domestic or foreign entities to facilitate the activities specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), consistent with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402e0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of agricultural supply</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term “agricultural supply” includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402e1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a farm supply; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402e2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402e3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> agriculture-related processing equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402e4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> agriculture-related machinery; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402e5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/b/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> other capital goods related to the storage or handling of agricultural commodities or products.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402e6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Loans, commitments, and assistance authorized by subsection (b) of this section shall be extended in accordance with policies adopted by the board of directors of the bank under regulations of the Farm Credit Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402e7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulatory limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The regulations of the Farm Credit Administration implementing subsection (b) of this section and other provisions of this subchapter relating to the authority under subsection (b) of this section may not confer upon the banks for cooperatives powers and authorities greater than those specified in this subchapter. The Farm Credit Administration shall, during the formulation of such regulations, closely consult on a continuing basis with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to insure that such regulations conform to national banking policies, objectives, and limitations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402e8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Speculative futures transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the banks for cooperatives shall not make or participate in loans or commitments for the purpose of financing speculative futures transactions by eligible borrowers in foreign currencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc402e9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Installation, expansion, or improvement of water and waste disposal facilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The banks for cooperatives may, for the purpose of installing, maintaining, expanding, improving, or operating water and waste disposal facilities in rural areas, make and participate in loans and commitments and extending other technical and financial assistance to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> cooperatives formed specifically for the purpose of establishing or operating such facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2128/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> public and quasi-public agencies and bodies, and other public and private entities that, under authority of State or local law, establish or operate such facilities.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this subsection, the term “rural area” means all territory of a State that is not within the outer boundary of any city or town having a population of more than 20,000 based on the latest decennial census of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcc402ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tIII/s3">Pub. L. 92–181, title III, § 3</ref>.7, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/605">85 Stat. 605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/592/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 96–592, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3444">94 Stat. 3444</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXIII/s2323/a">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2323(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4013">104 Stat. 4013</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tV/s502/e/1">Pub. L. 102–237, title V, § 502(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1868">105 Stat. 1868</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/552/tV">Pub. L. 102–552, title V</ref>, §§ 504, 505, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4131">106 Stat. 4131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/376/s3">Pub. L. 103–376, § 3</ref>, <date date="1994-10-19">Oct. 19, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3497">108 Stat. 3497</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tV/s5402">Pub. L. 107–171, title V, § 5402</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/350">116 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tV/s5411/7">Pub. L. 115–334, title V, § 5411(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4679">132 Stat. 4679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcc402ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcc402ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcc402ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> struck out “Such regulations may include provisions for avoiding duplication between the Central Bank and district banks for cooperatives.” before “Each bank may own”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(1), (2)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/s5402/1">Pub. L. 107–171, § 5402(1)</ref>, substituted “agricultural supplies” for “farm supplies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/s5402/2">Pub. L. 107–171, § 5402(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/376/s3/A">Pub. L. 103–376, § 3(A)</ref>, substituted “assistance to” for “assistance to (A)”, “bank for the import” for “bank for the export or import”, and “if the bank for cooperatives” for “and (B) a domestic or foreign party in which such an association has at least the minimum ownership interest approved under regulations of the Farm Credit Administration for the purpose of facilitating the association’s export or import operations of the type described in subparagraph (A): <i>Provided</i>, That a”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/376/s3/B">Pub. L. 103–376, § 3(B)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “A bank for cooperatives is authorized to make or participate in loans and commitments, and to extend other technical and financial assistance, to any domestic or foreign entity that is eligible for a guarantee or insurance as described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) with respect to transactions involving the Soviet Union (its successor entities or any of the individual republics of the Soviet Union) or an emerging democracy (as defined in section 1542(f) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s5622">7 U.S.C. 5622</ref> note)) for the export of agricultural commodities and products thereof from the United States, including (where applicable) the cost of freight, if in each case—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the loan involved is unconditionally guaranteed or insured by a department, agency, bureau, board, commission, or establishment of the United States or any corporation wholly owned directly or indirectly by the United States; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the guarantee or insurance—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) covers at least 95 percent of the amount loaned for the purchase of the commodities or products; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) is issued on or before <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/552/s504">Pub. L. 102–552, § 504</ref>, inserted “at any time (whether or not they have a loan from the bank outstanding)” after “assistance” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/552/s505">Pub. L. 102–552, § 505</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “installing, maintaining, expanding, improving, or operating” for “the installation, expansion, or improvement of” and “extending” for “to extend”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated cl. (1) as (A) and inserted “or products thereof” after “commodities”, redesignated cl. (2) as (B) and substituted “subparagraph (A)” for “clause (1) of this subsection”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/592">Pub. L. 96–592</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted provisions relating to currency exchanges and provisions relating to loans, etc., to domestic parties, and added subsecs. (b) to (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcc402f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcc402f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funding To Be Consistent With Other Laws</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dB/tVII/s757">Pub. L. 118–42, div. B, title VII, § 757</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/114">138 Stat. 114</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/42/dB/tVII/s757">“In this fiscal year and each fiscal year thereafter, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds made available by this or any other Act may be used to implement section 3.7(f) of the Farm Credit Act of 1971 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128/f">12 U.S.C. 2128(f)</ref>] in a manner inconsistent with section 343(a)(13) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1991/a/13">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)(13)</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
