<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcc402f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129"><num value="2129">§ 2129.</num><heading> Eligibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Any association of farmers, producers or harvesters of aquatic products, or any federation of such associations, which is operated on a cooperative basis, and has the powers for processing, preparing for market, handling, or marketing farm or aquatic products; or for purchasing, testing, grading, processing, distributing, or furnishing farm or aquatic supplies or furnishing farm or aquatic business services or services to eligible cooperatives and conforms to either of the two following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> no member of the association is allowed more than one vote because of the amount of stock or membership capital he may own therein; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> does not pay dividends on stock or membership capital in excess of such per centum per annum as may be approved under regulations of the Farm Credit Administration; and in any case</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> does not deal in farm products or aquatic products, or products processed therefrom, farm or aquatic supplies, farm or aquatic business services, or services to eligible cooperatives with or for nonmembers in an amount greater in value than the total amount of such business transacted by it with or for members, excluding from the total of member and nonmember business transactions with the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof or services or supplies furnished as a public utility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a percentage of the voting control of the association not less than 80 per centum (60 per centum (A) in the case of rural electric, telephone, public utility, and service cooperatives; (B) in the case of local farm supply cooperatives that have historically served needs of the community that would not adequately be served by other suppliers and have experienced a reduction in the percentage of farmer membership due to changed circumstances beyond their control such as, but not limited to, urbanization of the community; and (C) in the case of local farm supply cooperatives that provide or will provide needed services to a community and that are or will be in competition with a cooperative specified in paragraph (B)) or, with respect to any type of association or cooperative, such higher percentage as established by the bank board, is held by farmers, producers or harvesters of aquatic products, or eligible cooperative associations as defined herein;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives. Any such association that has received a loan from a bank for cooperatives shall, without regard to the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4), continue to be eligible for so long as more than 50 percent (or such higher percentage as is established by the bank board) of the voting control of the association is held by farmers, producers or harvesters of aquatic products, or eligible cooperative associations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc402f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The following entities shall also be eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Cooperatives and other entities that have received a loan, loan commitment, or loan guarantee from the Rural Electrification Administration (or any successor agency), or that are eligible under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) for a loan, loan commitment, or loan guarantee from the Administration or the Bank (or a successor of the Administration or the Bank), and subsidiaries of such cooperatives or other entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any legal entity that (i) holds more than 50 percent of the voting control of an association or other entity that is eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives under subsection (a) or subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, and (ii) borrows for the purpose of making funds available to that association or entity, and makes funds available to that association or entity under the same terms and conditions that the funds are borrowed from a bank for cooperatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any cooperative or other entity described in subsection (b) or (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128">section 2128 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcc402fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any creditworthy private entity that satisfies the requirements for a service cooperative under paragraphs (1), (2), and (4), or under the last sentence, of subsection (a) and subsidiaries of the entity, if the entity is organized to benefit agriculture in furtherance of the welfare of its farmer-members and is operated on a not-for-profit basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2130">section 2130 of this title</ref>, the board of directors of a bank for cooperatives may determine that, with respect to a loan to any borrower eligible to borrow from a bank under paragraph (1)(A) that is fully guaranteed by the United States, no stock purchase requirement shall apply, other than the requirement that a borrower eligible to own voting stock shall purchase one share of such stock.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc402ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Each association and other entity eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives under this subsection, for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128/a">section 2128(a) of this title</ref>, shall be treated as an eligible cooperative association and a stockholder eligible to borrow from the bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcc40300-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2129/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to adversely affect the eligibility, as it existed on <date date="1988-01-06">January 6, 1988</date>, of cooperatives and other entities for any other credit assistance under Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcc40301-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tIII/s3">Pub. L. 92–181, title III, § 3</ref>.8, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/605">85 Stat. 605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/184/s1/a">Pub. L. 94–184, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1060">89 Stat. 1060</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/592/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 96–592, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3445">94 Stat. 3445</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXIII/s1322">Pub. L. 99–198, title XIII, § 1322</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1534">99 Stat. 1534</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 421</ref>, title VIII, § 805(m), <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1654">101 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1715; <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 410</ref>, title IX, § 901(e), <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1003">102 Stat. 1003</ref>, 1007; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXIII/s2323/b">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2323(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4013">104 Stat. 4013</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tV/s502/e/2">Pub. L. 102–237, title V, § 502(e)(2)</ref>, (f), <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1869">105 Stat. 1869</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/552/tV/s506">Pub. L. 102–552, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4131">106 Stat. 4131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/376/s4">Pub. L. 103–376, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-10-19">Oct. 19, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3498">108 Stat. 3498</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/105/tII">Pub. L. 104–105, title II</ref>, §§ 204, 205, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/172">110 Stat. 172</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tV/s5411/8">Pub. L. 115–334, title V, § 5411(8)</ref>, title VI, § 6602(b)(17), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4680">132 Stat. 4680</ref>, 4777.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcc40302-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcc40303-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcc40304-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rural Electrification Act of 1936, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-05-20/ch432">act May 20, 1936, ch. 432</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1363">49 Stat. 1363</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 31 (§ 901 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">section 901 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcc40305-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s6602/b/17">Pub. L. 115–334, § 6602(b)(17)</ref>, struck out “or a loan or loan commitment from the Rural Telephone Bank,” before “or that are eligible”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s5411/8">Pub. L. 115–334, § 5411(8)</ref>, inserted “(or any successor agency)” after “Rural Electrification Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/105/s204/a">Pub. L. 104–105, § 204(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Any such association that has received a loan from a bank for cooperatives shall, without regard to the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4), continue to be eligible for so long as more than 50 percent (or such higher percentage as is established by the bank board) of the voting control of the association is held by farmers, producers or harvesters of aquatic products, or eligible cooperative associations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/105/s205">Pub. L. 104–105, § 205</ref>, substituted “are eligible under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) for” for “have been certified by the Administrator of the Rural Electrification Administration to be eligible for such” and “loan guarantee from the Administration or the Bank (or a successor of the Administration or the Bank), and” for “loan guarantee, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/104/105/s204/b">Pub. L. 104–105, § 204(b)</ref>, substituted “and (4), or under the last sentence, of subsection (a)” for “and (4) of subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1)(B) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/103/376">Pub. L. 103–376</ref> redesignated subpars. (C) to (E) as (B) to (D), respectively, realigned margin of subpar. (D), and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “Any legal entity more than 50 percent of the voting control of which is held by one or more associations or other entities that are eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives under subsection (a) of this section or subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, except that any such legal entity, when considered together with one or more such associations or other entities that hold such control, meet the requirement of subsection (a)(3) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/102/552">Pub. L. 102–552</ref> added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s502/f/1">Pub. L. 102–237, § 502(f)(1)</ref>, substituted “a percentage” for “A percentage”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s502/e/2">Pub. L. 102–237, § 502(e)(2)</ref>, (f)(2), substituted “subsection (b) or (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128">section 2128 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2128/f">section 2128(f) of this title</ref>” and realigned margin of subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref> added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s901/e">Pub. L. 100–399, § 901(e)</ref>, substituted “bank board” for “district board” in subsec. (a)(4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s410">Pub. L. 100–399, § 410</ref>, substituted “makes” for “make” in subsec. (b)(1)(C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s805/m">Pub. L. 100–233, § 805(m)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (1) as subsec. (a) and pars. (a) to (d) as pars. (1) to (4), respectively, in par. (4) redesignated cls. (1) to (3) as (A) to (C), respectively, and in cl. (C) substituted “paragraph (B)” for “paragraph (2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s421">Pub. L. 100–233, § 421</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (2) which read as follows: “Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, cooperatives and other entities that have received a loan, loan commitment, or loan guarantee from the Rural Electrification Administration, or a loan or loan commitment from the Rural Telephone Bank, or that have been certified by the Administrator of the Rural Electrification Administration to be eligible for such a loan, loan commitment, or loan guarantee, and subsidiaries of such cooperatives or other entities, shall also be eligible to borrow from a bank for cooperatives.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1322/1">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1322(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (1) and added subsec. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/592/s305/1">Pub. L. 96–592, § 305(1)</ref>, inserted reference to aquatic business in introductory text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/592/s305/2">Pub. L. 96–592, § 305(2)</ref>, inserted reference to aquatic business services or services to eligible cooperatives.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/592/s305/3">Pub. L. 96–592, § 305(3)</ref>, substituted “60” for “70”, and designated former parenthetical material as item (1), and added items (2) and (3) and limitation with respect to any type of association or cooperative.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/184">Pub. L. 94–184</ref> inserted provision relating to 70 per centum of voting control in the case of rural electric, telephone, and public utility cooperatives.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcc40306-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc40307-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s502/f">section 502(f) of Pub. L. 102–237</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, to which the amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s1101/b/4">section 1101(b)(4) of Pub. L. 102–237</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc40308-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> effective as if enacted immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/100/233">Pub. L. 100–233</ref>, which was approved <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 100–399</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
