<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcc64cb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155"><num value="2155">§ 2155.</num><heading> Liability of banks; United States not liable</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc64cb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability of banks</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each bank of the System shall be fully liable on notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations issued by it individually, and shall be liable for the interest payments on long-term notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations issued by other banks operating under the same subchapter of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cbb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cbc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each bank shall also be primarily liable for the portion of any issue of consolidated or System-wide obligations made on its behalf and be jointly and severally liable for the payment of any additional sums as called upon by the Farm Credit Administration in order to make payments of interest or principal which any bank primarily liable therefor shall be unable to make.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cbd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such calls first shall be made on all nondefaulting banks in proportion to each such bank’s proportionate share of the aggregate available collateral held by all such banks.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cbe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “available collateral” means the amount (determined at the close of the last calendar quarter ending before such call) by which a bank’s collateral as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2154">section 2154 of this title</ref> exceeds the collateral required to support the bank’s outstanding notes, bonds, debentures, and other similar obligations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cbf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> If the Farm Credit Administration makes any such call and the available collateral of all such banks does not fully satisfy the liability necessitating such calls, such calls shall be made on all nondefaulting banks in proportion to each such bank’s remaining assets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cc0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Any System bank that, pursuant to a call by the Farm Credit Administration, makes a payment of principal or interest to the holder of any consolidated or System-wide obligation issued on behalf of another System bank shall be subrogated to all rights of the holder against such other bank to the extent of such payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcc64cc1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> On making such a call with respect to obligations issued on behalf of a System bank, the Farm Credit Administration shall appoint a receiver for the bank, which shall expeditiously liquidate or otherwise wind up the affairs of the bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc64cc2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Resolutions as to liability; execution of obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each bank participating in an issue shall by appropriate resolution undertake such responsibility as provided in subsection (a), and in the case of consolidated or System-wide obligations shall authorize the execution of such long-term notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations on its behalf. When a consolidated or System-wide issue is approved, the notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations shall be executed and the banks shall be liable thereon as provided herein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc64cc3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> United States liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States shall not be liable or assume any liability directly or indirectly thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc64cc4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2155/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance Fund called on before invoking joint and several liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning 5 years after <date date="1988-01-06">January 6, 1988</date>, the Farm Credit Administration shall not call on any System institution to satisfy the liability of the institution on any joint, consolidated, or System-wide obligation participated in by the institution or with respect to which the institution is primarily, or jointly and severally, liable, before the Farm Credit Insurance Fund is exhausted, even if the Fund is only able to make a partial payment because of insufficient amounts in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcc64cc5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tIV/s4">Pub. L. 92–181, title IV, § 4</ref>.4, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/611">85 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/tI/s101/4">Pub. L. 99–205, title I, § 101(4)</ref>, title II, § 205(f)(2), <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1679">99 Stat. 1679</ref>, 1706; <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tII/s207/c">Pub. L. 100–233, title II, § 207(c)</ref>, title III, § 303, <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1608">101 Stat. 1608</ref>, 1620; <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 100–399, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/995">102 Stat. 995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcc64cc6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcc64cc7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcc64cc8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s303/a">Pub. L. 100–233, § 303(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “Each bank of the System shall be fully liable on notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations issued by it individually, and shall be liable for the interest payments on long-term notes, bonds, debentures, or other obligations issued by other banks operating under the same subchapter of this chapter. Each bank shall also be primarily liable for the portion of any issue of consolidated or System-wide obligations made on its behalf and be jointly and severally liable for the payment of any additional sums as called upon by the Farm Credit Administration in order to make payments of interest or principal which any bank primarily liable therefor shall be unable to make. Such calls shall be made first upon the other banks operating under the same subchapter of this chapter as the defaulting bank, and second upon banks operating under other subchapters of this chapter, taking into consideration the capital, surplus, bonds, debentures, or other obligations which each may have outstanding at the time of such assessment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s207/c">Pub. L. 100–233, § 207(c)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c), and struck out former subsec. (c) which provided that for purposes of this part, the term “bank” included the Capital Corporation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s207/c">Pub. L. 100–233, § 207(c)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s303/b">Pub. L. 100–233, § 303(b)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s205/f/2">Pub. L. 99–205, § 205(f)(2)</ref>, substituted “execution of” for “Governor to execute” in first sentence and struck out “by the Governor” after “shall be executed” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s101/4">Pub. L. 99–205, § 101(4)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcc64cc9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc64cca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> effective as if enacted immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/100/233">Pub. L. 100–233</ref>, which was approved <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 100–399</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc64ccb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/205">Pub. L. 99–205</ref> effective thirty days after <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 99–205</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
