<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcc8be22-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2183"><num value="2183">§ 2183.</num><heading> Dissolution; voluntary or involuntary liquidation; mergers; receiverships or conservators</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc8be23-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2183/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Voluntary liquidation; consent of Farm Credit Administration; rules and regulations; minimization of adverse effect; voluntary merger; mandatory merger on failure to comply or meet obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No institution of the System shall go into voluntary liquidation without the consent of the Farm Credit Administration and with such consent may liquidate only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Farm Credit Administration. In the case of a voluntary liquidation of an association, such regulations, among other things, shall direct the supervising bank to institute such measures as it deems appropriate to minimize the adverse effect of the liquidation on those borrowers whose loans are purchased by or otherwise transferred to another System institution. The Farm Credit Administration Board may require an association to merge with another association whenever it determines, with the concurrence of the board of the supervising bank, that an association has failed to meet its outstanding obligations or failed to conduct its operations in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc8be24-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2183/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of conservator or receiver; grounds; action for removal; stay of actions or proceedings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Farm Credit Administration Board may appoint a conservator or receiver for any System institution on the determination by the Farm Credit Administration Board that one or more of the following exists, or is occurring, with respect to the institution: (1) insolvency, in that the assets of the institution are less than its obligations to its creditors and others, including its members; (2) substantial dissipation of assets or earnings due to any violation of law, rules, or regulations, or to any unsafe or unsound practice; (3) an unsafe or unsound condition to transact business; (4) willful violation of a cease and desist order that has become final; (5) concealment of books, papers, records, or assets of the institution or refusal to submit books, papers, records, or other material relating to the affairs of the institution for inspection to any examiner or to any lawful agent of the Farm Credit Administration; (6) the institution is unable to timely pay principal or interest on any insured obligation (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2277a/3">section 2277a(3) of this title</ref>) issued by the institution. The Farm Credit Administration Board shall have exclusive power and jurisdiction to appoint a conservator or receiver, and such receiver or conservator, after the 5-year period beginning on <date date="1988-01-06">January 6, 1988</date>, shall be the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation. If the Farm Credit Administration Board determines that a ground for the appointment of a conservator or receiver as herein provided exists, the Farm Credit Administration Board may appoint ex parte and without notice a conservator or receiver for the institution. In the event of such appointment, the institution, within thirty days thereafter, may bring an action in the United States district court for the judicial district in which the home office of such institution is located, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for an order requiring the Farm Credit Administration Board to remove such conservator or receiver, and the court shall on the merits, dismiss such action or direct the Farm Credit Administration Board to remove such conservator or receiver. On the commencement of such an action, the court having jurisdiction of any other action or enforcement proceeding authorized under this chapter to which the institution is a party shall stay such action or proceeding during the pendency of the action for removal of the conservator or receiver.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcc8be25-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2183/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Involuntary liquidation; rules and regulations; minimization of adverse effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of an involuntary liquidation of an association, regulations of the Farm Credit Administration, among other things, shall direct the supervising bank to institute such measures as it deems appropriate to minimize the adverse effect of the liquidation on those borrowers whose loans are purchased by or otherwise transferred to another System institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcc8be26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tIV/s4">Pub. L. 92–181, title IV, § 4</ref>.12, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/612">85 Stat. 612</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/tI/s102">Pub. L. 99–205, title I, § 102</ref>, title II, § 205(f)(5), title III, § 305, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1679">99 Stat. 1679</ref>, 1706, 1708; <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 100–233, title III, § 306</ref>, title IV, § 418(a)(4), formerly § 415(a)(4), § 431(g), title VIII, § 805(r), <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1622">101 Stat. 1622</ref>, 1653, 1660, 1716, renumbered § 418(a)(4), <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIV/s409/a">Pub. L. 100–399, title IV, § 409(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1003">102 Stat. 1003</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/tIX/s901/f">Pub. L. 100–399, title IX, § 901(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-17">Aug. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1007">102 Stat. 1007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcc8be27-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcc8be28-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcc8be29-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s901/f">Pub. L. 100–399, § 901(f)</ref>, substituted “board of the supervising bank” for “district board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s415/a/4">Pub. L. 100–233, § 415(a)(4)</ref>, struck out third sentence which provided that Associations may voluntarily merge with other like associations upon the vote of a majority of each of their stockholders present and voting or voting by written proxy at duly authorized meetings, and with the approval of the supervising bank and the Farm Credit Administration, and substituted “Board may require an association to merge with another association” for “may require such merger” in fourth sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s431/g">Pub. L. 100–233, § 431(g)</ref>, substituted “Farm Credit Administration Board” for “Farm Credit Administration” wherever appearing other than in cl. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s306">Pub. L. 100–233, § 306</ref>, added cl. (6) and inserted “, and such receiver or conservator, after the 5-year period beginning on <date date="1988-01-06">January 6, 1988</date>, shall be the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation” before the period at end of second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s805/r">Pub. L. 100–233, § 805(r)</ref>, substituted “court shall” for “court, shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s205/f/5">Pub. L. 99–205, § 205(f)(5)</ref>, substituted “Farm Credit Administration” for “Federal Farm Credit Board” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s305/a">Pub. L. 99–205, § 305(a)</ref>, inserted after first sentence a sentence requiring the regulations, in the case of a voluntary liquidation of an association, to direct the supervising bank to institute appropriate measures to minimize the adverse effect of the liquidation on borrowers whose loans are purchased by or otherwise transferred to another System institution.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s102">Pub. L. 99–205, § 102</ref>, in revising subsec. (b), substituted expanded provisions respecting appointment of conservator or receiver for former provision, which read as follows: “Upon default of any obligation by any institution of the System, such institution may be declared insolvent and placed in the hands of a conservator or a receiver appointed by the Governor and the proceedings thereon shall be in accordance with regulations of the Farm Credit Administration regarding such insolvencies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s305/b">Pub. L. 99–205, § 305(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcc8be2a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc8be2b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/399">Pub. L. 100–399</ref> effective as if enacted immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/100/233">Pub. L. 100–233</ref>, which was approved <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/399/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 100–399</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcc8be2c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/205">Pub. L. 99–205</ref> effective thirty days after <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 99–205</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
