<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb24f86a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s222"><num value="222">§ 222.</num><heading> Federal reserve districts; membership of national banks</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The continental United States, excluding Alaska, shall be divided into not less than eight nor more than twelve districts. Such districts may be readjusted and new districts may from time to time be created by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, not to exceed twelve in all: <i>Provided</i>, That the districts shall be apportioned with due regard to the convenience and customary course of business and shall not necessarily be coterminous with any State or States. Such districts shall be known as Federal reserve districts and may be designated by number. When the State of Alaska or Hawaii is hereafter admitted to the Union the Federal Reserve <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002030"><num>1</num> Capitalized as in original.</note> districts shall be readjusted by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System in such manner as to include such State. Every national bank in any State shall, upon commencing business or within ninety days after admission into the Union of the State in which it is located, become a member bank of the Federal Reserve System by subscribing and paying for stock in the Federal Reserve bank of its district in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and shall thereupon be an insured bank under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.], and failure to do so shall subject such bank to the penalty provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s501a">section 501a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb24f86b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s2">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 2</ref> (part), <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s19">Pub. L. 85–508, § 19</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/350">72 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/3/s17">Pub. L. 86–3, § 17</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/12">73 Stat. 12</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb24f86c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb24f86d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb24f86e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Deposit Insurance Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-21/ch967/s2">act Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/873">64 Stat. 873</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1811 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb24f86f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on part of the first par. of section 2 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. Some of the other provisions of the first par. are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s223">section 223 of this title</ref>, and some were not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The second par. of section 2 is classified in part to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s225">section 225 of this title</ref>. The rest of the second par. was not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The third par. of section 2 is classified in part to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s282">section 282 of this title</ref>. The rest of the third par. was not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The fourth par. of section 2 is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s502">section 502 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The sixth and seventh pars. of section 2 are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s501a">section 501a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The ninth par. of section 2 is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s283">section 283 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The tenth par. of section 2 was classified in part to former <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s284">section 284 of this title</ref>. The rest of the tenth par. was not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The eleventh and twelfth pars. of section 2 are classified to sections 285 and 286, respectively, of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The thirteenth par. of section 2 is classified in part to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s224">section 224 of this title</ref> and in part to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>. The rest of the thirteenth par. was not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The fifth and eighth pars. of section 2 were not included in the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Former <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s141">section 141 of this title</ref> purportedly derived from part of section 2 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. But see Codification note set out under former <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb24f870-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref> required readjustment of districts when the State of Hawaii is admitted to the Union.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref> required readjustment of districts when the State of Alaska is admitted to the Union, and inserted provisions requiring national banks to become members of the Federal Reserve System upon commencing business or within 90 Days after admission into the Union of the State in which they are located.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb24f871-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb24f872-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb24f873-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb24f874-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Admission of Alaska and Hawaii to Statehood</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Alaska was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3269, <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 81, 73 Stat. C16, and Hawaii was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3309, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 6868, 73 Stat. C74. For Alaska Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. For Hawaii Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/4">73 Stat. 4</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s491">section 491 of Title 48</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
