<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddccfe9f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2262"><num value="2262">§ 2262.</num><heading> Temporary cease and desist orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccfe9f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2262/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Whenever the Farm Credit Administration shall determine that the violation or threatened violation or the unsafe or unsound practice or practices, specified in the notice of charges served upon the institution or any director, officer, employee, agent, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs of such institution under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2261">section 2261 of this title</ref>, or the continuation thereof, is likely to cause insolvency or substantial dissipation of assets or earnings of the institution, or is likely to seriously weaken the condition of the institution or otherwise seriously prejudice the interests of the investors in Farm Credit System obligations or shareholders in the institution prior to the completion of the proceedings conducted under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2261">section 2261 of this title</ref>, the Farm Credit Administration may issue a temporary order requiring the institution or such director, officer, employee, agent, or other person to cease and desist from any such violation or practice and to take affirmative action to prevent such insolvency, dissipation, condition, or prejudice pending completion of such proceedings. Such order shall become effective upon service upon the institution or such director, officer, employee, agent, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs of such institution and, unless set aside, limited, or suspended by a court in proceedings authorized by subsection (b), shall remain effective and enforceable pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to such notice and until such time as the Farm Credit Administration shall dismiss the charges specified in such notice, or if a cease and desist order is issued against the institution or such director, officer, employee, agent, or other person, until effective date of such order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccfe9f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2262/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Within ten days after the institution concerned or any director, officer, employee, agent, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs of such institution has been served with a temporary cease and desist order, the institution or such director, officer, employee, agent, or other person may apply to the United States district court for the judicial district in which the home office of the institution is located, or the United States district court for the District of Columbia, for an injunction setting aside, limiting, or suspending the enforcement, operation, or effectiveness of such order pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to the notice of charges served upon the institution or such director, officer, employee, agent, or other person under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2261">section 2261 of this title</ref>, and such court shall have jurisdiction to issue such injunction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddccfe9f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/181/tV/s5">Pub. L. 92–181, title V, § 5</ref>.26, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/tII/s204">Pub. L. 99–205, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1695">99 Stat. 1695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddccfe9f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddccfe9f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddccfe9f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5.26 of <ref href="/us/pl/92/181">Pub. L. 92–181</ref> was renumbered section 5.40 and is set out in part as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddccfe9f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddccfe9fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective thirty days after <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/205/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 99–205</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1985 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
