<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddceee2da-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2285"><num value="2285">§ 2285.</num><heading> Functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee2db-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2285/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase and sale of obligations issued, sold, or guaranteed by Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank is authorized to make commitments to purchase and sell, and to purchase and sell on terms and conditions determined by the Bank, any obligation which is issued, sold, or guaranteed by a Federal agency. Any Federal agency which is authorized to issue, sell, or guarantee any obligation is authorized to issue or sell such obligations directly to the Bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee2dc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2285/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Yield</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any purchase by the Bank shall be upon such terms and conditions as to yield a return at a rate not less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration (1) the current average yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturity, or (2) whenever the Bank’s own obligations outstanding are sufficient, the current average yield on outstanding obligations of the Bank of comparable maturity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee2dd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2285/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank is authorized to charge fees for its commitments and other services adequate to cover all expenses and to provide for the accumulation of reasonable contingency reserves.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddceee2de-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/224/s6">Pub. L. 93–224, § 6</ref>, <date date="1973-12-29">Dec. 29, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/938">87 Stat. 938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
