<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddceee2fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289"><num value="2289">§ 2289.</num><heading> General powers</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank shall have power—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee2fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to sue and be sued, complain, and defend, in its corporate name;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee2fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee2ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations as may be necessary for the conduct of its business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee300-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to conduct its business, carry on its operations, and have offices and exercise the powers granted by this chapter in any State without regard to any qualification or similar statute in any State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee301-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to lease, purchase, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, improve, use, or otherwise deal in and with any property, real, personal, or mixed, or any interest therein, wherever situated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee302-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to accept gifts or donations of services, or of property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, in aid of any of the purposes of the Bank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee303-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, and otherwise dispose of its property and assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee304-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> to appoint such officers, attorneys, employees, and agents as may be required, to define their duties, to fix and to pay such compensation for their services as may be determined, subject to the civil service and classification laws, to require bonds for them and pay the premium thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee305-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> to enter into contracts, to execute instruments to incur liabilities, and to do all things as are necessary or incidental to the proper management of its affairs and the proper conduct of its business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee306-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> to act through any corporate or other agency or instrumentality of the United States, and to utilize the services thereof on a reimbursable basis, and any such agency or instrumentality is authorized to provide services as requested by the Bank; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee307-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2289/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> to determine the character of and the necessity for its obligations and expenditures, and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, and paid, subject to provisions of law specifically applicable to Government corporations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddceee308-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/224/s10">Pub. L. 93–224, § 10</ref>, <date date="1973-12-29">Dec. 29, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/940">87 Stat. 940</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
