<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddceee341-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403"><num value="2403">§ 2403.</num><heading> Functions of Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee342-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study, investigation, and recommendations; considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall conduct a thorough study and investigation and recommend appropriate administrative action and legislation necessary in connection with the possible development of public or private electronic fund transfer systems, taking into account, among other things—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee343-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the need to preserve competition among the financial institutions and other business enterprises using such a system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee344-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the need to promote competition among financial institutions and to assure Government regulation and involvement or participation in a system competitive with the private sector be kept to a minimum;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee345-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the need to prevent unfair or discriminatory practices by any financial institution or business enterprise using or desiring to use such a system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee346-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the need to afford maximum user and consumer convenience;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee347-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the need to afford maximum user and consumer rights to privacy and confidentiality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee348-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the impact of such a system on economic and monetary policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee349-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the implications of such a system on the availability of credit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee34a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the implications of such a system expanding internationally and into other forms of electronic communications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddceee34b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the need to protect the legal rights of users and consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee34c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim and final reports; submission dates; transmittal of final report to President and Congress; contents; availability to public; termination date of Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall make an interim report within one year of the date of the confirmation by the Senate of the Chairperson or the appointment by the President of an acting Chairperson and at such other times as it deems advisable and shall transmit to the President and to the Congress not later than two years after the date of the confirmation by the Senate of the Chairperson or the appointment by the President of an acting Chairperson, a final report of its findings and recommendations. Any such report shall include all hearing transcripts, staff studies, and other material used in preparation of the report. The interim and final reports shall be made available to the public upon transmittal. Sixty days after transmission of its final report the Commission shall cease to exist.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddceee34d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2403/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Clearance by Federal agencies prior to transmittal of interim or final report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall not be required to obtain the clearance of any Federal agency prior to the transmittal of any interim or final report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddceee34e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tII/s203">Pub. L. 93–495, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1508">88 Stat. 1508</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/200/tII/s201">Pub. L. 94–200, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1124">89 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddceee34f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddceee350-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddceee351-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/200">Pub. L. 94–200</ref> changed the time for submission of interim and final reports from one year of the Commission’s findings and recommendations and two years after <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, to one year and two years respectively after the confirmation by the Senate of the Chairperson or the appointment by the President of an acting Chairperson.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
