<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb24f8d2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s242"><num value="242">§ 242.</num><heading> Ineligibility to hold office in member banks; qualifications and terms of office of members; chairman and vice chairman; oath of office</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The members of the Board shall be ineligible during the time they are in office and for two years thereafter to hold any office, position, or employment in any member bank, except that this restriction shall not apply to a member who has served the full term for which he was appointed. Upon the expiration of the term of any appointive member of the Federal Reserve Board in office on <date date="1935-08-23">August 23, 1935</date>, the President shall fix the term of the successor to such member at not to exceed fourteen years, as designated by the President at the time of nomination, but in such manner as to provide for the expiration of the term of not more than one member in any two-year period, and thereafter each member shall hold office for a term of fourteen years from the expiration of the term of his predecessor, unless sooner removed for cause by the President. Of the persons thus appointed, 1 shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Chairman of the Board for a term of 4 years, and 2 shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Vice Chairmen of the Board, each for a term of 4 years, 1 of whom shall serve in the absence of the Chairman, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s244">section 244 of this title</ref>, and 1 of whom shall be designated Vice Chairman for Supervision. The Vice Chairman for Supervision shall develop policy recommendations for the Board regarding supervision and regulation of depository institution holding companies and other financial firms supervised by the Board, and shall oversee the supervision and regulation of such firms. The Chairman of the Board, subject to its supervision, shall be its active executive officer. Each member of the Board shall within fifteen days after notice of appointment make and subscribe to the oath of office. Upon the expiration of their terms of office, members of the Board shall continue to serve until their successors are appointed and have qualified. Any person appointed as a member of the Board after <date date="1935-08-23">August 23, 1935</date>, shall not be eligible for reappointment as such member after he shall have served a full term of fourteen years.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb2769d3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s10">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 10</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/260">38 Stat. 260</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1922-06-03/ch205">June 3, 1922, ch. 205</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/620">42 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s6/a">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 6(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/166">48 Stat. 166</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(b), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/188/tII/s204/a">Pub. L. 95–188, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1388">91 Stat. 1388</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1108/a/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title XI, § 1108(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2126">124 Stat. 2126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb2769d4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb2769d5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb2769d6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of second par. of section 10 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. For classification to this title of other pars. of section 10, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s241">section 241 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb2769d7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> substituted “Of the persons thus appointed, 1 shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Chairman of the Board for a term of 4 years, and 2 shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Vice Chairmen of the Board, each for a term of 4 years, 1 of whom shall serve in the absence of the Chairman, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s244">section 244 of this title</ref>, and 1 of whom shall be designated Vice Chairman for Supervision. The Vice Chairman for Supervision shall develop policy recommendations for the Board regarding supervision and regulation of depository institution holding companies and other financial firms supervised by the Board, and shall oversee the supervision and regulation of such firms.” for “Of the persons thus appointed, one shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Chairman of the Board for a term of four years, and one shall be designated by the President, by and with the consent of the Senate, to serve as Vice Chairman of the Board for a term of four years.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/188">Pub. L. 95–188</ref> substituted in third sentence “one shall be designated by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Chairman of the Board for a term of four years, and one shall be designated by the President, by and with the consent of the Senate, to serve as Vice Chairman of the Board for a term of four years” for “one shall be designated by the President as chairman and one as vice chairman of the Board, to serve as such for a term of four years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, § 203(b), extended term of appointive members from twelve to fourteen years, and inserted provisions for continuance in office until successor qualified and against reappointment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1933—Act <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date>, extended term of appointive members from ten to twelve years.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb2769d8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb2769d9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb2769da-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1108/a/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title XI, § 1108(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2126">124 Stat. 2126</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1108/a/2">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] takes effect on the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>] and applies to individuals who are designated by the President on or after that date to serve as Vice Chairman of Supervision.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb2769db-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment; Applicability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/188/tII/s204/b">Pub. L. 95–188, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1388">91 Stat. 1388</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/188/tII/s204/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] takes effect on <date date="1979-01-01">January 1, 1979</date>, and applies to individuals who are designated by the President on or after such date to serve as Chairman or Vice Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="iddb2769dc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1919-03-03/ch101/s2">Act Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 101, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1315">40 Stat. 1315</ref>, formerly cited as a credit to this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/644">80 Stat. 644</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb2769dd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compensation of Chairman of Board</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Annual basic compensation of Chairman of Board of Governors, see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
