<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb276a09-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s247a"><num value="247a">§ 247a.</num><heading> Records of action on policy relating to open-market operation and policies determined generally; inclusion in report to Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall keep a complete record of the action taken by the Board and by the Federal Open Market Committee upon all questions of policy relating to open-market operations and shall record therein the votes taken in connection with the determination of open-market policies and the reasons underlying the action of the Board and the Committee in each instance. The Board shall keep a similar record with respect to all questions of policy determined by the Board, and shall include in its annual report to the Congress a full account of the action so taken during the preceding year with respect to open-market policies and operations and with respect to the policies determined by it and shall include in such report a copy of the records required to be kept under the provisions of this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb276a0a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s10">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 10</ref> (par.), as added <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(d), <ref href="/us/stat/49/705">49 Stat. 705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb276a0b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb276a0c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb276a0d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of tenth par. of section 10 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, as added <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>. For classification to this title of other pars. of section 10, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s241">section 241 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
