<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb276a15-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248"><num value="248">§ 248.</num><heading> Enumerated powers</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be authorized and empowered:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a16-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Examination of accounts and affairs of banks; publication of weekly statements; reports of liabilities and assets of depository institutions; covered institutions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a17-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To examine at its discretion the accounts, books, and affairs of each Federal reserve bank and of each member bank and to require such statements and reports as it may deem necessary. The said board shall publish once each week a statement showing the condition of each Federal reserve bank and a consolidated statement for all Federal reserve banks. Such statements shall show in detail the assets and liabilities of the Federal reserve banks, single and combined, and shall furnish full information regarding the character of the money held as reserve and the amount, nature, and maturities of the paper and other investments owned or held by Federal reserve banks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a18-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To require any depository institution specified in this paragraph to make, at such intervals as the Board may prescribe, such reports of its liabilities and assets as the Board may determine to be necessary or desirable to enable the Board to discharge its responsibility to monitor and control monetary and credit aggregates. Such reports shall be made (A) directly to the Board in the case of member banks and in the case of other depository institutions whose reserve requirements under sections 461, 463, 464, 465, and 466 of this title exceed zero, and (B) for all other reports to the Board through the (i) Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation in the case of insured State savings associations that are insured depository institutions (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of this title</ref>), State nonmember banks, savings banks, and mutual savings banks, (ii) National Credit Union Administration Board in the case of insured credit unions, (iii) the Comptroller of the Currency in the case of any Federal savings association which is an insured depository institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of this title</ref>) or which is a member as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1422">section 1422 of this title</ref>, and (iv) such State officer or agency as the Board may designate in the case of any other type of bank, savings association, or credit union. The Board shall endeavor to avoid the imposition of unnecessary burdens on reporting institutions and the duplication of other reporting requirements. Except as otherwise required by law, any data provided to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States pursuant to other reporting requirements shall be made available to the Board. The Board may classify depository institutions for the purposes of this paragraph and may impose different requirements on each such class.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a19-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Permitting or requiring rediscounting of paper at specified rate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To permit, or, on the affirmative vote of at least five members of the Board of Governors, to require Federal reserve banks to rediscount the discounted paper of other Federal reserve banks at rates of interest to be fixed by the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspending reserve requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To suspend for a period not exceeding thirty days, and from time to time to renew such suspension for periods not exceeding fifteen days, any reserve requirements specified in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Supervising and regulating issue and retirement of notes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To supervise and regulate through the Secretary of the Treasury the issue and retirement of Federal Reserve notes, except for the cancellation and destruction, and accounting with respect to such cancellation and destruction, of notes unfit for circulation, and to prescribe rules and regulations under which such notes may be delivered by the Secretary of the Treasury to the Federal Reserve agents applying therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Adding to or reclassifying reserve cities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To add to the number of cities classified as reserve cities under existing law in which national banking associations are subject to the reserve requirements set forth in section 20 of this Act, or to reclassify existing reserve cities or to terminate their designation as such.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspending or removing officers or directors of reserve banks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To suspend or remove any officer or director of any Federal reserve bank, the cause of such removal to be forthwith communicated in writing by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to the removed officer or director and to said bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Requiring writing off of doubtful or worthless assets of banks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To require the writing off of doubtful or worthless assets upon the books and balance sheets of Federal reserve banks.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a1f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspending operations of or liquidating or reorganizing banks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To suspend, for the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, the operations of any Federal reserve bank, to take possession thereof, administer the same during the period of suspension, and, when deemed advisable, to liquidate or reorganize such bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a20-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Requiring bonds of agents; safeguarding property in hands of agents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To require bonds of Federal reserve agents, to make regulations for the safeguarding of all collateral, bonds, Federal reserve notes, money, or property of any kind deposited in the hands of such agents, and said board shall perform the duties, functions, or services specified in this chapter, and make all rules and regulations necessary to enable said board effectively to perform the same.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a21-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Exercising supervision over reserve banks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To exercise general supervision over said Federal reserve banks.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a22-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation of certain functions; power to delegate; review of delegated activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To delegate, by published order or rule and subject to subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, any of its functions, other than those relating to rulemaking or pertaining principally to monetary and credit policies, to one or more administrative law judges, members or employees of the Board, or Federal Reserve banks. The assignment of responsibility for the performance of any function that the Board determines to delegate shall be a function of the Chairman. The Board shall, upon the vote of one member, review action taken at a delegated level within such time and in such manner as the Board shall by rule prescribe. The Board of Governors may not delegate to a Federal reserve bank its functions for the establishment of policies for the supervision and regulation of depository institution holding companies and other financial firms supervised by the Board of Governors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a23-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Employing attorneys, experts, assistants, and clerks; salaries and fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To employ such attorneys, experts, assistants, clerks, or other employees as may be deemed necessary to conduct the business of the board. All salaries and fees shall be fixed in advance by said board and shall be paid in the same manner as the salaries of the members of said board. All such attorneys, experts, assistants, clerks, and other employees shall be appointed without regard to the provisions of the Act of January sixteenth, eighteen hundred and eighty-three (volume twenty-two, United States Statutes at Large, page four hundred and three), and amendments thereto, or any rule or regulation made in pursuance thereof: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein shall prevent the President from placing said employees in the classified service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a24-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> [Repealed]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a25-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Board’s authority to examine depository institutions and affiliates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To examine, at the Board’s discretion, any depository institution, and any affiliate of such depository institution, in connection with any advance to, any discount of any instrument for, or any request for any such advance or discount by, such depository institution under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to appoint conservator or receiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may appoint the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as conservator or receiver for a State member bank under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1821/c/9">section 1821(c)(9) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a27-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may act in its own name and through its own attorneys in enforcing any provision of this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002032"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> regulations promulgated hereunder, or any other law or regulation, or in any action, suit, or proceeding to which the Board is a party and which involves the Board’s regulation or supervision of any bank, bank holding company (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841">section 1841 of this title</ref>), or other entity, or the administration of its operations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a28-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q"><num value="q" class="bold">(q)</num><heading class="bold"> Uniform protection authority for Federal reserve facilities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a29-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, to authorize personnel to act as law enforcement officers to protect and safeguard the premises, grounds, property, personnel, including members of the Board, of the Board, or any Federal reserve bank, and operations conducted by or on behalf of the Board or a reserve bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a2a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Board may, subject to the regulations prescribed under paragraph (5), delegate authority to a Federal reserve bank to authorize personnel to act as law enforcement officers to protect and safeguard the bank’s premises, grounds, property, personnel, and operations conducted by or on behalf of the bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a2b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Law enforcement officers designated or authorized by the Board or a reserve bank under paragraph (1) or (2) are authorized while on duty to carry firearms and make arrests without warrants for any offense against the United States committed in their presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States committed or being committed within the buildings and grounds of the Board or a reserve bank if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such a felony. Such officers shall have access to law enforcement information that may be necessary for the protection of the property or personnel of the Board or a reserve bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a2c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “law enforcement officers” means personnel who have successfully completed law enforcement training and are authorized to carry firearms and make arrests pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a2d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/q/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The law enforcement authorities provided for in this subsection may be exercised only pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Board and approved by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a2e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r"><num value="r" class="bold">(r)</num><heading class="bold"> Voting; documentation of determinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a2f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any action that this chapter provides may be taken only upon the affirmative vote of 5 members of the Board may be taken upon the unanimous vote of all members then in office if there are fewer than 5 members in office at the time of the action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a30-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a31-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Any action that the Board is otherwise authorized to take under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343/3">section 343(3) of this title</ref> may be taken upon the unanimous vote of all available members then in office, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb276a32-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> at least 2 members are available and all available members participate in the action;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb276a33-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the available members unanimously determine that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a34-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> unusual and exigent circumstances exist and the borrower is unable to secure adequate credit accommodations from other sources;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a35-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> action on the matter is necessary to prevent, correct, or mitigate serious harm to the economy or the stability of the financial system of the United States;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a36-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> despite the use of all means available (including all available telephonic, telegraphic, and other electronic means), the other members of the Board have not been able to be contacted on the matter; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a37-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> action on the matter is required before the number of Board members otherwise required to vote on the matter can be contacted through any available means (including all available telephonic, telegraphic, and other electronic means); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb276a38-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any credit extended by a Federal reserve bank pursuant to such action is payable upon demand of the Board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb276a39-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/r/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The available members of the Board shall document in writing the determinations required by subparagraph (A)(ii), and such written findings shall be included in the record of the action and in the official minutes of the Board, and copies of such record shall be provided as soon as practicable to the members of the Board who were not available to participate in the action and to the Chairman of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and to the Chairman of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a3a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s"><num value="s" class="bold">(s)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002033"><num>2</num> So in original. Two subsecs. (s) have been enacted.</note> Federal Reserve transparency and release of information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a3b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to ensure the disclosure in a timely manner consistent with the purposes of this chapter of information concerning the borrowers and counterparties participating in emergency credit facilities, discount window lending programs, and open market operations authorized or conducted by the Board or a Federal reserve bank, the Board of Governors shall disclose, as provided in paragraph (2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a3c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the names and identifying details of each borrower, participant, or counterparty in any credit facility or covered transaction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a3d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount borrowed by or transferred by or to a specific borrower, participant, or counterparty in any credit facility or covered transaction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a3e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the interest rate or discount paid by each borrower, participant, or counterparty in any credit facility or covered transaction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a3f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> information identifying the types and amounts of collateral pledged or assets transferred in connection with participation in any credit facility or covered transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a40-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory release date</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a41-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a credit facility, the Board shall disclose the information described in paragraph (1) on the date that is 1 year after the effective date of the termination by the Board of the authorization of the credit facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a42-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a covered transaction, the Board shall disclose the information described in paragraph (1) on the last day of the eighth calendar quarter following the calendar quarter in which the covered transaction was conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a43-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Earlier release date authorized</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Chairman of the Board may publicly release the information described in paragraph (1) before the relevant date specified in paragraph (2), if the Chairman determines that such disclosure would be in the public interest and would not harm the effectiveness of the relevant credit facility or the purpose or conduct of covered transactions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a44-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a45-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “credit facility” has the same meaning as in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s714/f/1/A">section 714(f)(1)(A) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a46-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered transaction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “covered transaction” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb276a47-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any open market transaction with a nongovernmental third party conducted under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s353">section 353 of this title</ref> or section 354, 355, or 356 of this title, after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb276a48-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any advance made under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s347b">section 347b of this title</ref> after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a49-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of credit facility by operation of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A credit facility shall be deemed to have terminated as of the end of the 24-month period beginning on the date on which the credit facility ceases to make extensions of credit and loans, unless the credit facility is otherwise terminated by the Board before such date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a4a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Consistent treatment of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in this subsection or <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/D">section 343(3)(D) of this title</ref>, or in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s714/f/3/C">section 714(f)(3)(C) of title 31</ref>, the information described in paragraph (1) and information concerning the transactions described in section 714(f) of such title, shall be confidential, including for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/3">section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>, until the relevant mandatory release date described in paragraph (2), unless the Chairman of the Board determines that earlier disclosure of such information would be in the public interest and would not harm the effectiveness of the relevant credit facility or the purpose of conduct of the relevant transactions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a4b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of personal privacy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C">section 343(3)(C) of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s714/f/3/C">section 714(f)(3)(C) of title 31</ref>, and subsection (a) or (c) of section 1109 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act shall not be construed as requiring any disclosure of nonpublic personal information (as defined for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s6802">section 6802 of title 15</ref>) concerning any individual who is referenced in collateral pledged or assets transferred in connection with a credit facility or covered transaction, unless the person is a borrower, participant, or counterparty under the credit facility or covered transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a4c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Study of FOIA exemption impact</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a4d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb276a4e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> conduct a study on the impact that the exemption from <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/3">section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref> (known as the Freedom of Information Act) established under paragraph (6) has had on the ability of the public to access information about the administration by the Board of Governors of emergency credit facilities, discount window lending programs, and open market operations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb276a4f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> make any recommendations on whether the exemption described in clause (i) should remain in effect.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a50-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 months after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, the Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall submit a report on the findings of the study required under subparagraph (A) to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and publish the report on the website of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a51-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section is meant to affect any pending litigation or lawsuit filed under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> (popularly known as the Freedom of Information Act) on or before <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a52-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s"><num value="s" class="bold">(s)</num><heading class="bold"> <sup>2</sup> Assessments, fees, and other charges for certain companies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a53-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board shall collect a total amount of assessments, fees, or other charges from the companies described in paragraph (2) that is equal to the total expenses the Board estimates are necessary or appropriate to carry out the supervisory and regulatory responsibilities of the Board with respect to such companies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a54-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Companies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The companies described in this paragraph are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a55-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all bank holding companies having total consolidated assets of $100,000,000,000 or more;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all savings and loan holding companies having total consolidated assets of $100,000,000,000 or more; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb276a57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> all nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5323">section 5323 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb276a58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s248/s/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Tailoring assessments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In collecting assessments, fees, or other charges under paragraph (1) from each company described in paragraph (2) with total consolidated assets of between $100,000,000,000 and $250,000,000,000, the Board shall adjust the amount charged to reflect any changes in supervisory and regulatory responsibilities resulting from the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act with respect to each such company.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb276a59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s11">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/261">38 Stat. 261</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1916-09-07/ch461">Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 461</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/752">39 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1918-09-26/ch177/s2">Sept. 26, 1918, ch. 177, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/968">40 Stat. 968</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1919-03-03/ch101/s3">Mar. 3, 1919, ch. 101, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1315">40 Stat. 1315</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1921-02-27/ch75">Feb. 27, 1921, ch. 75</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1146">41 Stat. 1146</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-26/ch612">June 26, 1930, ch. 612</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/814">46 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-03-09/ch1">Mar. 9, 1933, ch. 1</ref>, title I, § 3, <ref href="/us/stat/48/2">48 Stat. 2</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s7">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/167">48 Stat. 167</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), title III, §§ 321(a), 342, <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>, 713, 722; <ref href="/us/act/1945-06-12/ch186/s1/c">June 12, 1945, ch. 186, § 1(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/237">59 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/114/s3/b/6">Pub. L. 86–114, § 3(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1959-07-28">July 28, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/264">73 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/251/s3/c">Pub. L. 86–251, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-09">Sept. 9, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/488">73 Stat. 488</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/722/s3">Pub. L. 87–722, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-09-28">Sept. 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/670">76 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/427/s2">Pub. L. 89–427, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-05-20">May 20, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/161">80 Stat. 161</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/765">Pub. L. 89–765</ref>, <date date="1966-11-05">Nov. 5, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1314">80 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/269/s1">Pub. L. 90–269, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-03-18">Mar. 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/50">82 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/251/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 95–251, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/183">92 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tI/s102">Pub. L. 96–221, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/132">94 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s5/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1068">96 Stat. 1068</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/457/s17/b">Pub. L. 97–457, § 17(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2509">96 Stat. 2509</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tVII/s744/i/1">Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/439">103 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tI">Pub. L. 102–242, title I</ref>, §§ 133(f), 142(c), <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2273">105 Stat. 2273</ref>, 2281; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXVI/s1603/d/9">Pub. L. 102–550, title XVI, § 1603(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4080">106 Stat. 4080</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tIII">Pub. L. 103–325, title III</ref>, §§ 322(d), 331(d), title VI, § 602(g)(2), <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2227">108 Stat. 2227</ref>, 2232, 2293; <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tVII/s735">Pub. L. 106–102, title VII, § 735</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1479">113 Stat. 1479</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s364">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 364</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/333">115 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/297/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 107–297, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2340">116 Stat. 2340</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII">Pub. L. 111–203, title III</ref>, §§ 318(c), 366(1), title XI, §§ 1103(b), 1108(c), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1527">124 Stat. 1527</ref>, 1556, 2118, 2126; <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tIV/s401/c/2">Pub. L. 115–174, title IV, § 401(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1358">132 Stat. 1358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb29da5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb29da5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb29da5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 461, 463, 464, 465, and 466 of this title, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), was in the original “section 19 of the Federal Reserve Act”. Provisions of section 19 relating to reserve requirements are classified to the cited sections. For complete classification of section 19 to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (c), (h), (i), (n), and (r)(1) and in par. (1) of the first subsec. (s) (relating to Federal Reserve transparency and release of information), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference in subsec. (e) to “section 20 of this Act” means section 20 of the Federal Reserve Act which is not classified to the Code. Since section 20 does not set forth any reserve requirements, section 19 of the Federal Reserve Act might have been intended. For provisions of section 19 relating to reserve requirements, see note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of January sixteenth, eighteen hundred and eighty-three, referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>), is <ref href="/us/act/1883-01-16/ch27">act Jan. 16, 1883, ch. 27</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/22/403">22 Stat. 403</ref>, which enacted section 42 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and sections 632, 633, 635, 637, 638, and 640 to 642a of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. Section 42 of former Title 40 was repealed and reenacted as <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s8165">section 8165 of Title 40</ref>, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, §§ 1, 6(b), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>, 1304. The sections that were classified to former Title 5 were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. For distribution of former sections of Title 5 into the revised Title 5, see table at the beginning of Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsec. (p), probably should read “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act, which does not contain titles. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) or (c) of section 1109 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, referred to in par. (7) of the first subsec. (s) (relating to Federal Reserve transparency and release of information), is subsec. (a) or (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1109">section 1109 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, title XI, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2127">124 Stat. 2127</ref>, 2128, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, referred to in par. (8)(B) of the first subsec. (s) (relating to Federal Reserve transparency and release of information), was in the original “the date of enactment of this section”, which was translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> which added such subsec. (s), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act, referred to in par. (3) of the second subsec. (s) (relating to assessments, fees, and other charges for certain companies), is <ref href="/us/pl/115/174">Pub. L. 115–174</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1296">132 Stat. 1296</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2018 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb29da5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (k), “subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5” was substituted for “the Administrative Procedure Act” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">section 7(b) of Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of section 11 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. The fourteenth par. of section 16 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, which formerly constituted subsec. (<i>o</i>) of this section, is now classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248–1">section 248–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb29da5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (s)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s401/c/2/A">Pub. L. 115–174, § 401(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “$100,000,000,000” for “$50,000,000,000” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (s)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s401/c/2/B">Pub. L. 115–174, § 401(c)(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s366/1/A">Pub. L. 111–203, § 366(1)(A)</ref>, which directed insertion of “State savings associations that are insured depository institutions (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of this title</ref>),” after “case of insured”, was executed by making the insertion after “case of insured” in subpar. (B)(i), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s366/1/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 366(1)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “Comptroller of the Currency” for “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision” and inserted “Federal” before “savings association which”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s366/1/D">Pub. L. 111–203, § 366(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “savings association” for “savings and loan association”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1108/c">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1108(c)</ref>, inserted at end “The Board of Governors may not delegate to a Federal reserve bank its functions for the establishment of policies for the supervision and regulation of depository institution holding companies and other financial firms supervised by the Board of Governors.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (s). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1103/b">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1103(b)</ref>, added subsec. (s) relating to Federal Reserve transparency and release of information.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s318/c">Pub. L. 111–203, § 318(c)</ref>, added subsec. (s) relating to assessments, fees, and other charges for certain companies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/107/297">Pub. L. 107–297</ref> added subsec. (r).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Pub. L. 107–56</ref> added subsec. (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> substituted “[Repealed]” for text of subsec. (m) which related to percentage of capital and surplus represented by loans to be determined by the Federal Reserve Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s602/g/2">Pub. L. 103–325, § 602(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of the Treasury” for “bureau under the charge of the Comptroller of the Currency” before “the issue and retirement” and for “Comptroller” before “to the Federal Reserve agents”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s322/d">Pub. L. 103–325, § 322(d)</ref>, which directed substitution of “15 percent” for “10 percentum” wherever appearing, was executed by substituting “15 percent” for “10 per centum” in two places to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s331/d">Pub. L. 103–325, § 331(d)</ref>, added subsec. (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsecs. (<i>o</i>), (p). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> redesignated subsec. (p) as (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s142/c">Pub. L. 102–242, § 142(c)</ref>, which directed addition of subsec. (n) at end of section, was executed by adding subsec. (n) after subsec. (m). See Construction of 1991 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s133/f">Pub. L. 102–242, § 133(f)</ref>, added subsec. (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(2)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> substituted “the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision in the case of any savings association which is an insured depository institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of this title</ref>)” for “Federal Home Loan Bank Board in the case of any institution insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/97/457">Pub. L. 97–457</ref> substituted “under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s84/c/4">section 84(c)(4) of this title</ref>” for “under paragraph (8) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s84">section 84 of this title</ref>” after “in the case of national banks”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/97/258">Pub. L. 97–258</ref> struck out subsec. (n) which provided that, whenever in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury such action was necessary to protect the currency system of the United States, the Secretary of the Treasury, in his discretion, could require any or all individuals, partnerships, associations, and corporations to pay and deliver to the Treasurer of the United States any or all gold coin, gold bullion, and gold certificates owned by such individuals, partnerships, associations, and corporations and that, upon receipt of such gold coin, gold bullion or gold certificates, the Secretary of the Treasury would pay therefor an equivalent amount of any other form of coin or currency coined or issued under the laws of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/95/251">Pub. L. 95–251</ref> substituted “administrative law judges” for “hearing examiners”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/269">Pub. L. 90–269</ref> struck out requirements for establishment by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System of a graduated tax on the deficiency in the gold reserve whenever the reserve held against Federal Reserve notes fell below 25 percent and for an automatic increase in the rates of interest or discount fixed by the Board in an amount equal to the graduated tax imposed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/427">Pub. L. 89–427</ref> excepted the cancellation and destruction, and the accounting with respect to the cancellation and destruction, of notes unfit for circulation from the area of responsibility exercised by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System through the Bureau of the Comptroller of the Currency over the issue and retirement of Federal Reserve notes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/89/765">Pub. L. 89–765</ref> added subsec. (k). A former subsec. (k) was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/87/722/s3">Pub. L. 87–722, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-09-28">Sept. 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/670">76 Stat. 670</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/87/722">Pub. L. 87–722</ref> repealed subsec. (k) which related to the authority of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to permit national banks to act as trustees, etc., and is now covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s92a">section 92a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/86/114">Pub. L. 86–114</ref> substituted “reserve cities” for “reserve and central reserve cities” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/86/251">Pub. L. 86–251</ref> struck out “in the form of notes” after “represented by obligations” in proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1945—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1945-06-12">June 12, 1945</date>, substituted “25 per centum” for “40 per centum”, and “20 per centum” for “32½ per centum” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Subsec. (k). Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, § 342, amended last sentence of third par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, § 321(a), inserted proviso at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1933—Subsec. (m). Act <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date>, amended provisions generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). Act <date date="1933-03-09">Mar. 9, 1933</date>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1930—Subsec. (k). Act <date date="1930-06-26">June 26, 1930</date>, added last par.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb29da5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb29da60-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da61-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/174">Pub. L. 115–174</ref> effective 18 months after <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s401/d">section 401(d) of Pub. L. 115–174</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5365">section 5365 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da62-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s318/c">section 318(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s318/e">section 318(e) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s16">section 16 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s366/1">section 366(1) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s351">section 351 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1103(b) and 1108(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da63-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> effective as if included in the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991, <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, as of <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, except that where amendment is to any provision of law added or amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref> effective after <date date="1992-12-19">Dec. 19, 1992</date>, then amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> effective on effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1609">section 1609 of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s191">section 191 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da64-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s133/f">section 133(f) of Pub. L. 102–242</ref> effective 1 year after <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s133/g">section 133(g) of Pub. L. 102–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s191">section 191 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da65-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tI/s108">Pub. L. 96–221, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/141">94 Stat. 141</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/221/tI/s108">“This title [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248a">section 248a of this title</ref>, amending this section and sections 342, 347b, 355, 360, 412, 461, 463, 505, and 1425a of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 226 and 355 of this title] shall take effect on the first day of the sixth month which begins after the date of the enactment of this title [<date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>], except that the amendments regarding sections 19(b)(7) and 19(b)(8)(D) of the Federal Reserve Act [section 461(b)(7) and (b)(8)(D) of this title] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this title.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb29da66-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/86/114">Pub. L. 86–114</ref> effective three years after <date date="1959-07-28">July 28, 1959</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/114/s3/b">section 3(b) of Pub. L. 86–114</ref>, set out as a Central Reserve and Reserve Cities note under former <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb29da67-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For construction of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/174">Pub. L. 115–174</ref> as applied to certain foreign banking organizations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s401/g">section 401(g) of Pub. L. 115–174</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5365">section 5365 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb29da68-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 1991 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXVI/s1603/e/2">Pub. L. 102–550, title XVI, § 1603(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4081">106 Stat. 4081</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/550/tXVI/s1603/e/2">“The amendment made by section 142(c) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 [<ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref>] (adding a paragraph at the end of section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act [this section]) shall be considered to have been executed before the amendment made by section 133(f) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 [amending this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb29da69-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddb29da6a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 6359</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 6359, <date date="1933-10-25">Oct. 25, 1933</date>, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 11825, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, 40 F.R. 1003, which provided for receipt on consignment of gold by the United States mints and assay offices, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12553, <date date="1986-02-25">Feb. 25, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 7237.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddb29da6b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10547. Inspection of Statistical Transcript Cards</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10547, <date date="1954-07-27">July 27, 1954</date>, 19 F.R. 4661, required statistical transcript cards submitted with, or prepared by the Internal Revenue Service from, corporation income tax returns for the taxable years ending after <date date="1951-06-30">June 30, 1951</date>, and before <date date="1952-07-01">July 1, 1952</date>, to be open to inspection by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System as an aid in executing the powers conferred upon such Board by this section, such inspection to be in accordance and upon compliance with the rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury in T.D. 6081, 19 F.R. 4666.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
