<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb087008-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s26"><num value="26">§ 26.</num><heading> Comptroller to determine if association can commence business</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a certificate is transmitted to the Comptroller of the Currency, as provided in title 62 of the Revised Statutes, and the association transmitting the same notifies the Comptroller that all of its capital stock has been duly paid in, and that such association has complied with all the provisions of title 62 of the Revised Statutes required to be complied with before an association shall be authorized to commence the business of banking, the Comptroller shall examine into the condition of such association, ascertain especially the amount of money paid in on account of its capital, the name and place of residence of each of its directors, and the amount of the capital stock of which each is the owner in good faith, and generally whether such association has complied with all the provisions of title 62 of the Revised Statutes required to entitle it to engage in the business of banking; and shall cause to be made and attested by the oaths of a majority of the directors, and by the president or cashier of the association, a statement of all the facts necessary to enable the Comptroller to determine whether the association is lawfully entitled to commence the business of banking.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb0ae109-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(R.S. § 5168; <ref href="/us/pl/86/230/s2">Pub. L. 86–230, § 2</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/457">73 Stat. 457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb0ae10a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb0ae10b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb0ae10c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title 62 of the Revised Statutes, referred to in text, was in the original “this Title” meaning title LXII of the Revised Statutes, consisting of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244, which are classified this section and to sections 16, 21, 22 to 24a, 25a, 25b, 27, 29, 35 to 37, 39, 43, 52, 53, 55 to 57, 59 to 62, 66, 71, 72 to 76, 81, 83 to 86, 90, 91, 93, 93a, 94, 141 to 144, 161, 164, 181, 182, 192 to 194, 196, 215c, 481 to 485, 501, 541, 548, and 582 of this title. See, also, sections 8, 333, 334, 475, 656, 709, 1004, and 1005 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure. For complete classification of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244 to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb0ae10d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5168 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-06-03/ch106/s17">act June 3, 1864, ch. 106, § 17</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/13/104">13 Stat. 104</ref>, which was the National Bank Act. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb0ae10e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/230">Pub. L. 86–230</ref> substituted “all” for “at least 50 per centum” before “of its capital stock”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb0ae10f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb0ae110-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception as to Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by any provision of law in Comptroller of the Currency, referred to in this section, not included in transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
