<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb0ae111-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s27"><num value="27">§ 27.</num><heading> Certificate of authority to commence banking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb0ae112-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s27/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> If, upon a careful examination of the facts so reported, and of any other facts which may come to the knowledge of the Comptroller, whether by means of a special commission appointed by him for the purpose of inquiring into the condition of such association, or otherwise, it appears that such association is lawfully entitled to commence the business of banking, the Comptroller shall give to such association a certificate, under his hand and official seal, that such association has complied with all the provisions required to be complied with before commencing the business of banking, and that such association is authorized to commence such business. But the Comptroller may withhold from an association his certificate authorizing the commencement of business, whenever he has reason to suppose that the shareholders have formed the same for any other than the legitimate objects contemplated by title 62 of the Revised Statutes. A National Bank Association, to which the Comptroller of the Currency has heretofore issued or hereafter issues such certificate, is not illegally constituted solely because its operations are or have been required by the Comptroller of the Currency to be limited to those of a trust company and activities related thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb0ae113-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s27/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb0ae114-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s27/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Comptroller of the Currency may also issue a certificate of authority to commence the business of banking pursuant to this section to a national banking association which is owned exclusively (except to the extent directors’ qualifying shares are required by law) by other depository institutions or depository institution holding companies and is organized to engage exclusively in providing services to or for other depository institutions, their holding companies, and the officers, directors, and employees of such institutions and companies, and in providing correspondent banking services at the request of other depository institutions or their holding companies (also referred to as a “banker’s bank”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb0ae115-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s27/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any national banking association chartered pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and orders as the Comptroller deems appropriate, and, except as otherwise specifically provided in such rules, regulations, or orders, shall be vested with or subject to the same rights, privileges, duties, restrictions, penalties, liabilities, conditions, and limitations that would apply under the national banking laws to a national bank.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb0ae116-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(R.S. § 5169; <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXV/s1504">Pub. L. 95–630, title XV, § 1504</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3713">92 Stat. 3713</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVII/s712/a">Pub. L. 96–221, title VII, § 712(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/189">94 Stat. 189</ref>, 190; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tIV/s404/a">Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 404(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1511">96 Stat. 1511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tIII/s322/a/2">Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 322(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2227">108 Stat. 2227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb0ae117-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb0ae118-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb0ae119-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title 62 of the Revised Statutes, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Title” meaning title LXII of the Revised Statutes, consisting of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244, which are classified to this section and sections 16, 21, 22 to 24a, 25a, 25b, 26, 29, 35 to 37, 39, 43, 52, 53, 55 to 57, 59 to 62, 66, 71, 72 to 76, 81, 83 to 86, 90, 91, 93, 93a, 94, 141 to 144, 161, 164, 181, 182, 192 to 194, 196, 215c, 481 to 485, 501, 541, 548, and 582 of this title. See, also, sections 8, 333, 334, 475, 656, 709, 1004, and 1005 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure. For complete classification of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244 to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb0ae11a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5169 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-06-03/ch106">act June 3, 1864, ch. 106</ref>, §§ 12, 18, <ref href="/us/stat/13/102">13 Stat. 102</ref>, 104, which was the National Bank Act. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb0ae11b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s322/a/2/A">Pub. L. 103–325, § 322(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “or depository institution holding companies” after “by other depository institutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s322/a/2/B">Pub. L. 103–325, § 322(a)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed substitution of “services to or for other depository institutions, their holding companies, and the officers, directors, and employees of such institutions and companies, and in providing correspondent banking services at the request of other depository institutions or their holding companies (also referred to as a ‘banker’s bank’)” for “services for other depository institutions and their officers, directors and employees”, was executed by making the substitution for “services for other depository institutions and their officers, directors, and employees” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s712/a">Pub. L. 96–221, § 712(a)</ref>, (c), temporarily inserted provisions relating to treatment of national banking associations as additional banks within the contemplation of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref>. See Termination Date of 1980 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref> inserted provision that a National Bank Association, to which the Comptroller of the Currency has heretofore issued or hereafter issues such certificate, is not illegally constituted solely because its operations are or have been required by the Comptroller of the Currency to be limited to those of a trust company and activities related thereto.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb0ae11c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="iddb0ae11d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVII/s712/c">Pub. L. 96–221, title VII, § 712(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/190">94 Stat. 190</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/221/tVII/s712/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref>] are hereby repealed on <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb0ae11e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXV/s1505">Pub. L. 95–630, title XV, § 1505</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3713">92 Stat. 3713</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/630/tXV/s1505">“This title [amending this section and sections 1715z–10 and 2902 of this title and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666f">section 1666f of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade] shall take effect upon enactment [<date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb0ae11f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb0ae120-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception as to Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by any provision of law in Comptroller of the Currency, referred to in this section, not included in transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
