<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcf60f01-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707"><num value="2707">§ 2707.</num><heading> Authority of Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60f02-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60f03-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of expenses and charges relating to acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real and personal property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real or other property by the United States, the Secretary shall have power, for the protection of the interest of the fund authorized under this chapter, to pay out of such fund all expenses or charges in connection with the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of any property, real or personal, acquired by the Secretary as a result of recoveries under security, subrogation, or other rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60f04-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers with respect to property rights held by Secretary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the performance of, with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary by this chapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf60f05-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> have the power, notwithstanding any other provision of law, whether before or after default, to provide by contract or otherwise for the extinguishment upon default of any redemption, equitable, legal, or other right, title in any mortgage, deed, trust, or other instrument held by or held on behalf of the Secretary under the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf60f06-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> have the power to foreclose on any property or commence any action to protect or enforce any right conferred upon the Secretary by law, contract, or other agreement, and bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or other sale any property in connection with which assistance has been provided pursuant to this chapter. In the event of any such acquisition, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of real property by the United States, complete, remodel and convert, dispose of, lease, and otherwise deal with, such property. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary also shall have power to pursue to final collection by way of compromise or otherwise all claims acquired by him in connection with any security, subrogation, or other rights obtained by him in administering this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60f07-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2707/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Coverage of existing programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall allow funds to be administered by a State that has an existing program that is determined by the Secretary to provide substantially similar assistance to homeowners. After such determination is made such State shall not be required to modify such program to comply with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcf60f08-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/50/tI/s108">Pub. L. 94–50, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1975-07-02">July 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/252">89 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXIV/s1496/b/5">Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1496(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2208">124 Stat. 2208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcf60f09-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcf60f0a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcf60f0b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcf60f0c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcf60f0d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the date on which final regulations implementing that amendment take effect, or on the date that is 18 months after the designated transfer date if such regulations have not been issued by that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1400/c">section 1400(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
