<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcf60fc8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2805"><num value="2805">§ 2805.</num><heading> Relation to State laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60fc9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2805/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter does not annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any State chartered depository institution subject to the provisions of this chapter from complying with the laws of any State or subdivision thereof with respect to public disclosure and recordkeeping by depositor institutions, except to the extent that those laws are inconsistent with any provision of this chapter, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. The Bureau is authorized to determine whether such inconsistencies exist. The Bureau may not determine that any such law is inconsistent with any provision of this chapter if the Bureau determines that such law requires the maintenance of records with greater geographic or other detail than is required under this chapter, or that such law otherwise provides greater disclosure than is required under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf60fca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s2805/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bureau may, by regulation, exempt from the requirements of this chapter any State-chartered depository institution within any State or subdivision thereof, if the agency determines that, under the law of such State or subdivision, that institution is subject to requirements that are substantially similar to those imposed under this chapter, and that such law contains adequate provisions for enforcement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, compliance with the requirements imposed under this subsection shall be enforced by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref>, in the case of national banks and Federal savings associations, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcf858bb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/200/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 94–200, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1127">89 Stat. 1127</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/628/tX/s1087/b">Pub. L. 100–628, title X, § 1087(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3280">102 Stat. 3280</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tVII/s744/p/2">Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(p)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/440">103 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1094/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1094(1)</ref>, (5), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2097">124 Stat. 2097</ref>, 2100.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcf858bc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcf858bd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcf858be-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1094/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1094(1)</ref>, substituted “Bureau” for “Board” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1094/5">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1094(5)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “The Bureau may by regulation exempt from the requirements of this chapter any State chartered depository institution within any State or subdivision thereof if it determines that, under the law of such State or subdivision, that institution is subject to requirements substantially similar to those imposed under this chapter, and that such law contains adequate provisions for enforcement. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, compliance with the requirements imposed under this subsection shall be enforced under—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref> in the case of national banks, by the Comptroller of the Currency; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref>, by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision in the case of a savings association the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1464/d">section 1464(d) of this title</ref> in the case of any institution subject to that provision, by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/628">Pub. L. 100–628</ref> substituted “section” for “Section”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcf858bf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcf858c0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
