<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb0ae126-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s29"><num value="29">§ 29.</num><heading> Power to hold real property</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A national banking association may purchase, hold, and convey real estate for the following purposes, and for no others:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">First. Such as shall be necessary for its accommodation in the transaction of its business.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Second. Such as shall be mortgaged to it in good faith by way of security for debts previously contracted.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Third. Such as shall be conveyed to it in satisfaction of debts previously contracted in the course of its dealings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Fourth. Such as it shall purchase at sales under judgments, decrees, or mortgages held by the association, or shall purchase to secure debts due to it.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">But no such association shall hold the possession of any real estate under mortgage, or the title and possession of any real estate purchased to secure any debts due to it, for a longer period than five years except as otherwise provided in this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For real estate in the possession of a national banking association upon application by the association, the Comptroller of the Currency may approve the possession of any such real estate by such association for a period longer than five years, but not to exceed an additional five years, if (1) the association has made a good faith attempt to dispose of the real estate within the five-year period, or (2) disposal within the five-year period would be detrimental to the association. Upon notification by the association to the Comptroller of the Currency that such conditions exist that require the expenditure of funds for the development and improvement of such real estate, and subject to such conditions and limitations as the Comptroller of the Currency shall prescribe, the association may expend such funds as are needed to enable such association to recover its total investment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the five-year holding limitation of this section or any other provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes, any national banking association which on <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, held, directly or indirectly, real estate, including any subsurface rights or interests therein, that since <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, had not been valued on the books of such association for more than a nominal amount, may continue to hold such real estate, rights, or interests for such longer period of time as would be permitted a State chartered bank by the law of the State in which the association is located if the aggregate amount of earnings from such real estate, rights, or interests is separately disclosed in the annual financial statements of the association.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb0ae127-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(R.S. § 5137; <ref href="/us/act/1927-02-25/ch191/s3">Feb. 25, 1927, ch. 191, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1227">44 Stat. 1227</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 96–221, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/186">94 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/25/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 97–25, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1981-07-27">July 27, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/145">95 Stat. 145</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1521">96 Stat. 1521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb0ae128-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb0ae129-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb0ae12a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title 62 of the Revised Statutes, referred to in last par., was in the original “this title” meaning title LXII of the Revised Statutes, consisting of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244, which are classified to this section and sections 16, 21, 22 to 24a, 25a, 25b, 26, 27, 35 to 37, 39, 43, 52, 53, 55 to 57, 59 to 62, 66, 71, 72 to 76, 81, 83 to 86, 90, 91, 93, 93a, 94, 141 to 144, 161, 164, 181, 182, 192 to 194, 196, 215c, 481 to 485, 501, 541, 548, and 582 of this title. See, also, sections 8, 333, 334, 475, 656, 709, 1004, and 1005 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure. For complete classification of R.S. §§ 5133 to 5244 to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb0ae12b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5137 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-06-03/ch106/s28">act June 3, 1864, ch. 106, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/13/107">13 Stat. 107</ref>, which was the National Bank Act. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb0ae12c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> substituted “Notwithstanding the five-year holding limitation of this section or any other provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes, any national banking association which on <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, held, directly or indirectly, real estate, including any subsurface rights or interests therein, that since <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, had not been valued on the books of such association for more than a nominal amount, may continue to hold such real estate, rights, or interests for such longer period of time as would be permitted a State chartered bank by the law of the State in which the association is located if the aggregate amount of earnings from such real estate, rights, or interests is separately disclosed in the annual financial statements of the association” for “Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, any national banking association which, on <date date="1981-07-27">July 27, 1981</date>, held title to and possession of real estate which was carried on the association’s books at a nominal value on <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, may continue to hold such real estate until <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>, if the earnings from such real estate are separately disclosed in the financial statements of the association”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/25">Pub. L. 97–25</ref> inserted provision that any national banking association which, on <date date="1981-07-27">July 27, 1981</date>, held title to and possession of real estate which was carried on the association’s books at a nominal value on <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, may continue to hold such real estate until <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>, if the earnings from such real estate are separately disclosed in the financial statements of the association.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> inserted provisions relating to authorization to hold real estate in the possession of a national banking association upon application by the association.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1927—Par. First. Act <date date="1927-02-25">Feb. 25, 1927</date>, struck out “immediate,” before “accommodation,” in par. First.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
