<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcf8598a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011"><num value="3011">§ 3011.</num><heading> Creation and charter; principal office; venue; purposes</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress of the United States hereby creates and charters a body corporate to be known as the National Consumer Cooperative Bank (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Bank”). The Bank shall have perpetual existence unless and until its charter is revoked or modified by Act of Congress. The right to revise, amend, or modify the charter of the Bank is specifically and exclusively reserved to the Congress. The principal office of the Bank shall be in Washington, District of Columbia, and, for the purpose of venue, shall be considered a resident thereof. It shall make loans and offer its services throughout the United States, its territories and possessions, and in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. The Bank shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8598b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> encourage the development of new and existing cooperatives eligible for its assistance by providing specialized credit and technical assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8598c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> maintain broad-based control of the Bank by its voting stockholders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8598d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> encourage broad-based ownership, control, and active participation by members in eligible cooperatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8598e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assist in improving the quality and availability of goods and services to consumers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8598f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3011/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> encourage ownership of its equity securities by cooperatives and others as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3014">section 3014 of this title</ref>, so that the date when all of the Bank’s class A stock owned by the United States has been fully redeemed (the “Final Government Equity Redemption Date”) occurs as early as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddcf85990-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/351/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–351, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-08-20">Aug. 20, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/499">92 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s396/b">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 396(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/439">95 Stat. 439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcf85991-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcf85992-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcf85993-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/351">Pub. L. 95–351</ref>, <date date="1978-08-20">Aug. 20, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/499">92 Stat. 499</ref>, known as the National Consumer Cooperative Bank Act, which enacted this chapter, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and sections 856, 867, and 868 of former Title 31, Money and Finance, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcf85994-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted provisions respecting creation, and denomination of the National Consumer Cooperative Bank, for provisions respecting creation, denomination, and status of the National Consumer Cooperative Bank.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcf85995-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcf85996-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s396/i">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 396(i)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/441">95 Stat. 441</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s396/i">“The amendments made by subsections (b) through (h) [amending this section, sections 3014, 3017, 3018, 3024, and 3043 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and sections 856, 867, and 868 of former Title 31, Money and Finance] shall take effect on the day after the Final Government Equity Redemption Date [<date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>].”</quotedContent>
 For definition of “Final Government Equity Redemption Date”, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s396/a">section 396(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3012">section 3012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcf85997-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Final Government Equity Redemption Date Established</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For establishment of Final Government Equity Redemption Date as <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3026">section 3026 of this title</ref> and notes set out under that section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
