<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcf85998-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012"><num value="3012">§ 3012.</num><heading> General corporate powers</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank shall have the power to make and service loans, commitments for credit, guarantees, furnish financially related services, technical assistance and the results of research, issue its obligations within the limitations imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3017">section 3017 of this title</ref> in such amounts, at such times, and on such terms as the Bank may determine, and to exercise the other powers and duties prescribed in this chapter, and shall have the power to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf85999-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> operate under the direction of its Board of Directors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> elect by its Board of Directors a president, one or more vice presidents, a secretary, a treasurer, and provide for such other officers, employees, and agents as may be necessary, and define their duties in accordance with regulations and standards adopted by the Board, and require surety bonds or make other provisions against losses occasioned by acts of employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> prescribe by its Board of Directors its bylaws not inconsistent with law, which shall establish the terms of office and the procedure for election of elective members; provide in a manner not inconsistent with this chapter for the classes of its stock and the manner in which its stock shall be issued, transferred, and retired; and prescribe the manner in which its officers, employees, and agents are elected or selected, its property acquired, held and transferred, its loans, commitments, other financial assistance, guarantees and appraisals may be made, its general business conducted, and the privilege granted it by law exercised and enjoyed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> enter into contracts and make advance, progress, or other payments with respect to such contracts, without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> sue and be sued in its corporate name and complain and defend, in any court of competent jurisdiction, State or Federal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf8599f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> acquire, hold, lease, mortgage, or dispose of, at public or private sale, real and personal property and sell or exchange any securities or obligations, and otherwise exercise all the usual incidents of ownership of property necessary or convenient to its business: <i>Provided</i>, That any such acquisition or ownership of real property shall not deprive a State or political subdivision thereof of its civil or criminal jurisdiction in and over such property or impair the civil rights of the inhabitants of such property under Federal, State, or local laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf859a0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> obtain insurance against loss in connection with property and other assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf859a1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> modify or consent to the modification with respect to the rate of interest, time of payment of any installment of principal or interest, security, or any other term of any contract or agreement to which it is a party or has an interest pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf859a2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> utilize and act through any Federal, State, or local public agency or instrumentality, or private agency or organization, with the consent of the agency or organization concerned, and contract with such agency, instrumentality, or organization for furnishing or receiving technical services and benefits of research, services, funds or facilities; and make advance, progress, or other payments with respect to such contracts without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> within the limitations of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3017">section 3017 of this title</ref>, borrow money and issue notes, bonds and debentures or other obligations individually or in concert with other financial institutions, agencies or instrumentalities, of such character and such terms and conditions and at rates of interest as may be determined;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> issue certificates of indebtedness to its stockholders or members and pay interest on funds left with the Bank, and accept grants or interest free temporary use of funds made available to it;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> participate with one or more other financial institutions, agencies, instrumentalities, or foundations in loans or guarantees under this chapter on terms as may be agreed upon;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> accept guarantees from other agencies for which loans made by the Bank may be eligible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> establish one or more branch offices and one or more advisory councils in connection with any such branch offices, as may from time to time be authorized by the Board of Directors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> buy and sell obligations of, or insured by, the United States or any agency or instrumentalities thereof, or securities backed by the full faith and credit of any such agency or instrumentality and, after the final Government Equity Redemption Date, make such other investments as may be authorized by the Board of Directors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9a9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> approve the salary scale of officers and employees of the Bank, in accordance with regulations and standards adopted by the Board of Directors, without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, but, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the General Schedule pay rates shall be applicable until all class A stock held by the Secretary of the Treasury has been retired; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9aa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3012/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> have such other incidental powers as may be necessary or expedient to carry out its duties under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In determining whether a public offering is taking place for the purpose of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.], there shall be excluded from consideration all class B and class C stock purchases which took place prior to <date date="1981-08-13">August 13, 1981</date>.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfac9ab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/351/tI/s102">Pub. L. 95–351, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1978-08-20">Aug. 20, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/500">92 Stat. 500</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/d/1">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 394(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/436">95 Stat. 436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfac9ac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfac9ad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfac9ae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Act of 1933, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38/tI">act May 27, 1933, ch. 38, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/74">48 Stat. 74</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 77a et seq.) of chapter 2A of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">section 77a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfac9af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In pars. (5) and (10), “section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31” substituted for “section 3648 of the Revised Statutes [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfac9b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted provisions relating to a public offering for purposes of the Securities Act of 1933, for provisions setting forth criteria for the term “exempt securities”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcfac9b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcfac9b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/d/2">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 394(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/436">95 Stat. 436</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/d/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect on the day after the Final Government Equity Redemption Date [<date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>].”</quotedContent>
 See <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s396/a">section 396(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref> set out below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I74" class="centered smallCaps">“Final Government Equity Redemption Date” Defined</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s396/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 396(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/439">95 Stat. 439</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s396/a">“For purposes of this subtitle [see Short Title of 1981 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>], the term ‘Final Government Equity Redemption Date’ shall have the same meaning given such term in section 101(5) of the National Consumer Cooperative Bank Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3011/5">12 U.S.C. 3011(5)</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
