<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfac9eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015"><num value="3015">§ 3015.</num><heading> Eligibility of cooperatives</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac9ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of all subchapters of this chapter, subject to the limitations of subsection (d) of this section, an eligible cooperative is an organization chartered or operated on a cooperative, not-for-profit basis for producing or furnishing goods, services or facilities, primarily for the benefit of its members or voting stockholders who are ultimate consumers of such goods, services, or facilities, or a legally chartered entity primarily owned and controlled by any such organization or organizations, if it—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> makes such goods, services or facilities directly or indirectly available to its members or voting stockholders on a not-for-profit basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> does not pay dividends on voting stock or membership capital in excess of such percentage per annum as may be approved under the bylaws of the Bank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provides that its net savings shall be allocated or distributed to all members or patrons, in proportion to their patronage, or shall be retained for the actual or potential expansion of its services or the reduction of its charges to the patrons, or for such other purposes as may be authorized by its membership not inconsistent with its purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> makes membership available on a voluntary basis, without any social, political, racial, or religious discrimination and without any discrimination on the basis of age, sex, or marital status, to all persons who can make use of its services and are willing to accept the responsibilities of membership, subject only to limitations under applicable Federal or State laws or regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> in the case of primary cooperative organizations restricts its voting control to members or voting stockholders on a one vote per person basis (except that this requirement shall not apply to any housing cooperative in existence on <date date="1980-03-21">March 21, 1980</date>, which did not meet such requirement on such date) and takes positive steps to insure economic democracy and maximum participation by members of the cooperative including the holding of annual meetings and, in the case of organizations owned by groups of cooperatives, provides positive protections to insure economic democracy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcfac9f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> is not a credit union, mutual savings bank, or mutual savings and loan association.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac9f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Primary producers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No organization shall be ineligible because it produces, markets, or furnishes goods, services, or facilities on behalf of its members as primary producers, unless the dollar volume of loans made by the Bank to such organizations exceeds 10 per centum of the gross assets of the Bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac9f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Net savings” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “net savings” means, for any period, the borrower’s gross receipts, less the operating and other expenses deductible therefrom in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, including, without limitation, contributions to allowable reserves, and after deducting the amounts of any dividends on its capital stock or other membership capital payable during, or within forty-five days after, the close of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac9f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperatives eligible for other Federal credit assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An eligible cooperative which also has been determined to be eligible for credit assistance from the Rural Electrification Administration, the National Rural Utilities Cooperative Finance Corporation, the Banks for Cooperatives or other institutions of the Farm Credit System, or the Farmers Home Administration may receive the assistance authorized by this chapter only (1) if the Bank determines that a request for assistance from any such source or sources has been rejected or denied solely because of the un­availability of funds from such source or sources, or (2) by agreement between the Bank and the agency or agencies involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac9f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3015/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit unions eligible for technical assistance from Office of Self-Help Development and Technical Assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a credit union serving predominantly low-income members (as defined by the Administrator of the National Credit Union Administration) may receive technical assistance under subchapter II.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfac9f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/351/tI/s105">Pub. L. 95–351, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1978-08-20">Aug. 20, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/506">92 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/e/1">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 394(e)(1)</ref>, (f), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/436">95 Stat. 436</ref>, 437; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tVI/s6602/b/18">Pub. L. 115–334, title VI, § 6602(b)(18)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4777">132 Stat. 4777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfac9f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfac9f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfac9fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All subchapters of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “all titles of this Act”, meaning titles I to III of <ref href="/us/pl/95/351">Pub. L. 95–351</ref>. Titles I and II constitute this chapter and title III amended <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and sections 856, 867, and 868 of former Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfac9fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> struck out “the Rural Telephone Bank,” after “the National Rural Utilities Cooperative Finance Corporation,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s394/e/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 394(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “primarily owned” for “entirely owned”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s394/f">Pub. L. 97–35, § 394(f)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to exception for housing cooperatives in existence on <date date="1980-03-21">Mar. 21, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcfac9fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcfac9fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/e/2">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 394(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/437">95 Stat. 437</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s394/e/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect on the day after the Final Government Equity Redemption Date [<date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>].”</quotedContent>
 For definition of “Final Government Equity Redemption Date”, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s396/a">section 396(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3012">section 3012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddcfac9fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested in Administrator of National Credit Union Administration transferred and vested in National Credit Union Administration Board pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752a">section 1752a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
