<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd01f5f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201"><num value="3201">§ 3201.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f5f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “depository institution” means a commercial bank, a savings bank, a trust company, a savings and loan association, a building and loan association, a homestead association, a cooperative bank, an industrial bank, or a credit union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f5f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “depository holding company” means a bank holding company as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a">section 1841(a) of this title</ref>, a company which would be a bank holding company as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a">section 1841(a) of this title</ref> but for the exemption contained in subsection (a)(5)(F) thereof, or a savings and loan holding company as defined in section 1730a(a)(1)(D) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002333">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002333"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f5f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the characterization of any corporation (including depository institutions and depository holding companies), as an “affiliate of,” or as “affiliated” with any other corporation means that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd01f5f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> one of the corporations is a depository holding company and the other is a subsidiary thereof, or both corporations are subsidiaries of the same depository holding company, as the term “subsidiary” is defined in either <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841/d">section 1841(d) of this title</ref> in the case of a bank holding company or section 1730a(a)(1)(H) <sup>1</sup> of this title in the case of a savings and loan holding company; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd01f5fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> more than 25 percent of the voting stock of one corporation is beneficially owned in the aggregate by one or more persons who also beneficially own in the aggregate more than 25 percent of the voting stock of the other corporation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd01f5fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> one of the corporations is a trust company all of the stock of which, except for directors qualifying shares, was owned by one or more mutual savings banks on <date date="1978-11-10">November 10, 1978</date>, and the other corporation is a mutual savings bank; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd01f5fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> one of the corporations is a bank, insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and chartered under State law, and is a bankers’ bank, described in Paragraph Seventh of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd01f5fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> one of the corporations is a bank, chartered under State law and insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the voting securities of which are held only by persons who are officers of other banks, as permitted by State law, and which bank is primarily engaged in providing banking services for other banks and not the public: <i>Provided, however</i>, That in no case shall the voting securities of such corporation be held by such officers of other banks in excess of 6 per centum of the paid-in capital and 6 per centum of the surplus of such a bank.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002334">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002334"><num>2</num> So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f5fe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “management official” means an employee or officer with management functions, a director (including an advisory or honorary director, except in the case of a depository institution with total assets of less than $100,000,000), a trustee of a business organization under the control of trustees, or any person who has a representative or nominee serving in any such capacity: <i>Provided</i>, That if a corporator, trustee, director, or other officer of a State-chartered savings bank or cooperative bank is specifically authorized under the laws of the State in which said institution is located to serve as a trustee, director, or other officer of a State-chartered trust company which does not make real estate mortgage loans and does not accept savings deposits from natural persons, then, for the purposes of this chapter, such corporator, trustee, director, or other officer shall not be deemed to be a management official of such trust company: <i>And provided further</i>, That if a management official of a State-chartered trust company which does not make real estate mortgage loans and does not accept savings deposits from natural persons is specifically authorized under the laws of the State in which said institution is located to serve as a corporator, trustee, director, or other officer of a State-chartered savings bank or cooperative bank, then, for the purposes of this chapter, such management official shall not be deemed to be a management official of any such savings bank or cooperative bank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f5ff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “office” used with reference to a depository institution means either a principal office or a branch; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd01f600-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3201/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “appropriate Federal depository institutions regulatory agency” means, with respect to any depository institution or depository holding company, the agency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3207">section 3207 of this title</ref> in connection with such institution or company.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddd01f601-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tII/s202">Pub. L. 95–630, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3672">92 Stat. 3672</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/650">Pub. L. 100–650</ref>, §§ 2, 3, 5(b)(1), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3819">102 Stat. 3819</ref>, 3820; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tIII/s322/c/2">Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 322(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2227">108 Stat. 2227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd01f602-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd01f603-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd01f604-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3672">92 Stat. 3672</ref>, known as the Depository Institution Management Interlocks Act, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 1464, 1730, and 1818 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as a note below. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1730a">Section 1730a of this title</ref>, referred to in pars. (2) and (3)(A), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 101–73, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/363">103 Stat. 363</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd01f605-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Par. (3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref> substituted “and is a bankers’ bank, described in Paragraph Seventh of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>; or” for “the voting securities of which are held by other banks, as permitted by State law, and which bank is primarily engaged in providing banking services for other banks and not the public: <i>Provided, however</i>, That in no case shall the voting securities of such corporation be held by any such other bank in excess of 5 per centum of the paid-in capital and 5 per centum of the surplus of such other bank; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Par. (3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/650/s2">Pub. L. 100–650, § 2</ref>, substituted “25 percent” for “50 per centum” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/650/s3">Pub. L. 100–650, § 3</ref>, substituted “(including an advisory or honorary director, except in the case of a depository institution with total assets of less than $100,000,000)” for “(including an advisory or honorary director)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/650/s5/b/1">Pub. L. 100–650, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd01f606-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddd01f607-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of 120 days after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s2101">section 2101 of Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s375b">section 375b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddd01f608-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/650/s1">Pub. L. 100–650, § 1</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3819">102 Stat. 3819</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/650/s1">“This Act [amending sections 3201, 3204, and 3205 of this title] may be referred to as the ‘Management Interlocks Revision Act of 1988’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="iddd01f609-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–630, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3672">92 Stat. 3672</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/630/tII/s201">“This title [enacting this chapter and amending sections 1464, 1730, and 1818 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Depository Institution Management Interlocks Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
