<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb2e95a0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s324"><num value="324">§ 324.</num><heading> Laws applicable on becoming members</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All banks admitted to membership under authority of this section shall be required to comply with the reserve and capital requirements of this chapter, to conform to those provisions of law imposed on national banks which prohibit such banks from lending on or purchasing their own stock and which relate to the withdrawal or impairment of their capital stock, and to conform to the provisions of sections 56 and 60(b) of this title with respect to the payment of dividends; except that any reference in any such provision to the Comptroller of the Currency shall be deemed for the purposes of this sentence to be a reference to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Such banks and the officers, agents, and employees thereof shall also be subject to the provisions of and to the penalties prescribed by sections 334, 656, and 1005 of title 18, and shall be required to make reports of condition and of the payment of dividends to the Federal Reserve bank of which they become a member. Not less than three of such reports shall be made annually on call of the Federal Reserve bank on dates to be fixed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Any bank which (A) maintains procedures reasonably adapted to avoid any inadvertent error and, unintentionally and as a result of such an error, fails to make or publish any report required under this paragraph, within the period of time specified by the Board, or submits or publishes any false or misleading report or information, or (B) inadvertently transmits or publishes any report which is minimally late, shall be subject to a penalty of not more than $2,000 for each day during which such failure continues or such false or misleading information is not corrected. The bank shall have the burden of proving that an error was inadvertent and that a report was inadvertently transmitted or published late. Any bank which fails to make or publish such reports within the period of time specified by the Board, or submits or publishes any false or misleading report or information, in a manner not described in the 2nd preceding sentence shall be subject to a penalty of not more than $20,000 for each day during which such failure continues or such false or misleading information is not corrected. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if any bank knowingly or with reckless disregard for the accuracy of any information or report described in such sentence submits or publishes any false or misleading report or information, the Board may assess a penalty of not more than $1,000,000 or 1 percent of total assets of such bank, whichever is less, per day for each day during which such failure continues or such false or misleading information is not corrected. Any penalty imposed under any of the 4 preceding sentences shall be assessed and collected by the Board in the manner provided in subparagraphs (E), (F), (G), and (I) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818/i/2">section 1818(i)(2) of this title</ref> (for penalties imposed under such section) and any such assessment (including the determination of the amount of the penalty) shall be subject to the provisions of such section. Any bank against which any penalty is assessed under this subsection shall be afforded an agency hearing if such bank submits a request for such hearing within 20 days after the issuance of the notice of assessment. <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818/h">Section 1818(h) of this title</ref> shall apply to any proceeding under this paragraph. Such reports of condition shall be in such form and shall contain such information as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may require.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb2e95a1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s9">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 9</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/259">38 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1917-06-21/ch32/s3">June 21, 1917, ch. 32, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/233">40 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 320, <ref href="/us/stat/49/713">49 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s27">Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 27</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1236">68 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/230/s21/b">Pub. L. 86–230, § 21(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/466">73 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tIX/s911/d">Pub. L. 101–73, title IX, § 911(d)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/480">103 Stat. 480</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tIII/s308/c">Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 308(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2218">108 Stat. 2218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb2e95a2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb2e95a3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb2e95a4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb2e95a5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the sixth par. of section 9 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, as amended. The sixth par. constituted the fourth par. of section 9 in 1917 (<ref href="/us/stat/40/232">40 Stat. 232</ref>), became the fifth par. in 1927 (<ref href="/us/stat/44/1229">44 Stat. 1229</ref>), and became the sixth par. in 1950 (<ref href="/us/stat/64/458">64 Stat. 458</ref>). For further details, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb2e95a6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref> struck out before period at end “and shall be published by the reporting banks in such manner and in accordance with such regulations as the said Board may prescribe”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> substituted provisions for different and increasing levels of penalties, assessment and collection of penalties, and agency hearings for provision that failure to make such reports within ten days after the date they were called for would subject the offending bank to a penalty of $100 a day for each day that it failed to transmit such report, such penalty to have been collected by the Federal Reserve bank by suit or otherwise.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/230">Pub. L. 86–230</ref> required State member banks to comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s60/b">section 60(b) of this title</ref> and inserted provisions requiring a reference to the Comptroller of the Currency to be deemed a reference to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-09-03">Sept. 3, 1954</date>, substituted “sections 334, 656, and 1005 of title 18” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s592">section 592 of this title</ref>”, and “Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System” for “Federal Reserve Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date> inserted last sentence of section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb2e95a7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb2e95a8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> applicable with respect to reports filed or required to be filed after <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s911/i">section 911(i) of Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s161">section 161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
