<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd046800-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s3335"><num value="3335">§ 3335.</num><heading> Powers of Appraisal Subcommittee</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Appraisal Subcommittee may, for the purpose of carrying out this chapter, establish advisory committees, hold hearings prescribe <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002342">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002342"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by a comma.</note> regulations in accordance with chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly referred to as the Administrative Procedures Act) after notice and opportunity for comment,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002343">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002343"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> sit and act at times and places, take testimony, receive evidence, provide information, and perform research, as the Appraisal Subcommittee considers appropriate. Any regulations prescribed by the Appraisal Subcommittee shall (unless otherwise provided in this chapter) be limited to the following functions: temporary practice, national registry, information sharing, and enforcement. For purposes of prescribing regulations, the Appraisal Subcommittee shall establish an advisory committee of industry participants, including appraisers, lenders, consumer advocates, real estate agents, and government agencies, and hold meetings as necessary to support the development of regulations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd046801-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tXI/s1106">Pub. L. 101–73, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/512">103 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXIV/s1473/d">Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1473(d)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2191">124 Stat. 2191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd046802-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd046803-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd046804-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title XI of <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title XI to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd046805-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> inserted “prescribe regulations in accordance with chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly referred to as the Administrative Procedures Act) after notice and opportunity for comment,” after “hold hearings” and “Any regulations prescribed by the Appraisal Subcommittee shall (unless otherwise provided in this chapter) be limited to the following functions: temporary practice, national registry, information sharing, and enforcement. For purposes of prescribing regulations, the Appraisal Subcommittee shall establish an advisory committee of industry participants, including appraisers, lenders, consumer advocates, real estate agents, and government agencies, and hold meetings as necessary to support the development of regulations.” at the end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd046806-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd046807-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the date on which final regulations implementing that amendment take effect, or on the date that is 18 months after the designated transfer date if such regulations have not been issued by that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1400/c">section 1400(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
