<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb3106f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s334"><num value="334">§ 334.</num><heading> Reports from affiliates; penalty for failure to furnish</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each bank admitted to membership under this subchapter shall obtain from each of its affiliates other than member banks and furnish to the Federal reserve bank of its district and to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System not less than three reports during each year. Such reports shall be in such form as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe, shall be verified by the oath or affirmation of the president or such other officer as may be designated by the board of directors of such affiliate to verify such reports, and shall disclose the information hereinafter provided for as of dates identical with those fixed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System for reports of the condition of the affiliated member bank. Each such report of an affiliate shall be transmitted as herein provided at the same time as the corresponding report of the affiliated member bank, except that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may, in its discretion, extend such time for good cause shown. Each such report shall contain such information as in the judgment of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be necessary to disclose fully the relations between such affiliate and such bank and to enable the board to inform itself as to the effect of such relations upon the affairs of such bank. The reports of such affiliates shall be published by the bank under the same conditions as govern its own condition reports.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any such affiliated member bank may be required to obtain from any such affiliate such additional reports as in the opinion of its Federal reserve bank or the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may be necessary in order to obtain a full and complete knowledge of the condition of the affiliated member bank. Such additional reports shall be transmitted to the Federal reserve bank and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and shall be in such form as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any such affiliated member bank which fails to obtain from any of its affiliates and furnish any report provided for by the two preceding paragraphs of this section shall be subject to a penalty of $100 for each day during which such failure continues, which, by direction of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, may be collected, by suit or otherwise, by the Federal reserve bank of the district in which such member bank is located.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb3106f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s9">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 9</ref> (pars.), as added <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s5/c">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 5(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/165">48 Stat. 165</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/485/s13/f">Pub. L. 89–485, § 13(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-07-01">July 1, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/243">80 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb3106f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb3106f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb3106f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this section”, meaning section 9 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, which is classified generally to this subchapter (§ 321 et seq.).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb3106f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the seventeenth to nineteenth pars. of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, as amended. These pars. constituted pars. fifteen to seventeen of section 9 in 1933 (<ref href="/us/stat/48/165">48 Stat. 165</ref>), became pars. sixteen to eighteen in 1935 (<ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>), and became pars. seventeen to nineteen in 1950 (<ref href="/us/stat/64/458">64 Stat. 458</ref>). For further details, see Codification notes set out under sections 321 and 329a of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb3106f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/485">Pub. L. 89–485</ref> struck out last sentence of third par. stating that term “affiliate” shall include holding company affiliates as well as other affiliates for the purposes of such par. and preceding two pars.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb3106f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb3106f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
