<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb31070c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s338"><num value="338">§ 338.</num><heading> Examination of affiliates; forfeiture of membership on refusal of affiliate to give information or pay expense</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In connection with examinations of State member banks, examiners selected or approved by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall make such examinations of the affairs of all affiliates of such banks as shall be necessary to disclose fully the relations between such banks and their affiliates and the effect of such relations upon the affairs of such banks. The expense of examination of affiliates of any State member bank may, in the discretion of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, be assessed against such bank and, when so assessed, shall be paid by such bank. In the event of the refusal to give any information requested in the course of the examination of any such affiliate, or in the event of the refusal to permit such examination, or in the event of the refusal to pay any expenses so assessed, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may, in its discretion, require any or all State member banks affiliated with such affiliate to surrender their stock in the Federal Reserve bank and to forfeit all rights and privileges of membership in the Federal Reserve System, as provided in this subchapter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb31070d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s9">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 9</ref> (par.), as added <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s5/c">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 5(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/166">48 Stat. 166</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb31070e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb31070f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb310710-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this section”, meaning section 9 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, which is classified generally to this subchapter (§ 321 et seq.).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb310711-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the twenty-second par. of section 9 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, as amended. The twenty-second par. constituted the twenty-first par. of section 9 in 1933 (<ref href="/us/stat/48/166">48 Stat. 166</ref>), became the twenty-second par. in 1935 (<ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>), and became the twenty-third par. in 1950 (<ref href="/us/stat/64/458">64 Stat. 458</ref>), and became the twenty-second par. in 1966 (<ref href="/us/stat/80/243">80 Stat. 243</ref>). For further details, see Codification notes set out under sections 321 and 329a of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb310712-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb310713-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
