<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb335049-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343"><num value="343">§ 343.</num><heading> Discount of obligations arising out of actual commercial transactions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the indorsement of any of its member banks, which shall be deemed a waiver of demand, notice and protest by such bank as to its own indorsement exclusively, any Federal reserve bank may discount notes, drafts, and bills of exchange arising out of actual commercial transactions; that is, notes, drafts, and bills of exchange issued or drawn for agricultural, industrial, or commercial purposes, or the proceeds of which have been used, or are to be used, for such purposes, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to have the right to determine or define the character of the paper thus eligible for discount, within the meaning of this chapter. Nothing in this chapter contained shall be construed to prohibit such notes, drafts, and bills of exchange, secured by staple agricultural products, or other goods, wares, or merchandise from being eligible for such discount, and the notes, drafts, and bills of exchange of factors issued as such making advances exclusively to producers of staple agricultural products in their raw state shall be eligible for such discount; but such definition shall not include notes, drafts, or bills covering merely investments or issued or drawn for the purpose of carrying or trading in stocks, bonds, or other investment securities, except bonds and notes of the Government of the United States. Notes, drafts, and bills admitted to discount under the terms of this paragraph must have a maturity at the time of discount of not more than ninety days, exclusive of grace.</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002037">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002037"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> In unusual and exigent circumstances, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, by the affirmative vote of not less than five members, may authorize any Federal reserve bank, during such periods as the said board may determine, at rates established in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>, to discount for any participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility, notes, drafts, and bills of exchange when such notes, drafts, and bills of exchange are indorsed or otherwise secured to the satisfaction of the Federal reserve bank: <i>Provided</i>, That before discounting any such note, draft, or bill of exchange, the Federal reserve bank shall obtain evidence that such participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility is unable to secure adequate credit accommodations from other banking institutions. All such discounts for any participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility shall be subject to such limitations, restrictions, and regulations as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> As soon as is practicable after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, the Board shall establish, by regulation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the policies and procedures governing emergency lending under this paragraph. Such policies and procedures shall be designed to ensure that any emergency lending program or facility is for the purpose of providing liquidity to the financial system, and not to aid a failing financial company, and that the security for emergency loans is sufficient to protect taxpayers from losses and that any such program is terminated in a timely and orderly fashion. The policies and procedures established by the Board shall require that a Federal reserve bank assign, consistent with sound risk management practices and to ensure protection for the taxpayer, a lendable value to all collateral for a loan executed by a Federal reserve bank under this paragraph in determining whether the loan is secured satisfactorily for purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Board shall establish procedures to prohibit borrowing from programs and facilities by borrowers that are insolvent. Such procedures may include a certification from the chief executive officer (or other authorized officer) of the borrower, at the time the borrower initially borrows under the program or facility (with a duty by the borrower to update the certification if the information in the certification materially changes), that the borrower is not insolvent. A borrower shall be considered insolvent for purposes of this subparagraph, if the borrower is in bankruptcy, resolution under title II of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5381">12 U.S.C. 5381</ref> et seq.], or any other Federal or State insolvency proceeding.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb33504f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> A program or facility that is structured to remove assets from the balance sheet of a single and specific company, or that is established for the purpose of assisting a single and specific company avoid bankruptcy, resolution under title II of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, or any other Federal or State insolvency proceeding, shall not be considered a program or facility with broad-based eligibility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb335050-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The Board may not establish any program or facility under this paragraph without the prior approval of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb335051-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The Board shall provide to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb335052-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> not later than 7 days after the Board authorizes any loan or other financial assistance under this paragraph, a report that includes—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb335053-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the justification for the exercise of authority to provide such assistance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb335054-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the identity of the recipients of such assistance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb335055-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the date and amount of the assistance, and form in which the assistance was provided; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb335056-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> the material terms of the assistance, including—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb335057-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> duration;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb335058-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> collateral pledged and the value thereof;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb335059-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> all interest, fees, and other revenue or items of value to be received in exchange for the assistance;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb33505a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> any requirements imposed on the recipient with respect to employee compensation, distribution of dividends, or any other corporate decision in exchange for the assistance; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb33505b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/i/IV/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><content> the expected costs to the taxpayers of such assistance; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb33505c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> once every 30 days, with respect to any outstanding loan or other financial assistance under this paragraph, written updates on—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb33505d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the value of collateral;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb33505e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the amount of interest, fees, and other revenue or items of value received in exchange for the assistance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb33505f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the expected or final cost to the taxpayers of such assistance.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb335060-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> The information required to be submitted to Congress under subparagraph (C) related to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb335061-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the identity of the participants in an emergency lending program or facility commenced under this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb335062-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amounts borrowed by each participant in any such program or facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb335063-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> identifying details concerning the assets or collateral held by, under, or in connection with such a program or facility,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be kept confidential, upon the written request of the Chairman of the Board, in which case such information shall be made available only to the Chairpersons or Ranking Members of the Committees described in subparagraph (C).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb335064-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s343/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> If an entity to which a Federal reserve bank has provided a loan under this paragraph becomes a covered financial company, as defined in section 201 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5381">12 U.S.C. 5381</ref>], at any time while such loan is outstanding, and the Federal reserve bank incurs a realized net loss on the loan, then the Federal reserve bank shall have a claim equal to the amount of the net realized loss against the covered entity, with the same priority as an obligation to the Secretary of the Treasury under section 210(b) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5390/b">12 U.S.C. 5390(b)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddb335065-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s13">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 13</ref> (pars.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/263">38 Stat. 263</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1916-09-07/ch461">Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 461</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/752">39 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1923-03-04/ch252">Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 252</ref>, title IV, § 402, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1478">42 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1932-07-21/ch520/s210">July 21, 1932, ch. 520, § 210</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/715">47 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), title III, § 322, <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>, 714; <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tIV/s473">Pub. L. 102–242, title IV, § 473</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2386">105 Stat. 2386</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1101/a">Pub. L. 111–203, title XI, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2113">124 Stat. 2113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb335066-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb335067-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb335068-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in the first par., was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, referred to in par. (3)(B)(ii), (iii), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1376">124 Stat. 1376</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified principally to subchapter II (§ 5381 et seq.) of chapter 53 of this title. For complete classification of the Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb335069-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the second par. and par. (3) of section 13 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. Act <date date="1923-03-04">Mar. 4, 1923</date>, split the second par. of section 13, as amended in 1916 (<ref href="/us/stat/39/752">39 Stat. 752</ref>), into two pars., the first of which constitutes the first par. of this section and the second of which constitutes <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s344">section 344 of this title</ref>. Act <date date="1932-07-21">July 21, 1932</date>, added the second par. of this section which was designated to follow the second par. of section 13. <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1101/a/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1101(a)(1)</ref>, designated the second par. as par. (3). For classification to this title of other pars. of section 13, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s342">section 342 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb33506a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1101/a/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1101(a)(1)</ref>–(4), designated second par. as par. (3)(A), substituted “any participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility” for “any individual, partnership, or corporation”, “bill of exchange,” for “bill of exchange for an individual or a partnership or corporation”, and “such participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility” for “such individual, partnership, or corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1101/a/5">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1101(a)(5)</ref>, which directed substitution of “for any participant in any program or facility with broad-based eligibility” for “for individuals, partnerships, corporations”, was executed by making the substitution for “for individuals, partnerships, or corporations”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3)(B) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1101/a/6">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1101(a)(6)</ref>, added subpars. (B) to (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/242">Pub. L. 102–242</ref> struck out “of the kinds and maturities made eligible for discount for member banks under other provisions of this chapter” after first reference to “bills of exchange” in second par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, § 322, substituted words immediately preceding proviso for “indorsed and otherwise secured to the satisfaction of the Federal reserve bank.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1932—Act <date date="1932-07-21">July 21, 1932</date>, added second par.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb33506b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb33506c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb33506d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb33506e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of Div. N of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/tX/s1006">Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2147">134 Stat. 2147</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dN/tX/s1006">“Except as expressly set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) of section 4029 of the CARES Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9063/c/1">15 U.S.C. 9063(c)(1)</ref>, (2)], as added by this Act, nothing in this Act [div. N of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, see Tables for classification] shall be construed to modify or limit the authority of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System under section 13(3) of the Federal Reserve Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343/3">12 U.S.C. 343(3)</ref>) as of the day before the date of enactment of the CARES Act (<ref href="/us/pl/116/136">Public Law 116–136</ref>) [<date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb33506f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Third Undesignated Paragraph Deemed To Be References to Paragraph (3)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1101/c">Pub. L. 111–203, title XI, § 1101(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2115">124 Stat. 2115</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tXI/s1101/c">“On and after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>], any reference in any provision of Federal law to the third undesignated paragraph of section 13 of the Federal Reserve Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343">12 U.S.C. 343</ref>) shall be deemed to be a reference to section 13(3) of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s343/3">12 U.S.C. 343(3)</ref>], as so designated by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
