<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb33508d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s347a"><num value="347a">§ 347a.</num><heading> Advances to member bank groups; inadequate amounts of eligible and acceptable assets; liability of individual banks in group; distribution of loans among banks of group; rate of interest; notes accepted for advances as collateral security for Federal reserve notes; foreign obligations as security for advances</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receiving the consent of not less than five members of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, any Federal reserve bank may make advances, in such amount as the board of directors of such Federal reserve bank may determine, to groups of five or more member banks within its district, a majority of them independently owned and controlled, upon their time or demand promissory notes, provided the bank or banks which receive the proceeds of such advances as herein provided have no adequate amounts of eligible and acceptable assets available to enable such bank or banks to obtain sufficient credit accommodations from the Federal reserve bank through rediscounts or advances other than as provided in section 347b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002039"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title. The liability of the individual banks in each group must be limited to such proportion of the total amount advanced to such group as the deposit liability of the respective banks bears to the aggregate deposit liability of all banks in such group, but such advances may be made to a lesser number of such member banks if the aggregate amount of their deposit liability constitutes at least 10 per centum of the entire deposit liability of the member banks within such district. Such banks shall be authorized to distribute the proceeds of such loans to such of their number and in such amount as they may agree upon, but before so doing they shall require such recipient banks to deposit with a suitable trustee, representing the entire group, their individual notes made in favor of the group protected by such collateral security as may be agreed upon. Any Federal reserve bank making such advance shall charge interest or discount thereon at a rate not less than 1 per centum above its discount rate in effect at the time of making such advance. No such note upon which advances are made by a Federal reserve bank under this section shall be eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s412">section 412 of this title</ref> as collateral security for Federal reserve notes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No obligations of any foreign government, individual, partnership, association, or corporation organized under the laws thereof shall be eligible as collateral security for advances under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Member banks are authorized to obligate themselves in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb33508e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s10A">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 10A</ref>, formerly § 10(a), as added <ref href="/us/act/1932-02-27/ch58/s1">Feb. 27, 1932, ch. 58, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/56">47 Stat. 56</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; renumbered § 10A, <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tI/s142/a/1">Pub. L. 102–242, title I, § 142(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2279">105 Stat. 2279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb33508f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb335090-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb335091-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t12/s347b">Section 347b of this title</ref>, referred to in first par., was in the original a reference to section 10(b), meaning section 10(b) of the Federal Reserve Act. Section 10(b) of that Act was renumbered section 10B by <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tI/s142/a/2">Pub. L. 102–242, title I, § 142(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2279">105 Stat. 2279</ref>, without a corresponding amendment to this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb335092-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb335093-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
