<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb35c23f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s360"><num value="360">§ 360.</num><heading> Receiving checks and drafts on deposit at par; charges for collections, exchange, and clearances</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every Federal reserve bank shall receive on deposit at par from depository institutions or from Federal reserve banks checks and other items, including negotiable orders of withdrawal and share drafts and drafts drawn upon any of its depositors, and when remitted by a Federal reserve bank, checks and other items, including negotiable orders of withdrawal and share drafts and drafts drawn by any depositor in any other Federal reserve bank or depository institution upon funds to the credit of said depositor in said reserve bank or depository institution. Nothing herein contained shall be construed as prohibiting a depository institution from charging its actual expense incurred in collecting and remitting funds, or for exchange sold to its patrons. The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, by rule, fix the charges to be collected by the depository institutions from its patrons whose checks and other items, including negotiable orders of withdrawal and share drafts are cleared through the Federal reserve bank and the charge which may be imposed for the service of clearing or collection rendered by the Federal reserve bank.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb380b30-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s16">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 16</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/265">38 Stat. 265</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tI/s105/c">Pub. L. 96–221, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/140">94 Stat. 140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb380b31-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb380b32-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb380b33-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the twelfth par. (formerly the thirteenth par.) of section 16 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. For classification to this title of other pars. of section 16, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s411">section 411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb380b34-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref>, which directed amendment of “[t]he thirteenth paragraph of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s360">12 U.S.C. 360</ref>)” by substituting “depository institutions” for “member banks” wherever appearing and “depository institution” for “member bank” wherever appearing and by inserting “and other items, including negotiable orders of withdrawal and share drafts” after “checks” wherever appearing, was executed to this section to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb380b35-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb380b36-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb380b37-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> effective on first day of sixth month which begins after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–221</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248">section 248 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
