<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb380b56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s371b"><num value="371b">§ 371b.</num><heading> Rate of interest on time deposits; payment of time deposits before maturity; waiver of notice requirements for withdrawal of savings deposits</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may from time to time, after consulting with the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, prescribe rules governing the advertisement of interest on deposits by member banks on time and savings deposits. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any deposit which is payable only at an office of a member bank located outside of the States of the United States and the District of Columbia. During the period commencing on <date date="1962-10-15">October 15, 1962</date>, and ending on <date date="1968-10-15">October 15, 1968</date>, the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the rate of interest which may be paid by member banks on time deposits of foreign governments, monetary and financial authorities of foreign governments when acting as such, or international financial institutions of which the United States is a member.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb380b57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s19/j">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 19(j)</ref>, formerly § 19 (par. 13), as added <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s11/b">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 11(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/182">48 Stat. 182</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 324(c), <ref href="/us/stat/49/714">49 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/827/s1">Pub. L. 87–827, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/953">76 Stat. 953</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/79/s1">Pub. L. 89–79, § 1</ref>, <date date="1965-07-21">July 21, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/244">79 Stat. 244</ref>; renumbered § 19(j) and amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s2/b">Pub. L. 89–597, § 2(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/824">80 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/505/s2/a">Pub. L. 90–505, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-09-21">Sept. 21, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/856">82 Stat. 856</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tII/s207/b/4">Pub. L. 96–221, title II, § 207(b)(4)</ref>–(6), <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/144">94 Stat. 144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb380b58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb380b59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb380b5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> struck out provisions relating to payment of interest on deposits, prescribing of different limitations by the Board for different classes of deposits, and payment of time deposits before maturity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/505">Pub. L. 90–505</ref> gave Board power to prescribe rules governing the payment and advertising of interest on deposits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s2/c">Pub. L. 89–597, § 2(c)</ref>, made authority of Board to prescribe maximum permissible rates of interest that may be paid by member banks on time and savings deposits discretionary rather than mandatory, required prior consultations with the FDIC Board and the FHLB Board, authorized different rate limitations for different classes of deposits, for deposits of different amounts, or according to such other reasonable bases as the Board may deem desirable in the public interest, and struck out provision for rate limitation according to the varying discount rates of member banks in the several Federal Reserve districts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/79">Pub. L. 89–79</ref> extended until <date date="1968-10-15">Oct. 15, 1968</date>, the period during which the provisions of this paragraph do not apply to the rate of interest payable by member banks on time deposits of foreign governments, monetary and financial authorities of foreign governments when acting as such, or international financial institutions of which the United States is a member.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/827">Pub. L. 87–827</ref> inserted sentence making this paragraph inapplicable, during the period commencing on <date date="1962-10-15">October 15, 1962</date>, and ending upon the expiration of three years after such date, to the rate of interest which may be paid by member banks on time deposits of foreign governments, monetary and financial authorities of foreign governments when acting as such, or international financial institutions of which the United States is a member.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, among other changes, inserted “except upon such conditions and in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the said Board” to second sentence and proviso.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb380b5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb380b5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tII/s207/b">Pub. L. 96–221, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/144">94 Stat. 144</ref>, provided in part that the amendment made by that section is effective 6 years after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb380b5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s7">Pub. L. 89–597, § 7</ref>, <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/825">80 Stat. 825</ref>, as amended, formerly set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 1966 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461">section 461 of this title</ref> (which provided in part that amendment of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s2/c">section 2(c) of Pub. L. 89–597</ref> was effective only to <date date="1980-12-15">Dec. 15, 1980</date>, and that on <date date="1980-12-15">Dec. 15, 1980</date>, this section was amended to read as it would without the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s2/c">section 2(c) of Pub. L. 89–597</ref>), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tII/s207/a">Pub. L. 96–221, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/144">94 Stat. 144</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddb380b5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Home Loan Bank Board abolished and functions transferred, see sections 401 to 406 of <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb380b5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Time Deposits; Interest Rates, Limitation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/123">Pub. L. 93–123</ref>, <date date="1973-10-15">Oct. 15, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/448">87 Stat. 448</ref>, provided that in carrying out the Act of <date date="1966-09-21">September 21, 1966</date> (<ref href="/us/pl/89/597">Pub. L. 89–597</ref>) [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1425b">section 1425b of this title</ref>, amending sections 355, 371b, 461, and 1828 of this title and section 771 of former Title 31, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s462a–1">section 462a–1 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>] and other provisions of law, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board take action to limit rates of interest or dividends paid on time deposits of less than $100,000 by institutions regulated by them, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tII/s207/b/13">Pub. L. 96–221, title II, § 207(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/144">94 Stat. 144</ref>, eff. 6 years after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
