<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb3f37af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s378"><num value="378">§ 378.</num><heading> Dealers in securities engaging in banking business; individuals or associations engaging in banking business; examinations and reports; penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb3f37b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s378/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> After the expiration of one year after <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date>, it shall be unlawful—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb3f37b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s378/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For any person, firm, corporation, association, business trust, or other similar organization, engaged in the business of issuing, underwriting, selling, or distributing, at wholesale or retail, or through syndicate participation, stocks, bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities, to engage at the same time to any extent whatever in the business of receiving deposits subject to check or to repayment upon presentation of a passbook, certificate of deposit, or other evidence of debt, or upon request of the depositor: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this paragraph shall not prohibit national banks or State banks or trust companies (whether or not members of the Federal Reserve System) or other financial institutions or private bankers from dealing in, underwriting, purchasing, and selling investment securities, or issuing securities, to the extent permitted to national banking associations by the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided further</i>, That nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as affecting in any way such right as any bank, banking association, savings bank, trust company, or other banking institution, may otherwise possess to sell, without recourse or agreement to repurchase, obligations evidencing loans on real estate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb3f37b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s378/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For any person, firm, corporation, association, business trust, or other similar organization to engage, to any extent whatever with others than his or its officers, agents or employees, in the business of receiving deposits subject to check or to repayment upon presentation of a pass book, certificate of deposit, or other evidence of debt, or upon request of the depositor, unless such person, firm, corporation, association, business trust, or other similar organization (A) shall be incorporated under, and authorized to engage in such business by, the laws of the United States or of any State, Territory, or District, and subjected, by the laws of the United States, or of the State, Territory, or District wherein located, to examination and regulation, or (B) shall be permitted by the United States, any State, territory, or district to engage in such business and shall be subjected by the laws of the United States, or such State, territory, or district to examination and regulations or, (C) shall submit to periodic examination by the banking authority of the State, Territory, or District where such business is carried on and shall make and publish periodic reports of its condition, exhibiting in detail its resources and liabilities, such examination and reports to be made and published at the same times and in the same manner and under the same conditions as required by the law of such State, Territory, or District in the case of incorporated banking institutions engaged in such business in the same locality.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb3f37b3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s378/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whoever shall willfully violate any of the provisions of this section shall upon conviction be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both, and any officer, director, employee, or agent of any person, firm, corporation, association, business trust, or other similar organization who knowingly participates in any such violation shall be punished by a like fine or imprisonment or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb3f37b4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s21">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 21</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/189">48 Stat. 189</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 303, <ref href="/us/stat/49/707">49 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/230/s23">Pub. L. 86–230, § 23</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/466">73 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tVIII/s804/d">Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 804(d)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/543">82 Stat. 543</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/369/s12">Pub. L. 95–369, § 12</ref>, <date date="1978-09-17">Sept. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/624">92 Stat. 624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb3f37b5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb3f37b6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb3f37b7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/369">Pub. L. 95–369</ref> inserted reference to permission by the United States to engage in such business and subjection by the laws of the United States to examination and regulation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> inserted “, or issuing securities” in first proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/230">Pub. L. 86–230</ref> inserted “and subjected, by the laws of the United States, or of the State, Territory, or District wherein located, to examination and regulation,” after “District,” in cl. (2)(A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, added two provisos to end of par. (1) and amended par. (2) generally.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb3f37b8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb3f37b9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/s808">section 808 of Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1716b">section 1716b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
