<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb3f37c3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s392"><num value="392">§ 392.</num><heading> Depositaries of Government funds as confined to banks in Federal reserve system; member banks as depositaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No public funds of the postal savings, or any Government funds, shall be deposited in the continental United States in any bank not belonging to the system established by this chapter: <i>Provided, however</i>, That nothing in this chapter shall be construed to deny the right of the Secretary of the Treasury to use member banks as depositaries.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb3f37c4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s15">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 15</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/265">38 Stat. 265</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7517, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1352">60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb3f37c5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb3f37c6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb3f37c7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>, known as the Federal Reserve Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb3f37c8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “of the Philippine Islands, or” after “No public funds” were deleted on authority of 1946 Proc. No. 2695, which granted independence to the Philippine Islands pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1394">section 1394 of Title 22</ref>. Proc. No. 2695 is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1394">section 1394 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of second par. of section 15 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. Par. 1 of section 15 and par. 3 of section 15, as added <ref href="/us/act/1923-03-04/ch252">Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 252</ref>, title IV, § 406, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1480">42 Stat. 1480</ref>, are classified to sections 391 and 393, respectively, of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
