<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd177a26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107"><num value="4107">§ 4107.</num><heading> Plan of action</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a27-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a28-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 6 months after receipt of the information from the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4106">section 4106 of this title</ref> an owner seeking to terminate the low-income affordability restrictions through prepayment of the mortgage or voluntary termination under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4108">section 4108 of this title</ref>, or to extend the low-income affordability restriction on the housing under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4109">section 4109 of this title</ref>, shall submit a plan of action to the Secretary in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe. Any owner or purchaser seeking a transfer of the housing under section 4110 or 4111 of this title shall submit a plan of action under this section to the Secretary upon acceptance of a bona fide offer under section 4110(b) or (c) of this title or upon making of any bona fide offer under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4111">section 4111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a29-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Copies to tenants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each owner submitting a plan of action under this section to the Secretary shall also submit a copy to the tenants of the housing. The owner shall simultaneously submit the plan of action to the office of the chief executive officer of the appropriate State or local government for the jurisdiction within which the housing is located. Each owner and the Secretary shall also, upon request, make available to the tenants of the housing and to the office of the chief executive officer of the appropriate State or local government for the jurisdiction within which the housing is located all documentation supporting the plan of action, but not including any information that the Secretary determines is proprietary information. An appropriate agency of such State or local government shall review the plan and advise the tenants of the housing of any programs that are available to assist the tenants in carrying out the purposes of this title.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002364">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002364"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a2a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to submit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the owner does not submit a plan of action to the Secretary within the 6-month period referred to in paragraph (1) (or the applicable longer period), the notice of intent shall be ineffective for purposes of this subchapter and the owner may not submit another notice of intent under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4102">section 4102 of this title</ref> until 6 months after the expiration of such period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a2b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a2c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of affordability restrictions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the plan of action proposes to terminate the low-income affordability restrictions through prepayment or voluntary termination in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4108">section 4108 of this title</ref>, the plan shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a2d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of any proposed changes in the status or terms of the mortgage or regulatory agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a2e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of any proposed changes in the low-income affordability restrictions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a2f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of any change in ownership that is related to prepayment or voluntary termination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a30-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an assessment of the effect of the proposed changes on existing tenants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a31-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> an analysis of the effect of the proposed changes on the supply of housing affordable to low- and very low-income families or persons in the community within which the housing is located and in the area that the housing could reasonably be expected to serve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a32-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any other information that the Secretary determines is necessary to achieve the purposes of this title.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a33-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension of affordability restrictions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the plan of action proposes to extend the low-income affordability restrictions of the housing in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4109">section 4109 of this title</ref> or transfer the housing to a qualified purchaser in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4110">section 4110 of this title</ref>, the plan shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a34-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of any proposed changes in the status or terms of the mortgage or regulatory agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a35-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the Federal incentives requested (including cash flow projections), and analyses of how the owner will address any physical or financial deficiencies and maintain the low-income affordability restrictions of the housing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a36-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of any assistance from State or local government agencies, including low-income housing tax credits, that have been offered to the owner or purchaser or for which the owner or purchaser has applied or intends to apply;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a37-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a description of any transfer of the property, including the identity of the transferee and a copy of any documents of sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd177a38-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> any other information that the Secretary determines is necessary to achieve the purposes of this title.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd177a39-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4107/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Revisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An owner may from time to time revise and amend the plan of action as may be necessary to obtain approval of the plan under this subchapter. The owner shall submit any revision to the Secretary and to the tenants of the housing and make available to the Secretary and tenants all documentation supporting any revision, but not including any information that the Secretary determines is proprietary information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd177a3a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tII/s217">Pub. L. 100–242, title II, § 217</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4254">104 Stat. 4254</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 102–550, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3763">106 Stat. 3763</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd177a3b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd177a3c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd177a3d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (b)(1)(F), (2)(E), means title II of <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4249">104 Stat. 4249</ref>, known as the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4101">section 4101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd177a3e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s304/a">Pub. L. 102–550, § 304(a)</ref>, inserted after second sentence “Each owner and the Secretary shall also, upon request, make available to the tenants of the housing and to the office of the chief executive officer of the appropriate State or local government for the jurisdiction within which the housing is located all documentation supporting the plan of action, but not including any information that the Secretary determines is proprietary information.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s304/b">Pub. L. 102–550, § 304(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and make available to the Secretary and tenants all documentation supporting any revision, but not including any information that the Secretary determines is proprietary information”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
