<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd1c350c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117"><num value="4117">§ 4117.</num><heading> Delegated responsibility to State agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c350d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any responsibilities delegated under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4103/c">section 4103(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall delegate some or all responsibility for implementing this subchapter to a State housing agency if such agency submits a preservation plan acceptable to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c350e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">State preservation plans shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish. The Secretary may approve plans that contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c350f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an inventory of low-income housing located within the State that is or will be eligible low-income housing under this subchapter within 5 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3510-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of the agency’s experience in the area of multifamily financing and restructuring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3511-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a description of the administrative resources that the agency will commit to the processing of plans of action in accordance with this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3512-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a description of the administrative resources that the agency will commit to the monitoring of approved plans of action in accordance with this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3513-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an independent analysis of the performance of the multifamily housing inventory financed or otherwise monitored by the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3514-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a certification by the public official responsible for submitting the comprehensive housing affordability strategy under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12705">section 12705 of title 42</ref> that the proposed activities are consistent with the approved housing strategy of the State within which the eligible low-income housing is located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3515-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> such other certifications or information that the Secretary determines to be necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c3516-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4117/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into any agreements necessary to implement an approved State preservation plan, which may include incentives that are authorized under other provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd1c3517-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tII/s227">Pub. L. 100–242, title II, § 227</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4270">104 Stat. 4270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd1c3518-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd1c3519-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd1c351a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s315">Pub. L. 102–550, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3770">106 Stat. 3770</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s315">“The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall issue interim regulations implementing section 227 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 (as amended by section 601(a) of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4117">12 U.S.C. 4117</ref>] not later than the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>], which shall take effect upon issuance. The Secretary shall issue final regulations implementing such section 227 after notice and opportunity for public comment regarding the interim regulations, pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, United States Code (notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section). The duration of the period for public comment shall not be less than 60 days, and the final regulations shall be issued not later than the expiration of the 60-day period beginning upon the conclusion of the comment period and shall take effect upon issuance.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
