<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd1c3552-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122"><num value="4122">§ 4122.</num><heading> Preemption of State and local laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c3553-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No State or political subdivision of a State may establish, continue in effect, or enforce any law or regulation that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3554-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> restricts or inhibits the prepayment of any mortgage described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4119/1">section 4119(1) of this title</ref> (or the voluntary termination of any insurance contract pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715t">section 1715t of this title</ref>) on eligible low income housing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3555-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> restricts or inhibits an owner of such housing from receiving the authorized annual return provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4104">section 4104 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3556-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is inconsistent with any provision of this subchapter, including any law, regulation, or other restriction that limits or impairs the ability of any owner of eligible low income housing to receive incentives authorized under this subchapter (including authorization to increase rental rates, transfer the housing, obtain secondary financing, or use the proceeds of any of such incentives); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c3557-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in its applicability to low-income housing is limited only to eligible low-income housing for which the owner has prepaid the mortgage or terminated the insurance contract.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any law, regulation, or restriction described under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) shall be ineffective and any eligible low-income housing exempt from the law, regulation, or restriction, only to the extent that it violates the provisions of this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c3558-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4122/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not prevent the establishment, continuing in effect, or enforcement of any law or regulation of any State or political subdivision of a State not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, such as any law or regulation relating to building standards, zoning limitations, health, safety, or habitability standards for housing, rent control, or conversion of rental housing to condominium or cooperative ownership, to the extent such law or regulation is of general applicability to both housing receiving Federal assistance and nonassisted housing. This section shall not preempt, annul, or alter any contractual restrictions or obligations existing before <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, that prevent or limit an owner of eligible low-income housing from prepaying the mortgage on the housing (or terminating the insurance contract on the housing).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd1c3559-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tII/s232">Pub. L. 100–242, title II, § 232</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4273">104 Stat. 4273</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 102–550, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3765">106 Stat. 3765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd1c355a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd1c355b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd1c355c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> substituted “, such as any law or regulation” for “and” after “subchapter”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
