<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd1c3569-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4125"><num value="4125">§ 4125.</num><heading> State preservation project assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c356a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4125/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon application by a State or local housing authority (including public housing agencies), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may make available, from sources of assistance appropriated to preserve the low and moderate income status of projects with expiring Federal use restrictions, assistance to such State or local housing authorities for use in preventing the loss of housing affordable for low and moderate income families that is assisted under a State program under the terms of which the owner may prepay a State assisted or subsidized mortgage on such housing. The application of the State or local housing authority shall demonstrate to the Secretary that the total amount of incentives provided to the owner to induce the owner to preserve the low and moderate income status of the project shall not exceed the level of incentives which may be provided to a similarly situated project with expiring Federal use restrictions under subtitle B of title II of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4101">12 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c356b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4125/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Section 1437f</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of title 42</ref> made available pursuant to this section may be used (i) to supplement any assistance available on existing section 8 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</ref>] contracts, or (ii) to provide additional assistance to structures to ensure that all units occupied by tenants who are lower income families (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/b">section 1437a(b) of title 42</ref>) pay rents not exceeding 30 percent of their adjusted incomes. Any project receiving assistance hereunder shall be subject to standards, inspections and sanctions established by the Secretary under section 222(d) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4112/d">12 U.S.C. 4112(d)</ref>]. Any such section 8 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</ref>] assistance shall be provided for a term and at the fair market rent levels or such higher levels used as applicable for eligible low-income housing that receives incentives under subtitle B of title II of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4101">12 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c356c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4125/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Assistance may be provided under this section only to State and local housing authorities that require any housing receiving such assistance to remain affordable for lower and moderate income tenants for the period during which assistance under this section is received.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddd1c356d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s613/b">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 613(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4280">104 Stat. 4280</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s317/b">Pub. L. 102–550, title III, § 317(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3772">106 Stat. 3772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd1c356e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd1c356f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd1c3570-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing and Community Development Act of 1987, referred to in pars. (1) and (2), is <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1815">101 Stat. 1815</ref>. Subtitle B of title II of the Act is classified generally to this subchapter (§ 4101 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd1c3571-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act, and not as part of the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd1c3572-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> substituted “222(d)” for “224(e)”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
