<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd1c3599-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145"><num value="4145">§ 4145.</num><heading> Delivery of assistance through intermediaries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c359a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve and disburse assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4143">section 4143 of this title</ref> through eligible intermediaries selected by the Secretary under subsection (b). If the Secretary does not receive an acceptable proposal from an intermediary offering to administer assistance under this section in a given State, the Secretary shall administer the program in such State directly.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c359b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of eligible intermediaries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c359c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall develop criteria to select eligible intermediaries, through a competitive process, to administer assistance under this subchapter. The process shall include provision for a reasonable administrative fee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c359d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to all forms of grants available under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4143">section 4143 of this title</ref>, such criteria shall give priority to applications from eligible intermediaries with demonstrated expertise or experience with the program established under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002381">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002381"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or under the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c359e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The criteria developed under this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd1c359f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not assign any preference or priority to applications from eligible intermediaries based on their previous participation in administering or receiving Federal grants or loans (but may exclude applicants who have failed to perform under prior contracts of a similar nature);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd1c35a0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> require an applicant to prepare a proposal that demonstrates adequate staffing, qualifications, prior experience, and a plan for participation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd1c35a1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> permit an applicant to serve as the administrator of assistance made available under section 4143(d) or (e) of this title, based on the applicant’s suitability and interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c35a2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographic coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may select more than 1 State or regional intermediary for a single State or region. The number of intermediaries chosen for each State or region may be based on the number of eligible low-income housing projects in the State or region, provided there is no duplication of geographic coverage by intermediaries in the administration of the direct assistance grant program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c35a3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> National nonprofit intermediaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">National nonprofit intermediaries shall be selected to administer the assistance made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4143">section 4143 of this title</ref> only with respect to States or regions for which no other eligible intermediary, acceptable to the Secretary, has submitted a proposal to participate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c35a4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to assistance made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4144">section 4144 of this title</ref>, preference shall be given to eligible regional, State, and local intermediaries, over national nonprofit organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c35a5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Eligible intermediaries selected under subsection (b) to disburse assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4143">section 4143 of this title</ref> shall certify that they will serve only as delegated program administrators, charged with the responsibility for reviewing and approving grant applications on behalf of the Secretary. Selected intermediaries shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35a6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish appropriate procedures for grant administration and fiscal management, pursuant to standards established by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35a7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> receive a reasonable administrative fee, except that they may not provide other services to grant recipients with respect to projects that are the subject of the grant application and may not receive payment, directly or indirectly, from the proceeds of grants they have approved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd1c35a8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “Eligible intermediary” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “eligible intermediary” means a State, regional, or national organization (including a quasi-public organization) or a State or local housing agency that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35a9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has as a central purpose the preservation of existing affordable housing and the prevention of displacement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35aa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> does not receive direct Federal appropriations for operating support;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35ab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of a national nonprofit organization, has been in existence for at least 5 years prior to the date of application and has been classified by the Internal Revenue Service as an exempt organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35ac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the case of a regional or State nonprofit organization, has been in existence for at least 3 years prior to the date of application and has been classified by the Internal Revenue Service as an exempt organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> or is otherwise a tax-exempt entity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35ad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> has a record of service to low-income individuals or community-based nonprofit housing developers in multiple communities and, with respect to intermediaries administering assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4143">section 4143 of this title</ref>, has experience with the allocation or administration of grant or loan funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd1c35ae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4145/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> meets standards of fiscal responsibility established by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd1c35af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tII/s255">Pub. L. 100–242, title II, § 255</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 102–550, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3767">106 Stat. 3767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd1c35b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd1c35b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd1c35b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), means title II of <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4249">104 Stat. 4249</ref>, known as the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4101">section 4101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1877">101 Stat. 1877</ref>, which was classified principally as a note under section 1715<i>l</i> of this title. Title II of <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4249">104 Stat. 4249</ref>, and is now known as the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4101">section 4101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
