<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb41a809-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s416"><num value="416">§ 416.</num><heading> Withdrawal of collateral deposited to protect notes and substitution of other collateral; retirement of notes; payment of notes of series prior to 1928; recovery of collateral; reissue of deposited notes</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any Federal Reserve bank may at its discretion withdraw collateral deposited with the local Federal Reserve agent for the protection of its Federal Reserve notes issued to it, and shall at the same time substitute therefor other collateral of equal amount with the approval of the Federal Reserve agent under regulations to be prescribed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Any Federal Reserve bank may retire any of its Federal Reserve notes by depositing them with the Federal Reserve agent or with the Treasurer of the United States, and such Federal Reserve bank shall thereupon be entitled to receive back the collateral deposited with the Federal Reserve agent for the security of such notes. Any Federal Reserve bank shall further be entitled to receive back the collateral deposited with the Federal Reserve agent for the security of any notes with respect to which such bank has made payment to the Secretary of the Treasury under section 4 of the Old Series Currency Adjustment Act. Federal Reserve notes so deposited shall not be reissued except upon compliance with the conditions of an original issue.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb41a80a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s16">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 16</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/267">38 Stat. 267</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1917-06-21/ch32/s7">June 21, 1917, ch. 32, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/237">40 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/66/s8/b">Pub. L. 87–66, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/147">75 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/269/s6">Pub. L. 90–269, § 6</ref>, <date date="1968-03-18">Mar. 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/50">82 Stat. 50</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb41a80b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb41a80c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb41a80d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4 of the Old Series Currency Adjustment Act, referred to in text, which was classified to section 913 of former Title 31, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s5/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1068">96 Stat. 1068</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb41a80e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the sixth par. (formerly the seventh par.) of section 16 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. For classification to this title of other pars. of section 16, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s411">section 411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb41a80f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/269">Pub. L. 90–269</ref> repealed fourth sentence which provided that Federal Reserve banks shall not be required to maintain the reserve or the redemption fund against Federal Reserve notes which have been retired, or as to which payment has been made to the Secretary of the Treasury under section 4 of the Old Series Currency Adjustment Act, on notes of series prior to 1928.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/66">Pub. L. 87–66</ref> provided for recovery of collateral upon payment of notes of series prior to 1928 and removed requirement of reserve or redemption fund for such notes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb41a810-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb41a811-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb41a812-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddb41a813-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s55">section 55 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
