<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb41a814-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s417"><num value="417">§ 417.</num><heading> Custody and safe-keeping of notes issued to and collateral deposited with Reserve agent</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All Federal Reserve notes and all gold certificates, Special Drawing Right certificates, and lawful money issued to or deposited with any Federal Reserve agent under the provisions of the Federal Reserve Act shall hereafter be held for such agent, under such rules and regulations as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe, in the joint custody of himself and the Federal Reserve bank to which he is accredited. Such agent and such Federal Reserve bank shall be jointly liable for the safe-keeping of such Federal Reserve notes, gold certificates, Special Drawing Right certificates, and lawful money. Nothing herein contained, however, shall be construed to prohibit a Federal Reserve agent from depositing gold certificates and Special Drawing Right certificates with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, to be held by such Board subject to his order, or with the Treasurer of the United States for the purposes authorized by law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb41a815-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1917-06-21/ch32/s7">June 21, 1917, ch. 32, § 7</ref> (par.), <ref href="/us/stat/40/238">40 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-01-30/ch6/s2/b/6">Jan. 30, 1934, ch. 6, § 2(b)(6)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/339">48 Stat. 339</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/349/s5/c">Pub. L. 90–349, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/189">82 Stat. 189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb41a816-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb41a817-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb41a818-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Reserve Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/251">38 Stat. 251</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s226">section 226 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Hereafter, referred to in text, probably means on and after <date date="1917-06-21">June 21, 1917</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb41a819-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of last par. of section 7 of act <date date="1917-06-21">June 21, 1917</date>. The preceding pars. of section 7 amended pars. two, three, four, five, six, and seven of section 16 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>. For classification to this title of section 16, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s411">section 411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb41a81a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/349">Pub. L. 90–349</ref>, which directed amendment of “[t]he seventh paragraph of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s417">12 U.S.C. 417</ref>)” by inserting “, Special Drawing Right certificates,” after “gold certificates” in the first sentence, “Special Drawing Right certificates,” after “gold certificates,” in the second sentence, and “and Special Drawing Right certificates” after “gold certificates” in the third sentence, was executed by making the insertions in this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-01-30">Jan. 30, 1934</date>, which directed general amendment of the eighth par. of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act, was executed to this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “All Federal reserve notes and all gold, gold certificates, and lawful money issued to or deposited with any Federal reserve agent under the provisions of the Federal reserve Act shall hereafter be held for such agent, under such rules and regulations as the Federal Reserve Board may prescribe, in the joint custody of himself and the Federal reserve bank to which he is accredited. Such agent and such Federal reserve bank shall be jointly liable for the safe-keeping of such Federal reserve notes, gold, gold certificates, and lawful money. Nothing herein contained, however, shall be construed to prohibit a Federal reserve agent from depositing gold or gold certificates with the Federal Reserve Board, to be held by such board subject to his order, or with the Treasurer of the United States for the purposes authorized by law.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb41a81b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb41a81c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb41a81d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddb41a81e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s55">section 55 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
