<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd25ab89-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520"><num value="4520">§ 4520.</num><heading> Minority and women inclusion; diversity requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each regulated entity shall establish an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion, or designate an office of the entity, that shall be responsible for carrying out this section and all matters of the entity relating to diversity in management, employment, and business activities in accordance with such standards and requirements as the Director shall establish.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion in all levels of business activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each regulated entity shall develop and implement standards and procedures to ensure, to the maximum extent possible, the inclusion and utilization of minorities (as such term is defined in section 1204(c) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> note)) and women, and minority- and women-owned businesses (as such terms are defined in section 1441a(r)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002407">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002407"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title) (including financial institutions, investment banking firms, mortgage banking firms, asset management firms, broker-dealers, financial services firms, underwriters, accountants, brokers, investment consultants, and providers of legal services) in all business and activities of the regulated entity at all levels, including in procurement, insurance, and all types of contracts (including contracts for the issuance or guarantee of any debt, equity, or mortgage-related securities, the management of its mortgage and securities portfolios, the making of its equity investments, the purchase, sale and servicing of single- and multi-family mortgage loans, and the implementation of its affordable housing program and initiatives). The processes established by each regulated entity for review and evaluation for contract proposals and to hire service providers shall include a component that gives consideration to the diversity of the applicant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall apply to all contracts of a regulated entity for services of any kind, including services that require the services of investment banking, asset management entities, broker-dealers, financial services entities, underwriters, accountants, investment consultants, and providers of legal services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion in annual reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each regulated entity shall include, in the annual report submitted by the entity to the Director pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1723a/k">section 1723a(k) of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1456/c">section 1456(c) of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1440">section 1440 of this title</ref>, as applicable, detailed information describing the actions taken by the entity pursuant to this section, which shall include a statement of the total amounts paid by the entity to third party contractors since the last such report and the percentage of such amounts paid to businesses described in subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each regulated entity shall establish a minority outreach program to ensure the inclusion (to the maximum extent possible) in contracts entered into by the enterprises of minorities and women and businesses owned by minorities and women, including financial institutions, investment banking firms, underwriters, accountants, brokers, and providers of legal services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd25ab8f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Diversity in Agency workforce</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Agency shall take affirmative steps to seek diversity in its workforce at all levels of the agency consistent with the demographic diversity of the United States, which shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd25ab90-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> heavily recruiting at historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, women’s colleges, and colleges that typically serve majority minority populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd25ab91-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> sponsoring and recruiting at job fairs in urban communities, and placing employment advertisements in newspapers and magazines oriented toward women and people of color;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd25ab92-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> partnering with organizations that are focused on developing opportunities for minorities and women to place talented young minorities and women in industry internships, summer employment, and full-time positions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd25ab93-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4520/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> where feasible, partnering with inner-city high schools, girls’ high schools, and high schools with majority minority populations to establish or enhance financial literacy programs and provide mentoring.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd25ab94-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXIII/s1319A">Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1319A</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3950">106 Stat. 3950</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/dA/tI">Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1116, 1161(a)(2), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2681">122 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2779.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd25ab95-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd25ab96-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd25ab97-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1204(c) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s1204/c">section 1204(c) of Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1441a/r/4">Section 1441a(r)(4) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII/s364/b">Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 364(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1555">124 Stat. 1555</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd281b98-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/1">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(1)</ref>, substituted “Minority and women inclusion; diversity requirements” for “Equal opportunity in solicitation of contracts” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1161/a/2/A">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1161(a)(2)(A)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by striking out subsec. (a) designation and “In general” in subsec. (a) heading, could not be executed because of the prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/2">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(2)</ref>, (4). See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/2">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(2)</ref>, (4), added subsec. (a) and redesignated former subsec. (a) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1161/a/2/B">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1161(a)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed the striking out of subsec. (b), was not executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress. The amendment was probably intended to strike out subsec. (b) as it existed prior to being struck out by <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/3">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(3)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/3">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(3)</ref>, (4), added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Not later than the expiration of the 180-day period beginning on <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, each enterprise shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report describing the actions taken by the enterprise pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/4">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(4)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/2">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (a) as (e) and substituted “Outreach” for “In general” in heading and “Each regulated entity” for “Each enterprise” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s1116/5">Pub. L. 110–289, § 1116(5)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
