<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd281bb5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522"><num value="4522">§ 4522.</num><heading> Public disclosure of final orders and agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bb6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall make available to the public—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd281bb7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any written agreement or other written statement for which a violation may be redressed by the Director or any modification to or termination thereof, unless the Director, in the Director’s discretion, determines that public disclosure would be contrary to the public interest or determines under subsection (c) that public disclosure would seriously threaten the financial health or security of the enterprise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd281bb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any order that is issued with respect to any administrative enforcement proceeding initiated by the Director under subchapter III and that has become final; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd281bb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any modification to or termination of any final order made public pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All hearings on the record with respect to any action of the Director or notice of charges issued by the Director shall be open to the public, unless the Director, in the Director’s discretion, determines that holding an open hearing would be contrary to the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bbb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Delay of public disclosure under exceptional circumstances</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Director makes a determination in writing that the public disclosure of any final order pursuant to subsection (a) would seriously threaten the financial health or security of the enterprise, the Director may delay the public disclosure of such order for a reasonable time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bbc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Documents filed under seal in public enforcement hearings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may file any document or part thereof under seal in any hearing under subchapter III if the Director determines in writing that disclosure thereof would be contrary to the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bbd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of documents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall keep and maintain a record, for not less than 6 years, of all documents described in subsection (a) and all enforcement agreements and other supervisory actions and supporting documents issued with respect to or in connection with any enforcement proceeding initiated by the Director under subchapter III.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd281bbe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4522/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosures to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section may not be construed to authorize the withholding of any information from, or to prohibit the disclosure of any information to, the Congress or any committee or subcommittee thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd281bbf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXIII/s1319C">Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1319C</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3951">106 Stat. 3951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
