<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd2cd7a8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602"><num value="4602">§ 4602.</num><heading> Studies of effects of privatization of FNMA and FHLMC</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7a9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Comptroller General of the United States, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall each conduct and submit to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, a study regarding the desirability and feasibility of repealing the Federal charters of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, eliminating any Federal sponsorship of the enterprises, and allowing the enterprises to continue to operate as fully private entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7aa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each study shall particularly examine the effects of such privatization on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7ab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the requirements applicable to the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation under Federal law and the costs to the enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7ac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the cost of capital to the enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7ad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> housing affordability and availability and the cost of homeownership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7ae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the level of secondary mortgage market competition subsequently available in the private sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> whether increased amounts of capital would be necessary for the enterprises to continue operation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the secondary market for residential loans and the liquidity of such loans; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd2cd7b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> any other factors that the Comptroller General, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Director of the Congressional Budget Office deems appropriate to enable the Congress to evaluate the desirability and feasibility of privatization of the enterprises.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall provide full and prompt access to the Comptroller General, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to any books, records, and other information requested for the purposes of conducting the studies under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7b3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Views of FNMA and FHLMC</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7b4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration in studies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In conducting the studies under this section, the Comptroller General, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall each consider the views of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd2cd7b5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4602/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation may each report directly to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on its own analysis of the desirability and feasibility of repealing the Federal charters of the enterprises, eliminating any Federal sponsorship, and allowing the enterprises to continue to operate as fully private entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd2cd7b6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXIII/s1355">Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1355</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3970">106 Stat. 3970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd2cd7b7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd2cd7b8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddd2cd7b9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
