<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd2cd7ba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4603"><num value="4603">§ 4603.</num><heading> Transition</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Before the expiration of the period ending 18 months after the appointment of the Director under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4512">section 4512 of this title</ref>, any rules and regulations promulgated before <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, by the Secretary pursuant to the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1716">12 U.S.C. 1716</ref> et seq.] or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1451">12 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.] shall remain in effect unless modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by operation of law or in accordance with law. Such rules and regulations shall terminate, effective upon the expiration of such period.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd2cd7bb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tXIII/s1356">Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1356</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3971">106 Stat. 3971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd2cd7bc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd2cd7bd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd2cd7be-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act, referred to in text, is title III of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1252">48 Stat. 1252</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1716 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1716">section 1716 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act, referred to in text, is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/351">Pub. L. 91–351</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/451">84 Stat. 451</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 11A (§ 1451 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title and Statement of Purpose note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
