<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb41a844-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461"><num value="461">§ 461.</num><heading> Reserve requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb41a845-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of applicable definitions, payment of interest, obligations as deposits, and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board is authorized for the purposes of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002046"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> to define the terms used in this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> to determine what shall be deemed a payment of interest, to determine what types of obligations, whether issued directly by a member bank or indirectly by an affiliate of a member bank or by other means, and, regardless of the use of the proceeds, shall be deemed a deposit, and to prescribe such regulations as it may deem necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> and to prevent evasions thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb41a846-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional definitions; required amounts of reserves maintained against transaction accounts; waiver of ratio limits in extraordinary circumstances; supplemental reserves; reserves related to foreign obligations or assets; exemption for certain deposits; discount and borrowing; transitional adjustments; additional exemptions and waivers; earnings on balances</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a847-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The following definitions and rules apply to this subsection, subsection (c), and sections 248–1, 248a, 342, 360, and 412 of this title:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a848-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The term “depository institution” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a849-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any insured bank as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>] or any bank which is eligible to make application to become an insured bank under section 5 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1815">12 U.S.C. 1815</ref>];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any mutual savings bank as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act or any bank which is eligible to make application to become an insured bank under section 5 of such Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any savings bank as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act or any bank which is eligible to make application to become an insured bank under section 5 of such Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any insured credit union as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752">section 1752 of this title</ref> or any credit union which is eligible to make application to become an insured credit union pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1781">section 1781 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> any member as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1422">section 1422 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> any savings association (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>]) which is an insured depository institution (as defined in such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref> et seq.]) or is eligible to apply to become an insured depository institution under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb41a84f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> for the purpose of sections 248–1, 342 to 347, 347c, 347d, and 372 of this title, any association or entity which is wholly owned by or which consists only of institutions referred to in clauses (i) through (vi).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a850-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “bank” means any insured or noninsured bank, as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>], other than a mutual savings bank or a savings bank as defined in such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a851-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The term “transaction account” means a deposit or account on which the depositor or account holder is permitted to make withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instrument, payment orders of withdrawal, telephone transfers, or other similar items for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third persons or others. Such term includes demand deposits, negotiable order of withdrawal accounts, savings deposits subject to automatic transfers, and share draft accounts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a852-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The term “nonpersonal time deposits” means a transferable time deposit or account or a time deposit or account representing funds deposited to the credit of, or in which any beneficial interest is held by, a depositor who is not a natural person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a853-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The term “reservable liabilities” means transaction accounts, nonpersonal time deposits, and all net balances, loans, assets, and obligations which are, or may be, subject to reserve requirements under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a854-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> In order to prevent evasions of the reserve requirements imposed by this subsection, after consultation with the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System is authorized to determine, by regulation or order, that an account or deposit is a transaction account if such account or deposit may be used to provide funds directly or indirectly for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third persons or others.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a855-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a856-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Each depository institution shall maintain reserves against its transaction accounts as the Board may prescribe by regulation solely for the purpose of implementing monetary policy—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a857-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in a ratio of not greater than 3 percent (and which may be zero) for that portion of its total transaction accounts of $25,000,000 or less, subject to subparagraph (C); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a858-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the ratio of 12 per centum, or in such other ratio as the Board may prescribe not greater than 14 per centum (and which may be zero), for that portion of its total transaction accounts in excess of $25,000,000, subject to subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a859-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each depository institution shall maintain reserves against its nonpersonal time deposits in the ratio of 3 per centum, or in such other ratio not greater than 9 per centum and not less than zero per centum as the Board may prescribe by regulation solely for the purpose of implementing monetary policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a85a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Beginning in 1981, not later than December 31 of each year the Board shall issue a regulation increasing for the next succeeding calendar year the dollar amount which is contained in subparagraph (A) or which was last determined pursuant to this subparagraph for the purpose of such subparagraph, by an amount obtained by multiplying such dollar amount by 80 per centum of the percentage increase in the total transaction accounts of all depository institutions. The increase in such transaction accounts shall be determined by subtracting the amount of such accounts on June 30 of the preceding calendar year from the amount of such accounts on June 30 of the calendar year involved. In the case of any such 12-month period in which there has been a decrease in the total transaction accounts of all depository institutions, the Board shall issue such a regulation decreasing for the next succeeding calendar year such dollar amount by an amount obtained by multiplying such dollar amount by 80 per centum of the percentage decrease in the total transaction accounts of all depository institutions. The decrease in such transaction accounts shall be determined by subtracting the amount of such accounts on June 30 of the calendar year involved from the amount of such accounts on June 30 of the previous calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a85b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any reserve requirement imposed under this subsection shall be uniformly applied to all transaction accounts at all depository institutions. Reserve requirements imposed under this subsection shall be uniformly applied to nonpersonal time deposits at all depository institutions, except that such requirements may vary by the maturity of such deposits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a85c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon a finding by at least 5 members of the Board that extraordinary circumstances require such action, the Board, after consultation with the appropriate committees of the Congress, may impose, with respect to any liability of depository institutions, reserve requirements outside the limitations as to ratios and as to types of liabilities otherwise prescribed by paragraph (2) for a period not exceeding 180 days, and for further periods not exceeding 180 days each by affirmative action by at least 5 members of the Board in each instance. The Board shall promptly transmit to the Congress a report of any exercise of its authority under this paragraph and the reasons for such exercise of authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a85d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a85e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Board may, upon the affirmative vote of not less than 5 members, impose a supplemental reserve requirement on every depository institution of not more than 4 per centum of its total transaction accounts. Such supplemental reserve requirement may be imposed only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a85f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the sole purpose of such requirement is to increase the amount of reserves maintained to a level essential for the conduct of monetary policy;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a860-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such requirement is not imposed for the purpose of reducing the cost burdens resulting from the imposition of the reserve requirements pursuant to paragraph (2);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a861-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such requirement is not imposed for the purpose of increasing the amount of balances needed for clearing purposes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a862-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> on the date on which the supplemental reserve requirement is imposed, except as provided in paragraph (11), the total amount of reserves required pursuant to paragraph (2) is not less than the amount of reserves that would be required if the initial ratios specified in paragraph (2) were in effect.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a863-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Board may require the supplemental reserve authorized under subparagraph (A) only after consultation with the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the National Credit Union Administration Board. The Board shall promptly transmit to the Congress a report with respect to any exercise of its authority to require supplemental reserves under subparagraph (A) and such report shall state the basis for the determination to exercise such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a864-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If a supplemental reserve under subparagraph (A) has been required of depository institutions for a period of one year or more, the Board shall review and determine the need for continued maintenance of supplemental reserves and shall transmit annual reports to the Congress regarding the need, if any, for continuing the supplemental reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a865-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any supplemental reserve imposed under subparagraph (A) shall terminate at the close of the first 90-day period after such requirement is imposed during which the average amount of reserves required under paragraph (2) are less than the amount of reserves which would be required during such period if the initial ratios specified in paragraph (2) were in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a866-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Foreign branches, subsidiaries, and international banking facilities of nonmember depository institutions shall maintain reserves to the same extent required by the Board of foreign branches, subsidiaries, and international banking facilities of member banks. In addition to any reserves otherwise required to be maintained pursuant to this subsection, any depository institution shall maintain reserves in such ratios as the Board may prescribe against—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a867-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> net balances owed by domestic offices of such depository institution in the United States to its directly related foreign offices and to foreign offices of nonrelated depository institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a868-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> loans to United States residents made by overseas offices of such depository institution if such depository institution has one or more offices in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb41a869-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> assets (including participations) held by foreign offices of a depository institution in the United States which were acquired from its domestic offices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The requirements imposed under paragraph (2) shall not apply to deposits payable only outside the States of the United States and the District of Columbia, except that nothing in this subsection limits the authority of the Board to impose conditions and requirements on member banks under section 25 of this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s601">12 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.] or the authority of the Board under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3105">section 3105 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any depository institution in which transaction accounts or nonpersonal time deposits are held shall be entitled to the same discount and borrowing privileges as member banks. In the administration of discount and borrowing privileges, the Board and the Federal Reserve banks shall take into consideration the special needs of savings and other depository institutions for access to discount and borrowing facilities consistent with their long-term asset portfolios and the sensitivity of such institutions to trends in the national money markets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any depository institution required to maintain reserves under this subsection which was engaged in business on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, but was not a member of the Federal Reserve System on or after that date, shall maintain reserves against its deposits during the first twelve-month period following the effective date of this paragraph in amounts equal to one-eighth of those otherwise required by this subsection, during the second such twelve-month period in amounts equal to one-fourth of those otherwise required, during the third such twelve-month period in amounts equal to three-eighths of those otherwise required, during the fourth twelve-month period in amounts equal to one-half of those otherwise required, and during the fifth twelve-month period in amounts equal to five-eighths of those otherwise required, during the sixth twelve-month period in amounts equal to three-fourths of those otherwise required, and during the seventh twelve-month period in amounts equal to seven-eighths of those otherwise required. This subparagraph does not apply to any category of deposits or accounts which are first authorized pursuant to Federal law in any State after <date date="1980-04-01">April 1, 1980</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> With respect to any bank which was a member of the Federal Reserve System during the entire period beginning on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, and ending on the effective date of the Monetary Control Act of 1980, the amount of required reserves imposed pursuant to this subsection on and after the effective date of such Act that exceeds the amount of reserves which would have been required of such bank if the reserve ratios in effect during the reserve computation period immediately preceding such effective date were applied may, at the discretion of the Board and in accordance with such rules and regulations as it may adopt, be reduced by 75 per centum during the first year which begins after such effective date, 50 per centum during the second year, and 25 per centum during the third year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a86f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a870-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> With respect to any bank which is a member of the Federal Reserve System on the effective date of the Monetary Control Act of 1980, the amount of reserves which would have been required of such bank if the reserve ratios in effect during the reserve computation period immediately preceding such effective date were applied that exceeds the amount of required reserves imposed pursuant to this subsection shall, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Board may adopt, be reduced by 25 per centum during the first year which begins after such effective date, 50 per centum during the second year, and 75 per centum during the third year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a871-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If a bank becomes a member bank during the four-year period beginning on the effective date of the Monetary Control Act of 1980, and if the amount of reserves which would have been required of such bank, determined as if the reserve ratios in effect during the reserve computation period immediately preceding such effective date were applied, and as if such bank had been a member during such period, exceeds the amount of reserves required pursuant to this subsection, the amount of reserves required to be maintained by such bank beginning on the date on which such bank becomes a member of the Federal Reserve System shall be the amount of reserves which would have been required of such bank if it had been a member on the day before such effective date, except that the amount of such excess shall, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Board may adopt, be reduced by 25 per centum during the first year which begins after such effective date, 50 per centum during the second year, and 75 per centum during the third year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a872-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a873-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any bank which was a member bank on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, and which withdrew from membership in the Federal Reserve System during the period beginning <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, and ending on <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, shall maintain reserves during the first twelve-month period beginning on <date date="1982-10-15">October 15, 1982</date>, in amounts equal to one-half of those otherwise required by this subsection, during the second such twelve-month period in amounts equal to two-thirds of those otherwise required, and during the third such twelve-month period in amounts equal to five-sixths of those otherwise required.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a874-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any bank which withdraws from membership in the Federal Reserve System after <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, shall maintain reserves in the same amount as member banks are required to maintain under this subsection, pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb41a875-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/8/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> This subparagraph applies to any depository institution that, on <date date="1978-08-01">August 1, 1978</date>, (i) was engaged in business as a depository institution in a State outside the continental limits of the United States, and (ii) was not a member of the Federal Reserve System at any time on or after such date. Such a depository institution shall not be required to maintain reserves against its deposits held or maintained at its offices located in a State outside the continental limits of the United States until the first day of the sixth calendar year which begins after the effective date of the Monetary Control Act of 1980. Such a depository institution shall maintain reserves against such deposits during the sixth calendar year which begins after such effective date in an amount equal to one-eighth of that otherwise required by paragraph (2), during the seventh such year in an amount equal to one-fourth of that otherwise required, during the eighth such year in an amount equal to three-eighths of that otherwise required, during the ninth such year in an amount equal to one-half of that otherwise required, during the tenth such year in an amount equal to five-eighths of that otherwise required, during the eleventh such year in an amount equal to three-fourths of that otherwise required, and during the twelfth such year in an amount equal to seven-eighths of that otherwise required.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb441976-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> This subsection shall not apply with respect to any financial institution which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441977-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is organized solely to do business with other financial institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441978-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is owned primarily by the financial institutions with which it does business; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441979-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not do business with the general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> In individual cases, where a Federal supervisory authority waives a liquidity requirement, or waives the penalty for failing to satisfy a liquidity requirement, the Board shall waive the reserve requirement, or waive the penalty for failing to satisfy a reserve requirement, imposed pursuant to this subsection for the depository institution involved when requested by the Federal supervisory authority involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Notwithstanding the reserve requirement ratios established under paragraphs (2) and (5) of this subsection, a reserve ratio of zero per centum shall apply to any combination of reservable liabilities, which do not exceed $2,000,000 (as adjusted under subparagraph (B)), of each depository institution.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Each depository institution may designate, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Board shall prescribe, the types and amounts of reservable liabilities to which the reserve ratio of zero per centum shall apply, except that transaction accounts which are designated to be subject to a reserve ratio of zero per centum shall be accounts which would otherwise be subject to a reserve ratio of 3 per centum under paragraph (2).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44197f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Board shall minimize the reporting necessary to determine whether depository institutions have total reservable liabilities of less than $2,000,000 (as adjusted under subparagraph (B)). Consistent with the Board’s responsibility to monitor and control monetary and credit aggregates, depository institutions which have reserve requirements under this subsection equal to zero per centum shall be subject to less overall reporting requirements than depository institutions which have a reserve requirement under this subsection that exceeds zero per centum.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb441980-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb441981-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Beginning in 1982, not later than December 31 of each year, the Board shall issue a regulation increasing for the next succeeding calendar year the dollar amount specified in subparagraph (A), as previously adjusted under this subparagraph, by an amount obtained by multiplying such dollar amount by 80 per centum of the percentage increase in the total reservable liabilities of all depository institutions.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb441982-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/11/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The increase in total reservable liabilities shall be determined by subtracting the amount of total reservable liabilities on June 30 of the preceding calendar year from the amount of total reservable liabilities on June 30 of the calendar year involved. In the case of any such twelve-month period in which there has been a decrease in the total reservable liabilities of all depository institutions, no adjustment shall be made. A decrease in total reservable liabilities shall be determined by subtracting the amount of total reservable liabilities on June 30 of the calendar year involved from the amount of total reservable liabilities on June 30 of the previous calendar year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb441983-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Earnings on balances.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441984-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Balances maintained at a Federal Reserve bank by or on behalf of a depository institution may receive earnings to be paid by the Federal Reserve bank at least once each calendar quarter, at a rate or rates not to exceed the general level of short-term interest rates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441985-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations relating to payments and distributions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Board may prescribe regulations concerning—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb441986-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the payment of earnings in accordance with this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb441987-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the distribution of such earnings to the depository institutions which maintain balances at such banks, or on whose behalf such balances are maintained; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb441988-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the responsibilities of depository institutions, Federal Home Loan Banks, and the National Credit Union Administration Central Liquidity Facility with respect to the crediting and distribution of earnings attributable to balances maintained, in accordance with subsection (c)(1)(A), in a Federal Reserve bank by any such entity on behalf of depository institutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb441989-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/b/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Depository institutions defined</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, the term “depository institution”, in addition to the institutions described in paragraph (1)(A), includes any trust company, corporation organized under section 25A [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s611">12 U.S.C. 611</ref> et seq.] or having an agreement with the Board under section 25 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s601">12 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.], or any branch or agency of a foreign bank (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb44198a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of rules and regulations respecting maintenance of balances</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44198b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Reserves held by a depository institution to meet the requirements imposed pursuant to subsection (b) shall, subject to such rules and regulations as the Board shall prescribe, be in the form of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb44198c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> balances maintained for such purposes by such depository institution in the Federal Reserve bank of which it is a member or at which it maintains an account, except that (i) the Board may, by regulation or order, permit depository institutions to maintain all or a portion of their required reserves in the form of vault cash, except that any portion so permitted shall be identical for all depository institutions, and (ii) vault cash may be used to satisfy any supplemental reserve requirement imposed pursuant to subsection (b)(4), except that all such vault cash shall be excluded from any computation of earnings pursuant to subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb44198d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> balances maintained by a depository institution in a depository institution which maintains required reserve balances at a Federal Reserve bank, in a Federal Home Loan Bank, or in the National Credit Union Administration Central Liquidity Facility, if such depository institution, Federal Home Loan Bank, or National Credit Union Administration Central Liquidity Facility maintains such funds in the form of balances in a Federal Reserve bank of which it is a member or at which it maintains an account. Balances received by a depository institution from a second depository institution and used to satisfy the reserve requirement imposed on such second depository institution by this section shall not be subject to the reserve requirements of this section imposed on such first depository institution, and shall not be subject to assessments or reserves imposed on such first depository institution pursuant to section 7 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1817">12 U.S.C. 1817</ref>), section 404 of the National Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1727">12 U.S.C. 1727</ref>),<sup>1</sup> or section 202 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1782">12 U.S.C. 1782</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb44198e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s461/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The balances maintained to meet the reserve requirements of subsection (b) by a depository institution in a Federal Reserve bank or passed through a Federal Home Loan Bank or the National Credit Union Administration Central Liquidity Facility or another depository institution to a Federal Reserve bank may be used to satisfy liquidity requirements which may be imposed under other provisions of Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb44198f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s19/a">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 19(a)</ref>–(c), formerly § 19 (pars.), <ref href="/us/stat/38/270">38 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1917-06-21/ch32/s10">June 21, 1917, ch. 32, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/239">40 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 324(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/714">49 Stat. 714</ref>; renumbered § 19(a)–(c) and amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s2/a">Pub. L. 89–597, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/823">80 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/151/tI">Pub. L. 91–151, title I</ref>, §§ 4(a), 5, <date date="1969-12-23">Dec. 23, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/374">83 Stat. 374</ref>, 375; <ref href="/us/pl/93/501/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 93–501, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1557">88 Stat. 1557</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tI">Pub. L. 96–221, title I</ref>, §§ 103, 104(a), <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/133">94 Stat. 133</ref>, 138; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s385">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 385</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/433">95 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 97–320, title IV, § 411</ref>, title VII, § 708, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1520">96 Stat. 1520</ref>, 1540; <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tVII/s744/i/2">Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744(i)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/439">103 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tII">Pub. L. 109–351, title II</ref>, §§ 201, 202, title VI, § 603, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1968">120 Stat. 1968</ref>, 1969, 1980; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII/s366/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 366(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1556">124 Stat. 1556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb441990-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb441991-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb441992-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section, referred to in subsec. (a), means section 19 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, which is classified to sections 142, 371b, 371b–1, 374, 374a, 461, 463 to 466, 505, and 506 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Deposit Insurance Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A)(vi), is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-21/ch967/s2">act Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/873">64 Stat. 873</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1811 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 25 of this Act and section 25, referred to in subsec. (b)(6), (12)(C), mean section 25 of <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, which is classified to subchapter I (§ 601 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For the effective date of the Monetary Control Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (b)(8), see <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–221</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248">section 248 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 25A, referred to in subsec. (b)(12)(C), means section 25A of <ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6">act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6</ref>, known as the Edge Act, which is classified to subchapter II (§ 611 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 404 of the National Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1727">12 U.S.C. 1727</ref>), referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(B), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 101–73, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/363">103 Stat. 363</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb441993-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of subsecs. (a) to (c), formerly first six pars., of section 19 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date> (such first, second through fifth, and sixth pars. formerly classified to sections 461, 462, and 462b of this title, respectively), as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/89/597">Pub. L. 89–597</ref>. For credits prior to enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/89/597">Pub. L. 89–597</ref> on <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, see notes set out under sections 462 and 462b of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb441994-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(1)(F), (4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> substituted “Comptroller of the Currency” for “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s202">Pub. L. 109–351, § 202</ref>, substituted “a ratio of not greater than 3 percent (and which may be zero)” for “the ratio of 3 per centum” in cl. (i) and “(and which may be zero),” for “and not less than 8 per centum,” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(C) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 109–351, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (D) and (E) as (C) and (D), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “The supplemental reserve authorized under subparagraph (A) shall be maintained by the Federal Reserve banks in an Earnings Participation Account. Except as provided in subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii) of this section, such Earnings Participation Account shall receive earnings to be paid by the Federal Reserve banks during each calendar quarter at a rate not more than the rate earned on the securities portfolio of the Federal Reserve System during the previous calendar quarter. The Board may prescribe rules and regulations concerning the payment of earnings on Earnings Participation Accounts by Federal Reserve banks under this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s201/a">Pub. L. 109–351, § 201(a)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s201/b/2">Pub. L. 109–351, § 201(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)” for “subsection (b)(4)(C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/s603">Pub. L. 109–351, § 603</ref>, struck out “which is not a member bank” after “balances maintained by a depository institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s744/i/2">Pub. L. 101–73, § 744(i)(2)</ref>, amended cl. (vi) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (vi) read as follows: “any insured institution as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1724">section 1724 of this title</ref> or any institution which is eligible to make application to become an insured institution under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1726">section 1726 of this title</ref>; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(F), (4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/s744/i/3">Pub. L. 101–73, § 744(i)(3)</ref>, substituted “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision” for “Federal Home Loan Bank Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (b)(1)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s411/c">Pub. L. 97–320, § 411(c)</ref>, added subpar. (E) and redesignated former subpar. (E) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s411/b">Pub. L. 97–320, § 411(b)</ref>, inserted “except as provided in paragraph (11)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s708/1">Pub. L. 97–320, § 708(1)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to reserve requirements for banks which withdraw from the Federal Reserve System for provision that any bank which was a member bank on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, and which withdrew from membership in the Federal Reserve System during the period beginning on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, and ending on the day before <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, would maintain reserves beginning on <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, in an amount equal to the amount of reserves it would have been required to maintain if it had been a member bank on <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, and that after <date date="1980-03-31">March 31, 1980</date>, any such bank was directed to maintain reserves in the same amounts as member banks were required to maintain under this subsection, pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C)(i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(D)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s708/2">Pub. L. 97–320, § 708(2)</ref>, struck out “on or” after “Reserve System”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/s411/a">Pub. L. 97–320, § 411(a)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b)(8)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted provisions relating to applicability to any depository institution that was on <date date="1978-08-01">Aug. 1, 1978</date>, engaged in such business in a State outside the continental limits and was not a member of the Federal Reserve System at any time on or after such date, for provisions relating to applicability to any depository institution that was on <date date="1978-08-01">Aug. 1, 1978</date>, engaged in such business under the laws of a State, was not a member of the Federal Reserve System on that date, and the principal office of which was outside the continental limits on that date and has remained outside ever since.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s103">Pub. L. 96–221, § 103</ref>, substituted provisions setting forth additional definitions applicable to reserve requirements and requirements respecting amounts of reserves maintained against transaction accounts, waiver of ratio limits in extraordinary circumstances, supplemental reserves, reserves related to foreign obligations or assets, exemptions for certain deposits, discounts and borrowings, transitional adjustments, and additional exemptions and waivers, for provisions relating to determinations respecting maintenance of reserves against deposits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s104/a">Pub. L. 96–221, § 104(a)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to the promulgation of rules and regulations respecting maintenance of balances, for provisions relating to form of reserves held by member banks.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/501">Pub. L. 93–501</ref> substituted “and, regardless of the use of the proceeds, shall be deemed a deposit” for “shall be deemed a deposit”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/151/s4/a">Pub. L. 91–151, § 4(a)</ref>, authorized Board to determine type of obligations that would be deemed deposits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/151/s5">Pub. L. 91–151, § 5</ref>, authorized Board to prescribe ratio of indebtedness of member banks to foreign banks, up to a maximum of 22 percent.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/597">Pub. L. 89–597</ref> designated first par. provisions of section 19 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, as subsec. (a), substituted a general provision authorizing Board to define terms used in sections 142, 371a, 371b, 374, 374a, and 463 to 466 of this title for former provisions defining terms “demand deposits”, “gross demand deposits”, “deposits payable on demand”, “time deposits”, “savings deposits”, and “trust funds”, struck out inclusion of “savings deposits” in term “time deposits” in regard to reserve requirements of member banks, and added subsecs. (b) and (c) to such section 19, superseding second through sixth pars., which authorized Board to fix reserve requirements against time deposits between the limits of 3 and 10 percent, in lieu of prior limits of 3 and 6 percent, and struck out provision for modification of reserve requirements to prevent injurious credit to expansion or contraction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, abrogated statutory construction of demand deposits.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb441995-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb441996-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s351">section 351 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb441997-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tII/s203">Pub. L. 109–351, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1969">120 Stat. 1969</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/343/dA/tI/s128">Pub. L. 110–343, div. A, title I, § 128</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3796">122 Stat. 3796</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/343/dA/tI/s128">“The amendments made by this title [amending this section] shall take effect <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb441998-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> effective on first day of sixth month which begins after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, except that the amendments regarding subsec. (b)(7) and (8)(D) effective on <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–221</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s248">section 248 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb441999-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/501/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 93–501, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1557">88 Stat. 1557</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/501/tI/s101/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall not apply to any bank holding company which has filed prior to the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>], an irrevocable declaration with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to divest itself of all of its banks under section 4 of the Bank Holding Company Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1843">12 U.S.C. 1843</ref>], or to any debt obligation which is an exempted security under section 3(a)(3) of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77c/a/3">15 U.S.C. 77c(a)(3)</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb44199a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s7">Pub. L. 89–597, § 7</ref>, <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/825">80 Stat. 825</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/90/87">Pub. L. 90–87</ref>, <date date="1967-09-21">Sept. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/226">81 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/505/s1">Pub. L. 90–505, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-09-21">Sept. 21, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/856">82 Stat. 856</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/71">Pub. L. 91–71</ref>, <date date="1969-09-22">Sept. 22, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/115">83 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/151/tI/s1">Pub. L. 91–151, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-12-23">Dec. 23, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/371">83 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/8/s1">Pub. L. 92–8, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-03-31">Mar. 31, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/13">85 Stat. 13</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/15/s1">Pub. L. 92–15, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-05-18">May 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/38">85 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/63">Pub. L. 93–63</ref>, <date date="1973-07-06">July 6, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/147">87 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/100/s1">Pub. L. 93–100, § 1</ref>, <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/342">87 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tI/s107">Pub. L. 93–495, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1505">88 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/200/tI/s101">Pub. L. 94–200, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1124">89 Stat. 1124</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/22/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–22, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-04-19">Apr. 19, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/49">91 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/188/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–188, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1387">91 Stat. 1387</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXVI/s1601">Pub. L. 95–630, title XVI, § 1601</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3713">92 Stat. 3713</ref>, which provided effective and termination dates for 1966 amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/89/597">Pub. L. 89–597</ref> (affecting sections 371b, 1425b, and 1828(g) of this title), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tII/s207/a">Pub. L. 96–221, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/144">94 Stat. 144</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb44199b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Elimination or Reduction of Interest Rate Differential Between Savings Banks and Savings and Loan, Building and Loan, or Homestead Associations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/200/tI/s102">Pub. L. 94–200, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1124">89 Stat. 1124</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXVI/s1602">Pub. L. 95–630, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3713">92 Stat. 3713</ref>, which had provided that an interest rate differential for any category of deposits or accounts which was in effect on <date date="1975-12-10">December 10, 1975</date>, between (1) any bank (other than a savings bank) the deposits of which were insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and (2) any savings and loan, building and loan, or homestead association (including cooperative banks) the deposits or accounts of which were insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or any mutual savings bank as defined in section 3(f) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/j">12 U.S.C. 1813(j)</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/f">section 1813(f) of this title</ref>] could not be eliminated or reduced unless (A) written notification was given by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to the Congress; and (B) the House of Representatives and the Senate approved, by concurrent resolution, the proposed elimination or reduction of the interest rate differential, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tIII/s326/a">Pub. L. 97–320, title III, § 326(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1500">96 Stat. 1500</ref>. See section 326(b)–(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1828">section 1828 of this title</ref>. See, also, <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s207/b/1">section 207(b)(1) of Pub. L. 96–221</ref> providing for repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/94/200/s102">section 102 of Pub. L. 94–200</ref> effective 6 years after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb44199c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interest Rates: Controls</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s1">Pub. L. 89–597, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/823">80 Stat. 823</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/597/s1">“The Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, in implementation of their respective powers under existing law and this Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1425b">section 1425b of this title</ref>, amending this section, sections 355, 371b, and 1828 of this title, and section 771 of former Title 31, Money and Finance, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s462a–1">section 462a–1 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section], shall take action to bring about the reduction of interest rates to the maximum extent feasible in the light of prevailing money market and general economic conditions.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective and termination dates of control of interest rates provisions, see Effective and Termination Dates of 1966 Amendment note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb44199d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Outstanding Rate Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/597/s5">Pub. L. 89–597, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/825">80 Stat. 825</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/597/s5">“Any regulation prescribed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation with respect to the payment of deposits and interest thereon by member banks or insured nonmember banks which is in effect when this Act is enacted [<date date="1966-09-21">Sept. 21, 1966</date>] shall continue in effect unless and until it is modified or rescinded after consultation with the Board of Directors or the Board of Governors, as the case may be, and the Federal Home Loan Bank Board.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective and termination dates of existing rate regulations, see Effective and Termination Dates of 1966 Amendment note under this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
