<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd38bed4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708"><num value="4708">§ 4708.</num><heading> Training</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38bed5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Fund may operate a training program to increase the capacity and expertise of community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry to undertake community development finance activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38bed6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Program activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The training program shall provide educational programs to assist community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry in developing lending and investment products, underwriting and servicing loans, managing equity investments, and providing development services targeted to areas of economic distress, low-income persons, and persons who lack adequate access to loans and equity investments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38bed7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The training program shall be made available to community development financial institutions and other members of the financial services industry that serve or seek to serve areas of economic distress, low-income persons, and persons who lack adequate access to loans and equity investments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38bed8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Fund may offer the training program described in this section directly or through a contract with other organizations. The Fund may contract to provide the training program through organizations that possess special expertise in community development, without regard to whether the organizations receive or are eligible to receive assistance under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2ed9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Fund shall coordinate with other appropriate Federal departments or agencies that operate similar training programs in order to prevent duplicative efforts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2eda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulatory fee for providing training services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2edb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Fund may, at the discretion of the Administrator and in accordance with this subsection, assess and collect regulatory fees solely to cover the costs of the Fund in providing training services under a training program operated in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2edc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons subject to fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Fees may be assessed under paragraph (1) only on persons who participate in the training program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2edd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on manner of collection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Fees may be assessed and collected under this subsection only in such manner as may reasonably be expected to result in the collection of an aggregate amount of fees during any fiscal year which does not exceed the aggregate costs of the Fund for such year in providing training services under a training program operated in accordance with this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002435">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002435"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd3b2ede-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s4708/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on amount of fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount of any fee assessed under this subsection on any person may not exceed the amount which is reasonably based on the proportion of the training services provided under a training program operated in accordance with this section which relate to such person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd3b2edf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tI/s109">Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2176">108 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
