<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb0f9bb3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s51a"><num value="51a">§ 51a.</num><heading> Preferred stock; issuance authorized</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any national banking association may, with the approval of the Comptroller of the Currency and by vote of shareholders owning a majority of the stock of such association, upon not less than five days’ notice, given by registered mail or by certified mail pursuant to action taken by its board of directors, issue preferred stock of one or more classes, in such amount and with such par value as shall be approved by said Comptroller, and make such amendments to its articles of association as may be necessary for this purpose; but, in the case of any newly organized national banking association which has not yet issued common stock, the requirement of notice to and vote of shareholders shall not apply. No issue of preferred stock shall be valid until the par value of all stock so issued shall be paid in and notice thereof, duly acknowledged before a notary public by the president, vice president, or cashier of said association, has been transmitted to the Comptroller of the Currency and his certificate obtained specifying the amount of such issue of preferred stock and his approval thereof and that the amount has been duly paid in as a part of the capital of such association; which certificate shall be deemed to be conclusive evidence that such preferred stock has been duly and validly issued.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb0f9bb4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-03-09/ch1">Mar. 9, 1933, ch. 1</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref href="/us/stat/48/5">48 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-06-15/ch79">June 15, 1933, ch. 79</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/147">48 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title III, § 336, <ref href="/us/stat/49/720">49 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/507/s1/9">Pub. L. 86–507, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/200">74 Stat. 200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb0f9bb5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb0f9bb6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb0f9bb7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/507">Pub. L. 86–507</ref> inserted “or by certified mail” after “registered mail”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, amended last sentence generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1933—Act <date date="1933-06-15">June 15, 1933</date>, struck out all of former section and inserted a new section which incorporated all former provisions and inserted “of one or more classes,” in first sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb0f9bb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb0f9bb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception as to Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by any provision of law in Comptroller of the Currency, referred to in this section, not included in transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
