<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd4985df-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201"><num value="5201">§ 5201.</num><heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd4985e0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to immediately provide authority and facilities that the Secretary of the Treasury can use to restore liquidity and stability to the financial system of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd4985e1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> to ensure that such authority and such facilities are used in a manner that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd4985e2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> protects home values, college funds, retirement accounts, and life savings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd4985e3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> preserves homeownership and promotes jobs and economic growth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd4985e4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> maximizes overall returns to the taxpayers of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd4985e5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5201/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> provides public accountability for the exercise of such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddd4985e6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/343/dA/s2">Pub. L. 110–343, div. A, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3766">122 Stat. 3766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd4985e7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd4985e8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd4985e9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this division”, meaning div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/110/343">Pub. L. 110–343</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3765">122 Stat. 3765</ref>, known as the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. For complete classification of division A to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd4985ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddd4985eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 111–203, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2133">124 Stat. 2133</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tXIII/s1301">“This title [amending sections 1431, 1455, 1719, 5216, and 5225 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1455">section 1455 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Pay It Back Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddd4985ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2009 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/22/dA/s1/a">Pub. L. 111–22, div. A, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-20">May 20, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1632">123 Stat. 1632</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/22/dA/s1/a">“This division [enacting sections 1715z–25, 1735f–10, 1790e, 5220a, and 5231a of this title, amending sections 1708, 1710, 1715u, 1715z–20, 1715z–23, 1715z–24, 1735f–14, 1782, 1783, 1817, 1823, 1824, 5221, 5225, 5226, 5233, and 5241 of this title, sections 1639a, 1640, and 1641 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s714">section 714 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3703">section 3703 of Title 38</ref>, Veterans’ Benefits, and sections 1437f and 1472 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1735f–10">section 1735f–10 of this title</ref>, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section, sections 1708, 1715u, and 5220 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639a">section 1639a of Title 15</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3703">section 3703 of Title 38</ref>, and sections 1437f, 1472, and 5301 of Title 42, amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of Title 42</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5220">section 5220 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Helping Families Save Their Homes Act of 2009’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/22/dA/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 111–22, div. A, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2009-05-20">May 20, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1660">123 Stat. 1660</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/22/dA/tVII/s701">“This title [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5220">section 5220 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5220">section 5220 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s704">Section 704 of Pub. L. 111–22</ref>, as amended, formerly set out as a Termination Date of 2009 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, which provided that title VII of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/22">Pub. L. 111–22</ref>, and the amendments made such title, are repealed, and the requirements under such title terminated, effective <date date="2014-12-31">Dec. 31, 2014</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tIII/s304/a">Pub. L. 115–174, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1339">132 Stat. 1339</ref>, effective 30 days after <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/111/22/s701">Section 701 of Pub. L. 111–22</ref>, provisions of law amended by such section, and any regulations promulgated pursuant to such section, as in effect on <date date="2014-12-30">Dec. 30, 2014</date>, restored and revived, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s304/b">section 304(b) of Pub. L. 115–174</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.]</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/15/s1">Pub. L. 111–15, § 1</ref>, <date date="2009-04-24">Apr. 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1603">123 Stat. 1603</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/15/s1">“This Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5231">section 5231 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under section 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/452">Pub. L. 95–452</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees] may be cited as the ‘Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program Act of 2009’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="iddd4985ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/343/dA/s1/a">Pub. L. 110–343, div. A, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3765">122 Stat. 3765</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/343/dA/s1/a">“This division [enacting this chapter, amending sections 1715z–23, 1818, 1823, and 1828 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1638">section 1638 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, sections 108, 162, and 280G of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code, and sections 301, 1105, and 3101 of Title 31, Money and Finance, enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1638">section 1638 of Title 15</ref>, sections 108, 162, and 280G of Title 26, and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of Title 31</ref>, and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddd4985ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddd4985ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13501</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13501, <date date="2009-02-06">Feb. 6, 2009</date>, 74 F.R. 6983, which established the President’s Economic Recovery Advisory Board, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13564, § 5, <date date="2011-01-31">Jan. 31, 2011</date>, 76 F.R. 6310, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddd4985f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13564. Establishment of the President’s Council on Jobs and Competitiveness</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13564, <date date="2011-01-31">Jan. 31, 2011</date>, 76 F.R. 6309, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to continue to strengthen the Nation’s economy and ensure the competitiveness of the United States and to create jobs, opportunity, and prosperity for the American people by ensuring the availability of non-partisan advice to the President from participants in and experts on the economy, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. There is hereby established within the Department of the Treasury the President’s Council on Jobs and Competitiveness (PCJC). The PCJC shall consist of members appointed by the President from among distinguished citizens outside the Federal Government and shall include citizens chosen to serve as representatives of the various sectors of the economy to offer the diverse perspectives of the private sector, employers, and workers on how the Federal Government can best foster growth, competitiveness, innovation, and job creation. The members may also include citizens selected based on their expertise and experience to offer independent advice. The President shall designate a Chair from among the members. A Co-Chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology who is not serving in the Federal Government and the Chair and Vice Chair of the President’s Export Council shall serve as ex-officio members. The Treasury may provide the PCJC with a staff, as necessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. The functions of the PCJC are advisory only. The PCJC shall meet regularly and shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) solicit ideas from across the country about how to bolster the economy and the prosperity of the American people that can inform the decisionmaking of the President, and with respect to matters deemed appropriate by the President, provide information and recommendations to any executive department or agency (agency) with responsibilities related to the economy, growth, innovation, American competitiveness, or job creation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) report directly to the President on the design, implementation, and evaluation of policies to promote the growth of the American economy, enhance the skills and education of Americans, maintain a stable and sound financial and banking system, create stable jobs for American workers, and improve the long-term prosperity and competitiveness of the American people; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) provide analysis and information with respect to the operation, regulation, and healthy functioning of the economy and other factors that may contribute to the sustainable growth and competitiveness of American industry and the American labor force. As deemed appropriate by the President, this analysis and information shall be provided to the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the National Economic Council, or any agency with responsibilities related to the economy, growth, innovation, American competitiveness, or job creation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Administration of the PCJC</i>. (a) All agencies and all offices within the Executive Office of the President shall cooperate with the PCJC and provide such information and assistance to the PCJC as the Chair of the PCJC may request, to the extent permitted by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Department of the Treasury shall provide funding and administrative support for the PCJC to the extent permitted by law and within existing appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Members of the PCJC shall serve without compensation but may receive transportation expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by law for persons serving intermittently in the Government (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5701–570">5 U.S.C. 5701–570</ref>7), consistent with the availability of funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Termination</i>. The PCJC shall terminate 2 years after the date of this order unless extended by the President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Revocation of Executive Order 13501</i>. Executive Order 13501 of <date date="2009-02-06">February 6, 2009</date> (Establishing the President’s Economic Recovery Advisory Board), is hereby revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Insofar as the Federal Advisory Committee Act, as amended ([former] 5 U.S.C. App.) [see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1001">5 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] (the “Act”), may apply to the PCJC, any functions of the President under the Act, except for those in section 6 of the Act, shall be performed by the Secretary of the Treasury in accordance with the guidelines that have been issued by the Administrator of General Services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) authority granted by law to a department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
