<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd4986ae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a"><num value="5219a">§ 5219a.</num><heading> Home Affordable Modification Program guidelines</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986af-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Net present value input data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall revise the supplemental directives and other guidelines for the Home Affordable Modification Program of the Making Home Affordable initiative of the Secretary of the Treasury, authorized under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (<ref href="/us/pl/110/343">Public Law 110–343</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5201">12 U.S.C. 5201</ref> et seq.], to require each mortgage servicer participating in such program to provide each borrower under a mortgage whose request for a mortgage modification under the Program is denied with all borrower-related and mortgage-related input data used in any net present value (NPV) analyses performed in connection with the subject mortgage. Such input data shall be provided to the borrower at the time of such denial.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986b0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Web-based site for NPV calculator and application</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986b1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> NPV calculator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the Home Affordable Modification Program, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a site on the World Wide Web that provides a calculator for net present value analyses of a mortgage, based on the Secretary’s methodology for calculating such value, that mortgagors can use to enter information regarding their own mortgages and that provides a determination after entering such information regarding a mortgage of whether such mortgage would be accepted or rejected for modification under the Program, using such methodology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986b2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Such Web site shall also prominently disclose that each mortgage servicer participating in such Program may use a method for calculating net present value of a mortgage that is different than the method used by such calculator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986b3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall make a reasonable effort to include on such World Wide Web site a method for homeowners to apply for a mortgage modification under the Home Affordable Modification Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd4986b4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability of NPV methodology, computer model, and variables</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make publicly available, including by posting on a World Wide Web site of the Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd4986b5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary’s methodology and computer model, including all formulae used in such computer model, used for calculating net present value of a mortgage that is used by the calculator established pursuant to subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd4986b6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5219a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all non-proprietary variables used in such net present value analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd4986b7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXIV/s1482">Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1482</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2203">124 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd4986b8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd4986b9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd4986ba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, referred to in subsec. (a), is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/110/343">Pub. L. 110–343</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3765">122 Stat. 3765</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5201">section 5201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd4986bb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Mortgage Reform and Anti-Predatory Lending Act, and also as part of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, and not as part of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd4986bc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddd4986bd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date on which final regulations implementing such section take effect, or on the date that is 18 months after the designated transfer date if such regulations have not been issued by that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1400/c">section 1400(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2010 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
