<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd4bcfdf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5220a"><num value="5220a">§ 5220a.</num><heading> Application of GSE conforming loan limit to mortgages assisted with TARP funds</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making any assistance available to prevent and mitigate foreclosures on residential properties, including any assistance for mortgage modifications, using any amounts made available to the Secretary of the Treasury under title I of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5211">12 U.S.C. 5211</ref> et seq.], the Secretary shall provide that the limitation on the maximum original principal obligation of a mortgage that may be modified, refinanced, made, guaranteed, insured, or otherwise assisted, using such amounts shall not be less than the dollar amount limitation on the maximum original principal obligation of a mortgage that may be purchased by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation that is in effect, at the time that the mortgage is modified, refinanced, made, guaranteed, insured, or otherwise assisted using such amounts, for the area in which the property involved in the transaction is located.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd4bcfe0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/22/dA/tII/s205">Pub. L. 111–22, div. A, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2009-05-20">May 20, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1654">123 Stat. 1654</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd4bcfe1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd4bcfe2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd4bcfe3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, referred to in text, is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/110/343">Pub. L. 110–343</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3765">122 Stat. 3765</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5201">section 5201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd4bcfe4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Helping Families Save Their Homes Act of 2009, and not as part of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
