<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd52fc97-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322"><num value="5322">§ 5322.</num><heading> Council authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fc98-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes and duties of the Council</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fc99-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The purposes of the Council are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fc9a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to identify risks to the financial stability of the United States that could arise from the material financial distress or failure, or ongoing activities, of large, interconnected bank holding companies or nonbank financial companies, or that could arise outside the financial services marketplace;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fc9b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to promote market discipline, by eliminating expectations on the part of shareholders, creditors, and counterparties of such companies that the Government will shield them from losses in the event of failure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fc9c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to respond to emerging threats to the stability of the United States financial system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fc9d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Council shall, in accordance with this subchapter—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fc9e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> collect information from member agencies, other Federal and State financial regulatory agencies, the Federal Insurance Office and, if necessary to assess risks to the United States financial system, direct the Office of Financial Research to collect information from bank holding companies and nonbank financial companies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fc9f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide direction to, and request data and analyses from, the Office of Financial Research to support the work of the Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> monitor the financial services marketplace in order to identify potential threats to the financial stability of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002470">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002470"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear.</note> monitor domestic and international financial regulatory proposals and developments, including insurance and accounting issues, and to advise Congress and make recommendations in such areas that will enhance the integrity, efficiency, competitiveness, and stability of the U.S. financial markets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> facilitate information sharing and coordination among the member agencies and other Federal and State agencies regarding domestic financial services policy development, rulemaking, examinations, reporting requirements, and enforcement actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> recommend to the member agencies general supervisory priorities and principles reflecting the outcome of discussions among the member agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> identify gaps in regulation that could pose risks to the financial stability of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> require supervision by the Board of Governors for nonbank financial companies that may pose risks to the financial stability of the United States in the event of their material financial distress or failure, or because of their activities pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5323">section 5323 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> make recommendations to the Board of Governors concerning the establishment of heightened prudential standards for risk-based capital, leverage, liquidity, contingent capital, resolution plans and credit exposure reports, concentration limits, enhanced public disclosures, and overall risk management for nonbank financial companies and large, interconnected bank holding companies supervised by the Board of Governors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> identify systemically important financial market utilities and payment, clearing, and settlement activities (as that term is defined in subchapter IV);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> make recommendations to primary financial regulatory agencies to apply new or heightened standards and safeguards for financial activities or practices that could create or increase risks of significant liquidity, credit, or other problems spreading among bank holding companies, nonbank financial companies, and United States financial markets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fca9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> review and, as appropriate, may submit comments to the Commission and any standard-setting body with respect to an existing or proposed accounting principle, standard, or procedure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fcaa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><chapeau> provide a forum for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/M/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> discussion and analysis of emerging market developments and financial regulatory issues; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/M/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> resolution of jurisdictional disputes among the members of the Council; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fcad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><chapeau> annually report to and testify before Congress on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the activities of the Council;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcaf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> significant financial market and regulatory developments, including insurance and accounting regulations and standards, along with an assessment of those developments on the stability of the financial system;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcb0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> potential emerging threats to the financial stability of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcb1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> all determinations made under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5323">section 5323 of this title</ref> or subchapter IV, and the basis for such determinations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcb2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> all recommendations made under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5329">section 5329 of this title</ref> and the result of such recommendations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd52fcb3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><chapeau> recommendations—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddd52fcb4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/vi/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> to enhance the integrity, efficiency, competitiveness, and stability of United States financial markets;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddd52fcb5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/vi/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> to promote market discipline; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddd52fcb6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/a/2/N/vi/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> to maintain investor confidence.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcb7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Statements by voting members of the Council</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the time at which each report is submitted under subsection (a), each voting member of the Council shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd52fcb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if such member believes that the Council, the Government, and the private sector are taking all reasonable steps to ensure financial stability and to mitigate systemic risk that would negatively affect the economy, submit a signed statement to Congress stating such belief; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd52fcb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if such member does not believe that all reasonable steps described under paragraph (1) are being taken, submit a signed statement to Congress stating what actions such member believes need to be taken in order to ensure that all reasonable steps described under paragraph (1) are taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Testimony by the Chairperson</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairperson shall appear before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate at an annual hearing, after the report is submitted under subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd52fcbb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to discuss the efforts, activities, objectives, and plans of the Council; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd52fcbc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to discuss and answer questions concerning such report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcbd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to obtain information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcbe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Council may receive, and may request the submission of, any data or information from the Office of Financial Research, member agencies, and the Federal Insurance Office, as necessary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fcbf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to monitor the financial services marketplace to identify potential risks to the financial stability of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd52fcc0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to otherwise carry out any of the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submissions by the office and member agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Office of Financial Research, any member agency, and the Federal Insurance Office, are authorized to submit information to the Council.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial data collection</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Council, acting through the Office of Financial Research, may require the submission of periodic and other reports from any nonbank financial company or bank holding company for the purpose of assessing the extent to which a financial activity or financial market in which the nonbank financial company or bank holding company participates, or the nonbank financial company or bank holding company itself, poses a threat to the financial stability of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Mitigation of report burden</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before requiring the submission of reports from any nonbank financial company or bank holding company that is regulated by a member agency or any primary financial regulatory agency, the Council, acting through the Office of Financial Research, shall coordinate with such agencies and shall, whenever possible, rely on information available from the Office of Financial Research or such agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Mitigation in case of foreign financial companies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before requiring the submission of reports from a company that is a foreign nonbank financial company or foreign-based bank holding company, the Council shall, acting through the Office of Financial Research, to the extent appropriate, consult with the appropriate foreign regulator of such company and, whenever possible, rely on information already being collected by such foreign regulator, with English translation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Back-up examination by the Board of Governors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Council is unable to determine whether the financial activities of a U.S. nonbank financial company pose a threat to the financial stability of the United States, based on information or reports obtained under paragraphs (1) and (3), discussions with management, and publicly available information, the Council may request the Board of Governors, and the Board of Governors is authorized, to conduct an examination of the U.S. nonbank financial company for the sole purpose of determining whether the nonbank financial company should be supervised by the Board of Governors for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Council, the Office of Financial Research, and the other member agencies shall maintain the confidentiality of any data, information, and reports submitted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcc9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of privilege</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The submission of any nonpublicly available data or information under this subsection and part B shall not constitute a waiver of, or otherwise affect, any privilege arising under Federal or State law (including the rules of any Federal or State court) to which the data or information is otherwise subject.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd52fcca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5322/d/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Freedom of Information Act</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2"><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">Section 552 of title 5</ref>, including the exceptions thereunder, shall apply to any data or information submitted under this subsection and part B.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd52fccb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tI/s112">Pub. L. 111–203, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1394">124 Stat. 1394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd52fccc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd52fccd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd52fcce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (d)(1)(B), (4), (5)(A), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1391">124 Stat. 1391</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
