<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd556ecb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5362"><num value="5362">§ 5362.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd556ecc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5362/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors and any subsidiaries of such company (other than any depository institution subsidiary) shall be subject to the provisions of subsections (b) through (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref>, in the same manner and to the same extent as if the company were a bank holding company, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818/b/3">section 1818(b)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd556ecd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5362/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement authority for functionally regulated subsidiaries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd556ece-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5362/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Referral</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Board of Governors determines that a condition, practice, or activity of a depository institution subsidiary or functionally regulated subsidiary of a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors does not comply with the regulations or orders prescribed by the Board of Governors under this Act, or otherwise poses a threat to the financial stability of the United States, the Board of Governors may recommend, in writing, to the primary financial regulatory agency for the subsidiary that such agency initiate a supervisory action or enforcement proceeding. The recommendation shall be accompanied by a written explanation of the concerns giving rise to the recommendation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd556ecf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5362/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Back-up authority of the Board of Governors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the primary financial regulatory agency receives a recommendation under paragraph (1), the primary financial regulatory agency does not take supervisory or enforcement action against a subsidiary that is acceptable to the Board of Governors, the Board of Governors (upon a vote of its members) may take the recommended supervisory or enforcement action, as if the subsidiary were a bank holding company subject to supervision by the Board of Governors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd556ed0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tI/s162">Pub. L. 111–203, title I, § 162</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1421">124 Stat. 1421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd556ed1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd556ed2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd556ed3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1376">124 Stat. 1376</ref>, known as the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, which enacted this chapter and chapters 108 (§ 8201 et seq.) and 109 (§ 8301 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and enacted, amended, and repealed numerous other sections and notes in the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
