<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd5c99b4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384"><num value="5384">§ 5384.</num><heading> Orderly liquidation of covered financial companies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd5c99b5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose of orderly liquidation authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to provide the necessary authority to liquidate failing financial companies that pose a significant risk to the financial stability of the United States in a manner that mitigates such risk and minimizes moral hazard. The authority provided in this subchapter shall be exercised in the manner that best fulfills such purpose, so that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99b6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> creditors and shareholders will bear the losses of the financial company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99b7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> management responsible for the condition of the financial company will not be retained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99b8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Corporation and other appropriate agencies will take all steps necessary and appropriate to assure that all parties, including management, directors, and third parties, having responsibility for the condition of the financial company bear losses consistent with their responsibility, including actions for damages, restitution, and recoupment of compensation and other gains not compatible with such responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd5c99b9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Corporation as receiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the appointment of the Corporation under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5382">section 5382 of this title</ref>, the Corporation shall act as the receiver for the covered financial company, with all of the rights and obligations set forth in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd5c99ba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation, as receiver—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99bb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall consult with the primary financial regulatory agency or agencies of the covered financial company and its covered subsidiaries for purposes of ensuring an orderly liquidation of the covered financial company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99bc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may consult with, or under subsection (a)(1)(B)(v) or (a)(1)(L) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5390">section 5390 of this title</ref>, acquire the services of, any outside experts, as appropriate to inform and aid the Corporation in the orderly liquidation process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99bd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> shall consult with the primary financial regulatory agency or agencies of any subsidiaries of the covered financial company that are not covered subsidiaries, and coordinate with such regulators regarding the treatment of such solvent subsidiaries and the separate resolution of any such insolvent subsidiaries under other governmental authority, as appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99be-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> shall consult with the Commission and the Securities Investor Protection Corporation in the case of any covered financial company for which the Corporation has been appointed as receiver that is a broker or dealer registered with the Commission under section 78<i>o</i>(b) of title 15 and is a member of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation, for the purpose of determining whether to transfer to a bridge financial company organized by the Corporation as receiver, without consent of any customer, customer accounts of the covered financial company.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd5c99bf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding for orderly liquidation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon its appointment as receiver for a covered financial company, and thereafter as the Corporation may, in its discretion, determine to be necessary or appropriate, the Corporation may make available to the receivership, subject to the conditions set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5386">section 5386 of this title</ref> and subject to the plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5390/n/9">section 5390(n)(9) of this title</ref>, funds for the orderly liquidation of the covered financial company. All funds provided by the Corporation under this subsection shall have a priority of claims under subparagraph (A) or (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5390/b/1">section 5390(b)(1) of this title</ref>, as applicable, including funds used for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> making loans to, or purchasing any debt obligation of, the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> purchasing or guaranteeing against loss the assets of the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary, directly or through an entity established by the Corporation for such purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assuming or guaranteeing the obligations of the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary to 1 or more third parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> taking a lien on any or all assets of the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary, including a first priority lien on all unencumbered assets of the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary to secure repayment of any transactions conducted under this subsection, except that, if the covered financial company or covered subsidiary is an insurance company or a subsidiary of an insurance company, the Corporation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd5c99c4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall promptly notify the State insurance authority for the insurance company of the intention to take such lien; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd5c99c5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> may only take such lien—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd5c99c6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to secure repayment of funds made available to such covered financial company or covered subsidiary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd5c99c7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the Corporation determines, after consultation with the State insurance authority, that such lien will not unduly impede or delay the liquidation or rehabilitation of the insurance company, or the recovery by its policyholders;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> selling or transferring all, or any part, of such acquired assets, liabilities, or obligations of the covered financial company or any covered subsidiary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd5c99c9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5384/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> making payments pursuant to subsections (b)(4), (d)(4), and (h)(5)(E) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5390">section 5390 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd5c99ca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tII/s204">Pub. L. 111–203, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1454">124 Stat. 1454</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/tVII/s706/b/2">Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title VII, § 706(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/3029">129 Stat. 3029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd5c99cb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd5c99cc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd5c99cd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1442">124 Stat. 1442</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd5c99ce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> inserted “, except that, if the covered financial company or covered subsidiary is an insurance company or a subsidiary of an insurance company, the Corporation—” and subpars. (A) and (B) before semicolon at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd5c99cf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddd5c99d0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
