<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd660f46-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414"><num value="5414">§ 5414.</num><heading> Savings provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f47-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Office of Thrift Supervision</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f48-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing rights, duties, and obligations not affected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Sections 5412(b) and 5413 of this title shall not affect the validity of any right, duty, or obligation of the United States, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Office of Thrift Supervision, or any other person, that existed on the day before the transfer date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f49-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation of suits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002488">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002488"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> shall not abate any action or proceeding commenced by or against the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Office of Thrift Supervision before the transfer date, except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f4a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for any action or proceeding arising out of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Board of Governors by this title,<sup>1</sup> the Board of Governors shall be substituted for the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision as a party to the action or proceeding on and after the transfer date;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f4b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for any action or proceeding arising out of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Comptroller of the Currency by this title,<sup>1</sup> the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Comptroller of the Currency shall be substituted for the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, as the case may be, as a party to the action or proceeding on and after the transfer date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f4c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for any action or proceeding arising out of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Corporation by this title,<sup>1</sup> the Corporation shall be substituted for the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision as a party to the action or proceeding on and after the transfer date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f4d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation of existing OTS orders, resolutions, determinations, agreements, regulations, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All orders, resolutions, determinations, agreements, and regulations, interpretative rules, other interpretations, guidelines, procedures, and other advisory materials, that have been issued, made, prescribed, or allowed to become effective by the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions that are transferred by this title <sup>1</sup> and that are in effect on the day before the transfer date, shall continue in effect according to the terms of such orders, resolutions, determinations, agreements, and regulations, interpretative rules, other interpretations, guidelines, procedures, and other advisory materials, and shall be enforceable by or against—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd660f4e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Board of Governors, in the case of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Board of Governors, until modified, terminated, set aside, or superseded in accordance with applicable law by the Board of Governors, by any court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd660f4f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Comptroller of the Currency, in the case of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Comptroller of the Currency, respectively, until modified, terminated, set aside, or superseded in accordance with applicable law by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Comptroller of the Currency, by any court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd660f50-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Corporation, in the case of a function of the Office of Thrift Supervision or the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision transferred to the Corporation, until modified, terminated, set aside, or superseded in accordance with applicable law by the Corporation, by any court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f51-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of regulations continued</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f52-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> By the Board of Governors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than the transfer date, the Board of Governors shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f53-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify the regulations continued under subsection (b) that will be enforced by the Board of Governors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f54-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> publish a list of the regulations identified under subparagraph (A) in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f55-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> By Office of the Comptroller of the Currency</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than the transfer date, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> after consultation with the Corporation, identify the regulations continued under subsection (b) that will be enforced by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> publish a list of the regulations identified under subparagraph (A) in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> By the Corporation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than the transfer date, the Corporation shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> after consultation with the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, identify the regulations continued under subsection (b) that will be enforced by the Corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd660f5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> publish a list of the regulations identified under subparagraph (A) in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Status of regulations proposed or not yet effective</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposed regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any proposed regulation of the Office of Thrift Supervision, which the Office of Thrift Supervision in performing functions transferred by this title,<sup>1</sup> has proposed before the transfer date but has not published as a final regulation before such date, shall be deemed to be a proposed regulation of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Board of Governors, as appropriate, according to the terms of the proposed regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd660f5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5414/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations not yet effective</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any interim or final regulation of the Office of Thrift Supervision, which the Office of Thrift Supervision, in performing functions transferred by this title,<sup>1</sup> has published before the transfer date but which has not become effective before that date, shall become effective as a regulation of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Board of Governors, as appropriate, according to the terms of the interim or final regulation, unless modified, terminated, set aside, or superseded in accordance with applicable law by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency or the Board of Governors, as appropriate, by any court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd660f5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIII/s316">Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1524">124 Stat. 1524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd660f5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd660f60-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd660f61-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2), (b), and (d), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1520">124 Stat. 1520</ref>, known as the Enhancing Financial Institution Safety and Soundness Act of 2010, which enacted this subchapter and sections 4b and 16 of this title, amended sections 1, 11, 248, 461, 481, 482, 1438, 1462, 1462a, 1463, to 1464, 1466a, 1467, 1467a, 1468, 1468a, to 1468b, 1470, 1701c, 1701p–1, 1708, 1757, 1785, 1786, 1787, 1812, 1813, 1817, 1818, 1820, 1821, 1823, 1828, 1829, 1831e, 1831j, 1833b, 1833e, 1834, 1841, 1843, 1844, 1861, 1867, 1881, 1882, 1884, 1972, 2709, 2902, 2905, 3206 to 3208, 3332, 4515, and 4517 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, sections 78c, 78<i>l</i>, 78<i>o</i>–5, and 78w of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, sections 212, 657, 981, 982, 1006, 1014, and 1032 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, sections 321 and 714 of Title 31, Money and Finance, <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s41501">section 41501 of Title 34</ref>, Crime Control and Law Enforcement, sections 4003 and 8105 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3502">section 3502 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents, repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1441a">section 1441a of this title</ref>, enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1, 16, 1438, 1787, 1812, 1817, and 1821 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906">section 906 of Title 2</ref>, and amended provisions set out as notes under sections 1437, 1463, 1464, 1467a, 1707, 1812, and 1818 of this title. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd660f62-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddd660f63-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
