<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd6aca0a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466"><num value="5466">§ 5466.</num><heading> Examination of and enforcement actions against designated financial market utilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca0b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Examination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (d), the Supervisory Agency shall conduct examinations of a designated financial market utility at least once annually in order to determine the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6aca0c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The nature of the operations of, and the risks borne by, the designated financial market utility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6aca0d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The financial and operational risks presented by the designated financial market utility to financial institutions, critical markets, or the broader financial system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6aca0e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The resources and capabilities of the designated financial market utility to monitor and control such risks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6aca0f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The safety and soundness of the designated financial market utility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6aca10-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The designated financial market utility’s compliance with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca11-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca12-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the rules and orders prescribed under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca13-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Service providers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a service integral to the operation of a designated financial market utility is performed for the designated financial market utility by another entity, whether an affiliate or non-affiliate and whether on or off the premises of the designated financial market utility, the Supervisory Agency may examine whether the provision of that service is in compliance with applicable law, rules, orders, and standards to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility were performing the service on its own premises.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca14-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, a designated financial market utility shall be subject to, and the appropriate Supervisory Agency shall have authority under the provisions of subsections (b) through (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref> in the same manner and to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility was an insured depository institution and the Supervisory Agency was the appropriate Federal banking agency for such insured depository institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca15-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Governors involvement in examinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca16-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Governors consultation on examination planning</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Supervisory Agency shall consult annually with the Board of Governors regarding the scope and methodology of any examination conducted under subsections (a) and (b). The Supervisory Agency shall lead all examinations conducted under subsections (a) and (b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002500">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002500"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca17-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Governors participation in examination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board of Governors may, in its discretion, participate in any examination led by a Supervisory Agency and conducted under subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca18-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Governors enforcement recommendations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca19-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board of Governors may, after consulting with the Council and the Supervisory Agency, at any time recommend to the Supervisory Agency that such agency take enforcement action against a designated financial market utility in order to prevent or mitigate significant liquidity, credit, operational, or other risks to the financial markets or to the financial stability of the United States. Any such recommendation for enforcement action shall provide a detailed analysis supporting the recommendation of the Board of Governors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca1a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Supervisory Agency shall consider the recommendation of the Board of Governors and submit a response to the Board of Governors within 60 days.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca1b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Binding arbitration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Supervisory Agency rejects, in whole or in part, the recommendation of the Board of Governors, the Board of Governors may refer the recommendation to the Council for a binding decision on whether an enforcement action is warranted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca1c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement action</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon an affirmative vote by a majority of the Council in favor of the Board of Governors’ recommendation under paragraph (3), the Council may require the Supervisory Agency to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca1d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> exercise the enforcement authority referenced in subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca1e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> take enforcement action against the designated financial market utility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca1f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency enforcement actions by the Board of Governors</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca20-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Imminent risk of substantial harm</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board of Governors may, after consulting with the Supervisory Agency and upon an affirmative vote by a majority the Council, take enforcement action against a designated financial market utility if the Board of Governors has reasonable cause to conclude that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca21-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6aca22-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an action engaged in, or contemplated by, a designated financial market utility (including any change proposed by the designated financial market utility to its rules, procedures, or operations that would otherwise be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5465/e">section 5465(e) of this title</ref>) poses an imminent risk of substantial harm to financial institutions, critical markets, or the broader financial system of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6aca23-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the condition of a designated financial market utility poses an imminent risk of substantial harm to financial institutions, critical markets, or the broader financial system; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd6aca24-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the imminent risk of substantial harm precludes the Board of Governors’ use of the procedures in subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6aca25-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5466/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of taking enforcement action under paragraph (1), a designated financial market utility shall be subject to, and the Board of Governors shall have authority under <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002501">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002501"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> the provisions of subsections (b) through (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">section 1818 of this title</ref> in the same manner and to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility was an insured depository institution and the Board of Governors was the appropriate Federal banking agency for such insured depository institution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd6aca26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVIII/s807">Pub. L. 111–203, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1814">124 Stat. 1814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
