<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb48d4a2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s548"><num value="548">§ 548.</num><heading> State taxation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of any tax law enacted under authority of the United States or any State, a national bank shall be treated as a bank organized and existing under the laws of the State or other jurisdiction within which its principal office is located.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb48d4a3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(R.S. § 5219; <ref href="/us/act/1923-03-04/ch267">Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 267</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1499">42 Stat. 1499</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1926-03-25/ch88">Mar. 25, 1926, ch. 88</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/223">44 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/156">Pub. L. 91–156</ref>, §§ 1(a), 2(a), <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/434">83 Stat. 434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb48d4a4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb48d4a5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb48d4a6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5219 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-06-03/ch106/s41">act June 3, 1864, ch. 106, § 41</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/13/111">13 Stat. 111</ref>, which was the National Bank Act, and <ref href="/us/act/1868-02-10/ch7">act Feb. 10, 1868, ch. 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/15/34">15 Stat. 34</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb48d4a7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—<ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s2/a">Pub. L. 91–156, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted provisions directing that national banks, for purposes of both Federal and State tax laws, be treated as banks organized and existing under the laws of the State or other jurisdiction within which each bank’s principal office is located for provisions placing restrictions on the taxation of national bank shares and, for the period until the effective date of such amendment, set out interim provisions regarding intangible personal property taxes of States and local governments on national banks.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s1/a">Pub. L. 91–156, § 1(a)</ref>, added par. 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1926—Act <date date="1926-03-25">Mar. 25, 1926</date>, among other changes inserted “on their net income” in cl. (3) of former opening par., and added cl. (4) thereto, and inserted proviso in former subsec. 1(c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb48d4a8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb48d4a9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s1/b">Pub. L. 91–156, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/434">83 Stat. 434</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/156/s1/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) of this section [setting out interim provisions regarding intangible personal property taxes of State and local governments on national banks] shall be effective from the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>] until the effective date [<date date="1973-01-01">Jan. 1, 1973</date>] of the amendment made by section 2(a) of this Act [removing restrictions on the taxation of national bank shares and directing that national banks, for purposes of both Federal and State tax laws, be treated as banks organized and existing under the laws of the State or other jurisdiction within which each bank’s principal office is located].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s2/b">Pub. L. 91–156, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/434">83 Stat. 434</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/92/213/s4/a">Pub. L. 92–213, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-22">Dec. 22, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/775">85 Stat. 775</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/213/s4/a">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [removing all special restriction on the taxation of national bank shares by State and local taxing authorities] becomes effective on <date date="1973-01-01">January 1, 1973</date>”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="iddb48d4aa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s3">Pub. L. 91–156, § 3</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/435">83 Stat. 435</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/92/213/s4/a">Pub. L. 92–213, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-22">Dec. 22, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/775">85 Stat. 775</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/213/s4/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, prior to <date date="1973-01-01">January 1, 1973</date>, no tax may be imposed on any class of banks by or under authority of any State legislation in effect prior to the enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>] unless</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the tax was imposed on that class of banks prior to the enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>], or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the imposition of the tax is authorized by affirmative action of the State legislature after the enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The prohibition of subsection (a) of this section does not apply to</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any sales tax or use tax complementary thereto,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any tax (including a documentary stamp tax) on the execution, delivery, or recordation of documents, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any tax on tangible personal property (not including cash or currency), or for any license, registration, transfer, excise or other fee or tax imposed on the ownership, use or transfer of tangible personal property,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">imposed by a State which does not impose a tax, or an increased rate of tax, in lieu thereof.”</continuation>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb48d4ab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">State Taxation of Federally Insured Financial Institutions; Study and Report by Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/100/s7">Pub. L. 93–100, § 7</ref>, <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/347">87 Stat. 347</ref>, eff. on the 30th day after <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tI/s114">Pub. L. 93–495, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1507">88 Stat. 1507</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/222">Pub. L. 94–222</ref>, §§ 1, 4, <date date="1976-02-27">Feb. 27, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/197">90 Stat. 197</ref>, 198, eff. <date date="1976-01-01">Jan. 1, 1976</date>, provided that it was to be cited as the “State Taxation of Depositories Act”; that it was applicable to taxable years or periods beginning on or after <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date>; that an efficient banking system and the free flow of commerce would be furthered by clarification of principles as to State taxation of interstate transactions of banks and other depositories; that taxes measured by income or receipts or other “doing business” taxes in states where depositories do not have their principal offices, should be deferred until uniform and equitable methods are developed; that no such taxes should be imposed on or after <date date="1973-08-16">Aug. 16, 1973</date> and before <date date="1976-09-12">Sept. 12, 1976</date>; that “insured depository” means any bank or institution insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or any member institution of a Federal home loan bank; that “State” means the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa; and that the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations should study the matter of State “doing business” taxes and report to Congress no later than <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb48d4ac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study by Board of Governors of Federal Reserve System; Report by <date date="1972-06-22">June 22, 1972</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/92/213/s4/b">Pub. L. 92–213, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-22">Dec. 22, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/775">85 Stat. 775</ref>, required the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to make a study of the probable impact on the revenues of State and local governments of the extension until <date date="1973-01-01">Jan. 1, 1973</date>, under subsection (a), of the termination date of interim provisions regarding intangible personal property taxes of State and local governments on national banks and to report the results of its study to the Congress not later than six months after <date date="1971-12-22">Dec. 22, 1971</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb48d4ad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study by Board of Governors of Federal Reserve System; Report by <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/156/s4">Pub. L. 91–156, § 4</ref>, <date date="1969-12-24">Dec. 24, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/435">83 Stat. 435</ref>, provided that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System make a study to determine the probable impact on the banking system and other economic effects of the changes in existing law made by section 2 of this Act [amending this section] and that such study include the Board’s recommendation as to what additional Federal legislation may be needed to reconcile the promotion of economic efficiency in the banking system with the achievement of effectiveness and local autonomy in meeting the fiscal needs of the States and their political subdivisions. The results of the Board’s study were to be made to Congress not later than <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
