<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd6d3bcd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496"><num value="5496">§ 5496.</num><heading> Appearances before and reports to Congress</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appearances before Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau shall appear before the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives at semi-annual hearings regarding the reports required under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bcf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bureau shall, concurrent with each semi-annual hearing referred to in subsection (a), prepare and submit to the President and to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report, beginning with the session following the designated transfer date. The Bureau may also submit such report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bd0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The reports required by subsection (b) shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a discussion of the significant problems faced by consumers in shopping for or obtaining consumer financial products or services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a justification of the budget request of the previous year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a list of the significant rules and orders adopted by the Bureau, as well as other significant initiatives conducted by the Bureau, during the preceding year and the plan of the Bureau for rules, orders, or other initiatives to be undertaken during the upcoming period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an analysis of complaints about consumer financial products or services that the Bureau has received and collected in its central database on complaints during the preceding year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a list, with a brief statement of the issues, of the public supervisory and enforcement actions to which the Bureau was a party during the preceding year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the actions taken regarding rules, orders, and supervisory actions with respect to covered persons which are not credit unions or depository institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> an assessment of significant actions by State attorneys general or State regulators relating to Federal consumer financial law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> an analysis of the efforts of the Bureau to fulfill the fair lending mission of the Bureau; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd6d3bd9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5496/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> an analysis of the efforts of the Bureau to increase workforce and contracting diversity consistent with the procedures established by the Office of Minority and Women Inclusion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd6d3bda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1016">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1016</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1974">124 Stat. 1974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
