<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd6d3bec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497"><num value="5497">§ 5497.</num><heading> Funding; penalties and fines</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds from Board Of Governors</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each year (or quarter of such year), beginning on the designated transfer date, and each quarter thereafter, the Board of Governors shall transfer to the Bureau from the combined earnings of the Federal Reserve System, the amount determined by the Director to be reasonably necessary to carry out the authorities of the Bureau under Federal consumer financial law, taking into account such other sums made available to the Bureau from the preceding year (or quarter of such year).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding cap</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), and in accordance with this paragraph, the amount that shall be transferred to the Bureau in each fiscal year shall not exceed a fixed percentage of the total operating expenses of the Federal Reserve System, as reported in the Annual Report, 2009, of the Board of Governors, equal to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bf1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 10 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2011;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bf2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 11 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2012; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bf3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> 6.5 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2013, and in each year thereafter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment of amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The dollar amount referred to in subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be adjusted annually, using the percent increase, if any, in the employment cost index for total compensation for State and local government workers published by the Federal Government, or the successor index thereto, for the 12-month period ending on September 30 of the year preceding the transfer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Reviewability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision in this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002509">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002509"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the funds derived from the Federal Reserve System pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to review by the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Transition period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Beginning on <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, and until the designated transfer date, the Board of Governors shall transfer to the Bureau the amount estimated by the Secretary needed to carry out the authorities granted to the Bureau under Federal consumer financial law, from <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date> until the designated transfer date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget and financial management</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial operating plans and forecasts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director shall provide to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget copies of the financial operating plans and forecasts of the Director, as prepared by the Director in the ordinary course of the operations of the Bureau, and copies of the quarterly reports of the financial condition and results of operations of the Bureau, as prepared by the Director in the ordinary course of the operations of the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bf9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial statements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bureau shall prepare annually a statement of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bfa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assets and liabilities and surplus or deficit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bfb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> income and expenses; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddd6d3bfc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> sources and application of funds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bfd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial management systems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bureau shall implement and maintain financial management systems that comply substantially with Federal financial management systems requirements and applicable Federal accounting standards.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bfe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Assertion of internal controls</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director shall provide to the Comptroller General of the United States an assertion as to the effectiveness of the internal controls that apply to financial reporting by the Bureau, using the standards established in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3512/c">section 3512(c) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3bff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">This subsection may not be construed as implying any obligation on the part of the Director to consult with or obtain the consent or approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget with respect to any report, plan, forecast, or other information referred to in subparagraph (A) or any jurisdiction or oversight over the affairs or operations of the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3c00-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/4/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The financial statements of the Bureau shall not be consolidated with the financial statements of either the Board of Governors or the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3c01-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit of the Bureau</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6d3c02-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Comptroller General shall annually audit the financial transactions of the Bureau in accordance with the United States generally accepted government auditing standards, as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. The audit shall be conducted at the place or places where accounts of the Bureau are normally kept. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to the personnel and to all books, accounts, documents, papers, records (including electronic records), reports, files, and all other papers, automated data, things, or property belonging to or under the control of or used or employed by the Bureau pertaining to its financial transactions and necessary to facilitate the audit, and such representatives shall be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians. All such books, accounts, documents, records, reports, files, papers, and property of the Bureau shall remain in possession and custody of the Bureau. The Comptroller General may obtain and duplicate any such books, accounts, documents, records, working papers, automated data and files, or other information relevant to such audit without cost to the Comptroller General, and the right of access of the Comptroller General to such information shall be enforceable pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s716/c">section 716(c) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac03-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Comptroller General shall submit to the Congress a report of each annual audit conducted under this subsection. The report to the Congress shall set forth the scope of the audit and shall include the statement of assets and liabilities and surplus or deficit, the statement of income and expenses, the statement of sources and application of funds, and such comments and information as may be deemed necessary to inform Congress of the financial operations and condition of the Bureau, together with such recommendations with respect thereto as the Comptroller General may deem advisable. A copy of each report shall be furnished to the President and to the Bureau at the time submitted to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac04-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/a/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance and costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For the purpose of conducting an audit under this subsection, the Comptroller General may, in the discretion of the Comptroller General, employ by contract, without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>, professional services of firms and organizations of certified public accountants for temporary periods or for special purposes. Upon the request of the Comptroller General, the Director of the Bureau shall transfer to the Government Accountability Office from funds available, the amount requested by the Comptroller General to cover the full costs of any audit and report conducted by the Comptroller General. The Comptroller General shall credit funds transferred to the account established for salaries and expenses of the Government Accountability Office, and such amount shall be available upon receipt and without fiscal year limitation to cover the full costs of the audit and report.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac05-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumer Financial Protection Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac06-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Separate fund in Federal Reserve established</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established in the Federal Reserve a separate fund, to be known as the “Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Bureau Fund”). The Bureau Fund shall be maintained and established at a Federal reserve bank, in accordance with such requirements as the Board of Governors may impose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac07-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Fund receipts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All amounts transferred to the Bureau under subsection (a) shall be deposited into the Bureau Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac08-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment authority</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac09-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts in Bureau Fund may be invested</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bureau may request the Board of Governors to direct the investment of the portion of the Bureau Fund that is not, in the judgment of the Bureau, required to meet the current needs of the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible investments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Investments authorized by this paragraph shall be made in obligations of the United States or obligations that are guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States, with maturities suitable to the needs of the Bureau Fund, as determined by the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest and proceeds credited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Bureau Fund shall be credited to the Bureau Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds obtained by, transferred to, or credited to the Bureau Fund shall be immediately available to the Bureau and under the control of the Director, and shall remain available until expended, to pay the expenses of the Bureau in carrying out its duties and responsibilities. The compensation of the Director and other employees of the Bureau and all other expenses thereof may be paid from, obtained by, transferred to, or credited to the Bureau Fund under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Funds that are not Government funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds obtained by or transferred to the Bureau Fund shall not be construed to be Government funds or appropriated monies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac0f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts not subject to apportionment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts in the Bureau Fund and in the Civil Penalty Fund established under subsection (d) shall not be subject to apportionment for purposes of chapter 15 of title 31 or under any other authority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac10-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties and fines</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac11-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of victims relief fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established in the Federal Reserve a separate fund, to be known as the “Consumer Financial Civil Penalty Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Civil Penalty Fund”). The Civil Penalty Fund shall be maintained and established at a Federal reserve bank, in accordance with such requirements as the Board of Governors may impose. If the Bureau obtains a civil penalty against any person in any judicial or administrative action under Federal consumer financial laws, the Bureau shall deposit into the Civil Penalty Fund, the amount of the penalty collected.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac12-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment to victims</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts in the Civil Penalty Fund shall be available to the Bureau, without fiscal year limitation, for payments to the victims of activities for which civil penalties have been imposed under the Federal consumer financial laws. To the extent that such victims cannot be located or such payments are otherwise not practicable, the Bureau may use such funds for the purpose of consumer education and financial literacy programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac13-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; annual report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac14-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination regarding need for appropriated funds</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac15-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director is authorized to determine that sums available to the Bureau under this section will not be sufficient to carry out the authorities of the Bureau under Federal consumer financial law for the upcoming year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac16-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Report required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">When making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Director shall prepare a report regarding the funding of the Bureau, including the assets and liabilities of the Bureau, and the extent to which the funding needs of the Bureau are anticipated to exceed the level of the amount set forth in subsection (a)(2). The Director shall submit the report to the President and to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac17-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Director makes the determination and submits the report pursuant to paragraph (1), there are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Bureau, for the purposes of carrying out the authorities granted in Federal consumer financial law, $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2010, 2011, 2012, 2013, and 2014.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac18-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amounts in paragraph (2) shall be subject to apportionment under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1517">section 1517 of title 31</ref> and restrictions that generally apply to the use of appropriated funds in title 31 and other laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd6fac19-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5497/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall prepare and submit a report, on an annual basis, to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives regarding the financial operating plans and forecasts of the Director, the financial condition and results of operations of the Bureau, and the sources and application of funds of the Bureau, including any funds appropriated in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd6fac1a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1017">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1017</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1975">124 Stat. 1975</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tIII/s30001">Pub. L. 119–21, title III, § 30001</ref>, <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/126">139 Stat. 126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd6fac1b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd6fac1c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd6fac1d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(C), is title X of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1955">124 Stat. 1955</ref>, known as the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, which enacted this subchapter and enacted, amended, and repealed numerous other sections and notes in the Code. For complete classification of title X to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd6fac1e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(5)(C), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd6fac1f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/119/21">Pub. L. 119–21</ref> substituted “6.5 percent” for “12 percent”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
