<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb0f9bec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s56"><num value="56">§ 56.</num><heading> Prohibition on withdrawal of capital; unearned dividends</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No association, or any member thereof, shall, during the time it shall continue its banking operations, withdraw, or permit to be withdrawn, either in the form of dividends or otherwise, any portion of its capital. If losses have at any time been sustained by any such association, equal to or exceeding its undivided profits then on hand, no dividend shall be made; and no dividend shall ever be made by any association, while it continues its banking operations, to an amount greater than its undivided profits, subject to other applicable provisions of law. But nothing in this section shall prevent the reduction of the capital stock of the association under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s59">section 59 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb0f9bed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(R.S. § 5204; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tVI/s602/h/1">Pub. L. 103–325, title VI, § 602(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2294">108 Stat. 2294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb0f9bee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb0f9bef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb0f9bf0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5204 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-06-03/ch106/s38">act June 3, 1864, ch. 106, § 38</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/13/110">13 Stat. 110</ref>, which was the National Bank Act. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb0f9bf1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref> substituted “undivided profits, subject to other applicable provisions of law” for “net profits then on hand, deducting therefrom its losses and bad debts” in second sentence and struck out after second sentence “All debts due to any associations, on which interest is past due and unpaid for a period of six months, unless the same are well secured, and in process of collection, shall be considered bad debts within the meaning of this section.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
