<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd7b9317-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603"><num value="5603">§ 5603.</num><heading> Review, report, and program with respect to exchange facilitators</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd7b9318-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall review all Federal laws and regulations relating to the protection of consumers who use exchange facilitators for transactions primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd7b9319-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the designated transfer date, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b931a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> recommendations for legislation to ensure the appropriate protection of consumers who use exchange facilitators for transactions primarily for personal, family, or household purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b931b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> recommendations for updating the regulations of Federal departments and agencies to ensure the appropriate protection of such consumers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b931c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> recommendations for regulations to ensure the appropriate protection of such consumers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd7b931d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after the date of the submission of the report under subsection (b), the Bureau shall, consistent with part B, propose regulations or otherwise establish a program to protect consumers who use exchange facilitators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd7b931e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exchange facilitator defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “exchange facilitator” means a person that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b931f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> facilitates, for a fee, an exchange of like kind property by entering into an agreement with a taxpayer by which the exchange facilitator acquires from the taxpayer the contractual rights to sell the taxpayer’s relinquished property and transfers a replacement property to the taxpayer as a qualified intermediary (within the meaning of Treasury Regulations section 1.1031(k)–1(g)(4)) or enters into an agreement with the taxpayer to take title to a property as an exchange accommodation titleholder (within the meaning of Revenue Procedure 2000–37) or enters into an agreement with a taxpayer to act as a qualified trustee or qualified escrow holder (within the meaning of Treasury Regulations section 1.1031(k)–1(g)(3));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b9320-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> maintains an office for the purpose of soliciting business to perform the services described in paragraph (1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd7b9321-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s5603/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> advertises any of the services described in paragraph (1) or solicits clients in printed publications, direct mail, television or radio advertisements, telephone calls, facsimile transmissions, or other electronic communications directed to the general public for purposes of providing any such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd7b9322-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1079">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1079</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2077">124 Stat. 2077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
