<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb4b1dde-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s603"><num value="603">§ 603.</num><heading> Restrictions imposed by Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System on banks purchasing stock in corporations doing foreign business</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Before any national bank shall be permitted to purchase stock in any corporation described in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s601">section 601 of this title</ref>, the said corporation shall enter into an agreement or undertaking with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to restrict its operations or conduct its business in such manner or under such limitations and restrictions as the said board may prescribe for the place or places wherein such business is to be conducted. If at any time the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall ascertain that the regulations prescribed by it are not being complied with, said board is authorized and empowered to institute an investigation of the matter and to send for persons and papers, subpoena witnesses, and administer oaths in order to satisfy itself as to the actual nature of the transactions referred to. Should such investigation result in establishing the failure of the corporation in question, or of the national bank or banks which may be stockholders therein, to comply with the regulations laid down by the said Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, such national banks may be required to dispose of stock holdings in the said corporation upon reasonable notice.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb4b1ddf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-12-23/ch6/s25">Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 25</ref> (par.), as added <ref href="/us/act/1916-09-07/ch461">Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 461</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/755">39 Stat. 755</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb4b1de0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb4b1de1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb4b1de2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the fifth undesignated par. of section 25 of act <date date="1913-12-23">Dec. 23, 1913</date>, which comprises this subchapter. For classification of other pars. of section 25 of this Act, see Codification note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s601">section 601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb4b1de3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb4b1de4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 203(a) of act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
