<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb4fffb6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635"><num value="635">§ 635.</num><heading> Powers and functions of Bank</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb4fffb7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General banking business; use of mails; publication of documents, reports, contracts, etc.; use of assets and allocated or borrowed money; payment of dividends; medium-term financing; dissemination of information; enhancement of medium-term program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffb8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is created a corporation with the name Export-Import Bank of the United States, which shall be an agency of the United States of America. The objects and purposes of the Bank shall be to aid in financing and to facilitate exports of goods and services, imports, and the exchange of commodities and services between the United States or any of its territories or insular possessions and any foreign country or the agencies or nationals of any such country, and in so doing to contribute to the employment of United States workers. The Bank’s objective in authorizing loans, guarantees, insurance, and credits shall be to contribute to maintaining or increasing employment of United States workers. In connection with and in furtherance of its objects and purposes, the bank is authorized and empowered to do a general banking business except that of circulation; to receive deposits; to purchase, discount, rediscount, sell, and negotiate, with or without its endorsement or guaranty, and to guarantee notes, drafts, checks, bills of exchange, acceptances, including bankers’ acceptances, cable transfers, and other evidences of indebtedness; to guarantee, insure, coinsure, and reinsure against political and credit risks of loss; to purchase, sell, and guarantee securities but not to purchase with its funds any stock in any other corporation except that it may acquire any such stock through the enforcement of any lien or pledge or otherwise to satisfy a previously contracted indebtedness to it; to accept bills and drafts drawn upon it; to issue letters of credit; to purchase and sell coin, bullion, and exchange; to borrow and to lend money; to perform any act herein authorized in participation with any other person, including any individual, partnership, corporation, or association; to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed; to sue and to be sued, to complain and to defend in any court of competent jurisdiction; to represent itself or to contract for representation in all legal and arbitral proceedings outside the United States; and the enumeration of the foregoing powers shall not be deemed to exclude other powers necessary to the achievement of the objects and purposes of the bank. The bank shall be entitled to the use of the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as the executive departments of the Government. The Bank is authorized to publish or arrange for the publication of any documents, reports, contracts, or other material necessary in connection with or in furtherance of its objects and purposes without regard to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref> whenever the Bank determines that publication in accordance with the provisions of such section would not be practicable. Subject to regulations which the Bank shall issue pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, the Bank may impose and collect reasonable fees to cover the costs of conferences and seminars sponsored by, and publications provided by, the Bank, and may accept reimbursement for travel and subsistence expenses incurred by a director, officer, or employee of the Bank, in accordance with subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5. Amounts received under the preceding sentence shall be credited to the fund which initially paid for such activities and shall be offset against the expenses of the Bank for such activities. The bank is authorized to use all of its assets and all moneys which have been or may hereafter be allocated to or borrowed by it in the exercise of its functions. Net earnings of the bank after reasonable provision for possible losses shall be used for payment of dividends on capital stock. Any such dividends shall be deposited into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffb9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In order for the Bank to be competitive in all of its financing programs with countries whose exports compete with United States exports, the Bank shall establish a program that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> provides medium-term financing where necessary to be fully competitive—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4fffbb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> at rates of interest to the customer which are equal to rates established in international agreements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4fffbc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in amounts up to 85 percent of the total cost of the exports involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4fffbd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> with principal amounts of not more than $25,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffbe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> enables the Bank to cooperate fully with the Secretary of Commerce and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to develop a program for purposes of disseminating information (using existing private institutions) to small business concerns regarding the medium-term financing provided under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffbf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enhancement of Medium-Term Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To enhance the medium-term financing program established pursuant to paragraph (2), the Bank shall establish measures to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffc0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improve the competitiveness of the Bank’s medium-term financing and ensure that its medium-term financing is fully competitive with that of other major official export credit agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffc1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ease the administrative burdens and procedural and documentary requirements imposed on the users of medium-term financing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffc2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> attract the widest possible participation of private financial institutions and other sources of private capital in the medium-term financing of United States exports; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffc3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> render the Bank’s medium-term financing as supportive of United States exports as is its Direct Loan Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb4fffc4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Guarantees, insurance, and extension of credit functions; competitive with Government-supported rates and terms and conditions of foreign exporting countries; survey and report; interest rates; private capital encouragement; national interest determinations; delivery of United States services in international commerce; small business concern encouragement; coverage of losses by Foreign Credit Insurance Association; loans to Union of Soviet Socialist Republics for fossil fuel research, etc.; nuclear safeguards violations resulting in limitations on exports and credit; defense article credit sales to less developed countries; amount outstanding; supplementation of Commodity Credit Corporation programs; limitations on authority of Bank; prohibition relating to Angola</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffc5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffc6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> It is the policy of the United States to foster expansion of exports of manufactured goods, agricultural products, and other goods and services, thereby contributing to the promotion and maintenance of high levels of employment and real income, a commitment to reinvestment and job creation, and the increased development of the productive resources of the United States. To meet this objective in all its programs, the Export-Import Bank is directed, in the exercise of its functions, to provide guarantees, insurance, and extensions of credit at rates and on terms and other conditions which are fully competitive with the Government-supported rates and terms and other conditions available for the financing of exports of goods and services from the principal countries whose exporters compete with United States exporters, including countries the governments of which are not members of the Arrangement (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3/h/3">section 635i–3(h)(3) of this title</ref>). The Bank shall, in cooperation with the export financing instrumentalities of other governments, seek to minimize competition in government-supported export financing and shall, in cooperation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, seek to reach international agreements to reduce government subsidized export financing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffc7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> It is further the policy of the United States that loans made by the Bank in all its programs shall bear interest at rates determined by the Board of Directors, consistent with the Bank’s mandate to support United States exports at rates and on terms and conditions which are fully competitive with exports of other countries, and consistent with international agreements. For the purpose of the preceding sentence, rates and terms and conditions need not be identical in all respects to those offered by foreign countries, but should be established so that the effect of such rates, terms, and conditions for all the Bank’s programs, including those for small businesses and for medium-term financing, will be to neutralize the effect of such foreign credit on international sales competition. The Bank shall consider its average cost of money as one factor in its determination of interest rates, where such consideration does not impair the Bank’s primary function of expanding United States exports through fully competitive financing. The Bank may not impose a credit application fee unless (i) the fee is competitive with the average fee charged by the Bank’s primary foreign competitors, and (ii) the borrower or the exporter is given the option of paying the fee at the outset of the loan or over the life of the loan and the present value of the fee determined under either such option is the same amount. It is also the policy of the United States that the Bank in the exercise of its functions should supplement and encourage, and not compete with, private capital; that the Bank, in determining whether to provide support for a transaction under the loan, guarantee, or insurance program, or any combination thereof, shall consider the need to involve private capital in support of United States exports as well as the cost of the transaction as calculated in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661">2 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.]; that the Bank shall accord equal opportunity to export agents and managers, independent export firms, export trading companies, and small commercial banks in the formulation and implementation of its programs; that the Bank should give emphasis to assisting new and small business entrants in the agricultural export market, and shall, in cooperation with other relevant Government agencies, including the Commodity Credit Corporation, develop a program of education to increase awareness of export opportunities among small agribusinesses and cooperatives; that loans, so far as possible consistent with the carrying out of the purposes of subsection (a), shall generally be for specific purposes, and, in the judgment of the Board of Directors, offer reasonable assurance of repayment; and that in authorizing any loan or guarantee, the Board of Directors shall take into account any serious adverse effect of such loan or guarantee on the competitive position of United States industry, the availability of materials which are in short supply in the United States, and employment in the United States, and shall give particular emphasis to the objective of strengthening the competitive position of United States exporters and thereby of expanding total United States exports. Only in cases where the President, after consultation with the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, determines that such action would be in the national interest where such action would clearly and importantly advance United States policy in such areas as international terrorism (including, when relevant, a foreign nation’s lack of cooperation in efforts to eradicate terrorism), nuclear proliferation, the enforcement of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], the International Emergency Economic Powers Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], or the Export Administration Act of 1979, environmental protection and human rights (such as are provided in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights adopted by the United Nations General Assembly on <date date="1948-12-10">December 10, 1948</date>) (including child labor), should the Export-Import Bank deny applications for credit for nonfinancial or noncommercial considerations. Each such determination shall be delivered in writing to the President of the Bank, shall state that the determination is made pursuant to this section, and shall specify the applications or categories of applications for credit which should be denied by the Bank in furtherance of the national interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffc8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Consistent with the policy of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3261">section 3261 of title 22</ref> and section 2151q <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002057"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 22, the Board of Directors shall name an officer of the Bank whose duties shall include advising the President of the Bank on ways of promoting the export of goods and services to be used in the development, production, and distribution of nonnuclear renewable energy resources, disseminating information concerning export opportunities and the availability of Bank support for such activities, and acting as a liaison between the Bank and the Department of Commerce and other appropriate departments and agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffc9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> It is further the policy of the United States to foster the delivery of United States services in international commerce. In exercising its powers and functions, the Bank shall give full and equal consideration to making loans and providing guarantees for the export of services (independently, or in conjunction with the export of manufactured goods, equipment, hardware or other capital goods) consistent with the Bank’s policy to neutralize foreign subsidized credit competition and to supplement the private capital market.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffcb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffcc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> It is further the policy of the United States to encourage the participation of small business (including women-owned businesses, minority-owned businesses, veteran-owned businesses, businesses owned by persons with disabilities, and businesses in rural areas) and start-up businesses in international commerce, and to educate such businesses about how to export goods using the Bank.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffcd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> In exercising its authority, the Bank shall develop a program which gives fair consideration to making loans and providing guarantees for the export of goods and services by small businesses.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffce-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> It is further the policy of the United States that the Bank shall give due recognition to the policy stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631/a">section 631(a) of title 15</ref> that “the Government should aid, counsel, assist, and protect, insofar as is possible, the interests of small business concerns in order to preserve free competitive enterprise”.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffcf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> In furtherance of this policy, the Board of Directors shall designate an officer of the Bank who—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffd0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> shall be responsible to the President of the Bank for all matters concerning or affecting small business concerns; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffd1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> among other duties, shall be responsible for advising small business concerns of the opportunities for small business concerns in the functions of the Bank, with particular emphasis on conducting outreach and increasing loans to socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s637/a/4">section 637(a)(4) of title 15</ref>), small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/a">section 632(a) of title 15</ref>) owned by women, and small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/a">section 632(a) of title 15</ref>) employing fewer than 100 employees, and for maintaining liaison with the Small Business Administration and other departments and agencies in matters affecting small business concerns.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The Director appointed to represent the interests of small business under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a/c">section 635a(c) of this title</ref> shall ensure that the Bank carries out its responsibilities under clauses (ii) and (iii) of this subparagraph and that the Bank’s financial and other resources are, to the maximum extent possible, appropriately used for small business needs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> To assure that the purposes of clauses (i) and (ii) of this subparagraph are carried out, the Bank shall make available, from the aggregate loan, guarantee, and insurance authority available to it, an amount to finance exports directly by small business concerns (as defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">section 632 of title 15</ref>) which shall be not less than 30 percent of such authority for each fiscal year. From the amount made available under the preceding sentence, it shall be a goal of the Bank to increase the amount made available to finance exports directly by small business concerns referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a/i/1">section 635a(i)(1) of this title</ref>. For the purpose of calculating the amounts of authority required under this clause, the Bank shall, with respect to insurance, exclude unutilized authorizations that terminated during the fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The Bank shall utilize the amount set aside pursuant to clause (v) of this subparagraph to offer financing for small business exports on terms which are fully competitive with regard to interest rates and with regard to the portion of financing which may be provided, guaranteed, or insured. Financing under this clause (vi) shall be available without regard to whether financing for the particular transaction was disapproved by any other Federal agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The Bank shall utilize a part of the amount set aside pursuant to clause (v) to provide lines of credit or guarantees to consortia of small or medium size banks, export trading companies, State export finance agencies, export financing cooperatives, small business investment companies (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s662">section 662 of title 15</ref>), or other financing institutions or entities in order to finance small business exports.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Financing under this clause (vii) shall be made available only where the consortia or the participating institutions agree to undertake processing, servicing, and credit evaluation functions in connection with such financing.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> To the maximum extent practicable, the Bank shall delegate to the consortia or other financing institutions or entities the authority to approve financing under this clause (vii).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffd9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> In the administration of the program under this clause (vii), the Bank shall provide appropriate technical assistance to participating consortia and may require such consortia periodically to furnish information to the Bank regarding the number and amount of loans made and the creditworthiness of the borrowers.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> In order to assure that the policy stated in clause (i) is carried out, the Bank shall promote small business exports and its small business export financing programs in cooperation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Office of International Trade of the Small Business Administration, and the private sector, particularly small business organizations, State agencies, chambers of commerce, banking organizations, export management companies, export trading companies, and private industry.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffdb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> The Bank shall provide, through creditworthy trade associations, export trading companies, State export finance companies, export finance cooperatives, and other multiple-exporter organizations, medium-term risk protection coverage for the members and clients of such organizations. Such coverage shall be made available to each such organization under a single risk protection policy covering its members or clients. Nothing in this provision shall be interpreted as limiting the Bank’s authority to deny support for specific transactions or to disapprove a request by such an organization to participate in such coverage.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffdc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> The Bank shall implement technology improvements that are designed to improve small business outreach, including allowing customers to use the Internet to apply for the Bank’s small business programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffdd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Consistent with international agreements, the Bank shall urge the Foreign Credit Insurance Association to provide coverage against 100 per centum of any loss with respect to exports having a value of less than $100,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffde-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Participation in or access to long-, medium-, and short-term financing, guarantees, and insurance provided by the Bank shall not be denied solely because the entity seeking participation or access is not a bank or is not a United States person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffdf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> It is further the policy of the United States to foster the development of democratic institutions and market economies in countries seeking such development, and to assist the export of high technology items to such countries.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> In exercising its authority, the Bank shall develop a program for providing guarantees and insurance with respect to the export of high technology items to countries making the transition to market based economies, including eligible East European countries (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5402">section 5402 of title 22</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> As part of the ongoing marketing and outreach efforts of the Bank, the Bank shall, to the maximum extent practicable, inform high technology companies, particularly small business concerns (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">section 632 of title 15</ref>), about the programs of the Bank for United States companies interested in exporting high technology goods to countries making the transition to market based economies, including any eligible East European country (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5402">section 5402 of title 22</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> In carrying out clause (iii), the Bank shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffe4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> work with other agencies involved in export promotion and finance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffe5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/H/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> invite State and local governments, trade centers, commercial banks, and other appropriate public and private organizations to serve as intermediaries for the outreach efforts.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The President of the Bank shall undertake efforts to enhance the Bank’s capacity to provide information about the Bank’s programs to small and rural companies which have not previously participated in the Bank’s programs. Not later than 1 year after <date date="1997-11-26">November 26, 1997</date>, the President of the Bank shall submit to Congress a report on the activities undertaken pursuant to this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> The Bank shall implement an electronic system designed to track all pending transactions of the Bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> The Bank shall promote the export of goods and services related to renewable energy sources, energy efficiency (including battery electric vehicles, batteries for electric vehicles, and electric vehicle charging infrastructure), and energy storage. It shall be a goal of the Bank to ensure that not less than 5 percent of the applicable amount (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e/a/2">section 635e(a)(2) of this title</ref>) is made available each fiscal year for the financing of renewable energy, energy efficiency (including battery electric vehicles, batteries for electric vehicles, and electric vehicle charging infrastructure), and energy storage technology exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffe9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> The Bank shall require an applicant for assistance from the Bank to disclose whether the applicant has been found by a court of the United States to have violated the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], the International Emergency Economic Powers Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], or the Export Administration Act of 1979 within the preceding 12 months, and shall maintain, in cooperation with the Department of Justice, for not less than 3 years a record of such applicants so found to have violated any such Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><chapeau> Not later than 2 years after <date date="2015-12-04">December 4, 2015</date>, the Bank shall implement policies—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffeb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/M/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to accept electronic documents with respect to transactions whenever possible, including copies of bills of lading, certifications, and compliance documents, in such manner so as not to undermine any potential civil or criminal enforcement related to the transactions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/M/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to accept electronic payments in all of its programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb4fffed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Aid to Marxist-Leninist Countries.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4fffee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Bank in the exercise of its functions shall not guarantee, insure, extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4fffef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in connection with the purchase or lease of any product by a Marxist-Leninist country, or agency or national thereof; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffff0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in connection with the purchase or lease of any product by any other foreign country, or agency or national thereof, if the product to be purchased or leased by such other country, agency, or national is, to the knowledge of the Bank, principally for use in, or sale or lease to, a Marxist-Leninist country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4ffff1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Marxist-Leninist country defined.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffff2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, the term “Marxist-Leninist country” means any country that maintains a centrally planned economy based on the principles of Marxism-Leninism, or is economically and militarily dependent on any other such country.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffff3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specific countries deemed to be marxist-leninist</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Unless otherwise determined by the President in accordance with subparagraph (C), the following countries are deemed to be Marxist-Leninist countries for purposes of this paragraph:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Democratic Republic of Afghanistan.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> People’s Republic of China.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> Republic of Cuba.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> Socialist Republic of Vietnam.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4ffff9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/B/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> Tibet.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4ffffa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presidential determination that a country has ceased to be marxist-leninist</inline>.—</heading><content>If the President determines that any country on the list contained in subparagraph (B)(ii) has ceased to be a Marxist-Leninist country (within the definition of such term in subparagraph (B)(i)), such country shall not be treated as a Marxist-Leninist country for purposes of this paragraph after the date of such determination, unless the President subsequently determines that such country has again become a Marxist-Leninist country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb4ffffb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presidential determination relating to financing in the national interest.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffffc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to guarantees, insurance, or extensions of credit by the Bank to a country, agency, or national described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) (in connection with transactions described in such clauses) if the President determines that such guarantees, insurance, or extensions of credit are in the national interest.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffffd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Separate determination for certain transactions</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall make a separate determination under clause (i) for each transaction described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) for which the Bank would extend a loan in an amount equal to or greater than $50,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb4ffffe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report of clause</inline> (i) <inline class="small-caps">determinations to congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any determination by the President under clause (i) shall be reported to the Congress not later than the earlier of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb4fffff-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date of such determination; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb500000-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the date the Bank takes final action with respect to the first transaction involving the country, agency, or national for which such determination is made after <date date="1975-01-04">January 4, 1975</date>, unless a report of a determination with respect to such country, agency, or national was made and reported before <date date="1975-01-04">January 4, 1975</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500001-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report of clause</inline> (ii) <inline class="small-caps">determinations to congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any determination by the President under clause (ii) shall be reported to the Congress not later than the earlier of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb500002-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date of such determination; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb500003-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2/D/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the date the Bank takes final action with respect to the transaction for which such determination is made.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500004-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Except as provided by the fourth sentence of this paragraph, no loan or financial guarantee or general guarantee or insurance facility or combination thereof (i) in an amount which equals or exceeds $100,000,000, or (ii) for the export of technology, fuel, equipment, materials, or goods or services to be used in the construction, alteration, operation, or maintenance of nuclear power, enrichment, reprocessing, research, or heavy water production facilities, shall be finally approved by the Board of Directors of the Bank, unless in each case the Bank has submitted to the Congress with respect to such loan, financial guarantee, or combination thereof, a detailed statement describing and explaining the transaction, at least 25 days of continuous session of the Congress prior to the date of final approval. For the purpose of the preceding sentence, continuity of a session of the Congress shall be considered as broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain shall be excluded in the computation of the 25 day period referred to in such sentence. Such statement shall contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500005-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> in the case of a loan or financial guarantee—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500006-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a brief description of the purposes of the transaction;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500007-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the identity of the party or parties requesting the loan or financial guarantee;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500008-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the nature of the goods or services to be exported and the use for which the goods or services are to be exported; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500009-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> in the case of a general guarantee or insurance facility—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb50000a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a description of the nature and purpose of the facility;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb50000b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the total amount of guarantees or insurance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb50000c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/A/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the reasons for the facility and its methods of operation; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb50000d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a full explanation of the reasons for Bank financing of the transaction, the amount of the loan to be provided by the Bank, the approximate rate and repayment terms at which such loan will be made available and the approximate amount of the financial guarantee.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the Bank submits a statement to the Congress under this paragraph and either House of Congress is in an adjournment for a period which continues for at least ten days after the date of submission of the statement, then any such loan or guarantee or combination thereof may, subject to the second sentence of this paragraph, be finally approved by the Board of Directors upon the termination of the twenty-five-day period referred to in the first sentence of this paragraph or upon the termination of a thirty-five-calendar-day period (which commences upon the date of submission of the statement), whichever occurs sooner.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50000e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50000f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary of State determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500010-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any country that has agreed to International Atomic Energy Agency nuclear safeguards materially violates, abrogates, or terminates, after <date date="1977-10-26">October 26, 1977</date>, such safeguards;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500011-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any country that has entered into an agreement for cooperation concerning the civil use of nuclear energy with the United States materially violates, abrogates, or terminates, after <date date="1977-10-26">October 26, 1977</date>, any guarantee or other undertaking to the United States made in such agreement;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500012-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any country that is not a nuclear-weapon state detonates, after <date date="1977-10-26">October 26, 1977</date>, a nuclear explosive device;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500013-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any country willfully aids or abets, after <date date="1994-06-29">June 29, 1994</date>, any non-nuclear-weapon state to acquire any such nuclear explosive device or to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500014-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> any person knowingly aids or abets, after <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>, any non-nuclear-weapon state to acquire any such nuclear explosive device or to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of the Congress and to the Board of Directors of the Bank stating such determination and identifying each country or person the Secretary determines has so acted.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500015-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500016-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> If the Secretary of State makes a determination under subparagraph (A)(v) with respect to a foreign person, the Congress urges the Secretary to initiate consultations immediately with the government with primary jurisdiction over that person with respect to the imposition of the prohibition contained in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500017-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> In order that consultations with that government may be pursued, the Board of Directors of the Bank shall delay imposition of the prohibition contained in subparagraph (C) for up to 90 days if the Secretary of State requests the Board to make such delay. Following these consultations, the prohibition contained in subparagraph (C) shall apply immediately unless the Secretary determines and certifies to the Congress that that government has taken specific and effective actions, including appropriate penalties, to terminate the involvement of the foreign person in the activities described in subparagraph (A)(v). The Board of Directors of the Bank shall delay the imposition of the prohibition contained in subparagraph (C) for up to an additional 90 days if the Secretary requests the Board to make such additional delay and if the Secretary determines and certifies to the Congress that that government is in the process of taking the actions described in the preceding sentence.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500018-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after making a determination under subparagraph (A)(v), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of the Congress a report on the status of consultations with the appropriate government under this subparagraph, and the basis for any determination under clause (ii) that such government has taken specific corrective actions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500019-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Board of Directors of the Bank shall not give approval to guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in support of United States exports to any country, or to or by any person, identified in the report described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50001a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The prohibition in subparagraph (C) shall not apply to approvals to guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in support of United States exports to a country with respect to which a determination is made under clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv) of subparagraph (A) regarding any specific event described in such clause if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress not less than 45 days prior to the date of the first approval following the determination that it is in the national interest for the Bank to give such approvals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50001b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The prohibition in subparagraph (C) shall not apply to approvals to guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in support of United States exports to or by a person with respect to whom a determination is made under clause (v) of subparagraph (A) regarding any specific event described in such clause if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb50001c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary of State determines and certifies to the Congress that the appropriate government has taken the corrective actions described in subparagraph (B)(ii); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb50001d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress not less than 45 days prior to the date of the first approval following the determination that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb50001e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> reliable information indicates that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb50001f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> such person has ceased to aid or abet any non-nuclear-weapon state to acquire any nuclear explosive device or to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb500020-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> steps have been taken to ensure that the activities described in item (aa) will not resume; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb500021-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the prohibition would have a serious adverse effect on vital United States interests.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb500022-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500023-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The term “country” has the meaning given to “foreign state” in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1603/a">section 1603(a) of title 28</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500024-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The term “knowingly” is used within the meaning of the term “knowing” in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78dd–2/h/3">section 78dd–2(h)(3) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500025-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The term “person” means a natural person as well as a corporation, business association, partnership, society, trust, any other nongovernmental entity, organization, or group, and any governmental entity operating as a business enterprise, and any successor of any such entity.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500026-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The term “nuclear-weapon state” has the meaning given the term in Article IX(3) of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, signed at Washington, London, and Moscow on <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500027-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The term “non-nuclear-weapon state” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/5">section 6305(5) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500028-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The term “nuclear explosive device” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/4">section 6305(4) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb500029-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4/F/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> The term “unsafeguarded special nuclear material” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/8">section 6305(8) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50002a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Bank shall not guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in connection with (A) the purchase of any product, technical data, or other information by a national or agency of any nation which engages in armed conflict, declared or otherwise, with the Armed Forces of the United States, (B) the purchase by any nation (or national or agency thereof) of any product, technical data, or other information which is to be used principally by or in any such nation described in clause (A), or (C) the purchase of any liquid metal fast breeder nuclear reactor or any nuclear fuel reprocessing facility. The Bank shall not guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in connection with the purchase of any product, technical data, or other information by a national or agency of any nation if the President determines that any such transaction would be contrary to the national interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50002b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb50002c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Bank shall not guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in an extension of credit in connection with any credit sale of defense articles and defense services to any country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a1d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any sale of defense articles or services if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a1e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Bank is requested to provide a guarantee or insurance for the sale;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a1f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the President determines that the defense articles or services are being sold primarily for anti-narcotics purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a20-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j/e">section 2291j(e) of title 22</ref> does not apply with respect to the purchasing country;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a21-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the President determines, in accordance with subparagraph (C), that the sale is in the national interest of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a22-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the Bank determines that, notwithstanding the provision of a guarantee or insurance for the sale, not more than 5 percent of the guarantee and insurance authority available to the Bank in any fiscal year will be used by the Bank to support the sale of defense articles or services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a23-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> In determining whether a sale of defense articles or services would be in the national interest of the United States, the President shall take into account whether the sale would—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a24-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be consistent with the anti-narcotics policy of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a25-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> involve the end use of a defense article or service in a major illicit drug producing or major drug-transit country (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291/e">section 2291(e) of title 22</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a26-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> be made to a country with a democratic form of government.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a27-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a28-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The Board shall not give approval to guarantee or insure a sale of defense articles or services unless—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a29-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the President determines, in accordance with subparagraph (C), that it is in the national interest of the United States for the Bank to provide such guarantee or insurance;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a2a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the President determines, after consultation with the Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs, that the purchasing country has complied with all restrictions imposed by the United States on the end use of any defense articles or services for which a guarantee or insurance was provided under subparagraph (B), and has not used any such defense articles or services to engage in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a2b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> such determinations have been reported to the Speaker and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, not less than 25 days of continuous session of the Congress before the date of such approval.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a2c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For purposes of clause (i), continuity of a session of the Congress shall be considered as broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain shall be excluded in the computation of the 25-day period referred to in such clause.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a2d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The provision of a guarantee or insurance under subparagraph (B) shall be deemed to be the provision of security assistance for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2304">section 2304 of title 22</ref> (relating to governments which engage in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a2e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> To the extent that defense articles or services for which a guarantee or insurance is provided under subparagraph (B) are used for a purpose other than anti-narcotics purposes, they may be used only for those purposes for which defense articles and defense services sold under the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.] (relating to the foreign military sales program) may be used under section 4 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2754">22 U.S.C. 2754</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a2f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> As used in subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (F), the term “defense articles or services” means articles, services, and related technical data that are designated as defense articles and defense services pursuant to sections 38 and 47(7) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</ref>, 2794(7)] and listed on the United States Munitions List (part 121 of title 22 of the Code of Federal Regulations).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a30-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Once in each calendar quarter, the Bank shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on all instances in which the Bank, during the reporting quarter, guaranteed, insured, or extended credit or participated in an extension of credit in connection with any credit sale of an article, service, or related technical data described in subparagraph (G) that the Bank determined would not be put to a military use or described in subparagraph (I)(i). Such report shall include a description of each of the transactions and the justification for the Bank’s actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a31-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a32-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a transaction involving defense articles or services if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a33-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> the Bank determines that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a34-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/i/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the defense articles or services are nonlethal; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a35-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/i/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the primary end use of the defense articles or services will be for civilian purposes; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a36-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> at least 15 calendar days before the date on which the Board of Directors of the Bank gives final approval to Bank participation in the transaction, the Bank provides notice of the transaction to the Committees on Financial Services and on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a37-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Not more than 10 percent of the loan, guarantee, and insurance authority available to the Bank for a fiscal year may be used by the Bank to support the sale of defense articles or services to which subparagraph (A) does not apply by reason of clause (i) of this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a38-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/6/I/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Not later than September 1 of each fiscal year, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Bank, shall submit to the Committees on Financial Services and on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and on Appropriations of the Senate a report on the end uses of any defense articles or services described in clause (i) with respect to which the Bank provided support during the second preceding fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a39-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> In no event shall the Bank have outstanding at any time in excess of 7½ per centum of the limitation imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e">section 635e of this title</ref> for such guarantees, insurance, credits or participation in credits with respect to exports of defense articles and services to countries which, in the judgment of the Board of Directors of the Bank, are less developed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The Bank shall supplement but not compete with private capital and the programs of the Commodity Credit Corporation to ensure that adequate financing will be made available to assist the export of agricultural commodities, except that, consistent with paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the Bank in assisting any such export transactions shall, in cooperation with the export financing instrumentalities of other governments, seek to minimize competition in Government-supported export financing, and shall, in cooperation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, seek to reach international agreements to reduce Government subsidized export financing. In order to carry out the purposes of this subsection, the Bank shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture and where the Secretary of Agriculture has recommended against Bank financing of the export of a particular agricultural commodity, shall take such recommendation into consideration in determining whether to provide credit or other assistance for any export sale of such commodity, and shall consider the importance of agricultural commodity exports to the United States export market and the nation’s balance of trade in deciding whether or not to provide assistance under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board of Directors of the Bank shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee, take prompt measures, consistent with the credit standards otherwise required by law, to promote the expansion of the Bank’s financial commitments in sub-Saharan Africa under the loan, guarantee, and insurance programs of the Bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Board of Directors shall establish and use an advisory committee to advise the Board of Directors on the development and implementation of policies and programs designed to support the expansion described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a3f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The advisory committee shall make recommendations to the Board of Directors on how the Bank can facilitate greater support by United States commercial banks for trade with sub-Saharan Africa.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a40-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The advisory committee shall terminate on the date on which the authority of the Bank expires under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">section 635f of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a41-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The Bank shall include in the annual report to the Congress submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635g/a">section 635g(a) of this title</ref> a separate section that contains a report on the efforts of the Bank to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a42-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> improve its working relationships with the African Development Bank, the African Export-Import Bank, and other institutions in the region that are relevant to the purposes of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a43-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> coordinate closely with the United States Foreign Service and Foreign Commercial Service, and with the overall strategy of the United States Government for economic engagement with Africa pursuant to the African Growth and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3701">19 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a44-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Consistent with the requirement that the Bank obtain a reasonable assurance of repayment in connection with each transaction the Bank supports, the Bank shall, in consultation with the entities described in subparagraph (C), seek to qualify a greater number of appropriate African entities for participation in programs of the Bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a45-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a46-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Bank shall not, without a specific authorization by law, guarantee, insure, or extend credit (or participate in the extension of credit) to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a47-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/10/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assist specific countries with balance of payments financing; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a48-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/10/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> assist (as the primary purpose of any such guarantee, insurance, or credit) any country in the management of its international indebtedness, other than its outstanding obligations to the Bank.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a49-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Nothing contained in subparagraph (A) shall preclude guarantees, insurance, or credit the primary purpose of which is to support United States exports.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a4a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Relating to Angola</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Bank may not guarantee, insure, or extend (or participate in the extension of) credit in connection with any export of any good (other than food or an agricultural commodity) or service to the People’s Republic of Angola until the President certifies to the Congress that free and fair elections have been held in Angola in which all participants were afforded free and fair access, and that the government of Angola—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a4b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is willing, and is actively seeking, to achieve an equitable political settlement of the conflict in Angola, including free and fair elections, through a mutual cease-fire and a dialogue with the opposition armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a4c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> has demonstrated progress in protecting internationally recognized human rights, and particularly in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a4d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> ending, through prosecution or other means, involvement of members of the military and security forces in political violence and abuses of internationally recognized human rights;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a4e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> vigorously prosecuting persons engaged in political violence who are connected with the government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a4f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> bringing to justice those responsible for the abduction, torture, and murder of citizens of Angola and citizens of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a50-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> has demonstrated progress in its respect for, and protection of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a51-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the freedom of the press;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a52-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the freedom of speech;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a53-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the freedom of assembly;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a54-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the freedom of association (including the right to organize for political purposes);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a55-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> internationally recognized worker rights; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a56-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/11/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> other attributes of political pluralism and democracy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The President shall include in each report made pursuant to this paragraph a detailed statement with respect to each of the conditions set forth in this paragraph. This paragraph shall not be construed to impose any requirement with respect to Angola that is more restrictive than any requirement imposed by this section generally on all other countries.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a57-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition relating to russian transfers of certain missile systems</inline>.—</heading><content>If the President of the United States determines that the military or Government of the Russian Federation has transferred or delivered to the People’s Republic of China an SS–N–22 missile system and that the transfer or delivery represents a significant and imminent threat to the security of the United States, the President of the United States shall notify the Bank of the transfer or delivery as soon as practicable. Upon receipt of the notice and if so directed by the President of the United States, the Board of Directors of the Bank shall not give approval to guarantee, insure, extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in connection with the purchase of any good or service by the military or Government of the Russian Federation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a58-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on assistance to develop or promote certain railway connections and railway-related connections</inline>.—</heading><content>The Bank shall not guarantee, insure, or extend (or participate in the extension of) credit in connection with the export of any good or service relating to the development or promotion of any railway connection or railway-related connection that does not traverse or connect with Armenia and does traverse or connect Baku, Azerbaijan, Tbilisi, Georgia, and Kars, Turkey.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a59-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance functions; fractional charge; aggregate outstanding amount; fees and premiums; issuance, service and adjustments by agents; transferability of guarantees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a5a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Bank shall charge fees and premiums commensurate, in the judgment of the Bank, with risks covered in connection with the contractual liability that the Bank incurs for guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance against political and credit risks of loss.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a5b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Bank may issue such guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance to or with exporters, insurance companies, financial institutions, or others, or groups thereof, and where appropriate may employ any of the same to act as its agent in the issuance and servicing of such guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance, and the adjustment of claims arising thereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a5c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transferability of Guarantees.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a5d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to medium-term and long-term obligations insured or guaranteed by the Bank after <date date="1986-10-15">October 15, 1986</date>, the Bank shall authorize the unrestricted transfer of such obligations by the originating lenders or their transferees to other lenders without affecting, limiting, or terminating the guarantee or insurance provided by the Bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a5e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee coverage</inline>.—</heading><content>For the guarantee program provided for in this subsection, the Bank may provide up to 100 percent coverage of the interest and principal if the Board of Directors determines such coverage to be necessary to ensure acceptance of Bank guarantees by financial institutions for any transaction in any export market in which the Bank is open for business.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a5f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Equal and nondiscriminatory opportunities for domestic companies to bid for insurance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a60-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter, the Bank shall work to ensure that United States companies are afforded an equal and nondiscriminatory opportunity to bid for insurance in connection with transactions assisted by the Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a61-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Competitive opportunity for insurance companies</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of any long-term loan or guarantee of not less than $25,000,000, the Bank shall seek to ensure that United States insurance companies are accorded a fair and open competitive opportunity to provide insurance against risk of loss in connection with any transaction with respect to which such loan or guarantee is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a62-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsive actions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Bank becomes aware that a fair and open competitive opportunity is not accorded to any United States insurance company in a foreign country with respect to which the Bank is considering a loan or guarantee, the Bank—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a63-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may approve or deny the loan or guarantee after considering whether such action would be likely to achieve competitive access for United States insurance companies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a64-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall forward information regarding any foreign country that denies United States insurance companies a fair and open competitive opportunity to the Secretary of Commerce and to the United States Trade Representative for consideration of a recommendation to the President that access by such country to export credit of the United States should be restricted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a65-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of approval</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Bank approves a loan or guarantee with respect to a foreign country notwithstanding information regarding denial by that foreign country of competitive opportunities for United States insurance companies, the Bank shall include notice of such approval and the reason for such approval in the report on competition in officially supported export credit required under subsection (b)(1)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb524a66-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a67-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the term “United States insurance company”—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a68-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> includes an individual, partnership, corporation, holding company, or other legal entity which is authorized (or in the case of a holding company, subsidiaries of which are authorized) by a State to engage in the business of issuing insurance contracts or reinsuring the risk underwritten by insurance companies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a69-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> includes foreign operations, branches, agencies, subsidiaries, affiliates, or joint ventures of any entity described in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a6a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the term “fair and open competitive opportunity” means, with respect to the provision of insurance by a United States insurance company, that the company—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a6b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has received notice of the opportunity to provide such insurance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a6c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/d/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has been evaluated for such opportunity on a nondiscriminatory basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a6d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on assistance which adversely affects the United States</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a6e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Bank may not extend any direct credit or financial guarantee for establishing or expanding production of any commodity for export by any country other than the United States, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a6f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the Bank determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a70-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the commodity is likely to be in surplus on world markets at the time the resulting commodity will first be sold; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a71-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the resulting production capacity is expected to compete with United States production of the same, similar, or competing commodity; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a72-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Bank determines that the extension of such credit or guarantee will cause substantial injury to United States producers of the same, similar, or competing commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In making the determination under subparagraph (B), the Bank shall determine whether the facility that would benefit from the extension of a credit or guarantee is reasonably likely to produce a commodity in addition to, or other than, the commodity specified in the application and whether the production of the additional commodity may cause substantial injury to United States producers of the same, or a similar or competing, commodity.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a73-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Outstanding orders and preliminary injury determinations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a74-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bank shall not provide any loan or guarantee to an entity for the resulting production of substantially the same product that is the subject of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a75-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a countervailing duty or antidumping order under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a76-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a determination under title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2251">19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a77-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Affirmative determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 60 days after <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, the Bank shall establish procedures regarding loans or guarantees provided to any entity that is subject to a preliminary determination of a reasonable indication of material injury to an industry under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930. The procedures shall help to ensure that these loans and guarantees are likely to not result in a significant increase in imports of substantially the same product covered by the preliminary determination and are likely to not have a significant adverse impact on the domestic industry. The Bank shall report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on the implementation of these procedures.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a78-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Comment period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bank shall establish procedures under which the Bank shall notify interested parties and provide a comment period of not less than 14 days (which, on request of any affected party, shall be extended to a period of not more than 30 days) with regard to loans or guarantees reviewed pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (D).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a79-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of investigations under title II of the Trade Act of 1974</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In making any determination under paragraph (1) for a transaction involving more than $10,000,000, the Bank shall consider investigations under title II of the Trade Act of 1974 that have been initiated at the request of the President of the United States, the United States Trade Representative, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, or the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, or by the International Trade Commission on its own motion.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Anti-circumvention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bank shall not provide a loan or guarantee if the Bank determines that providing the loan or guarantee will facilitate circumvention of an order or determination referred to in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply in any case where, in the judgment of the Board of Directors of the Bank, the short- and long-term benefits to industry and employment in the United States are likely to outweigh the short- and long-term injury to United States producers and employment of the same, similar, or competing commodity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the extension of any credit or guarantee by the Bank will cause substantial injury if the amount of the capacity for production established, or the amount of the increase in such capacity expanded, by such credit or guarantee equals or exceeds 1 percent of United States production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of sensitive commercial sectors and products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>, the Bank shall submit a list to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, which designates sensitive commercial sectors and products with respect to which the provision of financing support by the Bank is deemed unlikely by the President of the Bank due to the significant potential for a determination that such financing support would result in an adverse economic impact on the United States. The President of the Bank shall review on an annual basis thereafter the list of sensitive commercial sectors and products and the Bank shall submit an updated list to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives of such sectors and products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial threshold determinations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of determining whether a proposed transaction exceeds a financial threshold under this subsection or under the procedures or rules of the Bank, the Bank shall aggregate the dollar amount of the proposed transaction and the dollar amounts of all loans and guarantees, approved by the Bank in the preceding 24-month period, that involved the same foreign entity and substantially the same product to be produced.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a7f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures to reduce adverse effects of loans and guarantees on industries and employment in United States</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a80-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of economic effects of proposed transactions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If, in making a determination under this paragraph with respect to a loan or guarantee, the Bank conducts a detailed economic impact analysis or similar study, the analysis or study, as the case may be, shall include consideration of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a81-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the factors set forth in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524a82-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the views of the public and interested parties.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a83-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and comment requirements</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a84-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If, in making a determination under this subsection with respect to a loan or guarantee, the Bank intends to conduct a detailed economic impact analysis or similar study, the Bank shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of the intent, and provide a period of not less than 14 days (which, on request by any affected party, shall be extended to a period of not more than 30 days) for the submission to the Bank of comments on the economic effects of the provision of the loan or guarantee, including comments on the factors set forth in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1). In addition, the Bank shall seek comments on the economic effects from the Department of Commerce, the Office of Management and Budget, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a85-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of notice</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The notice shall include appropriate, nonproprietary information about—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a86-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the country to which the goods involved in the transaction will be shipped;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a87-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the type of goods being exported;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a88-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the amount of the loan or guarantee involved;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a89-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> the goods that would be produced as a result of the provision of the loan or guarantee;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a8a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> the amount of increased production that will result from the transaction;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a8b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> the potential sales market for the resulting goods; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524a8c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/ii/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> the value of the transaction.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a8d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure regarding materially changed applications</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a8e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">If a material change is made to an application for a loan or guarantee from the Bank after a notice with respect to the intent described in clause (i) is published under this subparagraph, the Bank shall publish in the Federal Register a revised notice of the intent, and shall provide for a comment period, as provided in clauses (i) and (ii).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a8f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Material change defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">As used in subclause (I), the term “material change”, with respect to an application, includes—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="iddb524a90-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/iii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> a change of at least 25 percent in the amount of a loan or guarantee requested in the application; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="iddb524a91-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/B/iii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> a change in the principal product to be produced as a result of any transaction that would be facilitated by the provision of the loan or guarantee.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a92-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement to address views of adversely affected persons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before taking final action on an application for a loan or guarantee to which this section applies, the staff of the Bank shall provide in writing to the Board of Directors the views of any person who submitted comments pursuant to subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a93-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of conclusions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 30 days after a party affected by a final decision of the Board of Directors with respect to a loan or guarantee makes a written request therefor, the Bank shall provide to the affected party a non-confidential summary of the facts found and conclusions reached in any detailed economic impact analysis or similar study conducted pursuant to subparagraph (B) with respect to the loan or guarantee, that were submitted to the Board of Directors.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a94-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of documentation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bank shall maintain documentation relating to economic impact analyses and similar studies conducted under this subsection in a manner consistent with the Standards for Internal Control of the Federal Government issued by the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a95-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of interpretation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">This paragraph shall not be construed to make subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 applicable to the Bank.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a96-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/e/7/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Bank shall implement such regulations and procedures as may be appropriate to carry out this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a97-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to deny application for assistance based on fraud or corruption by party involved in the transaction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other authority of the Bank, the Bank may deny an application for assistance with respect to a transaction if the Bank has substantial credible evidence that any party to the transaction or any party involved in the transaction has committed an act of fraud or corruption in connection with the transaction, and shall deny an application for assistance if the end user, borrower, lender, or exporter has been convicted of an act of fraud or corruption in connection with an application for support from the Bank made in the preceding 5 years. The Bank may proceed with an application described in this subsection only if an end user, borrower, lender, or exporter can be fully excluded from the transaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a98-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for notifying applicants of application status</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank shall establish and adhere to a clearly defined process for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a99-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> acknowledging receipt of applications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a9a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> informing applicants that their applications are complete or, if incomplete or containing a minor defect, of the additional material or changes that, if supplied or made, would make the application eligible for consideration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb524a9b-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> keeping applicants informed of the status of their applications, including a clear and timely notification of approval or disapproval, and, in the case of disapproval, the reason for disapproval, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a9c-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Response to application for financing; implementation of online loan request and tracking process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524a9d-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Response to applications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 5 days after the Bank receives an application for financing, the Bank shall notify the applicant that the application has been received, and shall include in the notice—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a9e-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a request for such additional information as may be necessary to make the application complete;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524a9f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the name of a Bank employee who may be contacted with questions relating to the application; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524aa0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a unique identification number which may be used to review the status of the application at a website established by the Bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aa1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Website</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2007-09-01">September 1, 2007</date>, the Bank shall exercise the authority granted by subparagraphs (E)(x) and (J) of subsection (b)(1) to establish, and thereafter to maintain, a website through which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524aa2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Bank products may be applied for; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524aa3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> information may be obtained with respect to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524aa4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the status of any such application;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524aa5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Small Business Division of the Bank; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524aa6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/h/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> incentives, preferences, targets, and goals relating to small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/a">section 632(a) of title 15</ref>), including small business concerns exporting to Africa.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aa7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Due diligence standards for lender partners</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bank shall set due diligence standards for its lender partners and participants, which should be applied across all programs consistently. To minimize or prevent fraudulent activity, the Bank shall require all delegated lenders to implement “Know your customer practices”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aa8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-subordination requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In entering into financing contracts, the Bank shall seek a creditor status which is not subordinate to that of all other creditors, in order to reduce the risk to, and enhance recoveries for, the Bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aa9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on discrimination based on industry</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aaa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in this subchapter, the Bank may not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524aab-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> deny an application for financing based solely on the industry, sector, or business that the application concerns; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524aac-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> promulgate or implement policies that discriminate against an application based solely on the industry, sector, or business that the application concerns.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aad-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The prohibitions under paragraph (1) apply only to applications for financing by the Bank for projects concerning the exploration, development, production, or export of energy sources and the generation or transmission of electrical power, or combined heat and power, regardless of the energy source involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aae-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Program on China and Transformational Exports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524aaf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Bank shall establish a Program on China and Transformational Exports to support the extension of loans, guarantees, and insurance, at rates and on terms and other conditions, to the extent practicable, that are fully competitive with rates, terms, and other conditions established by the People’s Republic of China or by a covered country, that aim to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524ab0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> directly neutralize export subsidies for competing goods and services financed by official export credit, tied aid, or blended financing provided by the People’s Republic of China or by a covered country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524ab1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> advance the comparative leadership of the United States with respect to the People’s Republic of China, or support United States innovation, employment, and technological standards, through direct exports in any of the following areas:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Artificial intelligence.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Biotechnology.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Biomedical sciences.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Wireless communications equipment (including 5G or subsequent wireless technologies).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Quantum computing.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> Renewable energy, energy efficiency, and energy storage.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> Semiconductor and semiconductor machinery manufacturing.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ab9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><chapeau> Emerging financial technologies, including technologies that facilitate—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524aba-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/viii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> financial inclusion through increased access to capital and financial services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524abb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/viii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> data security and privacy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524abc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/viii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> payments, the transfer of funds, and associated messaging services; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddb524abd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/viii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> efforts to combat money laundering and the financing of terrorism.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524abe-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> Water treatment and sanitation, including technologies and infrastructure to reduce contaminants and improve water quality.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524abf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> High performance computing.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb524ac0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/1/B/xi"><num value="xi">(xi)</num><content> Associated services necessary for use of any of the foregoing exports.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524ac1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered countries</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “covered country” means any country that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524ac2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary of the Treasury designates as a covered country in a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Development of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524ac3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not a participant in the Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (in this subsection referred to as the “Arrangement”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb524ac4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is not in substantial compliance with the financial terms and conditions of the Arrangement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524ac5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Financing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524ac6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">It shall be a goal of the Bank to reserve not less than 20 percent of the applicable amount (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e/a/2">section 635e(a)(2) of this title</ref>) for support made pursuant to the Program on China and Transformational Exports.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb524ac7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary of the Treasury may reduce or eliminate the 20 percent goal in subparagraph (A), on reporting to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that the People’s Republic of China is in substantial compliance with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb54bac8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the financial terms and conditions of the Arrangement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb54bac9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the rules and principles of the Paris Club.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb54baca-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset and report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The program established under paragraph (1) shall expire on <date date="2026-12-31">December 31, 2026</date>. Not later than 4 years after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the President of the Bank shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate assessing the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb54bacb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The capacity and demand of United States entities to export goods and services in the areas described in paragraph (1)(B), as assessed in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb54bacc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The availability of private-sector financing for exports in the areas.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddb54bacd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The feasibility and advisability of continuing the goal of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph with respect to paragraph (1)(B) after <date date="2026-12-31">December 31, 2026</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="iddb54bace-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635/l/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems shall ensure that Bank authorizations pursuant to the Program on China and Transformational Exports are considered or reviewed expeditiously, consistent with the other credit standards required by law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb54bacf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch341/s2">July 31, 1945, ch. 341, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/526">59 Stat. 526</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1945-12-28/ch602">Dec. 28, 1945, ch. 602</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/666">59 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-06-09/ch101/s1">June 9, 1947, ch. 101, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/130">61 Stat. 130</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-05-21/ch64/s1">May 21, 1953, ch. 64, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/28">67 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/311">Pub. L. 87–311</ref>, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/673">75 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/101/s1/a">Pub. L. 88–101, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1963-08-20">Aug. 20, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/128">77 Stat. 128</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/a">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1968-03-13">Mar. 13, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/47-49">82 Stat. 47–49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, (2), (5), (6), <date date="1971-08-17">Aug. 17, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/345">85 Stat. 345</ref>, 346; <ref href="/us/pl/93/646">Pub. L. 93–646</ref>, §§ 2–6, 13, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2333-2335">88 Stat. 2333–2335</ref>, 2337; <ref href="/us/pl/95/143">Pub. L. 95–143</ref>, §§ 1–3, <date date="1977-10-26">Oct. 26, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1210">91 Stat. 1210</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX">Pub. L. 95–630, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1902–1904, 1907(a), 1909, 1910, 1915, 1916, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3724-3727">92 Stat. 3724–3727</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/470/tII/s210">Pub. L. 96–470, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2245">94 Stat. 2245</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VI, §§ 612, 616(a), 617, 618(a), (c), 619(b)–(d), 620(a), 622], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1255">97 Stat. 1255</ref>, 1257, 1258, 1260, 1261; <ref href="/us/pl/99/440/tII/s204">Pub. L. 99–440, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1986-10-02">Oct. 2, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1096">100 Stat. 1096</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/472">Pub. L. 99–472</ref>, §§ 2–11, 20(a), <date date="1986-10-15">Oct. 15, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1200-1203">100 Stat. 1200–1203</ref>, 1209; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3304">Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3304</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1384">102 Stat. 1384</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tIV/s4703">Pub. L. 100–690, title IV, § 4703</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4293">102 Stat. 4293</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/tI">Pub. L. 101–240, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), (c), (d), 102, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2493-2495">103 Stat. 2493–2495</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/513/tV/s562">Pub. L. 101–513, title V, § 562</ref> (part), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2031">104 Stat. 2031</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/623/s16">Pub. L. 101–623, § 16</ref>, <date date="1990-11-21">Nov. 21, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3357">104 Stat. 3357</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/145/s121/2">Pub. L. 102–145, § 121(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/266/s102">Pub. L. 102–266, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-04-01">Apr. 1, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/95">106 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/tI">Pub. L. 102–429, title I</ref>, §§ 104, 105, 107, 109(a), 110–112(d), 114, 116, 121(a), <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2189">106 Stat. 2189</ref>, 2190, 2193–2196, 2198; <ref href="/us/pl/102/583">Pub. L. 102–583</ref>, §§ 6(c), 12(a), (c)(1)(A), <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4932">106 Stat. 4932</ref>, 4935; <ref href="/us/pl/103/149/s4/b/5">Pub. L. 103–149, § 4(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-23">Nov. 23, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1505">107 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tVIII/s825">Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 825</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/514">108 Stat. 514</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/a">Pub. L. 103–428, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4375">108 Stat. 4375</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 103–447, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4693">108 Stat. 4693</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tXIII/s1303/a">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIII, § 1303(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2702">110 Stat. 2702</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/121">Pub. L. 105–121</ref>, §§ 5, 7(a), 9–12, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2529">111 Stat. 2529</ref>, 2530; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tXI">Pub. L. 106–569, title XI</ref>, §§ 1103(d)(1), 1104(a)(1), (2), <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3031">114 Stat. 3031</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/189">Pub. L. 107–189</ref>, §§ 2, 6(a), (b), 7–8(b), 11, 13, 15–19, 21, 24(a)(1)–(2)(D), (b)(1)–(3), <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/698">116 Stat. 698</ref>, 700, 704–709; <ref href="/us/pl/109/438">Pub. L. 109–438</ref>, §§ 3(a), (b)(2), (c), 5, 6(b)(2), 7, 8, 11, 12, 13(b), (c), 14(b), <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3268">120 Stat. 3268</ref>, 3269, 3272, 3273, 3276, 3277, 3279, 3280; <ref href="/us/pl/112/122">Pub. L. 112–122</ref>, §§ 7, 8, 12(b), 22, 23, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/354">126 Stat. 354</ref>, 357, 363; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLII/s52001/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LII, § 52001(a)</ref>, title LIII, § 53001, title LIV, §§ 54001(c), 54002(a), (b), title LV, § 55001, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1767-1769">129 Stat. 1767–1769</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV">Pub. L. 116–94, div. I, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(a), 403, 404(a), 405–407, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3021">133 Stat. 3021</ref>, 3023, 3024.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb54bad0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="iddb54bad1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For termination of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/c">section 1(c) of Pub. L. 103–428</ref>, see Effective and Termination Dates of 1994 Amendments note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb54bad2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb54bad3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(B), is title V of <ref href="/us/pl/93/344">Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13201/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13201(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-609">104 Stat. 1388–609</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 661 et seq.) of chapter 17A of Title 2, The Congress. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of Title 2</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(B), (L), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/95/213">Pub. L. 95–213</ref>, <date date="1977-12-19">Dec. 19, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1494">91 Stat. 1494</ref>, which enacted sections 78dd–1 to 78dd–3 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and amended sections 78m and 78ff of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1977 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(B), (L), (6)(F), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The International Emergency Economic Powers Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(B), (L), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/223">Pub. L. 95–223</ref>, <date date="1977-12-28">Dec. 28, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1626">91 Stat. 1626</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Export Administration Act of 1979, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(B), (L), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/72">Pub. L. 96–72</ref>, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/503">93 Stat. 503</ref>, which was classified principally to chapter 56 (§ 4601 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXVII/s1766/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVII, § 1766(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2232">132 Stat. 2232</ref>, except for sections 11A, 11B, and 11C thereof (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4611">50 U.S.C. 4611</ref>, 4612, 4613).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151q">Section 2151q of title 22</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(C), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tIII/s304/g">Pub. L. 96–533, title III, § 304(g)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3147">94 Stat. 3147</ref>. See section 2151d(a)(2), (b)(2), (c) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The African Growth and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(9)(C), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/106/200">Pub. L. 106–200</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/252">114 Stat. 252</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 3701 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3701">section 3701 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tariff Act of 1930, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(i), (B), is <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">act June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/590">46 Stat. 590</ref>. Title VII of the Act is classified generally to subtitle IV (§ 1671 et seq.) of chapter 4 of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1654">section 1654 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(ii), (D), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1978">88 Stat. 1978</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 2251 et seq.) of chapter 12 of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">section 2101 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="2006-12-20">December 20, 2006</date>, referred to in subsec. (e)(5), was in the original “the date of the enactment of this Act”, which was translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/438">Pub. L. 109–438</ref>, which enacted subsec. (e)(5), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb54bad4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/c">Section 1(c) of Pub. L. 90–267</ref> added pars. (2) to (5) of subsec. (b) and another section of <ref href="/us/pl/90/267">Pub. L. 90–267</ref> also designated 1(c) substituted “$3,500,000,000” for “$2,000,000,000” in subsec. (c)(1). See, also, 1968 Amendments hereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb54bad5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403</ref>, added subcl. (I) and struck out former subcl. (I) which read as follows: “It is further the policy of the United States to encourage the participation of small business in international commerce.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s405">Pub. L. 116–94, § 405</ref>, inserted at end “For the purpose of calculating the amounts of authority required under this clause, the Bank shall, with respect to insurance, exclude unutilized authorizations that terminated during the fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s404/a">Pub. L. 116–94, § 404(a)</ref>, substituted “30” for “25”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s407">Pub. L. 116–94, § 407</ref>, inserted before period at end “, energy efficiency (including battery electric vehicles, batteries for electric vehicles, and electric vehicle charging infrastructure), and energy storage. It shall be a goal of the Bank to ensure that not less than 5 percent of the applicable amount (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e/a/2">section 635e(a)(2) of this title</ref>) is made available each fiscal year for the financing of renewable energy, energy efficiency (including battery electric vehicles, batteries for electric vehicles, and electric vehicle charging infrastructure), and energy storage technology exports”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s406/1">Pub. L. 116–94, § 406(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, and shall deny an application for assistance if the end user, borrower, lender, or exporter has been convicted of an act of fraud or corruption in connection with an application for support from the Bank made in the preceding 5 years. The Bank may proceed with an application described in this subsection only if an end user, borrower, lender, or exporter can be fully excluded from the transaction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s406/2">Pub. L. 116–94, § 406(2)</ref>, substituted “shall require” for “should require”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s402/a">Pub. L. 116–94, § 402(a)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s54002/a">Pub. L. 114–94, § 54002(a)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s52001/a">Pub. L. 114–94, § 52001(a)</ref>, substituted “25 percent” for “20 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(M). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s53001">Pub. L. 114–94, § 53001</ref>, added subpar. (M).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s54001/c">Pub. L. 114–94, § 54001(c)</ref>, substituted “the date on which the authority of the Bank expires under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">section 635f of this title</ref>” for “<date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s54002/b">Pub. L. 114–94, § 54002(b)</ref>, substituted “$25,000,000” for “$10,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s55001">Pub. L. 114–94, § 55001</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s22">Pub. L. 112–122, § 22</ref>, redesignated subcls. (II), (III), (V), (VI), (VIII), and (IX) as (I) to (VI), respectively, and struck out subcls. (I), (IV), and (VII) which deemed Cambodian People’s Republic, Lao People’s Democratic Republic, and Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia as Marxist-Leninist countries for purposes of par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s23">Pub. L. 112–122, § 23</ref>, substituted “2014” for “2011”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(E) to (G). <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s12/b">Pub. L. 112–122, § 12(b)</ref>, added subpar. (E) and redesignated former subpars. (E) and (F) as (F) and (G), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s7">Pub. L. 112–122, § 7</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s8">Pub. L. 112–122, § 8</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s13/b">Pub. L. 109–438, § 13(b)</ref>, (c), inserted “, including countries the governments of which are not members of the Arrangement (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3/h/3">section 635i–3(h)(3) of this title</ref>)” after “United States exporters” in second sentence and struck out fourth to twelfth sentences which related to compliance reporting requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s14/b">Pub. L. 109–438, § 14(b)</ref>, inserted at end “From the amount made available under the preceding sentence, it shall be a goal of the Bank to increase the amount made available to finance exports directly by small business concerns referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a/i/1">section 635a(i)(1) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(vii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s6/b/2">Pub. L. 109–438, § 6(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “or other financing institutions or entities” after “consortia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s3/a">Pub. L. 109–438, § 3(a)</ref>, substituted “2011” for “2006”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 109–438, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, (c), added subpars. (C) and (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s11">Pub. L. 109–438, § 11</ref>, added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s7/1">Pub. L. 109–438, § 7(1)</ref>, inserted concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s8/b">Pub. L. 109–438, § 8(b)</ref>, inserted “of not less than 14 days (which, on request of any affected party, shall be extended to a period of not more than 30 days)” after “comment period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s7/2">Pub. L. 109–438, § 7(2)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438">Pub. L. 109–438</ref>, §§ 5, 7(3), 8(a), added pars. (5) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s12">Pub. L. 109–438, § 12</ref>, added subsecs. (g) and (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s2">Pub. L. 107–189, § 2</ref>, substituted “The objects and purposes of the Bank shall be to aid in financing and to facilitate exports of goods and services, imports, and the exchange of commodities and services between the United States or any of its territories or insular possessions and any foreign country or the agencies or nationals of any such country, and in so doing to contribute to the employment of United States workers. The Bank’s objective in authorizing loans, guarantees, insurance, and credits shall be to contribute to maintaining or increasing employment of United States workers.” for “The objects and purposes of the bank shall be to aid in financing and to facilitate exports and imports and the exchange of commodities and services between the United States or any of its Territories or insular possessions and any foreign country or the agencies or nationals thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189">Pub. L. 107–189</ref>, §§ 11, 13(b), substituted “not later than June 30 of each year” for “on an annual basis” in fourth sentence, inserted “(including through use of market windows)” after “which foreign exporters compete with the United States exporters” in fifth sentence, inserted “With respect to the preceding sentence, the Bank shall use all available information to estimate the annual amount of export financing available from each government and government-related agency.” after fifth sentence, and inserted at end “The Bank shall include in the annual report a description of all Bank transactions which shall be classified according to their principal purpose, such as to correct a market failure or to provide matching support. The Bank shall include in the annual report a description of the efforts undertaken under subparagraph (K).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189">Pub. L. 107–189</ref>, §§ 15, 17, 21, 24(a)(1), substituted “Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives” for “Committee on Banking and Financial Services of the House of Representatives” and inserted “(including, when relevant, a foreign nation’s lack of cooperation in efforts to eradicate terrorism)” after “international terrorism”, “the enforcement of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, the Arms Export Control Act, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, or the Export Administration Act of 1979,” after “nuclear proliferation,” and “(such as are provided in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights adopted by the United Nations General Assembly on <date date="1948-12-10">December 10, 1948</date>)” after “human rights”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s7/b">Pub. L. 107–189, § 7(b)</ref>, inserted “, with particular emphasis on conducting outreach and increasing loans to socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s637/a/4">section 637(a)(4) of title 15</ref>), small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/a">section 632(a) of title 15</ref>) owned by women, and small business concerns (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/a">section 632(a) of title 15</ref>) employing fewer than 100 employees,” after “Bank”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s7/a">Pub. L. 107–189, § 7(a)</ref>, substituted “20 percent” for “10 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(x). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s8/a">Pub. L. 107–189, § 8(a)</ref>, added cl. (x).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(H)(ii), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/b/1">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(b)(1)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5402">section 5402 of title 22</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(J). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s8/b">Pub. L. 107–189, § 8(b)</ref>, added subpar. (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s13/a">Pub. L. 107–189, § 13(a)</ref>, added subpar. (K).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(L). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s19">Pub. L. 107–189, § 19</ref>, added subpar. (L).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(D)(i)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/a/2/A">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives” for “Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/b/3">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “internationally” for “international”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/a/2/B">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives” for “Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(I)(i)(II), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/a/2/C">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(a)(2)(C)</ref>, (D), substituted “Committees on Financial Services” for “Committees on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s6/b">Pub. L. 107–189, § 6(b)</ref>, inserted “, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee,” after “shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s6/a">Pub. L. 107–189, § 6(a)</ref>, amended cl. (iii) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (iii) read as follows: “The advisory committee shall terminate 4 years after <date date="1997-11-26">November 26, 1997</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s24/b/2">Pub. L. 107–189, § 24(b)(2)</ref>, realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s18">Pub. L. 107–189, § 18</ref>, substituted “Paragraphs (1) and (2)” for “Paragraph (1)” in par. (2), added a new par. (2), and redesignated former pars. (2) and (3) as (3) and (4), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s16">Pub. L. 107–189, § 16</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s1103/d/1">Pub. L. 106–569, § 1103(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “The Bank shall, on an annual basis, report” for “The Bank shall, on a annual basis, report” and inserted at end “The annual report required under this subparagraph shall include the report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3/g">section 635i–3(g) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s1104/a/1">Pub. L. 106–569, § 1104(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “(i)” after “(D)” and struck out cl. (ii) which read as follows: “The Bank shall include in its annual report a summary of its programs regarding the export of services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s1104/a/2">Pub. L. 106–569, § 1104(a)(2)</ref>, struck out at end “The Bank shall include in the report to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635g/a">section 635g(a) of this title</ref> a description of the measures undertaken by it pursuant to this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s10">Pub. L. 105–121, § 10</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “real income, a commitment to reinvestment and job creation, and the increased development of the productive resources of the United States” for “real income and to the increased development of the productive resources of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s11">Pub. L. 105–121, § 11</ref>, inserted “(including child labor)” after “human rights” in penultimate sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s5/2">Pub. L. 105–121, § 5(2)</ref>, inserted at end “Each such determination shall be delivered in writing to the President of the Bank, shall state that the determination is made pursuant to this section, and shall specify the applications or categories of applications for credit which should be denied by the Bank in furtherance of the national interest.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s5/1">Pub. L. 105–121, § 5(1)</ref>, in penultimate sentence, inserted “, after consultation with the Committee on Banking and Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate,” after “President”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s9">Pub. L. 105–121, § 9</ref>, added subpar. (I).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s7/a">Pub. L. 105–121, § 7(a)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s12">Pub. L. 105–121, § 12</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> amended par. (4) generally, restating provisions of former single par. as subpars. (A) to (F) with addition of provisions relating to persons knowingly aiding or abetting non-nuclear-weapon states to acquire nuclear explosive devices or unsafeguarded special nuclear material and requiring Secretary of State to initiate consultations with governments having jurisdiction over such persons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> inserted “(as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/4">section 6305(4) of title 22</ref>), or that any country has willfully aided or abetted any non-nuclear-weapon state (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/5">section 6305(5) of title 22</ref>) to acquire any such nuclear explosive device or to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6305/8">section 6305(8) of title 22</ref>).” after “device” at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/447">Pub. L. 103–447</ref> substituted “defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291/e">section 2291(e) of title 22</ref>” for “determined under section 2291j(h) or 2291(e), as appropriate, of title 22”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/b">Pub. L. 103–428, § 1(b)</ref>, (c), temporarily inserted “or described in subparagraph (I)(i)” before period at end of first sentence. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1994 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/a">Pub. L. 103–428, § 1(a)</ref>, (c), temporarily added subpar. (I). See Effective and Termination Dates of 1994 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/103/149">Pub. L. 103–149</ref> struck out par. (9) which prohibited the Bank from taking certain actions with respect to business affecting Republic of South Africa.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s121/a/1">Pub. L. 102–429, § 121(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “(A) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—” before “To enhance the medium-term”, redesignated cls. (i) to (iv) as subpars. (A) to (D), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Report required</inline>.—Not later than <date date="1988-04-15">April 15, 1988</date>, the Bank shall transmit a report to the Congress analyzing the measures adopted to enhance medium-term financing.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s121/a/2">Pub. L. 102–429, § 121(a)(2)</ref>, added sentence at end and struck out former last sentence which read as follows: “The Bank shall also include in the annual report a description of each loan by the Bank involving the export of any product or service related to the production, refining or transportation of any type of energy or the development of any energy resource with a statement assessing the impact, if any, on the availability of such products, services, or energy supplies thus developed for use within the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s104">Pub. L. 102–429, § 104</ref>, inserted after first semicolon in fifth sentence “that the Bank, in determining whether to provide support for a transaction under the loan, guarantee, or insurance program, or any combination thereof, shall consider the need to involve private capital in support of United States exports as well as the cost of the transaction as calculated in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s121/a/3">Pub. L. 102–429, § 121(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “not less than 10 percent of such authority for each fiscal year.” for “not less than—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) 6 per centum of such authority for fiscal year 1984;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) 8 per centum of such authority for fiscal year 1985; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(III) 10 per centum of such authority for fiscal year 1986 and thereafter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s116">Pub. L. 102–429, § 116</ref>, inserted “directly” after “to finance exports”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s114">Pub. L. 102–429, § 114</ref>, added subpar. (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s110">Pub. L. 102–429, § 110</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(i) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—For the purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘Marxist-Leninist country’ means any country which—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) maintains a centrally planned economy based on the principles of Marxist-Leninism, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) is economically and militarily dependent on the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics or on any other Marxist-Leninist country.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(ii) <inline class="small-caps">Specific countries deemed to be marxist-leninist</inline>.—Unless otherwise determined by the President in the manner provided in subparagraph (C), the following countries are deemed to be Marxist-Leninist countries for purposes of this paragraph:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Cambodian People’s Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Cooperative Republic of Guyana.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Czechoslovak Socialist Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Democratic Republic of Afghanistan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Estonia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“German Democratic Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Hungarian People’s Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Lao People’s Democratic Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Latvia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Lithuania.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Mongolian People’s Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Democratic Republic of Yemen.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of Albania.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of Angola.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of Benin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of Bulgaria.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of China.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of the Congo.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“People’s Republic of Mozambique.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Polish People’s Republic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Republic of Cuba.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Republic of Nicaragua.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Socialist Ethiopia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Socialist Federal Republic of Yugo­slavia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Socialist Republic of Romania.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Socialist Republic of Vietnam.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Surinam.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Tibet.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (including its captive constituent republics).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s12/c/1/A">Pub. L. 102–583, § 12(c)(1)(A)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “, except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (B).” for “designated” and all that follows through the end of the subparagraph could not be executed because the words did not appear subsequent to the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/d/1">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(d)(1)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/d/1">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(d)(1)</ref>, struck out before period at end “designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4916">section 4916 of title 26</ref> as an economically less developed country for purposes of the tax imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4911">section 4911 of title 26</ref>. The prohibitions set forth in this subparagraph shall not apply with respect to any transaction the consummation of which the President determines would be in the national interest and reports such determination (within thirty days after making the same) to the Senate and House of Representatives. In making any such determination the President shall take into account, among other considerations, the national interest in avoiding arms races among countries not directly menaced by the Soviet Union or by Communist China; in avoiding arming military dictators who are denying social progress to their own peoples; and in avoiding expenditures by developing countries of scarce foreign exchange needed for peaceful economic progress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/d/2/A">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(d)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “, and section 32 of the Arms Export Control Act,” after “Subparagraph (A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s6/c/1">Pub. L. 102–583, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j/e">section 2291j(e) of title 22</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291/h/5">section 2291(h)(5) of title 22</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B)(iv), (v). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/a/1">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(a)(1)</ref>, (2), (d)(2)(B), inserted “and” at end of cl. (iv) and substituted “articles or services.” for “articles and services; and” at end of cl. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s12/a">Pub. L. 102–583, § 12(a)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “1997” for “1992” in cl. (vi), could not be executed because cl. (vi) was struck out by <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/a/3">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(a)(3)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/a/3">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(a)(3)</ref>, struck out cl. (vi) which read as follows: “the sale is made on or before <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s6/c/2">Pub. L. 102–583, § 6(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “determined under section 2291j(h) or 2291(e), as appropriate, of title 22” for “defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291/i">section 2291(i) of title 22</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/b">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(b)</ref>, (d)(3), struck out “and” at end of subcl. (I), added subcl. (II), redesignated former subcl. (II) as (III), and substituted “determinations have” for “determination has” in subcl. (III).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(D)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/d/4">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(d)(4)</ref>, substituted “clause” for “sentence” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/d/5">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(d)(5)</ref>, substituted “or services” for “and services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s112/c">Pub. L. 102–429, § 112(c)</ref>, added subpar. (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11), (12). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s111">Pub. L. 102–429, § 111</ref>, redesignated par. (12) as (11), substituted “The President” for “Notwithstanding any determination by the President under paragraph (2) or (11), the”, and struck out former par. (11) which read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Relating to Angola</inline>.—Notwithstanding any determination by the President under paragraph (2), the Bank may not guarantee, insure, or extend credit (or participate in the extension of credit) in connection with any export of goods or services, except food or agricultural commodities, to the People’s Republic of Angola until the President certifies to the Congress that no combatant forces or military advisors of the Republic of Cuba or of any other Marxist-Leninist country (as such term is defined in paragraph (2)(B)) remain in Angola.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s109/a">Pub. L. 102–429, § 109(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The Bank is authorized and empowered to charge against the limitations imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e">section 635e of this title</ref>, not less than 25 per centum of the related contractual liability which the Bank incurs for guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance against political and credit risks of loss. The aggregate amount of guarantees, insurance, coinsurance, and reinsurance which may be charged on this fractional basis pursuant to this section shall not exceed $25,000,000,000 outstanding at any one time. Fees and premiums shall be charged in connection with such contracts commensurate, in the judgment of the Bank, with risks covered.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s105">Pub. L. 102–429, § 105</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s107">Pub. L. 102–429, § 107</ref>, added pars. (2) to (5) and struck out former pars. (2) and (3) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) In furtherance of such effort, the Chairman of the Bank shall review Bank policies and programs in regard to this issue, and in coordination with the United States Trade Representative and the appropriate agencies of the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Commerce, undertake actions designed to promote equal and nondiscriminatory opportunities to bid for insurance in connection with all aspects of international trade activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) The Bank shall report to the Committee or Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate not later than <date date="1984-05-15">May 15, 1984</date>, regarding—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the existing obstacles to equal and nondiscriminatory bidding for insurance related to transactions assisted by the Bank;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the efforts that the Bank has taken in addressing such problems; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) recommendations for such legislative or administrative actions as the Bank considers necessary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s121/a/4">Pub. L. 102–429, § 121(a)(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which related to interest subsidy payments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/145/s121/2">Pub. L. 102–145, § 121(2)</ref>, (3), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/266">Pub. L. 102–266</ref>, amended par. (3) in introductory provisions by redesignating cl. (iii) as (ii) and striking out “(ii) in an amount which equals or exceeds $25,000,000 for the export of goods or services involving research, exploration, or production of fossil fuel energy resources in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(6)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/101/513">Pub. L. 101–513</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/101/623">Pub. L. 101–623</ref> amended cl. (vi) identically, substituting “1992” for “1990”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s101/c">Pub. L. 101–240, § 101(c)</ref>, substituted “Subject to regulations which the Bank shall issue pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, the Bank may” for “The Bank may” in sixth sentence and inserted before period “, and may accept reimbursement for travel and subsistence expenses incurred by a director, officer, or employee of the Bank, in accordance with subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5” and inserted before period in seventh sentence “and shall be offset against the expenses of the Bank for such activities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s101/d">Pub. L. 101–240, § 101(d)</ref>, substituted “subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (F)” for “this paragraph”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s102">Pub. L. 101–240, § 102</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 101–240, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Authority to make payments subject to minimum amount of direct loan authority</inline>.—The authority to enter into commitments to make interest subsidy payments under paragraph (1) shall be effective for any fiscal year only if the aggregate principal amount of direct loans the Bank may obligate in such fiscal year is equal to or greater than $700,000,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 101–240, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated par. (4) as (3) and amended it generally. Prior to amendment, such par. read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—Subject to subparagraph (B), there are authorized to be appropriated to the Bank, for any fiscal year beginning after fiscal year 1986, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Budget scoring</inline>.—No amount is authorized to be appropriated for commitments to make interest subsidy payments on loans for which the Bank extends a loan guarantee commitment if any amount of such loan guarantee commitment is scored as budget authority in any estimate of budget authority prepared pursuant to any provision of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974.” Former par. (3) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 101–240, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (5) as (4) and substituted “1991” for “1988”. Former par. (4) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> designated existing provision as subpar. (A), substituted “subparagraph” for “paragraph”, and added subpars. (B) to (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s3304/a">Pub. L. 100–418, § 3304(a)</ref>, substituted “commodity will first be sold” for “productive capacity is expected to become operative”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s3304/b">Pub. L. 100–418, § 3304(b)</ref>, substituted “short- and long-term injury” for “injury” and “producers and employment” for “producers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s3304/c">Pub. L. 100–418, § 3304(c)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s2">Pub. L. 99–472, § 2</ref>, inserted provisions which related to imposition and collection of reasonable fees by Bank to cover costs of conferences and seminars sponsored, and publications provided, by Bank, and credit of amounts thus received to fund which initially paid for such activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s4">Pub. L. 99–472, § 4</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472">Pub. L. 99–472</ref>, §§ 3, 5, substituted “need not be identical in all respects to those” for “need not be equivalent to those” and inserted provisions which prohibited Bank from imposing credit application fee unless Bank’s fee is competitive with average fee charged by Bank’s primary foreign competitors, and option of paying fee at outset of, or over life of, loan is given to borrower or exporter, and present value of fee determined under either option is same amount.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E)(ix). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s6">Pub. L. 99–472, § 6</ref>, added cl. (ix).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s7">Pub. L. 99–472, § 7</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s8">Pub. L. 99–472, § 8</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The Bank in the exercise of its functions shall not guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in any extension of credit—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) in connection with the purchase or lease of any product by a Communist country (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370/f">section 2370(f) of title 22</ref>), or agency, or national thereof, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) in connection with the purchase or lease of any product by any other foreign country, or agency or national thereof, if the product to be purchased or leased by such other country, agency, or national is, to the knowledge of the Bank, principally for use in, or sale or lease to, a Communist country (as so defined),</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless the President determines that guarantees, insurance, or extensions of credit in connection therewith to such Communist or such other country or agency or national thereof would be in the national interest. The President shall make a separate determination with respect to each transaction in which the bank would extend a loan to such Communist or other country, or agency, or national thereof an amount of $50,000,000 or more. Any determination required under the first sentence of this paragraph shall be reported to the Congress not later than the earlier of thirty days following the date of such determination, or the date on which the Bank takes final action on a transaction which is the first transaction involving such country or agency or national after <date date="1975-01-04">January 4, 1975</date>, unless a determination with respect to such country or agency or national has been made and reported prior to <date date="1975-01-04">January 4, 1975</date>. Any determination required to be made under the second sentence of this paragraph shall be reported to the Congress not later than the earlier of thirty days following the date of such determination or the date on which the Bank takes final action on the transaction involved.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/99/440">Pub. L. 99–440</ref> designated existing provisions of par. (9) as subpar. (A), substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in no event” for “In no event”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s9">Pub. L. 99–472, § 9</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s10">Pub. L. 99–472, § 10</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472">Pub. L. 99–472</ref>, §§ 11, 20(a), added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s616/a/1">Pub. L. 98–181, § 616(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “the exchange of commodities and services” for “the exchange of commodities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s622">Pub. L. 98–181, § 622</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref>, §§ 612(a), 616(a)(2), in second sentence inserted “in all its programs” after “To meet this objective”, inserted “fully” after “other conditions which are”, and substituted “exports of goods and services” for “exports”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref>, §§ 612(b), (c), 618(a)(1), substituted provisions that loans under this section shall bear interest at rates consistent with the Bank’s mandate to support exports at rates and on terms and conditions which are fully competitive with exports of other countries, and consistent with international agreements, and that such rates, terms and conditions need not be equivalent to those offered by foreign countries, but should be established so as to neutralize the effect of such foreign credit on international sales competition, and that the Board shall consider its average cost of money in determination of interest rates, where such consideration does not impair the Bank’s function of expanding exports through fully competitive financing for provisions that loans made by the Bank had to be at interest at rates determined by the Board of Directors of the Bank, taking into consideration the average cost of money to the Bank as well as the Bank’s mandate to support United States exports at rates and on terms and conditions which were competitive with exports of other countries; inserted “export trading companies,” after “independent export firms,”; and struck out provision which required the Bank to give due recognition to the policy stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631/a">section 631(a) of Title 15</ref> that the government should aid, counsel, assist, and protect the interests of small business in order to preserve free competitive enterprise, and that in furtherance of this policy the Board of Directors had to designate an officer of the Bank to handle small business concerns, including advising small businessmen and maintaining liaison with the Small Business Administration and other departments and agencies in matters affecting small business concerns.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s616/a/3">Pub. L. 98–181, § 616(a)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s618/a/2">Pub. L. 98–181, § 618(a)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s618/c">Pub. L. 98–181, § 618(c)</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s619/b">Pub. L. 98–181, § 619(b)</ref>, substituted “no loan or financial guarantee or general guarantee or insurance facility” for “no loan or financial guarantee” in provisions preceding subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s619/c">Pub. L. 98–181, § 619(c)</ref>, inserted language limiting existing provisions to loans or financial guarantees, designated existing provisions as cls. (i), (ii), and (iii), and added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s620/a">Pub. L. 98–181, § 620(a)</ref>, substituted “the Secretary” for “he” before “determines that any country” in first sentence, and before “has determined to have so acted” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s619/d">Pub. L. 98–181, § 619(d)</ref>, redesignated second par. (7) and par. (8), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, as pars. (8) and (9), respectively, and added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s617">Pub. L. 98–181, § 617</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/96/470">Pub. L. 96–470</ref> substituted “annual” for “semiannual” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s1910">Pub. L. 95–630, § 1910</ref>, substituted “manufactured goods, agricultural products, and other goods and services” for “goods and related services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, §§ 1904, 1916, inserted “that the Bank should give emphasis to assisting new and small business entrants in the agricultural export market, and shall, in cooperation with other relevant Government agencies, including the Commodity Credit Corporation, develop a program of education to increase awareness of export opportunities among small agribusinesses and cooperatives;” after “in matters affecting small business concerns;” and substituted “and shall give particular emphasis to the objective of strengthening the competitive position of the United States exporters and thereby of expanding total United States exports. Only in cases where the President determines that such action would be in the national interest where such action would clearly and importantly advance United States policy in such areas as international terrorism, nuclear proliferation, environmental protection and human rights, should the Export-Import Bank deny applications for credit for nonfinancial or noncommercial considerations” for “and shall also take into account, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the observance of and respect for human rights in the country to receive the exports supported by a loan or financial guarantee and the effect such exports may have on human rights in such country”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s1907/a">Pub. L. 95–630, § 1907(a)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s1902">Pub. L. 95–630, § 1902</ref>, substituted “Except as provided by the fourth sentence of this paragraph, no loan” for “No loan” and “$100,000,000” for “$60,000,000” and inserted provisions following subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, §§ 1909, 1915, added a second par. (7) and par. (8), which were editorially designated pars. (8) and (9). See 1983 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s1903">Pub. L. 95–630, § 1903</ref>, substituted “$25,000,000,000” for “$20,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/143/s1">Pub. L. 95–143, § 1</ref>, inserted “and shall, in cooperation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, seek to reach international agreements to reduce government subsidized export financing” after “government-supported export financing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/143/s2">Pub. L. 95–143, § 2</ref>, inserted “, and shall also take into account, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the observance of and respect for human rights in the country to receive the exports supported by a loan or financial guarantee and the effect such exports may have on human rights in such country” after “employment in the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/143/s3/a">Pub. L. 95–143, § 3(a)</ref>, inserted “(i)” after “No loan or financial guarantee or combination thereof” and “, or (iii) for the export of technology, fuel, equipment, materials, or goods or services to be used in the construction, alteration, operation, or maintenance of nuclear power, enrichment, reprocessing, research, or heavy water production facilities,” after “Union of Soviet Socialist Republics” and substituted “, (ii) in an amount” for “shall be finally approved by the Board of Directors of the Bank, and no loan or financial guarantee or combination thereof”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/143/s3/b">Pub. L. 95–143, § 3(b)</ref>, (c), added par. (4), redesignated former par. (4) as (5) and, as so redesignated, added cl. (C), and redesignated former pars. (5) and (6) as (6) and (7), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s2">Pub. L. 93–646, § 2</ref>, inserted provisions authorizing the Bank to guarantee, insure, coinsure, and reinsure against political and credit risks of loss, to represent itself or to contract for representation in all legal and arbitral proceedings outside the United States, and to publish any documents, reports, etc., without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref>, whenever compliance with such section would not be practicable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s13">Pub. L. 93–646, § 13</ref>, eff. at the close of <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, repealed par. (2), which related to inclusion of receipts and disbursements of the bank in the federal budget and exemption of such receipts and disbursements from budget limitations, to the transmittal to Congress of a budget for program activities and for administrative expenses of the bank, and to the annual report of the net lending of the bank.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s3">Pub. L. 93–646, § 3</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpars. (A) and (B), and as so designated, substituted provisions requiring a comparison of the rates and terms of the Bank with other countries for provisions requiring a report to include ways in which the Bank’s terms are equal to or superior to those of other countries, and inserted provisions requiring the appointment of a Bank officer to be responsible for all matters affecting small business, and to act as liaison with the Small Business Administration and other agencies in matters affecting small business concerns, in order to carry out the policy of the Small Business Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s4">Pub. L. 93–646, § 4</ref>, inserted provision requiring a separate Presidential determination of national interest with respect to each transaction over $50,000,000, and substituted provision requiring a report to Congress either within 30 days of the President’s finding or on the day the Bank takes final action on the proposed credit, whichever is earlier, for provision requiring a report of his finding to Congress within thirty days after making such finding.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s5">Pub. L. 93–646, § 5</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3), (4), and (5) as (4), (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s6">Pub. L. 93–646, § 6</ref>, removed the $10 billion limit on the Bank’s insurance authority, and increased the Bank’s authority to charge such guarantees and insurance on a fractional charge basis from $10 billion to $20 billion.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/b/6">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(b)(6)</ref>, inserted provisions declaring the policy of the United States to be to foster expansion of goods and related services, contributing to the proposition and maintenance of high levels of employment and real income and to the increased development of the productive resources of the United States and laid down directives to achieve this objective.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/b/5">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(b)(5)</ref>, substituted provisions prohibiting the Bank from extending assistance in export sales to any nation which engages in armed conflict with the United States or to any other nation when the export is to be used principally by or in any nation which engages in armed conflict with the United States and further prohibiting such assistance to any export sales which the President determines would be contrary to the national interest for provisions placing limitations on the Bank’s activity in connection with any nation which supplies goods or assistance to a country with whom the United States is engaged in armed conflict.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/b/2">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, increased the amount of insurance outstanding at any one time from “$3,500,000,000” to “$10,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/a">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(a)</ref>, changed name of “Export-Import Bank of Washington” to “Export-Import Bank of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/b">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and required the Board of Directors when authorizing loans to take into account the possible adverse effects upon the economy of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/c">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(c)</ref>, added pars. (2) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/a">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(a)</ref>, (c), increased amount of insurance outstanding at any one time from $2,000,000,000 to $3,500,000,000 and changed name of “Export-Import Bank of Washington” to “Export-Import Bank of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/88/101">Pub. L. 88–101</ref> substituted “$2,000,000,000” for “$1,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/311">Pub. L. 87–311</ref> amended subsection generally, and among other changes, authorized the Bank to guarantee, insure, coinsure, and reinsure United States exporters and foreign exporters doing business in the United States, increased the maximum amount of insurance, etc., outstanding at any one time to $1,000,000,000, limited the types of risks the Bank would insure, etc., to political and credit risks, required reserves to be maintained at not less than 25 per centum of the related contractual liability of the Bank, provided that for contracts of insurance, etc., only the Bank’s liabilities represented by the aforementioned reserves shall be considered for purposes of applying the limitations of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635e">section 635e of this title</ref>, required the charging of fees and premiums, and authorized issuance of insurance, etc., to exporters, insurance companies, financial institutions, or others, and where appropriate, to employ any of the same as agent, and struck out provisions authorizing insurance for the benefit of United States citizens against loss of tangible personal property of United States origin, exported from the United States, and located in a friendly country, from hostile or warlike actions including internal strife, or from governmental confiscation or expropriation, to the extent owned by the assured or constituting security for obligations owed the assured, limiting the issuance of insurance to the extent that it could not be obtained from private companies authorized to do business in the United States, or from United States Government agencies providing marine or air war-risk insurance, permitting reinsurance of companies authorized to do an insurance business in the United States, or to use such company or companies as agent, and limiting the term of coverage of any insurance issued to one year, subject to renewals or extensions, from time to time, of one year periods.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1953-05-21">May 21, 1953</date>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1947—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1947-06-09">June 9, 1947</date>, provided for the reincorporation of the Bank as a corporate agency of the United States and specifically provided for the following powers which the bank formerly possessed by implication: (1) to acquire stock through the enforcement of any lien or pledge or to satisfy an indebtedness; (2) to sue and be sued, to complain and defend in any court of competent jurisdiction; (3) to use the United States mails as any other executive department; and (4) after provision for possible losses to use the net earnings as dividends on capital stock and to deposit said dividends as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1945—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1945-12-28">Dec. 28, 1945</date>, inserted “(or the Philippine Islands)” after “any foreign country”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb572bd6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb572bd7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s404/b">Pub. L. 116–94, div. I, title IV, § 404(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3023">133 Stat. 3023</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s404/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb572bd8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLII/s52001/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LII, § 52001(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1767">129 Stat. 1767</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLII/s52001/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54001/d">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LIV, § 54001(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1768">129 Stat. 1768</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54001/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">section 635f of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under this section] shall take effect on the earlier of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>] or <date date="2015-06-30">June 30, 2015</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54002/e">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LIV, § 54002(e)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1769">129 Stat. 1769</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54002/e">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 635a and 635i–5 of this title] shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb572bd9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s25">Pub. L. 112–122, § 25</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/364">126 Stat. 364</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/122/s25">“Except as provided in section 9(b) [enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of this title</ref>], this Act [see Short Title of 2012 Amendment note set out below] and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the earlier of <date date="2012-06-01">June 1, 2012</date>, or the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb572bda-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1994 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/c">Pub. L. 103–428, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4376">108 Stat. 4376</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s4">Pub. L. 105–121, § 4</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2529">111 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s4">Pub. L. 109–438, § 4</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3269">120 Stat. 3269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s24">Pub. L. 112–122, § 24</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/364">126 Stat. 364</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/136/s1">Pub. L. 112–136, § 1</ref>, <date date="2012-06-21">June 21, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/385">126 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54001/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LIV, § 54001(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1768">129 Stat. 1768</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLIV/s54001/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall remain in effect during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>] and ending on the date on which the authority of the Export-Import Bank of the United States expires under section 7 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">12 U.S.C. 635f</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/tVI">Pub. L. 113–235, div. J, title VI</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2598">128 Stat. 2598</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/tVI">“That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/c">section 1(c) of Public Law 103–428</ref> [set out above], as amended, sections 1(a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/428">Public Law 103–428</ref> [amending this section] shall remain in effect through <date date="2015-10-01">October 1, 2015</date>.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
<p>[Prior similar extensions of section 1(a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/428">Pub. L. 103–428</ref> were contained in the following acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dK/tVI">Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title VI</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/489">128 Stat. 489</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dI/tVI">Pub. L. 112–74, div. I, title VI</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1191">125 Stat. 1191</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/111/117/dF/tVI">Pub. L. 111–117, div. F, title VI</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3341">123 Stat. 3341</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dH/tVI">Pub. L. 111–8, div. H, title VI</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/858">123 Stat. 858</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dJ/tII">Pub. L. 110–161, div. J, title II</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2289">121 Stat. 2289</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/109/102/tI">Pub. L. 109–102, title I</ref>, <date date="2005-11-14">Nov. 14, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2172">119 Stat. 2172</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dD/tI">Pub. L. 108–447, div. D, title I</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2968">118 Stat. 2968</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dD/tI">Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title I</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/143">118 Stat. 143</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dE/tI">Pub. L. 108–7, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/159">117 Stat. 159</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/107/229/s129">Pub. L. 107–229, § 129</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/107/240/s5">Pub. L. 107–240, § 5</ref>, <date date="2002-10-11">Oct. 11, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1494">116 Stat. 1494</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For provisions continuing functions of Export-Import Bank of the United States through <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/103/428/s1/c">section 1(c) of Pub. L. 103–428</ref>, set out above, see Continuation of Bank Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">section 635f of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s831">section 831 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6301">section 6301 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb572bdb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX/s1917">Pub. L. 95–630, title XIX, § 1917</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3727">92 Stat. 3727</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX/s1917">“This title [enacting sections 635a–1 to 635a–3 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153e–1">section 2153e–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and amending this section and sections 635e to 635g of this title] shall take effect upon enactment [<date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572bdc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/s50001">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, § 50001</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1763">129 Stat. 1763</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/s50001">“This division [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a–7">section 635a–7 of this title</ref>, amending this section and sections 635a, 635a–5, 635a–6, 635e to 635g, and 635i–5 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 635a, 635a–5, 635e, and 635g of this title, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2015’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572bdd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2012 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s1/a">Pub. L. 112–122, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/350">126 Stat. 350</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/122/s1/a">“This Act [enacting sections 635a–5 and 635a–6 of this title, amending this section and sections 635a and 635e to 635g of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 635a and 635a–2 of this title, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572bde-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s1/a">Pub. L. 109–438, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3268">120 Stat. 3268</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/438/s1/a">“This Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635g–1">section 635g–1 of this title</ref>, amending this section and sections 635a, 635e, 635f, 635g, 635i–3, and 635i–5 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2006’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572bdf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s1/a">Pub. L. 107–189, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/698">116 Stat. 698</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/189/s1/a">“This Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–9">section 635i–9 of this title</ref>, amending this section, sections 635a, 635e to 635g, 635i–3, 635i–6, and 635i–8 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, sections 9 and 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/452">Pub. L. 95–452</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section, sections 635a, 635g, and 635i–9 of this title, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2002’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s1/a">Pub. L. 105–121, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2528">111 Stat. 2528</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/121/s1/a">“This Act [amending this section and sections 635a, 635f, and 635i–3 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635f">section 635f of this title</ref>, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 1997’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s1/a">Pub. L. 102–429, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2186">106 Stat. 2186</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/429/s1/a">“This Act [enacting sections 635i–5 to 635i–7 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s831">section 831 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and sections 4727 to 4729 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, amending this section and sections 635a, 635b, 635e, 635f, and 635i–3 of this title, and sections 4052 and 4721 of Title 15, repealing sections 635c, 635i to 635i–2, and 635i–4 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713b">section 713b of Title 15</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2772">section 2772 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4728">section 4728 of Title 15</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Export Enhancement Act of 1992’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3301">Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3301</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1383">102 Stat. 1383</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3301">“This subtitle [subtitle D (§§ 3301–3304) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3">section 635i–3 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3">section 635i–3 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank and Tied Aid Credit Amendments of 1988’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s1">Pub. L. 99–472, § 1</ref>, <date date="1986-10-15">Oct. 15, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1200">100 Stat. 1200</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/472/s1">“This Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–3">section 635i–3 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262h">section 262h of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, amending this section and sections 635a, 635a–2, 635a–3, and 635e to 635g of this title, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635g">section 635g of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Act Amendments of 1986’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1983 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VI, § 601], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1254">97 Stat. 1254</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/181/tI">“This title [enacting sections 635i–1, 635i–2, and 635<i>o</i>–635t of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671g">section 1671g of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, amending this section, sections 635a, 635a–2, 635a–3, 635a–4, 635b, 635e, 635f, and 635g of this title, and sections 1671a and 1671b of Title 19, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 635a and 635<i>o</i> of this title] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Act Amendments of 1983’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of title I [part C (§§ 641–647) of title VI] of <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref>, which enacted subchapter III (§ 635<i>o</i> et seq.) of this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671g">section 1671g of Title 19</ref> and amended sections 1671a and 1671b of Title 19, as the “Trade and Development Enhancement Act of 1983”, see Short Title note set out under section 635<i>o</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s380">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 380</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/431">95 Stat. 431</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s380">“This subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 380–385) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, amending sections 461 and 635e of this title, and section 369 of former Title 31, Money and Finance, enacting provisions set out as a note under section 369 of former Title 31, and amending provisions set out as notes under sections 1735f–7 and 1904 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Banking and Related Programs Authorization Adjustment Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX/s1901">Pub. L. 95–630, title XIX, § 1901</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3724">92 Stat. 3724</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX/s1901">“That this title [enacting sections 635a–1 to 635a–3 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153e–1">section 2153e–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, amending this section and sections 635e to 635g of this title, and enacting provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Act Amendments of 1978’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s1">Pub. L. 93–646, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2333">88 Stat. 2333</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/646/s1">“This Act [amending this section and sections 82 and 635d to 635g of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Amendments of 1974’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="iddb572be8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1971 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/126/s1/a">Pub. L. 92–126, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-08-17">Aug. 17, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/345">85 Stat. 345</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/126/s1/a">“This Act [amending this section and sections 635e and 635f of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s95a">section 95a of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Export Expansion Finance Act of 1971’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="iddb572be9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch341/s1">Act July 31, 1945, ch. 341, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/526">59 Stat. 526</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch341/s1">“That this Act [this subchapter] may be cited as the ‘Export-Import Bank Act of 1945’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s402/c">Pub. L. 116–94, div. I, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3023">133 Stat. 3023</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s402/c">“Nothing in section 2(<i>l</i>)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">12 U.S.C. 635</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1)(B)] shall be construed to weaken any export controls affecting critical technologies (as defined in section 721(a)(6)(A) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4565/a/6/A">50 U.S.C. 4565(a)(6)(A)</ref>)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572beb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, and <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/d">section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Board of Directors</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A Board of Directors was reestablished for the Export-Import Bank of Washington by section 1 of <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-09/ch660">act Aug. 9, 1954, ch. 660</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/677">68 Stat. 677</ref>, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of this title</ref>. The Board had previously been abolished and its functions transferred to the Managing Director of the Bank by Reorg. Plan No. 5 of 1953, eff. <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3741, <ref href="/us/stat/67/637">67 Stat. 637</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of this title</ref>. The 1953 Reorg. Plan was superseded by sections 1, 4 of act <date date="1954-08-09">Aug. 9, 1954</date>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of this title</ref> and 1954 Amendment and Effective Date of 1954 Amendment notes thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">History of Bank</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Export-Import Bank of Washington was organized as a District of Columbia banking corporation under Ex. Ord. No. 6581, <date date="1934-02-02">Feb. 2, 1934</date>. It was continued as an agency of the United States by <ref href="/us/act/1935-01-31/ch2/s9">act Jan. 31, 1935, ch. 2, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/4">49 Stat. 4</ref>, formerly set out as <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713b">section 713b of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, as amended by acts <ref href="/us/act/1937-01-26/ch6/s2/a">Jan. 26, 1937, ch. 6, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/5">50 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1939-03-04/ch5/s1/b/c">Mar. 4, 1939, ch. 5, § 1(b)(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/53/510">53 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-03-02/ch34">Mar. 2, 1940, ch. 34</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/38">54 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-09-26/ch734/s3">Sept. 26, 1940, ch. 734, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/962">54 Stat. 962</ref>, and repealed by section 10 of act <date date="1945-07-31">July 31, 1945</date>. The Second Export-Import Bank of Washington, D.C., was established under Ex. Ord. No. 6638, <date date="1934-03-09">Mar. 9, 1934</date>. Its commitments were transferred to the Export-Import Bank of Washington and it was abolished by Ex. Ord. No. 7365, <date date="1936-05-07">May 7, 1936</date>, 1 F.R. 372. The “Export-Import Bank of Washington” was re­named the “Export-Import Bank of the United States”. See the 1968 Amendment note under this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Sanctions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sanctions contained in subsec. (b)(4) waived in certain regards with respect to India and Pakistan by the following Determinations of the President, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1">section 2799aa–1 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2000–4, <date date="1999-10-27">Oct. 27, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 60649.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2000–18, <date date="2000-03-16">Mar. 16, 2000</date>, 65 F.R. 16297.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting on Financing Related to China</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s408">Pub. L. 116–94, div. I, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3024">133 Stat. 3024</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dI/tIV/s408">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Interest Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before authorizing a loan or guarantee for a transaction in an amount greater than $25,000,000 for which the end user, lender, or obligor is the government of China, the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States (in this section referred to as the ‘Bank’) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that the Bank has consulted with the Secretary of State and any other relevant department or agency, as deemed appropriate by the President of the United States, to assess any risks posed by the entity or the transaction to the national interest of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> include a summary of the transaction and the consultation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form of Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The report described in subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Related Policies.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Board of Directors of the Bank shall prescribe policies for the Bank with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> procedures required by the consultation described in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> establishment of a period of not less than 25 days to complete the consultations described in subsection (a) during which time consulted parties may submit any appropriate information to the Bank; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> efforts by the Bank to assess and determine ownership or control by the government of China pursuant to the requirements of subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> In prescribing the policies described under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board of Directors of the Bank shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> consult with the Secretary of State with respect to the procedures referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection, and seek to ensure that the procedures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> are consistent, wherever appropriate, with national interest determinations made under section 2(b)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/B">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(B)</ref>]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> include coordination between the Secretary of State and the Director of National Intelligence, wherever appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> consult with the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to the efforts described in paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the purposes of this section, the term ‘government of China’ means any person that the Bank has reason to believe is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the state and the government of China, as well as any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by any of the foregoing, including any partnership, association, or other entity in which any of the foregoing owns a 50 percent or greater interest or a controlling interest, and any entity which is otherwise controlled by any of the foregoing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any person that is or has been acting or purporting to act, directly or indirectly, for or on behalf of any of the foregoing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any other person which the Secretary of the Treasury has notified the Bank is included in any of the foregoing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This section shall have no force or effect on the earlier of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> <date date="2026-12-31">December 31, 2026</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the date that is 30 days after the date that the President of the United States reports to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that China is in substantial compliance with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the financial terms and conditions of the Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the rules and principles of the Paris Club.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program for Reinsurance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLI/s51008">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LI, § 51008</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1766">129 Stat. 1766</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLI/s51008">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any provision of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">12 U.S.C. 635</ref> et seq.), the Export-Import Bank of the United States (in this section referred to as the ‘Bank’) may establish a pilot program under which the Bank may enter into contracts and other arrangements to share risks associated with the provision of guarantees, insurance, or credit, or the participation in the extension of credit, by the Bank under that Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Amount of Risk-Sharing.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Per contract or other arrangement</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of liability the Bank may transfer through risk-sharing pursuant to a contract or other arrangement entered into under subsection (a) may not exceed $1,000,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Per year</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of liability the Bank may transfer through risk-sharing during a fiscal year pursuant to contracts or other arrangements entered into under subsection (a) during that fiscal year may not exceed $10,000,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>], and annually thereafter through 2019, the Bank shall submit to Congress a written report that contains a detailed analysis of the use of the pilot program carried out under subsection (a) during the year preceding the submission of the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect, impede, or revoke any authority of the Bank.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program carried out under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2019-09-30">September 30, 2019</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publication of Guidelines for Economic Impact Analyses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s12/a">Pub. L. 112–122, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/357">126 Stat. 357</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/122/s12/a">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>], the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall develop and make publicly available methodological guidelines to be used by the Bank in conducting economic impact analyses or similar studies under section 2(e) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/e">12 U.S.C. 635(e)</ref>]. In developing the guidelines, the Bank shall take into consideration any relevant guidance from the Office of Management and Budget.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibitions on Financing for Certain Persons Involved in Sanctionable Activities With Respect to Iran</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s18">Pub. L. 112–122, § 18</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/360">126 Stat. 360</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/122/s18">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Financing for Persons That Engage in Certain Sanctionable Activities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>], the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States may not approve any transaction that is subject to approval by the Board with respect to the provision by the Bank of any guarantee, insurance, or extension of credit, or the participation by the Bank in any extension of credit, to a person in connection with the exportation of any good or service unless the person makes the certification described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The certification described in this paragraph is a certification by a person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> that neither the person nor any other person owned or controlled by the person—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> engages in any activity described in section 5(a) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note) for which the person may be subject to sanctions under that Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> exports sensitive technology, as defined in section 106 of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8515">22 U.S.C. 8515</ref>), to Iran; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> engages in any activity prohibited by part 560 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as the ‘Iranian Transactions Regulations’), unless the activity is disclosed to the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury when the activity is discovered; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> if the person or any other person owned or controlled by the person has engaged in an activity described in subparagraph (A), that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of an activity described in subparagraph (A)(i)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the President has waived the imposition of sanctions with respect to the person that engaged in that activity pursuant to section 4(c), 6(b)(5), or 9(c) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the President has invoked the special rule described in section 4(e)(3) of that Act with respect to the person that engaged in that activity; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="bb">     “(bb)</num><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> the person that engaged in that activity determines, based on its best knowledge and belief, that the person meets the criteria described in subparagraph (A) of such section 4(e)(3) and has provided to the President the assurances described in subparagraph (B) of that section; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="BB">     “(BB)</num><content> the Secretary of State has issued an advisory opinion to that person that the person meets such criteria and has provided to the President those assurances; or</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> the President has determined that the criteria have been met for the exception provided for under section 5(a)(3)(C) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 [<ref href="/us/pl/104/172">Pub. L. 104–172</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note] to apply with respect to the person that engaged in that activity; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in the case of an activity described in subparagraph (A)(ii), the President has waived, pursuant to section 401(b)(1) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8551/b/1">22 U.S.C. 8551(b)(1)</ref>), the application of the prohibition under section 106(a) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8515/a">22 U.S.C. 8515(a)</ref>) with respect to that person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Financing</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States may not approve any transaction that is subject to approval by the Board with respect to the provision by the Bank of any guarantee, insurance, or extension of credit, or the participation by the Bank in any extension of credit, in connection with a financing in which a person that is a borrower or controlling sponsor, or a person that is owned or controlled by such borrower or controlling sponsor, is subject to sanctions under section 5(a) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advisory Opinions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State is authorized to issue advisory opinions described in subsection (a)(2)(B)(i)(II).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary issues an advisory opinion pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the opinion not later than 30 days after issuing the opinion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees; person</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘appropriate congressional committees’ and ‘person’ have the meanings given those terms in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Controlling sponsor</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘controlling sponsor’ means a person providing controlling direct private equity investment (excluding investments made through publicly held investment funds, publicly held securities, public offerings, or similar public market vehicles) in connection with a financing.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Master Guarantee Agreements With African Regional Financial Institutions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 109–438, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3268">120 Stat. 3268</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/438/s3/b/1">“Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>], the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall seek to ensure that there is in effect a contract between each approved lender in Africa and the Bank, which sets forth the Bank’s guarantee undertakings and related obligations between the Bank and each lender.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhance Delegated Loan Authority for Medium Term Transactions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s6/b/1">Pub. L. 109–438, § 6(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3272">120 Stat. 3272</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/438/s6/b/1">“The Export-Import Bank of the United States shall seek to expand the exercise of authority under section 2(b)(1)(E)(vii) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(E)(vii)</ref>) with respect to medium term transactions for small business concerns.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadline for Enhancing Delegated Loan Authority for Medium Term Transactions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s6/b/3">Pub. L. 109–438, § 6(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3272">120 Stat. 3272</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/438/s6/b/3">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>], the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall make available lines of credit and guarantees to carry out section 2(b)(1)(E)(vii) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E/vii">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(E)(vii)</ref>] pursuant to policies and procedures established by the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">GAO Study of Bank Performance Standards for Assistance to Small Businesses, Especially Those Owned by Socially and Economically Disadvantaged Individuals and Those Owned by Women</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/438/s19">Pub. L. 109–438, § 19</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3282">120 Stat. 3282</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/438/s19">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Performance Standards</inline>.—</heading><content>The Bank shall develop a set of performance standards for determining the extent to which the Bank has carried out successfully subparagraphs (E) and (I) of section 2(b)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (I)], and the functions described in subsections (f)(1), (g)(1), (h)(1), and (i)(1) of section 3 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a/f/1">12 U.S.C. 635a(f)(1)</ref>, (g)(1), (h)(1), (i)(1)].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment of Standards</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Within 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall transmit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of the performance standards developed by the Bank pursuant to subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> using the performance standards developed pursuant to subsection (a), an assessment of the Bank’s efforts to carry out subparagraphs (E) and (I) of section 2(b)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/E">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (I)], and the functions described in subsections (f)(1), (g)(1), (h)(1), and (i)(1) of section 3 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a/f/1">12 U.S.C. 635a(f)(1)</ref>, (g)(1), (h)(1), (i)(1)].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">GAO Report on Comparative Reserve Practices of Export Credit Agencies and Private Banks</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s14">Pub. L. 107–189, § 14</ref>, <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/705">116 Stat. 705</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/189/s14">“Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report that examines the reserve ratios of the Export-Import Bank of the United States as compared with the reserve practices of private banks and foreign export credit agencies.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports to Congress</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/121/s7/b">Pub. L. 105–121, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2529">111 Stat. 2529</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/189/s6/c">Pub. L. 107–189, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-14">June 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/700">116 Stat. 700</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/189/s6/c">“Within 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>], and annually for each of the 8 years thereafter, the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the steps that the Board has taken to implement section 2(b)(9)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/9/B">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(9)(B)</ref>] and any recommendations of the advisory committee established pursuant to such section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb572bf9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Declaration of Policy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/tI/s101">Pub. L. 102–429, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2186">106 Stat. 2186</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/429/tI/s101">
<inline>“The Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> as the world’s largest economy, the United States has an enormous stake in the future of the global trading system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> exports are a crucial force driving the United States economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> during 1991, the value of United States exports increased by 7.1 percent from the 1990 level to $421,600,000,000, supporting more than 7,000,000 full-time United States jobs, and affecting the lives of all of the people of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> exports also support the global strategic position of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a significant part of a country’s influence is drawn from the reputation of its goods, its industrial connections with other countries, and the capital it has available for investment, and trade finance is a critical component of this equation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the growth in United States exports has increased the demand for financing from the Export-Import Bank of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> during 1991, the value of exports assisted by the Export-Import Bank rose 28.7 percent, from $9,700,000,000 to $12,100,000,000, the highest level since 1981;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> the Export-Import Bank used its entire budget authority provided for 1991, and still could not meet all of the demand for its financing assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> accordingly, the charter of the Export-Import Bank, which is scheduled to expire on <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>, must be renewed in order that the Bank continue to arrange competitive and innovative financing for the foreign sales of United States exporters.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Financing of Services</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/tI/s119">Pub. L. 102–429, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2197">106 Stat. 2197</ref>, directed Export-Import Bank of the United States, not later than 1 year after <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, to submit a report to Congress on ways of facilitating the export financing of high technology services.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Demand for Trade Finance for the Baltic States, the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union, and Central and Eastern Europe</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/429/tI/s120">Pub. L. 102–429, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2197">106 Stat. 2197</ref>, directed Export-Import Bank, not later than 1 year after <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, to transmit to Congress a report analyzing present and future demand for loans, guarantees, and insurance for trade between the United States and the Baltic States, between the United States and the independent States of the former Soviet Union, and between the United States and Central and Eastern Europe, and to make recommendations regarding the adequacy of financing for trade between the United States and such countries.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Export-Import Programs to People’s Republic of China Prohibited Unless Certain Conditions Met</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/240/tI/s103">Pub. L. 101–240, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2496">103 Stat. 2496</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/240/tI/s103">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the provisions of subsections (b) and (c), the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall not finance any trade with, nor extend any loan, credit, credit guarantee, insurance or reinsurance to the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The prohibitions described in subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to food or agricultural commodities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> The President may waive the prohibitions in subsection (a) if he makes a report to Congress either—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> that the Government of the People’s Republic of China has made progress on a program of political reform throughout the country, as well as in Tibet, which includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> lifting of martial law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> halting of executions and other reprisals against individuals for the nonviolent expression of their political beliefs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> release of political prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> increased respect for internationally recognized human rights, including freedom of expression, the press, assembly, and association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> permitting a freer flow of information, including an end to the jamming of Voice of America and greater access for foreign journalists; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> it is in the national interest of the United States to terminate a suspension under subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Export-Import Bank Programs for Poland and Hungary</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/179/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 101–179, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1989-11-28">Nov. 28, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1312">103 Stat. 1312</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/179/tIII/s303">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to Extend Credit to Poland and Hungary</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 2(b)(2) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/2">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(2)</ref>), the Export-Import Bank of the United States may guarantee, insure, finance, extend credit, and participate in the extension of credit in connection with the purchase or lease of any product by the Republic of Hungary or any agency or national thereof or by the Polish People’s Republic or any agency or national thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private Financial Intermediaries to Facilitate Exports to Poland</inline>.—</heading><content>Consistent with the provisions of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">12 U.S.C. 635</ref> and following), the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall work with private financial intermediaries in Poland to facilitate the export of goods and services to Poland.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Restrictions on Loans</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/646/s12">Pub. L. 93–646, § 12</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2337">88 Stat. 2337</ref>, provided that, until <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, no loan, guarantee, insurance, or credit could be extended by the Export-Import Bank of the United States to the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb5975ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="iddb5975f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of the President under subsec. (b)(6) of this section, see section 1(u) of Ex. Ord. No. 13637, <date date="2013-03-08">Mar. 8, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 16131, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. Functions were previously delegated by Ex. Ord. No. 11958, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref> and was revoked, subject to a savings provision, by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13637.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="iddb5975f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12166. Delegation of Function of President Relating to Application for Credit to Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12166, <date date="1979-10-19">Oct. 19, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 60971, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President of the United States of America by Section 2(b)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/B">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(B)</ref>), and by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">Section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–101. The function vested in the President by Section 2(b)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/B">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(B)</ref>), is delegated to the Secretary of State. That function is the authority to determine that a denial by the Export-Import Bank of an application for credit would be in the national interest, where such action could clearly and importantly advance United States policy in such areas as international terrorism, nuclear proliferation, environmental protection and human rights.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–102. Before making such a determination, the Secretary of State shall consult with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of other interested Executive agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–103. In accord with Section 2(b)(1)(B) of that Act, only in those cases where the Secretary of State has made such a determination should the Export-Import Bank deny an application for credit for nonfinancial or noncommercial considerations.</p>
<signature>
<name>Jimmy Carter.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Assignment of Functions Under Section 530 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995, and Section 2(b)(4) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as Amended</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2007-03-23">Mar. 23, 2007</date>, 72 F.R. 18103, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, I hereby assign to you:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) the functions of the President under section 530 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 (<ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Public Law 103–236</ref>) (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2429a–2">22 U.S.C. 2429a–2</ref>); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) the functions of the President under section 2(b)(4) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">12 U.S.C. 635</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5975f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Determinations Relating to Countries Deemed to Be Marxist-Leninist Countries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The following Presidential Determinations determined that the listed countries had ceased to be Marxist-Leninist countries within the definition of such term in subsection (b)(2)(B)(i) of this section:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination No. 2009–20, <date date="2009-06-12">June 12, 2009</date>, 74 F.R. 28865.—Kingdom of Cambodia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination No. 2009–21, <date date="2009-06-12">June 12, 2009</date>, 74 F.R. 28867.—Lao People’s Democratic Republic.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
