<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb5be6e8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5"><num value="635a–5">§ 635a–5.</num><heading> Negotiations to end export credit financing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6e9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall initiate and pursue negotiations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6ea-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with other major exporting countries, including members of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (in this section referred to as the “OECD”) and non-OECD members, to substantially reduce, with the possible goal of eliminating, before the date that is 10 years after <date date="2015-12-04">December 4, 2015</date>,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002059">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002059"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> subsidized export financing programs and other forms of export subsidies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6eb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> with all countries that finance air carrier aircraft with funds from a state-sponsored entity, to substantially reduce, with the ultimate goal of eliminating, aircraft export credit financing for all aircraft covered by the 2007 Sector Understanding on Export Credits for Civil Aircraft (in this section referred to as the “ASU”), including any modification thereof, and all of the following types of aircraft:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb5be6ec-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Heavy aircraft that are capable of a takeoff weight of 300,000 pounds or more, whether or not operating at such a weight during a particular phase of flight.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb5be6ed-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Large aircraft that are capable of a takeoff weight of more than 41,000 pounds, and have a maximum certificated takeoff weight of not more than 300,000 pounds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddb5be6ee-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Small aircraft that have a maximum certificated takeoff weight of 41,000 pounds or less.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6ef-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports on progress of negotiations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6f0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a report on the progress of any negotiations described in subsection (a)(1), until the President certifies in writing to the committees that all countries that support subsidized export financing programs have agreed to end the support; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6f1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a report on the progress of any negotiations described in subsection (a)(2), including the progress of any negotiations with respect to each classification of aircraft set forth in subsection (a)(2), until the President certifies in writing to the committees that all countries that support subsidized export financing programs have agreed to end the support of aircraft covered by the ASU.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6f2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on strategy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2015-12-04">December 4, 2015</date>, the President shall submit to Congress a proposal, and a strategy for achieving the proposal, that the United States Government will pursue with other major exporting countries, including OECD members and non-OECD members, to eliminate over a period of not more than 10 years subsidized export-financing programs, tied aid, export credits, and all other forms of government-supported export subsidies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6f3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Negotiations with non-OECD members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall initiate and pursue negotiations with countries that are not OECD members to bring those countries into a multilateral agreement establishing rules and limitations on officially supported export credits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6f4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports on progress of negotiations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2015-12-04">December 4, 2015</date>, and annually thereafter through calendar year 2019, the President shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of any negotiations described in subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb5be6f5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/112/122/s11">Pub. L. 112–122, § 11</ref>, <date date="2012-05-30">May 30, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/356">126 Stat. 356</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLV/s55002/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LV, § 55002(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1769">129 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb5be6f6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb5be6f7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb5be6f8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012, and not as part of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb5be6f9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s55002/a/1/A">Pub. L. 114–94, § 55002(a)(1)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “President” for “Secretary of the Treasury (in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s55002/a/1/B">Pub. L. 114–94, § 55002(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “(in this section referred to as the ‘OECD’)” for “(OECD)” and “possible goal of eliminating, before the date that is 10 years after <date date="2015-12-04">December 4, 2015</date>,” for “ultimate goal of eliminating”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s55002/a/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 55002(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “President” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s55002/a/3">Pub. L. 114–94, § 55002(a)(3)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) to (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb5be6fa-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddb5be6fb-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLV/s55002/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. E, title LV, § 55002(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1770">129 Stat. 1770</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dE/tLV/s55002/b">“The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to reports required to be submitted under section 11(b) of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a–5/b">12 U.S.C. 635a–5(b)</ref>) after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb5be6fc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb5be6fd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority Under Section 11 of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2016-03-11">Mar. 11, 2016</date>, 81 F.R. 14367, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of the Treasury</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the functions and authorities vested in the President by section 11 of the Export-Import Bank Reauthorization Act of 2012, as amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In exercising functions and authority delegated by this memorandum, you shall ensure that all actions taken by you are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to (A) conduct the foreign affairs of the United States, including the commencement, conduct, and termination of negotiations with foreign countries and international organizations; and (B) withhold information the disclosure of which could impair the foreign relations, the national security, the deliberative processes of the Executive, or the performance of the Executive’s constitutional duties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
