<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb5be6cf-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3"><num value="635a–3">§ 635a–3.</num><heading> Export-Import Bank financing to match foreign financing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6d0-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Noncompetitive financing; inquiry by Secretary; notification of foreign country and prospective parties to transaction</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb5be6d1-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon receipt of information that foreign sales to the United States are being offered involving foreign official export credits which exceed limits under existing standstills, minutes, or practices to which the United States and other major exporting countries have agreed, irrespective of whether these credits are being offered by governments which are signatories to such standstills, minutes, or practices, the Secretary of the Treasury shall immediately conduct an inquiry to determine whether “noncompetitive financing” is being offered. The inquiry, and where appropriate, the determination and authorization to the Export-Import Bank of the United States referred to in this section shall be completed and made within 60 days of the receipt of such information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb5be6d2-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary determines that such foreign “noncompetitive” financing is being offered, the Secretary shall request the immediate withdrawal of such financing by the foreign official export credit agency involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddb5be6d3-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the offer is not withdrawn or if there is no immediate response to the withdrawal request, the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the country offering such financing and all parties to the proposed transaction that the Eximbank may be authorized to provide competing United States sellers with financing to match that available through the foreign official export financing entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6d4-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of authorization to Bank to provide guarantees, insurance, and credits to competing United States sellers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue such authorization to the Bank to provide guarantees, insurance, and credits to competing United States sellers, unless the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6d5-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the availability of foreign official noncompetitive financing is not likely to be a significant factor in the sale; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb5be6d6-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the foreign noncompetitive financing has been withdrawn.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddb5be6d7-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635a–3/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of financing by Bank pursuant to authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of authorization by the Secretary of the Treasury, the Export-Import Bank may provide financing to match that offered by the foreign official export credit entity: <i>Provided, however</i>, That loans, guarantees and insurance provided under this authority shall conform to all provisions of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">12 U.S.C. 635</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddb5be6d8-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXIX/s1912">Pub. L. 95–630, title XIX, § 1912</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3726">92 Stat. 3726</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VI, §§ 631, 633], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1262">97 Stat. 1262</ref>, 1263; <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s15">Pub. L. 99–472, § 15</ref>, <date date="1986-10-15">Oct. 15, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1204">100 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb5be6d9-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb5be6da-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddb5be6db-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as amended, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch341">act July 31, 1945, ch. 341</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/526">59 Stat. 526</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter 1 (§ 635 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">section 635 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddb5be6dc-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Export-Import Bank Act Amendments of 1978, and not as part of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb5be6dd-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s15/b">Pub. L. 99–472, § 15(b)</ref>, which directed the insertion of “irrespective of whether these credits are being offered by governments which are signatories to such standstills, minutes, or practices,” after “major export countries have agreed,” was executed by inserting that phrase after “major exporting countries have agreed,” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/472/s15/a">Pub. L. 99–472, § 15(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Secretary of the Treasury shall only issue such authorization to the Bank to provide guarantees, insurance and credits to competing United States sellers, if the Secretary determines that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the availability of foreign official noncompetitive financing is likely to be a significant factor in the sale, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the foreign noncompetitive financing has not been withdrawn on the date the Bank is authorized to provide competitive financing.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s631/1">Pub. L. 98–181, § 631(1)</ref>, inserted provision that the inquiry, and where appropriate, the determination and authorization to the Export-Import Bank of the United States referred to in this section shall be completed and made within 60 days of the receipt of such information.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s633/b">Pub. L. 98–181, § 633(b)</ref>, substituted “the Secretary shall request” for “he shall request”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s633/a">Pub. L. 98–181, § 633(a)</ref>, substituted “if the Secretary determines that” for “if he determines that” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/s631/2">Pub. L. 98–181, § 631(2)</ref>, substituted “significant factor” for “determining factor”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb5be6de-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddb5be6df-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/s1917">section 1917 of Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635">section 635 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
