<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb63137f-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p"><num value="635p">§ 635p.</num><heading> Presidential mandate to negotiate; objectives</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall vigorously pursue negotiations to limit and set rules for the use of tied aid for exports. The negotiating objectives of the United States should include reaching agreements—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631380-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to define the various forms of tied aid credit, particularly mixed credits under the Arrangement on Guidelines for Officially Supported Export Credits established through the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Arrangement”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631381-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to phase out the use of government-mixed credits by a date certain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631382-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to set rules governing the use of public-private cofinancing, or other forms of mixed financing, which may have the same result as government-mixed credits of drawing on concessional development assistance to produce subsidized export financing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631383-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to raise the threshold for notification of the use of tied aid credit to a 50 per centum level of concessionality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631384-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to improve notification procedures so that advance notification must be given on all uses of tied aid credit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddb631385-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s635p/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to prohibit the use of tied aid credit for production facilities for goods which are in structural oversupply in the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddb631386-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VI, § 643], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1263">97 Stat. 1263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
