<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddb11e632-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06" identifier="/us/usc/t12/s71a"><num value="71a">§ 71a.</num><heading> Number of directors; penalties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After one year from <date date="1933-06-16">June 16, 1933</date>, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the board of directors, board of trustees, or other similar governing body of every national banking association and of every State bank or trust company which is a member of the Federal Reserve System shall consist of not less than five nor more than twenty-five members, except that the Comptroller of the Currency may, by regulation or order, exempt a national bank from the 25-member limit established by this section. If any national banking association violates the provisions of this section and continues such violation after thirty days’ notice from the Comptroller of the Currency, the said Comptroller may appoint a receiver or conservator therefor, in accordance with the provisions of existing law. If any State bank or trust company which is a member of the Federal Reserve System violates the provisions of this section and continues such violation after thirty days’ notice from the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, it shall be subject to the forfeiture of its membership in the Federal Reserve System in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s327">section 327 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddb11e633-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-06-16/ch89/s31">June 16, 1933, ch. 89, § 31</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/194">48 Stat. 194</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-16/ch546/s4">June 16, 1934, ch. 546, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/971">48 Stat. 971</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614">Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614</ref>, title II, § 203(a), title III, § 306, <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>, 708; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tXII/s1205/b">Pub. L. 106–569, title XII, § 1205(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3034">114 Stat. 3034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddb11e634-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddb11e635-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddb11e636-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/569">Pub. L. 106–569</ref> inserted before period at end of first sentence “, except that the Comptroller of the Currency may, by regulation or order, exempt a national bank from the 25-member limit established by this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1934-06-16">June 16, 1934</date>, as amended by act <date date="1935-08-23">Aug. 23, 1935</date>, § 306, repealed a former provision of this section relating to stock ownership requirements of directors, trustees, or members of similar governing bodies of any national banking association, or of any State bank or trust company which is a member of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-06-16">June 16, 1934</date>, repealed a former provision of this section relating to stock ownership requirements of directors, trustees, or members of similar governing bodies of member banks of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddb11e637-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddb11e638-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1935-08-23/ch614/tII/s203/a">Act Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/704">49 Stat. 704</ref>, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddb11e639-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddb11e63a-3a6f-11f1-8fa0-c065796a7f06">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception as to Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by any provision of law in Comptroller of the Currency, referred to in this section, not included in transfer of functions to Secretary of the Treasury, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
