<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb91096c2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033"><num value="1033">§ 1033.</num><heading> Crimes by or affecting persons engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096c3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096c4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Whoever is engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce and knowingly, with the intent to deceive, makes any false material statement or report or willfully and materially overvalues any land, property or security—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096c5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in connection with any financial reports or documents presented to any insurance regulatory official or agency or an agent or examiner appointed by such official or agency to examine the affairs of such person, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096c6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for the purpose of influencing the actions of such official or agency or such an appointed agent or examiner,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be punished as provided in paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096c7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The punishment for an offense under paragraph (1) is a fine as established under this title or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, except that the term of imprisonment shall be not more than 15 years if the statement or report or overvaluing of land, property, or security jeopardized the safety and soundness of an insurer and was a significant cause of such insurer being placed in conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation by an appropriate court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096c8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096c9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Whoever—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096ca-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> acting as, or being an officer, director, agent, or employee of, any person engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096cb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce or is involved (other than as an insured or beneficiary under a policy of insurance) in a transaction relating to the conduct of affairs of such a business,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">willfully embezzles, abstracts, purloins, or misappropriates any of the moneys, funds, premiums, credits, or other property of such person so engaged shall be punished as provided in paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096cc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The punishment for an offense under paragraph (1) is a fine as provided under this title or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, except that if such embezzlement, abstraction, purloining, or misappropriation described in paragraph (1) jeopardized the safety and soundness of an insurer and was a significant cause of such insurer being placed in conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation by an appropriate court, such imprisonment shall be not more than 15 years. If the amount or value so embezzled, abstracted, purloined, or misappropriated does not exceed $5,000, whoever violates paragraph (1) shall be fined as provided in this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096cd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096ce-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whoever is engaged in the business of insurance and whose activities affect interstate commerce or is involved (other than as an insured or beneficiary under a policy of insurance) in a transaction relating to the conduct of affairs of such a business, knowingly makes any false entry of material fact in any book, report, or statement of such person engaged in the business of insurance with intent to deceive any person, including any officer, employee, or agent of such person engaged in the business of insurance, any insurance regulatory official or agency, or any agent or examiner appointed by such official or agency to examine the affairs of such person, about the financial condition or solvency of such business shall be punished as provided in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096cf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The punishment for an offense under paragraph (1) is a fine as provided under this title or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, except that if the false entry in any book, report, or statement of such person jeopardized the safety and soundness of an insurer and was a significant cause of such insurer being placed in conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation by an appropriate court, such imprisonment shall be not more than 15 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Whoever, by threats or force or by any threatening letter or communication, corruptly influences, obstructs, or impedes or endeavors corruptly to influence, obstruct, or impede the due and proper administration of the law under which any proceeding involving the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce is pending before any insurance regulatory official or agency or any agent or examiner appointed by such official or agency to examine the affairs of a person engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce, shall be fined as provided in this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any individual who has been convicted of any criminal felony involving dishonesty or a breach of trust, or who has been convicted of an offense under this section, and who willfully engages in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce or participates in such business, shall be fined as provided in this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any individual who is engaged in the business of insurance whose activities affect interstate commerce and who willfully permits the participation described in subparagraph (A) shall be fined as provided in this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person described in paragraph (1)(A) may engage in the business of insurance or participate in such business if such person has the written consent of any insurance regulatory official authorized to regulate the insurer, which consent specifically refers to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91096d6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096d7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the term “business of insurance” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096d8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the writing of insurance, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096d9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the reinsuring of risks,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">by an insurer, including all acts necessary or incidental to such writing or reinsuring and the activities of persons who act as, or are, officers, directors, agents, or employees of insurers or who are other persons authorized to act on behalf of such persons;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096da-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “insurer” means any entity the business activity of which is the writing of insurance or the reinsuring of risks, and includes any person who acts as, or is, an officer, director, agent, or employee of that business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096db-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the term “interstate commerce” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096dc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> commerce within the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096dd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all commerce between any point in the State, territory, possession, or the District of Columbia and any point outside thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096de-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> all commerce between points within the same State through any place outside such State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91096df-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> all other commerce over which the United States has jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91096e0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1033/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “State” includes any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb91096e1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXII/s320603/a">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320603(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2115">108 Stat. 2115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb91096e2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb91096e3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb91096e4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
