<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9130777-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1074"><num value="1074">§ 1074.</num><heading> Flight to avoid prosecution for damaging or destroying any building or other real or personal property</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9130778-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1074/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Whoever moves or travels in interstate or foreign commerce with intent either (1) to avoid prosecution, or custody, or confinement after conviction, under the laws of the place from which he flees, for willfully attempting to or damaging or destroying by fire or explosive any building, structure, facility, vehicle, dwelling house, synagogue, church, religious center or educational institution, public or private, or (2) to avoid giving testimony in any criminal proceeding relating to any such offense shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9130779-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1074/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Violations of this section may be prosecuted in the Federal judicial district in which the original crime was alleged to have been committed or in which the person was held in custody or confinement: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this section shall not be construed as indicating an intent on the part of Congress to prevent any State, Territory, Commonwealth, or possession of the United States of any jurisdiction over any offense over which they would have jurisdiction in the absence of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb913077a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/86/449/tII/s201">Pub. L. 86–449, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1960-05-06">May 6, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/86">74 Stat. 86</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330016/1/K">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(K)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2147">108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb913077b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb913077c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb913077d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $5,000”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
