<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb917c2cf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1163"><num value="1163">§ 1163.</num><heading> Embezzlement and theft from Indian tribal organizations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever embezzles, steals, knowingly converts to his use or the use of another, willfully misapplies, or willfully permits to be misapplied, any of the moneys, funds, credits, goods, assets, or other property belonging to any Indian tribal organization or intrusted to the custody or care of any officer, employee, or agent of an Indian tribal organization; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever, knowing any such moneys, funds, credits, goods, assets, or other property to have been so embezzled, stolen, converted, misapplied or permitted to be misapplied, receives, conceals, or retains the same with intent to convert it to his use or the use of another—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both; but if the value of such property does not exceed the sum of $1,000, he shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “Indian tribal organization” means any tribe, band, or community of Indians which is subject to the laws of the United States relating to Indian affairs or any corporation, association, or group which is organized under any of such laws.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb917c2d0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch822/s2">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 822, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/792">70 Stat. 792</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330016/1/H">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, (K), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2147">108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tVI/s606/a">Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3511">110 Stat. 3511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb917c2d1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb917c2d2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb917c2d3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/294">Pub. L. 104–294</ref> substituted “$1,000” for “$100” in third par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref>, in third par., substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $5,000” after “Shall be” and for “fined not more than $1,000” after “he shall be”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
