<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb91a0cce-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307"><num value="1307">§ 1307.</num><heading> Exceptions relating to certain advertisements and other information and to State-conducted lotteries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91a0ccf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The provisions of sections 1301, 1302, 1303, and 1304 shall not apply to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91a0cd0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> an advertisement, list of prizes, or other information concerning a lottery conducted by a State acting under the authority of State law which is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91a0cd1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contained in a publication published in that State or in a State which conducts such a lottery; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91a0cd2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> broadcast by a radio or television station licensed to a location in that State or a State which conducts such a lottery; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91a0cd3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> an advertisement, list of prizes, or other information concerning a lottery, gift enterprise, or similar scheme, other than one described in paragraph (1), that is authorized or not otherwise prohibited by the State in which it is conducted and which is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91a0cd4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conducted by a not-for-profit organization or a governmental organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91a0cd5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> conducted as a promotional activity by a commercial organization and is clearly occasional and ancillary to the primary business of that organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91a0cd6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The provisions of sections 1301, 1302, and 1303 shall not apply to the transportation or mailing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91a0cd7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to addresses within a State of equipment, tickets, or material concerning a lottery which is conducted by that State acting under the authority of State law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91a0cd8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to an addressee within a foreign country of equipment, tickets, or material designed to be used within that foreign country in a lottery which is authorized by the law of that foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91a0cd9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> For the purposes of this section (1) “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States; and (2) “foreign country” means any empire, country, dominion, colony, or protectorate, or any subdivision thereof (other than the United States, its territories or possessions).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91a0cda-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1307/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> For the purposes of subsection (b) of this section “lottery” means the pooling of proceeds derived from the sale of tickets or chances and allotting those proceeds or parts thereof by chance to one or more chance takers or ticket purchasers. “Lottery” does not include the placing or accepting of bets or wagers on sporting events or contests. For purposes of this section, the term a “not-for-profit organization” means any organization that would qualify as tax exempt under section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb91a0cdb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/93/583/s1">Pub. L. 93–583, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1916">88 Stat. 1916</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/525/s1">Pub. L. 94–525, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2478">90 Stat. 2478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/90/s1">Pub. L. 96–90, § 1</ref>, <date date="1979-10-23">Oct. 23, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/698">93 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/625">Pub. L. 100–625</ref>, §§ 2(a), (b), 3(a)(1), (3), <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3205">102 Stat. 3205</ref>, 3206.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb91a0cdc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb91a0cdd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb91a0cde-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (d), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501">section 501 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb91a0cdf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/625/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 100–625, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Exceptions relating to certain advertisements and other information and to State-conducted lotteries” for “State-conducted lotteries” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/625/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–625, § 2(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The provisions of sections 1301, 1302, 1303, and 1304 shall not apply to an advertisement, list of prizes, or information concerning a lottery conducted by a State acting under the authority of State law—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) contained in a newspaper published in that State or in an adjacent State which conducts such a lottery, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) broadcast by a radio or television station licensed to a location in that State or an adjacent State which conducts such a lottery.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/625">Pub. L. 100–625</ref>, §§ 2(b), 3(a)(3), inserted “subsection (b) of” after “purposes of” and inserted at end “For purposes of this section, the term a ‘not-for-profit organization’ means any organization that would qualify as tax exempt under section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/90/s1/a">Pub. L. 96–90, § 1(a)</ref>, incorporated existing provision in text designated cl. (1), included mailing of equipment, and added cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/90/s1/b">Pub. L. 96–90, § 1(b)</ref>, designated existing text as cl. (1) and added cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/525">Pub. L. 94–525</ref> inserted “or in an adjacent State which conducts such a lottery” after “State”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb91a0ce0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91a0ce1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/625">Pub. L. 100–625</ref> effective 18 months after <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/625/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 100–625</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1304">section 1304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idb91a0ce2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Severability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/625/s4">Pub. L. 100–625, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3206">102 Stat. 3206</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/625/s4">“If any provision of this Act or the amendments made by this Act [amending sections 1304 and 1307 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s3005">section 3005 of Title 39</ref>, Postal Service, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 1301 and 1304 of this title], or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected by such invalidation.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
