<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9344a93-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836"><num value="1836">§ 1836.</num><heading> Civil proceedings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9344a94-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Attorney General may, in a civil action, obtain appropriate injunctive relief against any violation of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9344a95-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private Civil Actions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9344a96-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>An owner of a trade secret that is misappropriated may bring a civil action under this subsection if the trade secret is related to a product or service used in, or intended for use in, interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9344a97-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Civil seizure.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344a98-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344a99-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><content>Based on an affidavit or verified complaint satisfying the requirements of this paragraph, the court may, upon ex parte application but only in extraordinary circumstances, issue an order providing for the seizure of property necessary to prevent the propagation or dissemination of the trade secret that is the subject of the action.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344a9a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for issuing order</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The court may not grant an application under clause (i) unless the court finds that it clearly appears from specific facts that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344a9b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an order issued pursuant to Rule 65 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or another form of equitable relief would be inadequate to achieve the purpose of this paragraph because the party to which the order would be issued would evade, avoid, or otherwise not comply with such an order;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344a9c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an immediate and irreparable injury will occur if such seizure is not ordered;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344a9d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the harm to the applicant of denying the application outweighs the harm to the legitimate interests of the person against whom seizure would be ordered of granting the application and substantially outweighs the harm to any third parties who may be harmed by such seizure;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344a9e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> the applicant is likely to succeed in showing that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idb9344a9f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the information is a trade secret; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idb9344aa0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><chapeau> the person against whom seizure would be ordered—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idb9344aa1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/IV/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> misappropriated the trade secret of the applicant by improper means; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idb9344aa2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/IV/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> conspired to use improper means to misappropriate the trade secret of the applicant;</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344aa3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><chapeau> the person against whom seizure would be ordered has actual possession of—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idb9344aa4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/V/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the trade secret; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idb9344aa5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/V/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> any property to be seized;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344aa6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> the application describes with reasonable particularity the matter to be seized and, to the extent reasonable under the circumstances, identifies the location where the matter is to be seized;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344aa7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> the person against whom seizure would be ordered, or persons acting in concert with such person, would destroy, move, hide, or otherwise make such matter inaccessible to the court, if the applicant were to proceed on notice to such person; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344aa8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/A/ii/VIII"><num value="VIII">(VIII)</num><content> the applicant has not publicized the requested seizure.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344aa9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of order</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If an order is issued under subparagraph (A), it shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aaa-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> set forth findings of fact and conclusions of law required for the order;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aab-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provide for the narrowest seizure of property necessary to achieve the purpose of this paragraph and direct that the seizure be conducted in a manner that minimizes any interruption of the business operations of third parties and, to the extent possible, does not interrupt the legitimate business operations of the person accused of misappropriating the trade secret;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aac-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aad-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> be accompanied by an order protecting the seized property from disclosure by prohibiting access by the applicant or the person against whom the order is directed, and prohibiting any copies, in whole or in part, of the seized property, to prevent undue damage to the party against whom the order has issued or others, until such parties have an opportunity to be heard in court; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aae-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provide that if access is granted by the court to the applicant or the person against whom the order is directed, the access shall be consistent with subparagraph (D);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aaf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> provide guidance to the law enforcement officials executing the seizure that clearly delineates the scope of the authority of the officials, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344ab0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the hours during which the seizure may be executed; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344ab1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> whether force may be used to access locked areas;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> set a date for a hearing described in subparagraph (F) at the earliest possible time, and not later than 7 days after the order has issued, unless the party against whom the order is directed and others harmed by the order consent to another date for the hearing, except that a party against whom the order has issued or any person harmed by the order may move the court at any time to dissolve or modify the order after giving notice to the applicant who obtained the order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> require the person obtaining the order to provide the security determined adequate by the court for the payment of the damages that any person may be entitled to recover as a result of a wrongful or excessive seizure or wrongful or excessive attempted seizure under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ab4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection from publicity</inline>.—</heading><content>The court shall take appropriate action to protect the person against whom an order under this paragraph is directed from publicity, by or at the behest of the person obtaining the order, about such order and any seizure under such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ab5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Materials in custody of court.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any materials seized under this paragraph shall be taken into the custody of the court. The court shall secure the seized material from physical and electronic access during the seizure and while in the custody of the court.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Storage medium</inline>.—</heading><content>If the seized material includes a storage medium, or if the seized material is stored on a storage medium, the court shall prohibit the medium from being connected to a network or the Internet without the consent of both parties, until the hearing required under subparagraph (B)(v) and described in subparagraph (F).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection of confidentiality</inline>.—</heading><content>The court shall take appropriate measures to protect the confidentiality of seized materials that are unrelated to the trade secret information ordered seized pursuant to this paragraph unless the person against whom the order is entered consents to disclosure of the material.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ab9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment of special master</inline>.—</heading><content>The court may appoint a special master to locate and isolate all misappropriated trade secret information and to facilitate the return of unrelated property and data to the person from whom the property was seized. The special master appointed by the court shall agree to be bound by a non-disclosure agreement approved by the court.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344aba-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service of order</inline>.—</heading><content>The court shall order that service of a copy of the order under this paragraph, and the submissions of the applicant to obtain the order, shall be made by a Federal law enforcement officer who, upon making service, shall carry out the seizure under the order. The court may allow State or local law enforcement officials to participate, but may not permit the applicant or any agent of the applicant to participate in the seizure. At the request of law enforcement officials, the court may allow a technical expert who is unaffiliated with the applicant and who is bound by a court-approved non-disclosure agreement to participate in the seizure if the court determines that the participation of the expert will aid the efficient execution of and minimize the burden of the seizure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344abb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Seizure hearing.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344abc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date</inline>.—</heading><content>A court that issues a seizure order shall hold a hearing on the date set by the court under subparagraph (B)(v).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344abd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burden of proof</inline>.—</heading><content>At a hearing held under this subparagraph, the party who obtained the order under subparagraph (A) shall have the burden to prove the facts supporting the findings of fact and conclusions of law necessary to support the order. If the party fails to meet that burden, the seizure order shall be dissolved or modified appropriately.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344abe-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dissolution or modification of order</inline>.—</heading><content>A party against whom the order has been issued or any person harmed by the order may move the court at any time to dissolve or modify the order after giving notice to the party who obtained the order.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344abf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discovery time limits</inline>.—</heading><content>The court may make such orders modifying the time limits for discovery under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure as may be necessary to prevent the frustration of the purposes of a hearing under this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ac0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action for damage caused by wrongful seizure</inline>.—</heading><content>A person who suffers damage by reason of a wrongful or excessive seizure under this paragraph has a cause of action against the applicant for the order under which such seizure was made, and shall be entitled to the same relief as is provided under section 34(d)(11) of the Trademark Act of 1946 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1116/d/11">15 U.S.C. 1116(d)(11)</ref>). The security posted with the court under subparagraph (B)(vi) shall not limit the recovery of third parties for damages.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ac1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Motion for encryption</inline>.—</heading><content>A party or a person who claims to have an interest in the subject matter seized may make a motion at any time, which may be heard ex parte, to encrypt any material seized or to be seized under this paragraph that is stored on a storage medium. The motion shall include, when possible, the desired encryption method.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9344ac2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Remedies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In a civil action brought under this subsection with respect to the misappropriation of a trade secret, a court may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ac3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> grant an injunction—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ac4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> to prevent any actual or threatened misappropriation described in paragraph (1) on such terms as the court deems reasonable, provided the order does not—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344ac5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> prevent a person from entering into an employment relationship, and that conditions placed on such employment shall be based on evidence of threatened misappropriation and not merely on the information the person knows; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb9344ac6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> otherwise conflict with an applicable State law prohibiting restraints on the practice of a lawful profession, trade, or business;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ac7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if determined appropriate by the court, requiring affirmative actions to be taken to protect the trade secret; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344ac8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in exceptional circumstances that render an injunction inequitable, that conditions future use of the trade secret upon payment of a reasonable royalty for no longer than the period of time for which such use could have been prohibited;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ac9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> award—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344aca-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344acb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> damages for actual loss caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344acc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> damages for any unjust enrichment caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret that is not addressed in computing damages for actual loss; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9344acd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in lieu of damages measured by any other methods, the damages caused by the misappropriation measured by imposition of liability for a reasonable royalty for the misappropriator’s unauthorized disclosure or use of the trade secret;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344ace-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if the trade secret is willfully and maliciously misappropriated, award exemplary damages in an amount not more than 2 times the amount of the damages awarded under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9344acf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> if a claim of the misappropriation is made in bad faith, which may be established by circumstantial evidence, a motion to terminate an injunction is made or opposed in bad faith, or the trade secret was willfully and maliciously misappropriated, award reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9344ad0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading><content>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction of civil actions brought under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9344ad1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1836/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period of Limitations</inline>.—</heading><content>A civil action under subsection (b) may not be commenced later than 3 years after the date on which the misappropriation with respect to which the action would relate is discovered or by the exercise of reasonable diligence should have been discovered. For purposes of this subsection, a continuing misappropriation constitutes a single claim of misappropriation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9344ad2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 104–294, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3490">110 Stat. 3490</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dB/tIV/s4002/e/9">Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(e)(9)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1810">116 Stat. 1810</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/153/s2/a">Pub. L. 114–153, § 2(a)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="2016-05-11">May 11, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/376">130 Stat. 376</ref>, 381.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9344ad3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9344ad4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb9344ad5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(A)(ii)(I), (F)(iv), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9344ad6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/153/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 114–153, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “Civil proceedings” for “Civil proceedings to enjoin violations” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/153/s2/a">Pub. L. 114–153, § 2(a)</ref>, added subsecs. (b) to (d) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive original jurisdiction of civil actions under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s4002/e/9/A">Pub. L. 107–273, § 4002(e)(9)(A)</ref>, substituted “this chapter” for “this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s4002/e/9/B">Pub. L. 107–273, § 4002(e)(9)(B)</ref>, substituted “this section” for “this subsection”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9344ad7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9344ad8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/153">Pub. L. 114–153</ref> applicable with respect to any misappropriation of a trade secret (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1839">section 1839 of this title</ref>) for which any act occurs on or after <date date="2016-05-11">May 11, 2016</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/153/s2/e">section 2(e) of Pub. L. 114–153</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1833">section 1833 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
