<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb940314f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963"><num value="1963">§ 1963.</num><heading> Criminal penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403150-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Whoever violates any provision of section 1962 of this chapter shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years (or for life if the violation is based on a racketeering activity for which the maximum penalty includes life imprisonment), or both, and shall forfeit to the United States, irrespective of any provision of State law—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403151-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any interest the person has acquired or maintained in violation of section 1962;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403152-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> any—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403153-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> interest in;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403154-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> security of;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403155-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> claim against; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403156-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> property or contractual right of any kind affording a source of influence over;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">any enterprise which the person has established, operated, controlled, conducted, or participated in the conduct of, in violation of section 1962; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403157-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any property constituting, or derived from, any proceeds which the person obtained, directly or indirectly, from racketeering activity or unlawful debt collection in violation of section 1962.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The court, in imposing sentence on such person shall order, in addition to any other sentence imposed pursuant to this section, that the person forfeit to the United States all property described in this subsection. In lieu of a fine otherwise authorized by this section, a defendant who derives profits or other proceeds from an offense may be fined not more than twice the gross profits or other proceeds.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403158-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Property subject to criminal forfeiture under this section includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403159-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> real property, including things growing on, affixed to, and found in land; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940315a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> tangible and intangible personal property, including rights, privileges, interests, claims, and securities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940315b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> All right, title, and interest in property described in subsection (a) vests in the United States upon the commission of the act giving rise to forfeiture under this section. Any such property that is subsequently transferred to a person other than the defendant may be the subject of a special verdict of forfeiture and thereafter shall be ordered forfeited to the United States, unless the transferee establishes in a hearing pursuant to subsection (<i>l</i>) that he is a bona fide purchaser for value of such property who at the time of purchase was reasonably without cause to believe that the property was subject to forfeiture under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940315c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940315d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon application of the United States, the court may enter a restraining order or injunction, require the execution of a satisfactory performance bond, or take any other action to preserve the availability of property described in subsection (a) for forfeiture under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940315e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> upon the filing of an indictment or information charging a violation of section 1962 of this chapter and alleging that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940315f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> prior to the filing of such an indictment or information, if, after notice to persons appearing to have an interest in the property and opportunity for a hearing, the court determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403160-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> there is a substantial probability that the United States will prevail on the issue of forfeiture and that failure to enter the order will result in the property being destroyed, removed from the jurisdiction of the court, or otherwise made unavailable for forfeiture; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9403161-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the need to preserve the availability of the property through the entry of the requested order outweighs the hardship on any party against whom the order is to be entered:</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<proviso style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0"><i>Provided, however</i>, That an order entered pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be effective for not more than ninety days, unless extended by the court for good cause shown or unless an indictment or information described in subparagraph (A) has been filed.</proviso>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403162-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A temporary restraining order under this subsection may be entered upon application of the United States without notice or opportunity for a hearing when an information or indictment has not yet been filed with respect to the property, if the United States demonstrates that there is probable cause to believe that the property with respect to which the order is sought would, in the event of conviction, be subject to forfeiture under this section and that provision of notice will jeopardize the availability of the property for forfeiture. Such a temporary order shall expire not more than fourteen days after the date on which it is entered, unless extended for good cause shown or unless the party against whom it is entered consents to an extension for a longer period. A hearing requested concerning an order entered under this paragraph shall be held at the earliest possible time, and prior to the expiration of the temporary order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403163-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The court may receive and consider, at a hearing held pursuant to this subsection, evidence and information that would be inadmissible under the Federal Rules of Evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403164-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Upon conviction of a person under this section, the court shall enter a judgment of forfeiture of the property to the United States and shall also authorize the Attorney General to seize all property ordered forfeited upon such terms and conditions as the court shall deem proper. Following the entry of an order declaring the property forfeited, the court may, upon application of the United States, enter such appropriate restraining orders or injunctions, require the execution of satisfactory performance bonds, appoint receivers, conservators, appraisers, accountants, or trustees, or take any other action to protect the interest of the United States in the property ordered forfeited. Any income accruing to, or derived from, an enterprise or an interest in an enterprise which has been ordered forfeited under this section may be used to offset ordinary and necessary expenses to the enterprise which are required by law, or which are necessary to protect the interests of the United States or third parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403165-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Following the seizure of property ordered forfeited under this section, the Attorney General shall direct the disposition of the property by sale or any other commercially feasible means, making due provision for the rights of any innocent persons. Any property right or interest not exercisable by, or transferable for value to, the United States shall expire and shall not revert to the defendant, nor shall the defendant or any person acting in concert with or on behalf of the defendant be eligible to purchase forfeited property at any sale held by the United States. Upon application of a person, other than the defendant or a person acting in concert with or on behalf of the defendant, the court may restrain or stay the sale or disposition of the property pending the conclusion of any appeal of the criminal case giving rise to the forfeiture, if the applicant demonstrates that proceeding with the sale or disposition of the property will result in irreparable injury, harm or loss to him. Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302/b">31 U.S.C. 3302(b)</ref>, the proceeds of any sale or other disposition of property forfeited under this section and any moneys forfeited shall be used to pay all proper expenses for the forfeiture and the sale, including expenses of seizure, maintenance and custody of the property pending its disposition, advertising and court costs. The Attorney General shall deposit in the Treasury any amounts of such proceeds or moneys remaining after the payment of such expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403166-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><chapeau> With respect to property ordered forfeited under this section, the Attorney General is authorized to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403167-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> grant petitions for mitigation or remission of forfeiture, restore forfeited property to victims of a violation of this chapter, or take any other action to protect the rights of innocent persons which is in the interest of justice and which is not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403168-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> compromise claims arising under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403169-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> award compensation to persons providing information resulting in a forfeiture under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940316a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> direct the disposition by the United States of all property ordered forfeited under this section by public sale or any other commercially feasible means, making due provision for the rights of innocent persons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940316b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> take appropriate measures necessary to safeguard and maintain property ordered forfeited under this section pending its disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940316c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><chapeau> The Attorney General may promulgate regulations with respect to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940316d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> making reasonable efforts to provide notice to persons who may have an interest in property ordered forfeited under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940316e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> granting petitions for remission or mitigation of forfeiture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940316f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the restitution of property to victims of an offense petitioning for remission or mitigation of forfeiture under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403170-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the disposition by the United States of forfeited property by public sale or other commercially feasible means;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403171-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the maintenance and safekeeping of any property forfeited under this section pending its disposition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403172-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the compromise of claims arising under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Pending the promulgation of such regulations, all provisions of law relating to the disposition of property, or the proceeds from the sale thereof, or the remission or mitigation of forfeitures for violation of the customs laws, and the compromise of claims and the award of compensation to informers in respect of such forfeitures shall apply to forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this section, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions hereof. Such duties as are imposed upon the Customs Service or any person with respect to the disposition of property under the customs law shall be performed under this chapter by the Attorney General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403173-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (<i>l</i>), no party claiming an interest in property subject to forfeiture under this section may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403174-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> intervene in a trial or appeal of a criminal case involving the forfeiture of such property under this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403175-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> commence an action at law or equity against the United States concerning the validity of his alleged interest in the property subsequent to the filing of an indictment or information alleging that the property is subject to forfeiture under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403176-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to enter orders as provided in this section without regard to the location of any property which may be subject to forfeiture under this section or which has been ordered forfeited under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403177-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> In order to facilitate the identification or location of property declared forfeited and to facilitate the disposition of petitions for remission or mitigation of forfeiture, after the entry of an order declaring property forfeited to the United States the court may, upon application of the United States, order that the testimony of any witness relating to the property forfeited be taken by deposition and that any designated book, paper, document, record, recording, or other material not privileged be produced at the same time and place, in the same manner as provided for the taking of depositions under Rule 15 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403178-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403179-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Following the entry of an order of forfeiture under this section, the United States shall publish notice of the order and of its intent to dispose of the property in such manner as the Attorney General may direct. The Government may also, to the extent practicable, provide direct written notice to any person known to have alleged an interest in the property that is the subject of the order of forfeiture as a substitute for published notice as to those persons so notified.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940317a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person, other than the defendant, asserting a legal interest in property which has been ordered forfeited to the United States pursuant to this section may, within thirty days of the final publication of notice or his receipt of notice under paragraph (1), whichever is earlier, petition the court for a hearing to adjudicate the validity of his alleged interest in the property. The hearing shall be held before the court alone, without a jury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940317b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The petition shall be signed by the petitioner under penalty of perjury and shall set forth the nature and extent of the petitioner’s right, title, or interest in the property, the time and circumstances of the petitioner’s acquisition of the right, title, or interest in the property, any additional facts supporting the petitioner’s claim, and the relief sought.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940317c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The hearing on the petition shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with the interests of justice, be held within thirty days of the filing of the petition. The court may consolidate the hearing on the petition with a hearing on any other petition filed by a person other than the defendant under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940317d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> At the hearing, the petitioner may testify and present evidence and witnesses on his own behalf, and cross-examine witnesses who appear at the hearing. The United States may present evidence and witnesses in rebuttal and in defense of its claim to the property and cross-examine witnesses who appear at the hearing. In addition to testimony and evidence presented at the hearing, the court shall consider the relevant portions of the record of the criminal case which resulted in the order of forfeiture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940317e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> If, after the hearing, the court determines that the petitioner has established by a preponderance of the evidence that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb940317f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the petitioner has a legal right, title, or interest in the property, and such right, title, or interest renders the order of forfeiture invalid in whole or in part because the right, title, or interest was vested in the petitioner rather than the defendant or was superior to any right, title, or interest of the defendant at the time of the commission of the acts which gave rise to the forfeiture of the property under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403180-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the petitioner is a bona fide purchaser for value of the right, title, or interest in the property and was at the time of purchase reasonably without cause to believe that the property was subject to forfeiture under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court shall amend the order of forfeiture in accordance with its determination.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403181-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/l/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Following the court’s disposition of all petitions filed under this subsection, or if no such petitions are filed following the expiration of the period provided in paragraph (2) for the filing of such petitions, the United States shall have clear title to property that is the subject of the order of forfeiture and may warrant good title to any subsequent purchaser or transferee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9403182-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><chapeau> If any of the property described in subsection (a), as a result of any act or omission of the defendant—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403183-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> cannot be located upon the exercise of due diligence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403184-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has been transferred or sold to, or deposited with, a third party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403185-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has been placed beyond the jurisdiction of the court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403186-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> has been substantially diminished in value; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9403187-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1963/m/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> has been commingled with other property which cannot be divided without difficulty;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court shall order the forfeiture of any other property of the defendant up to the value of any property described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9403188-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tIX/s901/a">Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/943">84 Stat. 943</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII">Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 302, 2301(a)–(c), <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2040">98 Stat. 2040</ref>, 2192; <ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tI/s1153/a">Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1153(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-13">100 Stat. 3207–13</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/646/s23">Pub. L. 99–646, § 23</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3597">100 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7034, 7058(d), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4398">102 Stat. 4398</ref>, 4403; <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/tXXXV/s3561">Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3561</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4927">104 Stat. 4927</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/16/s3/4">Pub. L. 111–16, § 3(4)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1607">123 Stat. 1607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9403189-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb940318a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb940318b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Evidence, referred to in subsec. (d)(3), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb940318c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/16">Pub. L. 111–16</ref> substituted “fourteen days” for “ten days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647">Pub. L. 101–647</ref> substituted “or both” for “or both.” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7058/d">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7058(d)</ref>, substituted “shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years (or for life if the violation is based on a racketeering activity for which the maximum penalty includes life imprisonment), or both.” for “shall be fined not more than $25,000 or imprisoned not more than twenty years, or both”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (m), (n). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7034">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7034</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (n) as (m) and substituted “act or omission” for “act of omission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (c) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/99/646">Pub. L. 99–646</ref> substituted “(<i>l</i>)” for “(m)” in subsec. (c), redesignated subsecs. (e) to (m) as (d) to (<i>l</i>), respectively, and substituted “(<i>l</i>)” for “(m)” in subsec. (i) as redesignated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref> added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s2301/a">Pub. L. 98–473, § 2301(a)</ref>, inserted “In lieu of a fine otherwise authorized by this section, a defendant who derives profits or other proceeds from an offense may be fined not more than twice the gross profits or other proceeds.” following par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s302">Pub. L. 98–473, § 302</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally, designating existing provisions as pars. (1) and (2), inserting par. (3), and provisions following par. (3) relating to power of the court to order forfeiture to the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s302">Pub. L. 98–473, § 302</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally, substituting provisions relating to property subject to forfeiture, for provisions relating to jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s302">Pub. L. 98–473, § 302</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally, substituting provisions relating to transfer of rights, etc., in property to the United States, or to other transferees, for provisions relating to seizure and transfer of property to the United States and procedures related thereto.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s2301/b">Pub. L. 98–473, § 2301(b)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which provided: “If any of the property described in subsection (a): (1) cannot be located; (2) has been transferred to, sold to, or deposited with, a third party; (3) has been placed beyond the jurisdiction of the court; (4) has been substantially diminished in value by any act or omission of the defendant; or (5) has been commingled with other property which cannot be divided without difficulty; the court shall order the forfeiture of any other property of the defendant up to the value of any property described in paragraphs (1) through (5).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s302">Pub. L. 98–473, § 302</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s302">Pub. L. 98–473, § 302</ref>, added subsecs. (d) to (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s2301/c">Pub. L. 98–473, § 2301(c)</ref>, struck out “for at least seven successive court days” after “dispose of the property”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb940318d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb940318e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/16">Pub. L. 111–16</ref> effective <date date="2009-12-01">Dec. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/16/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 111–16</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s109">section 109 of Title 11</ref>, Bankruptcy.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb940318f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
