<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb940319d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1965"><num value="1965">§ 1965.</num><heading> Venue and process</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940319e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1965/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any civil action or proceeding under this chapter against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district in which such person resides, is found, has an agent, or transacts his affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb940319f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1965/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In any action under section 1964 of this chapter in any district court of the United States in which it is shown that the ends of justice require that other parties residing in any other district be brought before the court, the court may cause such parties to be summoned, and process for that purpose may be served in any judicial district of the United States by the marshal thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb94031a0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1965/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> In any civil or criminal action or proceeding instituted by the United States under this chapter in the district court of the United States for any judicial district, subpenas issued by such court to compel the attendance of witnesses may be served in any other judicial district, except that in any civil action or proceeding no such subpena shall be issued for service upon any individual who resides in another district at a place more than one hundred miles from the place at which such court is held without approval given by a judge of such court upon a showing of good cause.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb94031a1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s1965/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> All other process in any action or proceeding under this chapter may be served on any person in any judicial district in which such person resides, is found, has an agent, or transacts his affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb94031a2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tIX/s901/a">Pub. L. 91–452, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/944">84 Stat. 944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
