<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb942a342-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101"><num value="2101">§ 2101.</num><heading> Riots</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a343-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Whoever travels in interstate or foreign commerce or uses any facility of interstate or foreign commerce, including, but not limited to, the mail, telegraph, telephone, radio, or television, with intent—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb942a344-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to incite a riot; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb942a345-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to organize, promote, encourage, participate in, or carry on a riot; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb942a346-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to commit any act of violence in furtherance of a riot; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb942a347-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to aid or abet any person in inciting or participating in or carrying on a riot or committing any act of violence in furtherance of a riot;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and who either during the course of any such travel or use or thereafter performs or attempts to perform any other overt act for any purpose specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of this paragraph— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002136">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002136"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of this subsection—”.</note></continuation>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Shall be fined under this title, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a348-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In any prosecution under this section, proof that a defendant engaged or attempted to engage in one or more of the overt acts described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) of subsection (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002137">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002137"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a)”.</note> and (1) has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or (2) has use of or used any facility of interstate or foreign commerce, including but not limited to, mail, telegraph, telephone, radio, or television, to communicate with or broadcast to any person or group of persons prior to such overt acts, such travel or use shall be admissible proof to establish that such defendant traveled in or used such facility of interstate or foreign commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a349-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A judgment of conviction or acquittal on the merits under the laws of any State shall be a bar to any prosecution hereunder for the same act or acts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a34a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Whenever, in the opinion of the Attorney General or of the appropriate officer of the Department of Justice charged by law or under the instructions of the Attorney General with authority to act, any person shall have violated this chapter, the Department shall proceed as speedily as possible with a prosecution of such person hereunder and with any appeal which may lie from any decision adverse to the Government resulting from such prosecution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a34b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to make it unlawful for any person to travel in, or use any facility of, interstate or foreign commerce for the purpose of pursuing the legitimate objectives of organized labor, through orderly and lawful means.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb942a34c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2101/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed as indicating an intent on the part of Congress to prevent any State, any possession or Commonwealth of the United States, or the District of Columbia, from exercising jurisdiction over any offense over which it would have jurisdiction in the absence of this section; nor shall anything in this section be construed as depriving State and local law enforcement authorities of responsibility for prosecuting acts that may be violations of this section and that are violations of State and local law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb942a34d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/284/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 90–284, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/75">82 Stat. 75</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/386/tI/s106">Pub. L. 99–386, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1986-08-22">Aug. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/822">100 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330016/1/L">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2147">108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tVI/s601/f/15">Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(f)(15)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3500">110 Stat. 3500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb942a34e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb942a34f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb942a350-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/294">Pub. L. 104–294</ref> struck out par. (1) designation and redesignated subpars. (A) to (D) as pars. (1) to (4), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $10,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/386">Pub. L. 99–386</ref> struck out “; or in the alternative shall report in writing, to the respective Houses of the Congress, the Department’s reason for not so proceeding” after “such prosecution”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
