<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb950faf3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257"><num value="2257">§ 2257.</num><heading> Record keeping requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950faf4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Whoever produces any book, magazine, periodical, film, videotape, digital image, digitally- or computer-manipulated image of an actual human being, picture, or other matter which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950faf5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> contains one or more visual depictions made after <date date="1990-11-01">November 1, 1990</date> of actual sexually explicit conduct; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950faf6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is produced in whole or in part with materials which have been mailed or shipped in interstate or foreign commerce, or is shipped or transported or is intended for shipment or transportation in interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall create and maintain individually identifiable records pertaining to every performer portrayed in such a visual depiction.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950faf7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Any person to whom subsection (a) applies shall, with respect to every performer portrayed in a visual depiction of actual sexually explicit conduct—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950faf8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> ascertain, by examination of an identification document containing such information, the performer’s name and date of birth, and require the performer to provide such other indicia of his or her identity as may be prescribed by regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950faf9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ascertain any name, other than the performer’s present and correct name, ever used by the performer including maiden name, alias, nickname, stage, or professional name; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fafa-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> record in the records required by subsection (a) the information required by paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection and such other identifying information as may be prescribed by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fafb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any person to whom subsection (a) applies shall maintain the records required by this section at his business premises, or at such other place as the Attorney General may by regulation prescribe and shall make such records available to the Attorney General for inspection at all reasonable times.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fafc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fafd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No information or evidence obtained from records required to be created or maintained by this section shall, except as provided in this section, directly or indirectly, be used as evidence against any person with respect to any violation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fafe-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not preclude the use of such information or evidence in a prosecution or other action for a violation of this chapter or chapter 71, or for a violation of any applicable provision of law with respect to the furnishing of false information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950faff-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb00-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any person to whom subsection (a) applies shall cause to be affixed to every copy of any matter described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section, in such manner and in such form as the Attorney General shall by regulations prescribe, a statement describing where the records required by this section with respect to all performers depicted in that copy of the matter may be located. In this paragraph, the term “copy” includes every page of a website on which matter described in subsection (a) appears.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb01-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the person to whom subsection (a) of this section applies is an organization the statement required by this subsection shall include the name, title, and business address of the individual employed by such organization responsible for maintaining the records required by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb02-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> It shall be unlawful—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb03-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for any person to whom subsection (a) applies to fail to create or maintain the records as required by subsections (a) and (c) or by any regulation promulgated under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb04-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for any person to whom subsection (a) applies knowingly to make any false entry in or knowingly to fail to make an appropriate entry in, any record required by subsection (b) of this section or any regulation promulgated under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb05-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> for any person to whom subsection (a) applies knowingly to fail to comply with the provisions of subsection (e) or any regulation promulgated pursuant to that subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb06-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> for any person knowingly to sell or otherwise transfer, or offer for sale or transfer, any book, magazine, periodical, film, video, or other matter, produce in whole or in part with materials which have been mailed or shipped in interstate or foreign commerce or which is intended for shipment in interstate or foreign commerce, which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb950fb07-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contains one or more visual depictions made after the effective date of this subsection of actual sexually explicit conduct; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb950fb08-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is produced in whole or in part with materials which have been mailed or shipped in interstate or foreign commerce, or is shipped or transported or is intended for shipment or transportation in interstate or foreign commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">which does not have affixed thereto, in a manner prescribed as set forth in subsection (e)(1), a statement describing where the records required by this section may be located, but such person shall have no duty to determine the accuracy of the contents of the statement or the records required to be kept; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb09-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> for any person to whom subsection (a) applies to refuse to permit the Attorney General or his or her designee to conduct an inspection under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb0a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The Attorney General shall issue appropriate regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb0b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><chapeau> In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb0c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “actual sexually explicit conduct” means actual but not simulated conduct as defined in clauses (i) through (v) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2256/2/A">section 2256(2)(A) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb0d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the term “produces”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb950fb0e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb0f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> actually filming, videotaping, photographing, creating a picture, digital image, or digitally- or computer-manipulated image of an actual human being;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb10-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> digitizing an image, of a visual depiction of sexually explicit conduct; or, assembling, manufacturing, publishing, duplicating, reproducing, or reissuing a book, magazine, periodical, film, videotape, digital image, or picture, or other matter intended for commercial distribution, that contains a visual depiction of sexually explicit conduct; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb11-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> inserting on a computer site or service a digital image of, or otherwise managing the sexually explicit content,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002152"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> of a computer site or service that contains a visual depiction of, sexually explicit conduct; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb950fb12-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> does not include activities that are limited to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb13-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> photo or film processing, including digitization of previously existing visual depictions, as part of a commercial enterprise, with no other commercial interest in the sexually explicit material, printing, and video duplication;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb14-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> distribution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb15-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any activity, other than those activities identified in subparagraph (A), that does not involve the hiring, contracting for, managing, or otherwise arranging for the participation of the depicted performers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb16-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the provision of a telecommunications service, or of an Internet access service or Internet information location tool (as those terms are defined in section 231 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s231">47 U.S.C. 231</ref>)); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb950fb17-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the transmission, storage, retrieval, hosting, formatting, or translation (or any combination thereof) of a communication, without selection or alteration of the content of the communication, except that deletion of a particular communication or material made by another person in a manner consistent with section 230(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s230/c">47 U.S.C. 230(c)</ref>) shall not constitute such selection or alteration of the content of the communication; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb950fb18-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “performer” includes any person portrayed in a visual depiction engaging in, or assisting another person to engage in, sexually explicit conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb950fb19-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s2257/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Whoever violates this section shall be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, and fined in accordance with the provisions of this title, or both. Whoever violates this section after having been convicted of a violation punishable under this section shall be imprisoned for any period of years not more than 10 years but not less than 2 years, and fined in accordance with the provisions of this title, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb950fb1a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7513/a">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7513(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4487">102 Stat. 4487</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/tIII">Pub. L. 101–647, title III</ref>, §§ 301(b), 311, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4816">104 Stat. 4816</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330004/14">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(14)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2142">108 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/21/tV/s511/a">Pub. L. 108–21, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/684">117 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/tV/s502/a">Pub. L. 109–248, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/625">120 Stat. 625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb950fb1b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb950fb1c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb950fb1d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (f)(4)(A), see <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s312">section 312 of Pub. L. 101–647</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1990 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb950fb1e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s502/a/1">Pub. L. 109–248, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “digital image, digitally- or computer-manipulated image of an actual human being, picture,” after “videotape,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s502/a/2">Pub. L. 109–248, § 502(a)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “In this paragraph, the term ‘copy’ includes every page of a website on which matter described in subsection (a) appears.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s502/a/3">Pub. L. 109–248, § 502(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s502/a/4">Pub. L. 109–248, § 502(a)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which defined “actual sexually explicit conduct”, “identification document”, “produces”, and “performer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/21/s511/a/1">Pub. L. 108–21, § 511(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “of this chapter or chapter 71,” for “of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/21/s511/a/2">Pub. L. 108–21, § 511(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “, computer generated image, digital image, or picture,” after “video tape”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/21/s511/a/3">Pub. L. 108–21, § 511(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “not more than 5 years” for “not more than 2 years” and “10 years” for “5 years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> struck out subsecs. (f) and (g) as enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref>. Subsec. (f) authorized Attorney General to issue regulations to carry out this section and subsec. (g) defined “actual sexually explicit conduct”, “identification document”, “produces”, and “performer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s301/b">Pub. L. 101–647, § 301(b)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1990-11-01">November 1, 1990</date>” for “<date date="1978-02-06">February 6, 1978</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s311">Pub. L. 101–647, § 311</ref>, substituted pars. (1) and (2) for former pars. (1) and (2) which were substantially the same and struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “In a prosecution of any person to whom subsection (a) applies for an offense in violation of sub<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2251/a">section 2251(a) of this title</ref> which has as an element the production of a visual depiction of a minor engaging in or assisting another person to engage in sexually explicit conduct and in which that element is sought to be established by showing that a performer within the meaning of this section is a minor—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) proof that the person failed to comply with the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) of this section concerning the creation and maintenance of records, or a regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall raise a rebuttable presumption that such performer was a minor; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) proof that the person failed to comply with the provisions of subsection (e) of this section concerning the statement required by that subsection shall raise the rebuttable presumption that every performer in the matter was a minor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s311">Pub. L. 101–647, § 311</ref>, substituted pars. (1) and (2) for former pars. (1) and (2) which were substantially the same and struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “In any prosecution of a person for an offense in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2252">section 2252 of this title</ref> which has as an element the transporting, mailing, or distribution of a visual depiction involving the use of a minor engaging in sexually explicit conduct, and in which that element is sought to be established by a showing that a performer within the meaning of this section is a minor, proof that the matter in which the visual depiction is contained did not contain the statement required by this section shall raise a rebuttable presumption that such performer was a minor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s311">Pub. L. 101–647, § 311</ref>, added subsec. (f) relating to unlawful acts and omissions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s311">Pub. L. 101–647, § 311</ref>, added subsec. (g) relating to issuance of regulations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/s311">Pub. L. 101–647, § 311</ref>, added subsecs. (h) and (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb950fb1f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb950fb20-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/647/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 101–647, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4817">104 Stat. 4817</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/647/tIII/s312">
<inline>“Subsections (d), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2257">section 2257 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, as added by this title shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>] except—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Attorney General shall prepare the initial set of regulations required or authorized by subsections (d), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of section 2257 within 60 days of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> subsection (e) of section 2257 and of any regulation issued pursuant thereto shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb950fb21-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7513/c">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7513(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4488">102 Stat. 4488</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7513/c">
<inline>“<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2257">Section 2257 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, as added by this section shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>] except—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Attorney General shall prepare the initial set of regulations required or authorized by section 2257 within 90 days of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> subsection (e) of section 2257 of such title and of any regulation issued pursuant thereto shall take effect 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb950fb22-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/248/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 109–248, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/626">120 Stat. 626</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/248/tV/s502/b">“The provisions of section 2257 [of title 18, United States Code] shall not apply to any depiction of actual sexually explicit conduct as described in clause (v) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2256/2/A">section 2256(2)(A) of title 18</ref>, United States Code, produced in whole or in part, prior to the effective date of this section [<date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>] unless that depiction also includes actual sexually explicit conduct as described in clauses (i) through (iv) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2256/2/A">section 2256(2)(A) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb950fb23-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/21/tV/s511/b">Pub. L. 108–21, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/685">117 Stat. 685</ref>, provided that, not later than 1 year after <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, the Attorney General was to submit to Congress a report detailing the number of times since January 1993 that the Department of Justice had inspected records pursuant to this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s75">section 75 of title 28</ref> of the Code of Federal Regulations, and the number of violations prosecuted as a result of those inspections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
