<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb993a8c9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167"><num value="3167">§ 3167.</num><heading> Reports to Congress</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb993a8ca-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Administrative Office of the United States Courts, with the approval of the Judicial Conference, shall submit periodic reports to Congress detailing the plans submitted pursuant to section 3165. The reports shall be submitted within three months following the final dates for the submission of plans under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3165/e">section 3165(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb993a8cb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Such reports shall include recommendations for legislative changes or additional appropriations to achieve the time limits and objectives of this chapter. The report shall also contain pertinent information such as the state of the criminal docket at the time of the adoption of the plan; the extent of pretrial detention and release; and a description of the time limits, procedural techniques, innovations, systems, and other methods by which the trial or other disposition of criminal cases have been expedited or may be expedited in the districts. Such reports shall also include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8cc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The reasons why, in those cases not in compliance with the time limits of subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161, the provisions of section 3161(h) have not been adequate to accommodate reasonable periods of delay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8cd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The category of offenses, the number of defendants, and the number of counts involved in those cases which are not meeting the time limits specified in subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8ce-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The additional judicial resources which would be necessary in order to achieve compliance with the time limits specified in subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8cf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The nature of the remedial measures which have been employed to improve conditions and practices in those districts with low compliance experience under this chapter or to promote the adoption of practices and procedures which have been successful in those districts with high compliance experience under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If a district has experienced difficulty in complying with this chapter, but an application for relief under section 3174 has not been made, the reason why such application has not been made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The impact of compliance with the time limits of subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161 upon the civil case calendar in each district as demonstrated by the information assembled and statistics compiled and submitted under sections 3166 and 3170.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb993a8d2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>, the Department of Justice shall prepare and submit to the Congress a report which sets forth the impact of the implementation of this chapter upon the office of the United States Attorney in each district and which shall also include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the reasons why, in those cases not in compliance, the provisions of section 3161(h) have not been adequate to accommodate reasonable periods of delay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the nature of the remedial measures which have been employed to improve conditions and practices in the offices of the United States Attorneys in those districts with low compliance experience under this chapter or to promote the adoption of practices and procedures which have been successful in those districts with high compliance experience under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the additional resources for the offices of the United States Attorneys which would be necessary to achieve compliance with the time limits of subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> suggested changes in the guidelines or other rules implementing this chapter or statutory amendments which the Department of Justice deems necessary to further improve the administration of justice and meet the objectives of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb993a8d7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3167/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the impact of compliance with the time limits of subsections (b) and (c) of section 3161 upon the litigation of civil cases by the offices of the United States Attorneys and the rule changes, statutory amendments, and resources necessary to assure that such litigation is not prejudiced by full compliance with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb993a8d8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/93/619/tI/s101">Pub. L. 93–619, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2083">88 Stat. 2083</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/43/s9/e">Pub. L. 96–43, § 9(e)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-02">Aug. 2, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/330">93 Stat. 330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb993a8d9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb993a8da-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb993a8db-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/43/s9/e/1">Pub. L. 96–43, § 9(e)(1)</ref>, inserted last sentence containing pars. (1) to (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/43/s9/e/2">Pub. L. 96–43, § 9(e)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
