<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb99ad52d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3332"><num value="3332">§ 3332.</num><heading> Powers and duties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb99ad52e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3332/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> It shall be the duty of each such grand jury impaneled within any judicial district to inquire into offenses against the criminal laws of the United States alleged to have been committed within that district. Such alleged offenses may be brought to the attention of the grand jury by the court or by any attorney appearing on behalf of the United States for the presentation of evidence. Any such attorney receiving information concerning such an alleged offense from any other person shall, if requested by such other person, inform the grand jury of such alleged offense, the identity of such other person, and such attorney’s action or recommendation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb99ad52f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3332/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whenever the district court determines that the volume of business of the special grand jury exceeds the capacity of the grand jury to discharge its obligations, the district court may order an additional special grand jury for that district to be impaneled.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb99ad530-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 91–452, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/924">84 Stat. 924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb99ad531-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb99ad532-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb99ad533-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The criminal laws of the United States, referred to in subsec. (a), are classified generally to this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
