<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9bc3f62-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664"><num value="3664">§ 3664.</num><heading> Procedure for issuance and enforcement of order of restitution</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f63-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> For orders of restitution under this title, the court shall order the probation officer to obtain and include in its presentence report, or in a separate report, as the court may direct, information sufficient for the court to exercise its discretion in fashioning a restitution order. The report shall include, to the extent practicable, a complete accounting of the losses to each victim, any restitution owed pursuant to a plea agreement, and information relating to the economic circumstances of each defendant. If the number or identity of victims cannot be reasonably ascertained, or other circumstances exist that make this requirement clearly impracticable, the probation officer shall so inform the court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f64-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The court shall disclose to both the defendant and the attorney for the Government all portions of the presentence or other report pertaining to the matters described in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f65-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The provisions of this chapter, chapter 227, and Rule 32(c) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure shall be the only rules applicable to proceedings under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f66-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f67-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon the request of the probation officer, but not later than 60 days prior to the date initially set for sentencing, the attorney for the Government, after consulting, to the extent practicable, with all identified victims, shall promptly provide the probation officer with a listing of the amounts subject to restitution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f68-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The probation officer shall, prior to submitting the presentence report under subsection (a), to the extent practicable—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f69-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> provide notice to all identified victims of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the offense or offenses of which the defendant was convicted;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amounts subject to restitution submitted to the probation officer;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the opportunity of the victim to submit information to the probation officer concerning the amount of the victim’s losses;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the scheduled date, time, and place of the sentencing hearing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the availability of a lien in favor of the victim pursuant to subsection (m)(1)(B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f6f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the opportunity of the victim to file with the probation officer a separate affidavit relating to the amount of the victim’s losses subject to restitution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f70-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide the victim with an affidavit form to submit pursuant to subparagraph (A)(vi).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f71-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Each defendant shall prepare and file with the probation officer an affidavit fully describing the financial resources of the defendant, including a complete listing of all assets owned or controlled by the defendant as of the date on which the defendant was arrested, the financial needs and earning ability of the defendant and the defendant’s dependents, and such other information that the court requires relating to such other factors as the court deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f72-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> After reviewing the report of the probation officer, the court may require additional documentation or hear testimony. The privacy of any records filed, or testimony heard, pursuant to this section shall be maintained to the greatest extent possible, and such records may be filed or testimony heard in camera.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f73-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If the victim’s losses are not ascertainable by the date that is 10 days prior to sentencing, the attorney for the Government or the probation officer shall so inform the court, and the court shall set a date for the final determination of the victim’s losses, not to exceed 90 days after sentencing. If the victim subsequently discovers further losses, the victim shall have 60 days after discovery of those losses in which to petition the court for an amended restitution order. Such order may be granted only upon a showing of good cause for the failure to include such losses in the initial claim for restitutionary relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f74-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The court may refer any issue arising in connection with a proposed order of restitution to a magistrate judge or special master for proposed findings of fact and recommendations as to disposition, subject to a de novo determination of the issue by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f75-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Any dispute as to the proper amount or type of restitution shall be resolved by the court by the preponderance of the evidence. The burden of demonstrating the amount of the loss sustained by a victim as a result of the offense shall be on the attorney for the Government. The burden of demonstrating the financial resources of the defendant and the financial needs of the defendant’s dependents, shall be on the defendant. The burden of demonstrating such other matters as the court deems appropriate shall be upon the party designated by the court as justice requires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f76-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f77-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f78-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In each order of restitution, the court shall order restitution to each victim in the full amount of each victim’s losses as determined by the court and without consideration of the economic circumstances of the defendant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f79-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In no case shall the fact that a victim has received or is entitled to receive compensation with respect to a loss from insurance or any other source be considered in determining the amount of restitution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f7a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Upon determination of the amount of restitution owed to each victim, the court shall, pursuant to section 3572, specify in the restitution order the manner in which, and the schedule according to which, the restitution is to be paid, in consideration of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f7b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the financial resources and other assets of the defendant, including whether any of these assets are jointly controlled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f7c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> projected earnings and other income of the defendant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f7d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any financial obligations of the defendant; including obligations to dependents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f7e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f7f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A restitution order may direct the defendant to make a single, lump-sum payment, partial payments at specified intervals, in-kind payments, or a combination of payments at specified intervals and in-kind payments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f80-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A restitution order may direct the defendant to make nominal periodic payments if the court finds from facts on the record that the economic circumstances of the defendant do not allow the payment of any amount of a restitution order, and do not allow for the payment of the full amount of a restitution order in the foreseeable future under any reasonable schedule of payments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f81-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> An in-kind payment described in paragraph (3) may be in the form of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f82-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> return of property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f83-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> replacement of property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f84-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if the victim agrees, services rendered to the victim or a person or organization other than the victim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f85-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f86-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No victim shall be required to participate in any phase of a restitution order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f87-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A victim may at any time assign the victim’s interest in restitution payments to the Crime Victims Fund in the Treasury without in any way impairing the obligation of the defendant to make such payments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f88-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> If the court finds that more than 1 defendant has contributed to the loss of a victim, the court may make each defendant liable for payment of the full amount of restitution or may apportion liability among the defendants to reflect the level of contribution to the victim’s loss and economic circumstances of each defendant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f89-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> If the court finds that more than 1 victim has sustained a loss requiring restitution by a defendant, the court may provide for a different payment schedule for each victim based on the type and amount of each victim’s loss and accounting for the economic circumstances of each victim. In any case in which the United States is a victim, the court shall ensure that all other victims receive full restitution before the United States receives any restitution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f8a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f8b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a victim has received compensation from insurance or any other source with respect to a loss, the court shall order that restitution be paid to the person who provided or is obligated to provide the compensation, but the restitution order shall provide that all restitution of victims required by the order be paid to the victims before any restitution is paid to such a provider of compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f8c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any amount paid to a victim under an order of restitution shall be reduced by any amount later recovered as compensatory damages for the same loss by the victim in—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f8d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any Federal civil proceeding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f8e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any State civil proceeding, to the extent provided by the law of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f8f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> A restitution order shall provide that the defendant shall notify the court and the Attorney General of any material change in the defendant’s economic circumstances that might affect the defendant’s ability to pay restitution. The court may also accept notification of a material change in the defendant’s economic circumstances from the United States or from the victim. The Attorney General shall certify to the court that the victim or victims owed restitution by the defendant have been notified of the change in circumstances. Upon receipt of the notification, the court may, on its own motion, or the motion of any party, including the victim, adjust the payment schedule, or require immediate payment in full, as the interests of justice require.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f90-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> A conviction of a defendant for an offense involving the act giving rise to an order of restitution shall estop the defendant from denying the essential allegations of that offense in any subsequent Federal civil proceeding or State civil proceeding, to the extent consistent with State law, brought by the victim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f91-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f92-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f93-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f94-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An order of restitution may be enforced by the United States in the manner provided for in subchapter C of chapter 227 and subchapter B of chapter 229 of this title; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f95-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> by all other available and reasonable means.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f96-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At the request of a victim named in a restitution order, the clerk of the court shall issue an abstract of judgment certifying that a judgment has been entered in favor of such victim in the amount specified in the restitution order. Upon registering, recording, docketing, or indexing such abstract in accordance with the rules and requirements relating to judgments of the court of the State where the district court is located, the abstract of judgment shall be a lien on the property of the defendant located in such State in the same manner and to the same extent and under the same conditions as a judgment of a court of general jurisdiction in that State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f97-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An order of in-kind restitution in the form of services shall be enforced by the probation officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f98-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> If a person obligated to provide restitution, or pay a fine, receives substantial resources from any source, including inheritance, settlement, or other judgment, during a period of incarceration, such person shall be required to apply the value of such resources to any restitution or fine still owed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3f99-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><chapeau> A sentence that imposes an order of restitution is a final judgment notwithstanding the fact that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f9a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> such a sentence can subsequently be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f9b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> corrected under Rule 35 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure and section 3742 of chapter 235 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f9c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> appealed and modified under section 3742;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f9d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> amended under subsection (d)(5); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9bc3f9e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> adjusted under section 3664(k), 3572, or 3613A; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9bc3f9f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/o/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the defendant may be resentenced under section 3565 or 3614.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9bc3fa0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s3664/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> Nothing in this section or sections 2248, 2259, 2264, 2327, 3663, and 3663A and arising out of the application of such sections, shall be construed to create a cause of action not otherwise authorized in favor of any person against the United States or any officer or employee of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9bc3fa1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/291/s5/a">Pub. L. 97–291, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1255">96 Stat. 1255</ref>, § 3580; renumbered § 3664, <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s212/a/1">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1987">98 Stat. 1987</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/tXXXV/s3596">Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3596</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4931">104 Stat. 4931</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tII/s206/a">Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1232">110 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dB/tIV/s4002/e/1">Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4002(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1810">116 Stat. 1810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9bc3fa2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9bc3fa3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb9bc3fa4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (<i>o</i>)(1)(A), are set out in the Appendix to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9bc3fa5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> substituted “subsection (d)(5)” for “section 3664(d)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/132">Pub. L. 104–132</ref> amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to procedure for issuance and enforcement of orders of restitution for provisions relating to procedure for issuing orders of restitution.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/647">Pub. L. 101–647</ref> substituted “3663” for “3579”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9bc3fa6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9bc3fa7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/132">Pub. L. 104–132</ref> to be effective, to extent constitutionally permissible, for sentencing proceedings in cases in which defendant is convicted on or after <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s211">section 211 of Pub. L. 104–132</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2248">section 2248 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb9bc3fa8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to offenses occurring after <date date="1983-01-01">Jan. 1, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/291/s9/b/2">section 9(b)(2) of Pub. L. 97–291</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1512">section 1512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
