<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9c5dc55-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047"><num value="4047">§ 4047.</num><heading> Prison impact assessments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9c5dc56-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any submission of legislation by the Judicial or Executive branch which could increase or decrease the number of persons incarcerated in Federal penal institutions shall be accompanied by a prison impact statement (as defined in subsection (b)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9c5dc57-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The Attorney General shall, in consultation with the Sentencing Commission and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, prepare and furnish prison impact assessments under subsection (c) of this section, and in response to requests from Congress for information relating to a pending measure or matter that might affect the number of defendants processed through the Federal criminal justice system. A prison impact assessment on pending legislation must be supplied within 21 days of any request. A prison impact assessment shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9c5dc58-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> projections of the impact on prison, probation, and post prison supervision populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9c5dc59-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an estimate of the fiscal impact of such population changes on Federal expenditures, including those for construction and operation of correctional facilities for the current fiscal year and 5 succeeding fiscal years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9c5dc5a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an analysis of any other significant factor affecting the cost of the measure and its impact on the operations of components of the criminal justice system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9c5dc5b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a statement of the methodologies and assumptions utilized in preparing the assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9c5dc5c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4047/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Attorney General shall prepare and transmit to the Congress, by March 1 of each year, a prison impact assessment reflecting the cumulative effect of all relevant changes in the law taking effect during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9c5dc5d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tII/s20402/a">Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20402(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1824">108 Stat. 1824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
