<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8a79b85-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42"><num value="42">§ 42.</num><heading> Importation or shipment of injurious mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibia, and reptiles; permits, specimens for museums; regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b86-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b87-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The importation into the United States, any territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any possession of the United States, or any shipment between the continental United States, the District of Columbia, Hawaii, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any possession of the United States, of the mongoose of the species Herpestes auropunctatus; of the species of so-called “flying foxes” or fruit bats of the genus Pteropus; of the zebra mussel of the species Dreissena polymorpha; of the quagga mussel of the species Dreissena rostriformis or Dreissena bugensis; of the bighead carp of the species Hypophthalmichthys nobilis; and such other species of wild mammals, wild birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibians, reptiles, brown tree snakes, or the offspring or eggs of any of the foregoing which the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe by regulation to be injurious to human beings, to the interests of agriculture, horticulture, forestry, or to wildlife or the wildlife resources of the United States, is hereby prohibited. All such prohibited mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibians, and reptiles, and the eggs or offspring therefrom, shall be promptly exported or destroyed at the expense of the importer or consignee. Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal or modify any provision of the Public Health Service Act or Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Also, this section shall not authorize any action with respect to the importation of any plant pest as defined in the Federal Plant Pest Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002016"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> insofar as such importation is subject to regulation under that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b88-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> As used in this subsection, the term “wild” relates to any creatures that, whether or not raised in captivity, normally are found in a wild state; and the terms “wildlife” and “wildlife resources” include those resources that comprise wild mammals, wild birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), and all other classes of wild creatures whatsoever, and all types of aquatic and land vegetation upon which such wildlife resources are dependent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b89-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Secretary of the Interior, when he finds that there has been a proper showing of responsibility and continued protection of the public interest and health, shall permit the importation for zoological, educational, medical, and scientific purposes of any mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibia, and reptiles, or the offspring or eggs thereof, where such importation would be prohibited otherwise by or pursuant to this Act, and this Act shall not restrict importations by Federal agencies for their own use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b8a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall restrict the importation of dead natural-history specimens for museums or for scientific collections, or the importation of domesticated canaries, parrots (including all other species of psittacine birds), or such other cage birds as the Secretary of the Interior may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b8b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Interior shall enforce the provisions of this subsection, including any regulations issued hereunder, and, if requested by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Treasury may require the furnishing of an appropriate bond when desirable to insure compliance with such provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b8c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whoever violates this section, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a79b8d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior within one hundred and eighty days of the enactment of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 shall prescribe such requirements and issue such permits as he may deem necessary for the transportation of wild animals and birds under humane and healthful conditions, and it shall be unlawful for any person, including any importer, knowingly to cause or permit any wild animal or bird to be transported to the United States, or any Territory or district thereof, under inhumane or unhealthful conditions or in violation of such requirements. In any criminal prosecution for violation of this subsection and in any administrative proceeding for the suspension of the issuance of further permits—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a79b8e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the condition of any vessel or conveyance, or the enclosures in which wild animals or birds are confined therein, upon its arrival in the United States, or any Territory or district thereof, shall constitute relevant evidence in determining whether the provisions of this subsection have been violated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a79b8f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s42/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the presence in such vessel or conveyance at such time of a substantial ratio of dead, crippled, diseased, or starving wild animals or birds shall be deemed prima facie evidence of the violation of the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8a79b90-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645">June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/687">62 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s2">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/89">63 Stat. 89</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/702/s1">Pub. L. 86–702, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/753">74 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/79/s9/d">Pub. L. 97–79, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1079">95 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/646/tI/s1208">Pub. L. 101–646, title I, § 1208</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4772">104 Stat. 4772</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1013/e">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1013(e)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1901">105 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330016/1/G">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2147">108 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/h/1">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4091">110 Stat. 4091</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/307/s2">Pub. L. 111–307, § 2</ref>, <date date="2010-12-14">Dec. 14, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3282">124 Stat. 3282</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tIX/s903/e">Pub. L. 115–282, title IX, § 903(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4357">132 Stat. 4357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8a79b91-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8a79b92-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8a79b93-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered">1948 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., §§ 391, 394 (<ref href="/us/act/1909-03-04/ch321">Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321</ref>, §§ 241, 244, <ref href="/us/stat/35/1137">35 Stat. 1137</ref>, 1138; <ref href="/us/act/1935-06-15/ch261">June 15, 1935, ch. 261</ref>, title II, § 201, <ref href="/us/stat/49/381">49 Stat. 381</ref>; Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section consolidates the provisions of sections 391 and 394 of title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., as subsections (a) and (b), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a) the words “Territory or District thereof” were omitted as unnecessary in view of the definition of the United States in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s5">section 5 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b) the words “upon conviction thereof”, were omitted as surplusage because punishment can only be imposed after conviction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The amount of the fine was reduced from $1,000 to $500, thus making the violation a petty offense as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>. (See also <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s41">section 41 of this title</ref> which provides a similar punishment.)</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Minor verbal changes were also made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8aa0c94-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered">1949 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section [section 2] incorporates in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s42">section 42 of title 18</ref>, U.S.C., with slight changes in phraseology, the provisions of act of <date date="1948-06-29">June 29, 1948</date> (ch. 716, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1096">62 Stat. 1096</ref>), which became law subsequent to the enactment of the revision of title 18.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8aa0c95-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8aa0c96-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6A (§ 201 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675">act June 25, 1938, ch. 675</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1040">52 Stat. 1040</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 9 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 21, Foods and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">section 301 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Plant Pest Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/36/tI">Pub. L. 85–36, title I</ref>, <date date="1957-05-23">May 23, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/31">71 Stat. 31</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 7B (§ 150aa et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/106/224/tIV/s438/a/2">Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 438(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/454">114 Stat. 454</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), probably refers to <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref>, which amended this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s43">section 43 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The enactment of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981, referred to in subsec. (c), means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/97/79">Pub. L. 97–79</ref>, which was approved <date date="1981-11-16">Nov. 16, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8aa0c97-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> inserted “of the quagga mussel of the species Dreissena rostriformis or Dreissena bugensis;” after “Dreissena polymorpha;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/307">Pub. L. 111–307</ref> inserted “of the bighead carp of the species Hypophthalmichthys nobilis;” after “Dreissena polymorpha;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332">Pub. L. 104–332</ref> made technical amendment to <ref href="/us/pl/101/646/s1208">Pub. L. 101–646, § 1208</ref>. See 1990 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> inserted “brown tree snakes,” after “reptiles,” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/646">Pub. L. 101–646</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/332">Pub. L. 104–332</ref>, inserted “of the zebra mussel of the species Dreissena polymorpha;” after “Pteropus;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/79">Pub. L. 97–79</ref> substituted “Secretary of the Interior within one hundred and eighty days of the enactment of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981” for “Secretary of the Treasury”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> substituted “Importation or shipment of injurious mammals, birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibia and reptiles; permits; specimens for museums; regulations” for “Importation of injurious animals and birds; permits; specimens for museums” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> designated first sentence of subsec. (a) as par. (1), prohibited importation into the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or any possession of the United States and shipments between the continental United States, the District of Columbia, Hawaii, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any possession of the United States, described the mongoose and flying foxes by their scientific names, extended the provisions prohibiting importation or shipment to include wild mammals, wild birds, fish (including mollusks and crustacea), amphibians, reptiles, or their eggs or offspring, empowered the Secretary to prohibit importation or shipment if injurious to human beings, forestry, or to wildlife or wildlife resources, required prompt exportation or destruction at the expense of the importer or consignee, provided that this section shall not be construed to repeal or modify any provision of the Public Health Service Act or Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and that it shall not authorize any action with respect to the importation of plant pests, and deleted provisions which required destruction of prohibited birds and animals or their return at the expense of the owner, and which prohibited the importation of the English sparrow and the starling.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> designated second sentence of subsec. (a) as par. (4), limited importation of natural-history specimens to dead ones, and included all species of psittacine birds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> designated third sentence of subsec. (a) as par. (5), authorized enforcement by the Secretary of the Interior, and permitted the Secretary of the Treasury, if requested by the Secretary of the Interior, to require the furnishing of a bond.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/702">Pub. L. 86–702</ref> included violations of regulations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, made section applicable to any Territory or district thereof as well as to the United States, and changed phraseology.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, reenacted subsec. (b) without change.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8aa0c98-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8aa0c99-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Invasive Species</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to restrictions on the introduction of invasive species into natural ecosystems of the United States, see Ex. Ord. No. 13112, <date date="1999-02-03">Feb. 3, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 6183, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
