<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9cf524b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241"><num value="4241">§ 4241.</num><heading> Determination of mental competency to stand trial to undergo postrelease proceedings <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002284">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002284"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “stand trial or to undergo postrelease proceedings”.</note></heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf524c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Motion To Determine Competency of Defendant</inline>.—</heading><content>At any time after the commencement of a prosecution for an offense and prior to the sentencing of the defendant, or at any time after the commencement of probation or supervised release and prior to the completion of the sentence, the defendant or the attorney for the Government may file a motion for a hearing to determine the mental competency of the defendant. The court shall grant the motion, or shall order such a hearing on its own motion, if there is reasonable cause to believe that the defendant may presently be suffering from a mental disease or defect rendering him mentally incompetent to the extent that he is unable to understand the nature and consequences of the proceedings against him or to assist properly in his defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf524d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Psychiatric or Psychological Examination and Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Prior to the date of the hearing, the court may order that a psychiatric or psychological examination of the defendant be conducted, and that a psychiatric or psychological report be filed with the court, pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(b) and (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf524e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hearing</inline>.—</heading><content>The hearing shall be conducted pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf524f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination and Disposition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If, after the hearing, the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the defendant is presently suffering from a mental disease or defect rendering him mentally incompetent to the extent that he is unable to understand the nature and consequences of the proceedings against him or to assist properly in his defense, the court shall commit the defendant to the custody of the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall hospitalize the defendant for treatment in a suitable facility—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5250-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for such a reasonable period of time, not to exceed four months, as is necessary to determine whether there is a substantial probability that in the foreseeable future he will attain the capacity to permit the proceedings to go forward; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5251-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> for an additional reasonable period of time until—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf5252-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> his mental condition is so improved that trial may proceed, if the court finds that there is a substantial probability that within such additional period of time he will attain the capacity to permit the proceedings to go forward; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf5253-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the pending charges against him are disposed of according to law;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">whichever is earlier.</continuation>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If, at the end of the time period specified, it is determined that the defendant’s mental condition has not so improved as to permit the proceedings to go forward, the defendant is subject to the provisions of sections 4246 and 4248.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5254-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discharge</inline>.—</heading><content>When the director of the facility in which a defendant is hospitalized pursuant to subsection (d) determines that the defendant has recovered to such an extent that he is able to understand the nature and consequences of the proceedings against him and to assist properly in his defense, he shall promptly file a certificate to that effect with the clerk of the court that ordered the commitment. The clerk shall send a copy of the certificate to the defendant’s counsel and to the attorney for the Government. The court shall hold a hearing, conducted pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(d), to determine the competency of the defendant. If, after the hearing, the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the defendant has recovered to such an extent that he is able to understand the nature and consequences of the proceedings against him and to assist properly in his defense, the court shall order his immediate discharge from the facility in which he is hospitalized and shall set the date for trial or other proceedings. Upon discharge, the defendant is subject to the provisions of chapters 207 and 227.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5255-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4241/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Admissibility of Finding of Competency</inline>.—</heading><content>A finding by the court that the defendant is mentally competent to stand trial shall not prejudice the defendant in raising the issue of his insanity as a defense to the offense charged, and shall not be admissible as evidence in a trial for the offense charged.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9cf5256-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645">June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/855">62 Stat. 855</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s403/a">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2057">98 Stat. 2057</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/tIII/s302/2">Pub. L. 109–248, title III, § 302(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/619">120 Stat. 619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9cf5257-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb9cf5258-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 876 (<ref href="/us/act/1930-05-13/ch254/s6">May 13, 1930, ch. 254, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/271">46 Stat. 271</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology and surplusage omitted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9cf5259-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9cf525a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/2/A">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “to undergo postrelease proceedings” after “trial” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/2/B">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “or at any time after the commencement of probation or supervised release and prior to the completion of the sentence,” after “sentencing of the defendant,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/2/C">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “proceedings to go forward” for “trial to proceed” wherever appearing and “sections 4246 and 4248” for “section 4246” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/2/D">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(2)(D)</ref>, inserted “or other proceedings” after “trial” and substituted “chapters 207 and 227” for “chapter 207”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> amended section generally, substituting “Determination of mental competency to stand trial” for “Examination and transfer to hospital” in section catchline, and substituting provisions relating to motion, report, hearing, etc., for determination of competency of defendant, for provisions relating to boards of examiners for examination of inmates of Federal penal and correctional institutions and transfer of such inmates to hospitals.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9cf525b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idb9cf525c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s401">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 401</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2057">98 Stat. 2057</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s401">“This chapter [chapter IV (§§ 401–406) of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s20">section 20 of this title</ref> and amending this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3006A">section 3006A of this title</ref>, and rule 12.2 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure and rule 704 of the Federal Rules of Evidence set out in the Appendix to this title] may be sited [cited] as the ‘Insanity Defense Reform Act of 1984’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
