<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9cf5268-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243"><num value="4243">§ 4243.</num><heading> Hospitalization of a person found not guilty only by reason of insanity</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5269-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of Present Mental Condition of Acquitted Person</inline>.—</heading><content>If a person is found not guilty only by reason of insanity at the time of the offense charged, he shall be committed to a suitable facility until such time as he is eligible for release pursuant to subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf526a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Psychiatric or Psychological Examination and Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Prior to the date of the hearing, pursuant to subsection (c), the court shall order that a psychiatric or psychological examination of the defendant be conducted, and that a psychiatric or psychological report be filed with the court, pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(b) and (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf526b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hearing</inline>.—</heading><content>A hearing shall be conducted pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(d) and shall take place not later than forty days following the special verdict.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf526c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burden of Proof</inline>.—</heading><content>In a hearing pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, a person found not guilty only by reason of insanity of an offense involving bodily injury to, or serious damage to the property of, another person, or involving a substantial risk of such injury or damage, has the burden of proving by clear and convincing evidence that his release would not create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage of property of another due to a present mental disease or defect. With respect to any other offense, the person has the burden of such proof by a preponderance of the evidence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf526d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination and Disposition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If, after the hearing, the court fails to find by the standard specified in subsection (d) of this section that the person’s release would not create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage of property of another due to a present mental disease or defect, the court shall commit the person to the custody of the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall release the person to the appropriate official of the State in which the person is domiciled or was tried if such State will assume responsibility for his custody, care, and treatment. The Attorney General shall make all reasonable efforts to cause such a State to assume such responsibility. If, notwithstanding such efforts, neither such State will assume such responsibility, the Attorney General shall hospitalize the person for treatment in a suitable facility until—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf526e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such a State will assume such responsibility; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf526f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the person’s mental condition is such that his release, or his conditional release under a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment, would not create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever is earlier. The Attorney General shall continue periodically to exert all reasonable efforts to cause such a State to assume such responsibility for the person’s custody, care, and treatment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5270-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discharge</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>When the director of the facility in which an acquitted person is hospitalized pursuant to subsection (e) determines that the person has recovered from his mental disease or defect to such an extent that his release, or his conditional release under a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment, would no longer create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another, he shall promptly file a certificate to that effect with the clerk of the court that ordered the commitment. The clerk shall send a copy of the certificate to the person’s counsel and to the attorney for the Government. The court shall order the discharge of the acquitted person or, on the motion of the attorney for the Government or on its own motion, shall hold a hearing, conducted pursuant to the provisions of section 4247(d), to determine whether he should be released. If, after the hearing, the court finds by the standard specified in subsection (d) that the person has recovered from his mental disease or defect to such an extent that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5271-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> his release would no longer create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another, the court shall order that he be immediately discharged; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5272-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> his conditional release under a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment would no longer create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another, the court shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf5273-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> order that he be conditionally discharged under a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment that has been prepared for him, that has been certified to the court as appropriate by the director of the facility in which he is committed, and that has been found by the court to be appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf5274-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> order, as an explicit condition of release, that he comply with the prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The court at any time may, after a hearing employing the same criteria, modify or eliminate the regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5275-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revocation of Conditional Discharge</inline>.—</heading><content>The director of a medical facility responsible for administering a regimen imposed on an acquitted person conditionally discharged under subsection (f) shall notify the Attorney General and the court having jurisdiction over the person of any failure of the person to comply with the regimen. Upon such notice, or upon other probable cause to believe that the person has failed to comply with the prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment, the person may be arrested, and, upon arrest, shall be taken without unnecessary delay before the court having jurisdiction over him. The court shall, after a hearing, determine whether the person should be remanded to a suitable facility on the ground that, in light of his failure to comply with the prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological care or treatment, his continued release would create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf5276-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Furloughs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual who is hospitalized under subsection (e) of this section after being found not guilty only by reason of insanity of an offense for which subsection (d) of this section creates a burden of proof of clear and convincing evidence, may leave temporarily the premises of the facility in which that individual is hospitalized only—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5277-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with the approval of the committing court, upon notice to the attorney for the Government and such individual, and after opportunity for a hearing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5278-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in an emergency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5279-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> when accompanied by a Federal law enforcement officer (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s115">section 115 of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cf527a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Persons Found Not Guilty by Reason of Insanity in the District of Columbia.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf527b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer to custody of the attorney general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t24/s301/h">section 301(h) of title 24</ref> of the District of Columbia Code, and notwithstanding sub<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4247/j">section 4247(j) of this title</ref>, all persons who have been committed to a hospital for the mentally ill pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t24/s301/d/1">section 301(d)(1) of title 24</ref> of the District of Columbia Code, and for whom the United States has continuing financial responsibility, may be transferred to the custody of the Attorney General, who shall hospitalize the person for treatment in a suitable facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf527c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf527d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General may establish custody over such persons by filing an application in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, demonstrating that the person to be transferred is a person described in this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf527e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General shall, by any means reasonably designed to do so, provide written notice of the proposed transfer of custody to such person or such person’s guardian, legal representative, or other lawful agent. The person to be transferred shall be afforded an opportunity, not to exceed 15 days, to respond to the proposed transfer of custody, and may, at the court’s discretion, be afforded a hearing on the proposed transfer of custody. Such hearing, if granted, shall be limited to a determination of whether the constitutional rights of such person would be violated by the proposed transfer of custody.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf527f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Order</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon application of the Attorney General, the court shall order the person transferred to the custody of the Attorney General, unless, pursuant to a hearing under this paragraph, the court finds that the proposed transfer would violate a right of such person under the United States Constitution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cf5280-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9cf5281-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> create in any person a liberty interest in being granted a hearing or notice on any matter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9cf5282-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> create in favor of any person a cause of action against the United States or any officer or employee of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9cf5283-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> limit in any manner or degree the ability of the Attorney General to move, transfer, or otherwise manage any person committed to the custody of the Attorney General.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cf5284-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction with other sections</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsections (f) and (g) and section 4247 shall apply to any person transferred to the custody of the Attorney General pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9cf5285-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645">June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/855">62 Stat. 855</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s403/a">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2059">98 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7043">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7043</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4400">102 Stat. 4400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 104–294, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3494">110 Stat. 3494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9cf5286-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb9cf5287-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 878 (<ref href="/us/act/1930-05-13/ch254/s8">May 13, 1930, ch. 254, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/272">46 Stat. 272</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in translations and phraseology, and unnecessary words omitted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9cf5288-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9cf5289-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/294">Pub. L. 104–294</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> amended section generally, substituting “Hospitalization of a person found not guilty only by reason of insanity” for “Delivery to state authorities on expiration of sentence” in section catchline, and substituting provisions relating to determination of present mental condition of acquitted person, examination and report, hearing, etc., for provisions relating to duties of the superintendent of the United States hospital for defective delinquents regarding delivery to state authorities on expiration of sentence of any insane person.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9cf528a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idb9cf528b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Severability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/d">Pub. L. 104–294, title III, § 301(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3495">110 Stat. 3495</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/d">“If any provision of this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes below], an amendment made by this section, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section and the amendments made by this section shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb9cf528c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Records</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 104–294, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3495">110 Stat. 3495</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/b">
<inline>“Notwithstanding any provision of the District of Columbia Code or any other provision of law, the District of Columbia and St. Elizabeth’s Hospital—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>], shall provide to the Attorney General copies of all records in the custody or control of the District or the Hospital on such date of enactment pertaining to persons described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i">section 4243(i) of title 18</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 30 days after the creation of any records by employees, agents, or contractors of the District of Columbia or of St. Elizabeth’s Hospital pertaining to persons described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i">section 4243(i) of title 18</ref>, United States Code, provide to the Attorney General copies of all such records created after the date of enactment of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> shall not prevent or impede any employee, agent, or contractor of the District of Columbia or of St. Elizabeth’s Hospital who has obtained knowledge of the persons described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i">section 4243(i) of title 18</ref>, United States Code, in the employee’s professional capacity from providing that knowledge to the Attorney General, nor shall civil or criminal liability attach to such employees, agents, or contractors who provide such knowledge; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> shall not prevent or impede interviews of persons described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4243/i">section 4243(i) of title 18</ref>, United States Code, by representatives of the Attorney General, if such persons voluntarily consent to such interviews.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb9cf528d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification of Effect on Certain Testimonial Privileges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/c">Pub. L. 104–294, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3495">110 Stat. 3495</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/294/tIII/s301/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes above] shall not be construed to affect in any manner any doctor-patient or psychotherapist-patient testimonial privilege that may be otherwise applicable to persons found not guilty by reason of insanity and affected by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
