<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9d1c3ba-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247"><num value="4247">§ 4247.</num><heading> General provisions for chapter</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3bb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3bc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “rehabilitation program” includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3bd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> basic educational training that will assist the individual in understanding the society to which he will return and that will assist him in understanding the magnitude of his offense and its impact on society;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3be-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> vocational training that will assist the individual in contributing to, and in participating in, the society to which he will return;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3bf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> drug, alcohol, and sex offender treatment programs, and other treatment programs that will assist the individual in overcoming a psychological or physical dependence or any condition that makes the individual dangerous to others; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3c0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> organized physical sports and recreation programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “suitable facility” means a facility that is suitable to provide care or treatment given the nature of the offense and the characteristics of the defendant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “State” includes the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “bodily injury” includes sexual abuse;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “sexually dangerous person” means a person who has engaged or attempted to engage in sexually violent conduct or child molestation and who is sexually dangerous to others; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> “sexually dangerous to others” with respect <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002285">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002285"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “to”.</note> a person, means that the person suffers from a serious mental illness, abnormality, or disorder as a result of which he would have serious difficulty in refraining from sexually violent conduct or child molestation if released.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3c6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Psychiatric or Psychological Examination</inline>.—</heading><content>A psychiatric or psychological examination ordered pursuant to this chapter shall be conducted by a licensed or certified psychiatrist or psychologist, or, if the court finds it appropriate, by more than one such examiner. Each examiner shall be designated by the court, except that if the examination is ordered under section 4245, 4246, or 4248, upon the request of the defendant an additional examiner may be selected by the defendant. For the purposes of an examination pursuant to an order under section 4241, 4244, or 4245, the court may commit the person to be examined for a reasonable period, but not to exceed thirty days, and under section 4242, 4243, 4246, or 4248, for a reasonable period, but not to exceed forty-five days, to the custody of the Attorney General for placement in a suitable facility. Unless impracticable, the psychiatric or psychological examination shall be conducted in the suitable facility closest to the court. The director of the facility may apply for a reasonable extension, but not to exceed fifteen days under section 4241, 4244, or 4245, and not to exceed thirty days under section 4242, 4243, 4246, or 4248, upon a showing of good cause that the additional time is necessary to observe and evaluate the defendant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3c7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Psychiatric or Psychological Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A psychiatric or psychological report ordered pursuant to this chapter shall be prepared by the examiner designated to conduct the psychiatric or psychological examination, shall be filed with the court with copies provided to the counsel for the person examined and to the attorney for the Government, and shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the person’s history and present symptoms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3c9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of the psychiatric, psychological, and medical tests that were employed and their results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3ca-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the examiner’s findings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3cb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> the examiner’s opinions as to diagnosis, prognosis, and—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3cc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if the examination is ordered under section 4241, whether the person is suffering from a mental disease or defect rendering him mentally incompetent to the extent that he is unable to understand the nature and consequences of the proceedings against him or to assist properly in his defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3cd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the examination is ordered under section 4242, whether the person was insane at the time of the offense charged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3ce-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if the examination is ordered under section 4243 or 4246, whether the person is suffering from a mental disease or defect as a result of which his release would create a substantial risk of bodily injury to another person or serious damage to property of another;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3cf-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> if the examination is ordered under section 4248, whether the person is a sexually dangerous person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3d0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> if the examination is ordered under section 4244 or 4245, whether the person is suffering from a mental disease or defect as a result of which he is in need of custody for care or treatment in a suitable facility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9d1c3d1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/c/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> if the examination is ordered as a part of a presentence investigation, any recommendation the examiner may have as to how the mental condition of the defendant should affect the sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hearing</inline>.—</heading><content>At a hearing ordered pursuant to this chapter the person whose mental condition is the subject of the hearing shall be represented by counsel and, if he is financially unable to obtain adequate representation, counsel shall be appointed for him pursuant to section 3006A. The person shall be afforded an opportunity to testify, to present evidence, to subpoena witnesses on his behalf, and to confront and cross-examine witnesses who appear at the hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Periodic Report and Information Requirements</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The director of the facility in which a person is committed pursuant to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3d5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> section 4241 shall prepare semiannual reports; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3d6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> section 4243, 4244, 4245, 4246, or 4248 shall prepare annual reports concerning the mental condition of the person and containing recommendations concerning the need for his continued commitment. The reports shall be submitted to the court that ordered the person’s commitment to the facility and copies of the reports shall be submitted to such other persons as the court may direct. A copy of each such report concerning a person committed after the beginning of a prosecution of that person for violation of section 871, 879, or 1751 of this title shall be submitted to the Director of the United States Secret Service. Except with the prior approval of the court, the Secret Service shall not use or disclose the information in these copies for any purpose other than carrying out protective duties under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3056/a">section 3056(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The director of the facility in which a person is committed pursuant to section 4241, 4243, 4244, 4245, 4246, or 4248 shall inform such person of any rehabilitation programs that are available for persons committed in that facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Videotape Record</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon written request of defense counsel, the court may order a videotape record made of the defendant’s testimony or interview upon which the periodic report is based pursuant to subsection (e). Such videotape record shall be submitted to the court along with the periodic report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3d9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Habeas Corpus Unimpaired</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing contained in section 4243, 4246, or 4248 precludes a person who is committed under either of such sections from establishing by writ of habeas corpus the illegality of his detention.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3da-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discharge</inline>.—</heading><content>Regardless of whether the director of the facility in which a person is committed has filed a certificate pursuant to the provisions of subsection (e) of section 4241, 4244, 4245, 4246, or 4248, or subsection (f) of section 4243, counsel for the person or his legal guardian may, at any time during such person’s commitment, file with the court that ordered the commitment a motion for a hearing to determine whether the person should be discharged from such facility, but no such motion may be filed within one hundred and eighty days of a court determination that the person should continue to be committed. A copy of the motion shall be sent to the director of the facility in which the person is committed and to the attorney for the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3db-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority and Responsibility of the Attorney General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Attorney General—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3dc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/i/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may contract with a State, a political subdivision, a locality, or a private agency for the confinement, hospitalization, care, or treatment of, or the provision of services to, a person committed to his custody pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3dd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/i/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may apply for the civil commitment, pursuant to State law, of a person committed to his custody pursuant to section 4243, 4246, or 4248;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3de-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/i/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall, before placing a person in a facility pursuant to the provisions of section 4241, 4243, 4244, 4245, 4246, or 4248, consider the suitability of the facility’s rehabilitation programs in meeting the needs of the person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9d1c3df-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/i/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall consult with the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services in the general implementation of the provisions of this chapter and in the establishment of standards for facilities used in the implementation of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9d1c3e0-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s4247/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> Sections 4241, 4242, 4243, and 4244 do not apply to a prosecution under an Act of Congress applicable exclusively to the District of Columbia or the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9d1c3e1-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/act/1949-09-07/ch535/s1">Sept. 7, 1949, ch. 535, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/687">63 Stat. 687</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s403/a">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2065">98 Stat. 2065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7044, 7047(a), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4400">102 Stat. 4400</ref>, 4401; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330003/d">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330003(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2141">108 Stat. 2141</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tXI/s11204/2">Pub. L. 105–33, title XI, § 11204(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/739">111 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/tIII/s302/3">Pub. L. 109–248, title III, § 302(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/619">120 Stat. 619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9d1c3e2-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9d1c3e3-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb9d1c3e4-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Acts of Congress applicable exclusively to the District of Columbia, referred to in subsec. (j), are classified generally to the District of Columbia Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Uniform Code of Military Justice, referred to in subsec. (j), is classified generally to chapter 47 (§ 801 et seq.) of Title 10, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9d1c3e5-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/A">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “, 4246, or 4248” for “, or 4246” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/C/i">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(C)(i)</ref>, amended subpar. (C) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (C) read as follows: “drug, alcohol, and other treatment programs that will assist the individual in overcoming his psychological or physical dependence; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/C/ii">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(C)(ii)</ref>–(iv), added pars. (4) to (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/D">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(D)</ref>, substituted “4245, 4246, or 4248” for “4245 or 4246”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(D) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/E">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(E)</ref>, added subpar. (D) and redesignated former subpars. (D) and (E) as (E) and (F), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/F">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(F)</ref>, substituted “committed” for “hospitalized” wherever appearing and “continued commitment” for “continued hospitalization” in par. (1)(B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/B">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “4243, 4246, or 4248” for “4243 or 4246”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/F">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(F)</ref>, substituted “committed” for “hospitalized” wherever appearing and “person’s commitment” for “person’s hospitalization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/248/s302/3/B">Pub. L. 109–248, § 302(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “4243, 4246, or 4248” for “4243 or 4246”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s11024/2/C">Pub. L. 105–33, § 11024(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s11024/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 11024(3)</ref>, substituted “Sections 4241, 4242, 4243, and 4244 do” for “This chapter does”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “subsection (e) of section 4241, 4244, 4245, or 4246, or subsection (f) of section 4243,” for “subsection (e) of section 4241, 4243, 4244, 4245, or 4246,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7047/a">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7047(a)</ref>, substituted “psychologist” for “clinical psychologist” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7044">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7044</ref>, inserted at end “A copy of each such report concerning a person hospitalized after the beginning of a prosecution of that person for violation of section 871, 879, or 1751 of this title shall be submitted to the Director of the United States Secret Service. Except with the prior approval of the court, the Secret Service shall not use or disclose the information in these copies for any purpose other than carrying out protective duties under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3056/a">section 3056(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> amended section generally, substituting “General provisions for chapter” for “Alternate procedure of expiration of sentence” in section catchline, and substituting provisions relating to definitions, examinations, reports, etc., as applicable to chapter, for provisions relating to powers and duties regarding alternate procedure on expiration of sentence of prisoner.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9d1c3e6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9d1c3e7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, except as otherwise provided in title XI of <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s11721">section 11721 of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4246">section 4246 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb9d1c3e8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of the functions, personnel, assets, and obligations of the United States Secret Service, including the functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 381, 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
