<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9d40df6-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s5034"><num value="5034">§ 5034.</num><heading> Duties of magistrate judge</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The magistrate judge shall insure that the juvenile is represented by counsel before proceeding with critical stages of the proceedings. Counsel shall be assigned to represent a juvenile when the juvenile and his parents, guardian, or custodian are financially unable to obtain adequate representation. In cases where the juvenile and his parents, guardian, or custodian are financially able to obtain adequate representation but have not retained counsel, the magistrate judge may assign counsel and order the payment of reasonable attorney’s fees or may direct the juvenile, his parents, guardian, or custodian to retain private counsel within a specified period of time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The magistrate judge may appoint a guardian ad litem if a parent or guardian of the juvenile is not present, or if the magistrate judge has reason to believe that the parents or guardian will not cooperate with the juvenile in preparing for trial, or that the interests of the parents or guardian and those of the juvenile are adverse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the juvenile has not been discharged before his initial appearance before the magistrate judge, the magistrate judge shall release the juvenile to his parents, guardian, custodian, or other responsible party (including, but not limited to, the director of a shelter-care facility) upon their promise to bring such juvenile before the appropriate court when requested by such court unless the magistrate judge determines, after hearing, at which the juvenile is represented by counsel, that the detention of such juvenile is required to secure his timely appearance before the appropriate court or to insure his safety or that of others.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb9d67df7-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645">June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/858">62 Stat. 858</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/428">Pub. L. 87–428</ref>, <date date="1962-03-31">Mar. 31, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/52">76 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/415/tV/s504">Pub. L. 93–415, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1135">88 Stat. 1135</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7045">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7045</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4400">102 Stat. 4400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5117">104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9d67df8-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb9d67df9-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 924 (<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-16/ch486/s4">June 16, 1938, ch. 486, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/765">52 Stat. 765</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “foster homes” were inserted to remove any doubt as to the authority to commit to such foster homes in accordance with past and present administrative practice.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reference to particular sections dealing with probation was omitted as unnecessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology and arrangement.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9d67dfa-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9d67dfb-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> substituted “facility) upon” for “facility upon” in last par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/415">Pub. L. 93–415</ref> amended section generally, substituting “Duties of magistrate”, for “Probation; commitment to custody of Attorney General; support” in section catchline, and substituting provisions relating to procedure before, and duties of, magistrate, for provisions relating to probation, commitment to custody of Attorney General, duties of Attorney General, and procedures aiding court in determining whether to place juvenile on probation or commit him to custody of Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/428">Pub. L. 87–428</ref> added fourth par. authorizing commitment of a juvenile delinquent to the custody of the Attorney General for observation and study.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9d67dfc-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb9d67dfd-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “magistrate judge” substituted for “magistrate” in catchline and wherever appearing in text pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/s321">section 321 of Pub. L. 101–650</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s631">section 631 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="idb9d67dfe-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/415/tV/s504">Pub. L. 93–415, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1135">88 Stat. 1135</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 115–385, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5152">132 Stat. 5152</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
