<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8d2a374-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s555"><num value="555">§ 555.</num><heading> Border tunnels and passages</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8d2a375-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s555/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any person who knowingly constructs or finances the construction of a tunnel or subterranean passage that crosses the international border between the United States and another country, other than a lawfully authorized tunnel or passage known to the Secretary of Homeland Security and subject to inspection by Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for not more than 20 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8d2a376-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s555/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any person who knows or recklessly disregards the construction or use of a tunnel or passage described in subsection (a) on land that the person owns or controls shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for not more than 10 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8d2a377-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s555/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any person who uses a tunnel or passage described in subsection (a) to unlawfully smuggle an alien, goods (in violation of section 545), controlled substances, weapons of mass destruction (including biological weapons), or a member of a terrorist organization (as defined in section 2339B(g)(6)) shall be subject to a maximum term of imprisonment that is twice the maximum term of imprisonment that would have otherwise been applicable had the unlawful activity not made use of such a tunnel or passage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8d2a378-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s555/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Any person who attempts or conspires to commit any offense under subsection (a) or subsection (c) of this section shall be subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8d2a379-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tV/s551/a">Pub. L. 109–295, title V, § 551(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1389">120 Stat. 1389</ref>, § 554; renumbered § 555, <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dE/tV/s553/a/1">Pub. L. 110–161, div. E, title V, § 553(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2082">121 Stat. 2082</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/127/s3">Pub. L. 112–127, § 3</ref>, <date date="2012-06-05">June 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/371">126 Stat. 371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8d2a37a-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8d2a37b-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8d2a37c-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/127">Pub. L. 112–127</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—<ref href="/us/pl/110/161">Pub. L. 110–161</ref> renumbered section 554, relating to border tunnels and passages, as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8d2a37d-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8d2a37e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/127/s2">Pub. L. 112–127, § 2</ref>, <date date="2012-06-05">June 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/370">126 Stat. 370</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/127/s2">
<inline>“Congress finds the following:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Trafficking and smuggling organizations are intensifying their efforts to enter the United States through tunnels and other subterranean passages between Mexico and the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Border tunnels are most often used to transport narcotics from Mexico to the United States, but can also be used to transport people and other contraband.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> From Fiscal Year 1990 to Fiscal Year 2011, law enforcement authorities discovered 149 cross-border tunnels along the border between Mexico and the United States, 139 of which have been discovered since Fiscal Year 2001. There has been a dramatic increase in the number of cross-border tunnels discovered in Arizona and California since Fiscal Year 2006, with 40 tunnels discovered in California and 74 tunnels discovered in Arizona.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> Section 551 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/295">Public Law 109–295</ref>) added a new section to title 18, United States Code (<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s555">18 U.S.C. 555</ref>), which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> criminalizes the construction or financing of an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage across an international border into the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> prohibits any person from recklessly permitting others to construct or use an unauthorized tunnel or subterranean passage on the person’s land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Any person convicted of using a tunnel or subterranean passage to smuggle aliens, weapons, drugs, terrorists, or illegal goods is subject to an enhanced sentence for the underlying offense. Additional sentence enhancements would further deter tunnel activities and increase prosecutorial options.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
