<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8e3452e-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8" identifier="/us/usc/t18/s836"><num value="836">§ 836.</num><heading> Transportation of fireworks into State prohibiting sale or use</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever, otherwise than in the course of continuous interstate transportation through any State, transports fireworks into any State, or delivers them for transportation into any State, or attempts so to do, knowing that such fireworks are to be delivered, possessed, stored, transshipped, distributed, sold, or otherwise dealt with in a manner or for a use prohibited by the laws of such State specifically prohibiting or regulating the use of fireworks, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to a common or contract carrier or to international or domestic water carriers engaged in interstate commerce or to the transportation of fireworks into a State for the use of Federal agencies in the carrying out or the furtherance of their operations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the enforcement of this section, the definitions of fireworks contained in the laws of the respective States shall be applied.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “State” includes the several States, Territories, and possessions of the United States, and the District of Columbia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall be effective from and after <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb8e3452f-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">(Added <ref href="/us/act/1954-06-04/ch261/s1">June 4, 1954, ch. 261, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/170">68 Stat. 170</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330016/1/H">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(H)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2147">108 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8e34530-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8e34531-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8e34532-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $1,000” in first par.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8e34533-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8e34534-47c4-11f1-9a61-b1559996dfe8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fireworks for Agricultural Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-06-04/ch261/s3">Act June 4, 1954, ch. 261, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/171">68 Stat. 171</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-06-04/ch261/s3">
<inline>“This Act [enacting this section] shall not be effective with respect to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the transportation of fireworks into any State or Territory for use solely for agricultural purposes,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the delivery of fireworks for transportation into any State or Territory for use solely for agricultural purposes, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any attempt to engage in any such transportation or delivery for use solely for agricultural purposes, until sixty days have elapsed after the commencement of the next regular session of the legislature of such State or Territory which begins after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1954-06-04">June 4, 1954</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
