<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14bc9f8d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037"><num value="1037">§ 1037.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f8e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f8f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No person shall buy, sell, or transport, or offer to buy or sell, or offer or receive for transportation, in any business in commerce any restricted eggs, capable of use as human food, except as authorized by regulations of the Secretary under such conditions as he may prescribe to assure that only eggs fit for human food are used for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f90-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No egg handler shall possess with intent to use, or use, any restricted eggs in the preparation of human food for commerce except that such eggs may be so possessed and used when authorized by regulations of the Secretary under such conditions as he may prescribe to assure that only eggs fit for human food are used for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f91-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f92-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No person shall process any egg products for commerce at any plant except in compliance with the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f93-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No person shall buy, sell, or transport, or offer to buy or sell, or offer or receive for transportation, in commerce any egg products required to be inspected under this chapter unless they have been so inspected and are labeled and packaged in accordance with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1036">section 1036 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f94-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No operator of any official plant shall fail to comply with any requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1035/a">section 1035(a) of this title</ref> or the regulations thereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f95-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> No operator of any official plant shall allow any egg products to be moved from such plant if they are adulterated or misbranded and capable of use as human food.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f96-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> No egg handler shall possess any eggs after the eggs have been packed into a container that is destined for the ultimate consumer unless the eggs are stored and transported under refrigeration at an ambient temperature of no greater than 45 degrees Fahrenheit, as prescribed by rules and regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f97-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> No person shall violate any provision of section 1039, 1040 or 1046 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9f98-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> No person shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f99-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> manufacture, cast, print, lithograph, or otherwise make any device containing any official mark or simulation thereof, or any label bearing any such mark or simulation, or any form of official certificate or simulation thereof, except as authorized by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> forge or alter any official device, mark, or certificate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> without authorization from the Secretary, use any official device, mark, or certificate, or simulation thereof, or detach, deface, or destroy any official device or mark; or use any labeling or container ordered to be withheld from use under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1036">section 1036 of this title</ref> after final judicial affirmance of such order or expiration of the time for appeal if no appeal is taken under said section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> contrary to the regulations prescribed by the Secretary, fail to use, or to detach, deface, or destroy any official device, mark, or certificate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> knowingly possess, without promptly notifying the Secretary or his representative, any official device or any counterfeit, simulated, forged, or improperly altered official certificate or any device or label, or any eggs or egg products bearing any counterfeit, simulated, forged, or improperly altered official mark;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> knowingly make any false statement in any shipper’s certificate or other nonofficial or official certificate provided for in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9f9f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> knowingly represent that any article has been inspected or exempted, under this chapter, when, in fact, it has, respectively, not been so inspected or exempted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bc9fa0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> refuse access, at any reasonable time, to any representative of the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to any plant or other place of business subject to inspection under any provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14bc9fa1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1037/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> No person, while an official or employee of the United States Government or any State or local governmental agency, or thereafter, shall use to his own advantage, or reveal other than to the authorized representatives of the United States Government or any State or other government in their official capacity, or as ordered by a court in a judicial proceeding, any information acquired under the authority of this chapter concerning any matter which is entitled to protection as a trade secret.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14bc9fa2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/597/s8">Pub. L. 91–597, § 8</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1626">84 Stat. 1626</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1012/c">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1012(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1899">105 Stat. 1899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14bc9fa3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14bc9fa4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14bc9fa5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1), (2), (e)(7), (8), and (f), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/597">Pub. L. 91–597</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1620">84 Stat. 1620</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id14bc9fa6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsecs. (c) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) to (e) as (d) to (f), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14bc9fa7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id14bc9fa8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsec. (e)(8) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14bc9fa9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> effective 12 months after promulgation of final implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s1012/h">section 1012(h) of Pub. L. 102–237</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1034">section 1034 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id14bc9faa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/597/s29">section 29 of Pub. L. 91–597</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
