<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14bc9fb2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1039"><num value="1039">§ 1039.</num><heading> Eggs and egg products not intended for use as human food; inspection; denaturing or otherwise identifying</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Inspection shall not be provided under this chapter at any plant for the processing of any egg products which are not intended for use as human food, but such articles, prior to their offer for sale or transportation in commerce, shall be denatured or otherwise identified as prescribed by regulations of the Secretary to deter their use for human food. No person shall buy, sell, or transport or offer to buy or sell, or offer or receive for transportation, in commerce, any restricted eggs or egg products which are not intended for use as human food unless they are denatured or otherwise identified as required by the regulations of the Secretary.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id14bc9fb3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/597/s10">Pub. L. 91–597, § 10</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1627">84 Stat. 1627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14bc9fb4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14bc9fb5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14bc9fb6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/597">Pub. L. 91–597</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1620">84 Stat. 1620</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14bc9fb7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id14bc9fb8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/597/s29">section 29 of Pub. L. 91–597</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
