<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14bf108e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1102"><num value="1102">§ 1102.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of national policy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress declares that it is the policy of the United States and the purpose of this chapter to focus the comprehensive resources of the Federal Government and bring them to bear on drug abuse with the objective of significantly reducing the incidence, as well as the social and personal costs, of drug abuse in the United States, and to develop and assure the implementation of a comprehensive, coordinated long-term Federal strategy to combat drug abuse. To reach these goals, the Congress further declares that it is the policy of the United States and the purpose of this chapter to meet the problems of drug abuse through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bf108f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1102/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> comprehensive Federal, State, and local planning for, and effective use of, Federal assistance to States and to community-based programs to meet the urgent needs of special populations, in coordination with all other governmental and nongovernmental sources of assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bf1090-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1102/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the development and support of community-based prevention programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bf1091-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1102/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the development and encouragement of effective occupational prevention and treatment programs within the Government and in cooperation with the private sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14bf1092-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s1102/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> increased Federal commitment to research into the behavioral and biomedical etiology of, the treatment of, and the mental and physical health and social and economic consequences of, drug abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id14bf1093-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/255/tI/s102">Pub. L. 92–255, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1972-03-21">Mar. 21, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/66">86 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/237/s2">Pub. L. 94–237, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-03-19">Mar. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/241">90 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/181/s3">Pub. L. 96–181, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1309">93 Stat. 1309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14bf1094-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14bf1095-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14bf1096-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/92/255">Pub. L. 92–255</ref>, <date date="1972-03-21">Mar. 21, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/65">86 Stat. 65</ref>, known as the Drug Abuse Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act, which comprises this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id14bf1097-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/181">Pub. L. 96–181</ref> inserted additional declarations of policy prescribing methods and programs by which the goals are to be reached.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/237">Pub. L. 94–237</ref> substituted “objective of significantly reducing the incidence, as well as the social and personal costs, of drug abuse in the United States, and to develop and assure the implementation of” for “immediate objective of significantly reducing the incidence of drug abuse in the United States within the shortest possible period of time, and to develop”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
