<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id13ce4836-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347"><num value="347">§ 347.</num><heading> Intrastate sales of colored oleomargarine</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13ce4837-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Law governing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Colored oleomargarine or colored margarine which is sold in the same State or Territory in which it is produced shall be subject in the same manner and to the same extent to the provisions of this chapter as if it had been introduced in interstate commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13ce4838-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Labeling and packaging requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall sell, or offer for sale, colored oleomargarine or colored margarine unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13ce4839-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such oleomargarine or margarine is packaged,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13ce483a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the net weight of the contents of any package sold in a retail establishment is one pound or less,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13ce483b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> there appears on the label of the package (A) the word “oleomargarine” or “margarine” in type or lettering at least as large as any other type or lettering on such label, and (B) a full and accurate statement of all the ingredients contained in such oleomargarine or margarine, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13ce483c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> each part of the contents of the package is contained in a wrapper which bears the word “oleomargarine” or “margarine” in type or lettering not smaller than 20-point type.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The requirements of this subsection shall be in addition to and not in lieu of any of the other requirements of this chapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13ce483d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sales in public eating places</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall possess in a form ready for serving colored oleomargarine or colored margarine at a public eating place unless a notice that oleomargarine or margarine is served is displayed prominently and conspicuously in such place and in such manner as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual being served in such eating place or is printed or is otherwise set forth on the menu in type or lettering not smaller than that normally used to designate the serving of other food items. No person shall serve colored oleomargarine or colored margarine at a public eating place, whether or not any charge is made therefor, unless (1) each separate serving bears or is accompanied by labeling identifying it as oleomargarine or margarine, or (2) each separate serving thereof is triangular in shape.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13ce483e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from labeling requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Colored oleomargarine or colored margarine when served with meals at a public eating place shall at the time of such service be exempt from the labeling requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s343">section 343 of this title</ref> (except paragraphs (a) and (f)) if it complies with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13ce483f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s347/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Color content of oleomargarine</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section colored oleomargarine or colored margarine is oleomargarine or margarine having a tint or shade containing more than one and six-tenths degrees of yellow, or of yellow and red collectively, but with an excess of yellow over red, measured in terms of Lovibond tintometer scale or its equivalent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id13ce4840-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s407">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 407</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1950-03-16/ch61/s3/c">Mar. 16, 1950, ch. 61, § 3(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/20">64 Stat. 20</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id13ce4841-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id13ce4842-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id13ce4843-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1950-03-16/ch61/s7">Act Mar. 16, 1950, ch. 61, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/22">64 Stat. 22</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1950-03-16/ch61/s7">“This Act [enacting this section and sections 347a and 347b of this title and amending sections 331 and 342 of this title and sections 45 and 55 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade] shall become effective on <date date="1950-07-01">July 1, 1950</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id13ce4844-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1950-03-16/ch61/s5">Act Mar. 16, 1950, ch. 61, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/22">64 Stat. 22</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1950-03-16/ch61/s5">“So much of the unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds (including funds available for the fiscal year ending <date date="1950-06-30">June 30, 1950</date>) for the use of the Bureau of Internal Revenue of the Treasury Department in the exercise of functions under the Oleomargarine Tax Act (26 U.S.C., § 2300, subchapter A) [now section 4591 et seq. of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code], as the Director of the Bureau of the Budget [now Director of the Office of Management and Budget] may determine, shall be transferred to the Federal Security Agency (Food and Drug Administration) [now the Department of Health and Human Services] for use in the enforcement of this Act [see Effective Date note above].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
