<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id13d302a2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b"><num value="350b">§ 350b.</num><heading> New dietary ingredients</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302a3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A dietary supplement which contains a new dietary ingredient shall be deemed adulterated under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s342/f">section 342(f) of this title</ref> unless it meets one of the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302a4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The dietary supplement contains only dietary ingredients which have been present in the food supply as an article used for food in a form in which the food has not been chemically altered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302a5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> There is a history of use or other evidence of safety establishing that the dietary ingredient when used under the conditions recommended or suggested in the labeling of the dietary supplement will reasonably be expected to be safe and, at least 75 days before being introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce, the manufacturer or distributor of the dietary ingredient or dietary supplement provides the Secretary with information, including any citation to published articles, which is the basis on which the manufacturer or distributor has concluded that a dietary supplement containing such dietary ingredient will reasonably be expected to be safe.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall keep confidential any information provided under paragraph (2) for 90 days following its receipt. After the expiration of such 90 days, the Secretary shall place such information on public display, except matters in the information which are trade secrets or otherwise confidential, commercial information.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302a6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person may file with the Secretary a petition proposing the issuance of an order prescribing the conditions under which a new dietary ingredient under its intended conditions of use will reasonably be expected to be safe. The Secretary shall make a decision on such petition within 180 days of the date the petition is filed with the Secretary. For purposes of chapter 7 of title 5, the decision of the Secretary shall be considered final agency action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302a7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302a8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that the information in a new dietary ingredient notification submitted under this section for an article purported to be a new dietary ingredient is inadequate to establish that a dietary supplement containing such article will reasonably be expected to be safe because the article may be, or may contain, an anabolic steroid or an analogue of an anabolic steroid, the Secretary shall notify the Drug Enforcement Administration of such determination. Such notification by the Secretary shall include, at a minimum, the name of the dietary supplement or article, the name of the person or persons who marketed the product or made the submission of information regarding the article to the Secretary under this section, and any contact information for such person or persons that the Secretary has.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302a9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id13d302aa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “anabolic steroid” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802/41">section 802(41) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id13d302ab-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “analogue of an anabolic steroid” means a substance whose chemical structure is substantially similar to the chemical structure of an anabolic steroid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302ac-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “New dietary ingredient” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “new dietary ingredient” means a dietary ingredient that was not marketed in the United States before <date date="1994-10-15">October 15, 1994</date> and does not include any dietary ingredient which was marketed in the United States before <date date="1994-10-15">October 15, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id13d302ad-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s413">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 413</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/417/s8">Pub. L. 103–417, § 8</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4331">108 Stat. 4331</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/353/tI/s113/a">Pub. L. 111–353, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3920">124 Stat. 3920</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id13d302ae-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id13d302af-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id13d302b0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id13d302b1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id13d302b2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/353/tI/s113/b">Pub. L. 111–353, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3921">124 Stat. 3921</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/353/tI/s113/b">“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>], the Secretary shall publish guidance that clarifies when a dietary supplement ingredient is a new dietary ingredient, when the manufacturer or distributor of a dietary ingredient or dietary supplement should provide the Secretary with information as described in section 413(a)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350b/a/2">21 U.S.C. 350b(a)(2)</ref>], the evidence needed to document the safety of new dietary ingredients, and appropriate methods for establishing the identify [sic] of a new dietary ingredient.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id13d302b3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref> to be construed to apply to certain alcohol-related facilities, to alter jurisdiction and authorities established under certain other Acts, or in a manner inconsistent with international agreements to which the United States is a party, see sections 2206, 2251, and 2252 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
