<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id13d302b4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c"><num value="350c">§ 350c.</num><heading> Maintenance and inspection of records</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302b5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Records inspection</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302b6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Adulterated food</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary has a reasonable belief that an article of food, and any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner, is adulterated and presents a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals, each person (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufactures, processes, packs, distributes, receives, holds, or imports such article shall, at the request of an officer or employee duly designated by the Secretary, permit such officer or employee, upon presentation of appropriate credentials and a written notice to such person, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, to have access to and copy all records relating to such article, and to any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner, that are needed to assist the Secretary in determining whether the food is adulterated and presents a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302b7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of or exposure to food of concern</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary believes that there is a reasonable probability that the use of or exposure to an article of food, and any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner, will cause serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals, each person (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufactures, processes, packs, distributes, receives, holds, or imports such article shall, at the request of an officer or employee duly designated by the Secretary, permit such officer or employee, upon presentation of appropriate credentials and a written notice to such person, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, to have access to and copy all records relating to such article and to any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner, that are needed to assist the Secretary in determining whether there is a reasonable probability that the use of or exposure to the food will cause serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302b8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirement under paragraphs (1) and (2) applies to all records relating to the manufacture, processing, packing, distribution, receipt, holding, or importation of such article maintained by or on behalf of such person in any format (including paper and electronic formats) and at any location.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302b9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations concerning recordkeeping</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation and coordination, as appropriate, with other Federal departments and agencies with responsibilities for regulating food safety, may by regulation establish requirements regarding the establishment and maintenance, for not longer than two years, of records by persons (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufacture, process, pack, transport, distribute, receive, hold, or import food, which records are needed by the Secretary for inspection to allow the Secretary to identify the immediate previous sources and the immediate subsequent recipients of food, including its packaging, in order to address credible threats of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals. The Secretary shall take into account the size of a business in promulgating regulations under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302ba-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of sensitive information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall take appropriate measures to ensure that there are in effect effective procedures to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of any trade secret or confidential information that is obtained by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id13d302bb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not be construed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302bc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to limit the authority of the Secretary to inspect records or to require establishment and maintenance of records under any other provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302bd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to authorize the Secretary to impose any requirements with respect to a food to the extent that it is within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s601">21 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.), the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">21 U.S.C. 451</ref> et seq.), or the Egg Products Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">21 U.S.C. 1031</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302be-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to have any legal effect on <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id13d302bf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to extend to recipes for food, financial data, pricing data, personnel data, research data, or sales data (other than shipment data regarding sales).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id13d302c0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s414">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 414</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tIII/s306/a">Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 306(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/669">116 Stat. 669</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/353/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 111–353, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3886">124 Stat. 3886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id13d302c1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id13d302c2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id13d302c3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Meat Inspection Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is titles I to V of <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">act Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/201">Pub. L. 90–201</ref>, <date date="1967-12-15">Dec. 15, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/584">81 Stat. 584</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/tXI/s11015/a">Pub. L. 110–246, title XI, § 11015(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2124">122 Stat. 2124</ref>, which are classified generally to subchapters I to IV–A (§ 601 et seq.) of chapter 12 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s601">section 601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Poultry Products Inspection Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/172">Pub. L. 85–172</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/441">71 Stat. 441</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 10 (§ 451 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">section 451 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Egg Products Inspection Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/597">Pub. L. 91–597</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1620">84 Stat. 1620</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 1031 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id13d302c4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref> reenacted heading without change, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted heading, substituted “If the Secretary has a reasonable belief that an article of food, and any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner, is” for “If the Secretary has a reasonable belief that an article of food is”, inserted “, and to any other article of food that the Secretary reasonably believes is likely to be affected in a similar manner,” after “relating to such article”, struck out at end “The requirement under the preceding sentence applies to all records relating to the manufacture, processing, packing, distribution, receipt, holding, or importation of such article maintained by or on behalf of such person in any format (including paper and electronic formats) and at any location.”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id13d302c5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id13d302c6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expedited Rulemaking</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tIII/s306/d">Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 306(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/670">116 Stat. 670</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/188/tIII/s306/d">“Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>], the Secretary shall promulgate proposed and final regulations establishing recordkeeping requirements under subsection 414(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/b">21 U.S.C. 350c(b)</ref>] (as added by subsection (a)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id13d302c7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref> to be construed to apply to certain alcohol-related facilities, to alter jurisdiction and authorities established under certain other Acts, or in a manner inconsistent with international agreements to which the United States is a party, see sections 2206, 2251, and 2252 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
