<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14050ff8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k"><num value="356k">§ 356k.</num><heading> Platform technologies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14050ff9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program for the designation of platform technologies that meet the criteria described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14050ffa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A platform technology incorporated within or utilized by a drug or biological product is eligible for designation as a designated platform technology under this section if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14050ffb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the platform technology is incorporated in, or utilized by, a drug approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355">section 355 of this title</ref> or a biological product licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">42 U.S.C. 262</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14050ffc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> preliminary evidence submitted by the sponsor of the approved or licensed drug described in paragraph (1), or a sponsor that has been granted a right of reference to data submitted in the application for such drug, demonstrates that the platform technology has the potential to be incorporated in, or utilized by, more than one drug without an adverse effect on quality, manufacturing, or safety; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14077ffd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> data or information submitted by the applicable person under paragraph (2) indicates that incorporation or utilization of the platform technology has a reasonable likelihood to bring significant efficiencies to the drug development or manufacturing process and to the review process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14077ffe-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Request for designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person may request the Secretary designate a platform technology as a designated platform technology concurrently with, or at any time after, submission under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/i">section 355(i) of this title</ref> or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a/3">42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)</ref>] for the investigation of a drug that incorporates or utilizes the platform technology that is the subject of the request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14077fff-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14078000-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 calendar days after the receipt of a request under subsection (c), the Secretary shall determine whether the platform technology that is the subject of the request meets the criteria described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14078001-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that the platform technology meets the criteria described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall designate the platform technology as a designated platform technology and may expedite the development and review of any subsequent application submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</ref>] for a drug that uses or incorporates the platform technology pursuant to subsection (e), as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14078002-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination not to designate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that the platform technology does not meet the criteria under subsection (b), the Secretary shall include with the determination not to designate the technology a written description of the rationale for such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14078003-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation of designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may revoke a designation made under paragraph (2), if the Secretary determines that the designated platform technology no longer meets the criteria described in subsection (b). The Secretary shall communicate the determination to revoke a designation to the requesting sponsor in writing, including a description of the rationale for such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14078004-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall prevent a product that uses or incorporates a designated platform technology from being eligible for expedited approval pathways if it is otherwise eligible under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14078005-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may take actions to expedite the development and review of an application for a drug that incorporates or utilizes a designated platform technology, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078006-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> engaging in early interactions with the sponsor to discuss the use of the designated platform technology and what is known about such technology, including data previously submitted that is relevant to establishing, as applicable, safety or efficacy under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or safety, purity, or potency under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078007-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing timely advice to, and interactive communication with, the sponsor regarding the development of the drug that proposes to use the designated platform technology to ensure that the development program designed to gather data necessary for approval or licensure is as efficient as practicable, which may include holding meetings with the sponsor and the review team throughout the development of the drug; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078008-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> considering inspectional findings, including prior findings, related to the manufacture of a drug that incorporates or utilizes the designated platform technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14078009-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Leveraging data from designated platform technologies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, consistent with applicable standards for approval, authorization, or licensure under this chapter and section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</ref>], allow the sponsor of an application under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act or a request for emergency use authorization under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb–3">section 360bbb–3 of this title</ref>, in order to support approval, licensure, or authorization, to reference or rely upon data and information within an application or request for a drug or biological product that incorporates or utilizes the same platform technology designated under subsection (d), provided that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1407800a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such data and information was submitted by the same sponsor, pursuant to the application for the drug with respect to which designation of the designated platform technology under subsection (d) was granted; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1407800b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the sponsor relying on such data and information received a right of reference to such data and information from the sponsor described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1407800c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Changes to a designated platform technology</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A sponsor of more than one application approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</ref>] for drugs that incorporate or utilize a designated platform technology may submit a single supplemental application for proposed changes to the designated platform technology that may be applicable to more than one such drug that incorporates or utilizes the same designated platform technology. Such supplemental application may cross-reference data and information submitted in other applications and may include one or more comparability protocols regarding how such changes to the platform technology would be made for each applicable drug or biological product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1407800d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1407800e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “platform technology” means a well-understood and reproducible technology, which may include a nucleic acid sequence, molecular structure, mechanism of action, delivery method, vector, or a combination of any such technologies that the Secretary determines to be appropriate, that the sponsor demonstrates—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id1407800f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is incorporated in or utilized by a drug or biological product and is essential to the structure or function of such drug or biological product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14078010-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> can be adapted for, incorporated into, or utilized by, more than one drug or biological product sharing common structural elements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14078011-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> facilitates the manufacture or development of more than one drug or biological product through a standardized production or manufacturing process or processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078012-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “designated platform technology” means a platform technology that is designated as a platform technology under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14078013-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078014-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> alter the authority of the Secretary to approve drugs pursuant to section 505 of this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355">21 U.S.C. 355</ref>] or license biological products pursuant to section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">42 U.S.C. 262</ref>], including standards of evidence and applicable conditions for approval or licensure under the applicable Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14078015-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s356k/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> confer any new rights with respect to the permissibility of a sponsor of an application for a drug product or biological product referencing information contained in another application submitted by the holder of an approved application under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/c">section 355(c) of this title</ref> or of a license under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262/a">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14078016-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s506K">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 506K</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2503/a">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2503(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5798">136 Stat. 5798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14078017-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14078018-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14078019-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(5), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6A (§ 201 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1407801a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id1407801b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2503/b">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2503(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5801">136 Stat. 5801</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2503/b">“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) shall issue draft guidance on the implementation of this section. Such guidance shall include examples of drugs that can be manufactured using platform technologies, including drugs that contain or consist of vectors and nucleic acids, information about the Secretary’s review of platform technologies, information regarding submitting for designation, considerations for persons submitting a request for designation who have been granted a right of reference, the implementation of the designated platform technology designation program, efficiencies that may be achieved in the development and review of products that incorporate or utilize designated platform technologies, and recommendations and requirements for making and reporting manufacturing changes to a designated platform technology in accordance with section 506K(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356k/g">21 U.S.C. 356k(g)</ref>] (as added by subsection (a)) and section 506A of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356a">21 U.S.C. 356a</ref>), as applicable.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
