<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14267a69-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb"><num value="360bb">§ 360bb.</num><heading> Designation of drugs for rare diseases or conditions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14267a6a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Request by sponsor; preconditions; “rare disease or condition” defined</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14267a6b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The manufacturer or the sponsor of a drug may request the Secretary to designate the drug as a drug for a rare disease or condition. A request for designation of a drug shall be made before the submission of an application under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> for the drug, or the submission of an application for licensing of the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>. If the Secretary finds that a drug for which a request is submitted under this subsection is being or will be investigated for a rare disease or condition and—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14267a6c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if an application for such drug is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355">section 355 of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14267a6d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if a license for such drug is issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the approval, certification, or license would be for use for such disease or condition, the Secretary shall designate the drug as a drug for such disease or condition. A request for a designation of a drug under this subsection shall contain the consent of the applicant to notice being given by the Secretary under subsection (b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002077">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002077"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> respecting the designation of the drug.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14267a6e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “rare disease or condition” means any disease or condition which (A) affects less than 200,000 persons in the United States, or (B) affects more than 200,000 in the United States and for which there is no reasonable expectation that the cost of developing and making available in the United States a drug for such disease or condition will be recovered from sales in the United States of such drug. Determinations under the preceding sentence with respect to any drug shall be made on the basis of the facts and circumstances as of the date the request for designation of the drug under this subsection is made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14267a6f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of discontinuance of drug or application as condition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A designation of a drug under subsection (a) shall be subject to the condition that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14267a70-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if an application was approved for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or a license was issued for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>, the manufacturer of the drug will notify the Secretary of any discontinuance of the production of the drug at least one year before discontinuance, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14267a71-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if an application has not been approved for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or a license has not been issued for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref> and if preclinical investigations or investigations under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/i">section 355(i) of this title</ref> are being conducted with the drug, the manufacturer or sponsor of the drug will notify the Secretary of any decision to discontinue active pursuit of approval of an application under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> or approval of a license under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14267a72-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notice respecting the designation of a drug under subsection (a) shall be made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14267a73-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bb/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation promulgate procedures for the implementation of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14267a74-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s526">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 526</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/414/s2/a">Pub. L. 97–414, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2050">96 Stat. 2050</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/551/s4/a">Pub. L. 98–551, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2817">98 Stat. 2817</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/91/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 99–91, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/387">99 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/290/s2">Pub. L. 100–290, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-04-18">Apr. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/90">102 Stat. 90</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/tI/s125/b/2/H">Pub. L. 105–115, title I, § 125(b)(2)(H)</ref>, (I), <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2326">111 Stat. 2326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14267a75-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14267a76-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14267a77-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b), referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was redesignated as subsec. (c) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/100/290/s2/b">Pub. L. 100–290, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-18">Apr. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/90">102 Stat. 90</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id14267a78-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s125/b/2/H">Pub. L. 105–115, § 125(b)(2)(H)</ref>, struck out “the submission of an application for certification of the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>,” before “or the submission of an application for licensing of the drug” in introductory provisions, inserted “or” at end of subpar. (A), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B), and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “if a certification for such drug is issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>, or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s125/b/2/I/i">Pub. L. 105–115, § 125(b)(2)(I)(i)</ref>, struck out “, a certificate was issued for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>,” before “or a license was issued”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s125/b/2/I/ii">Pub. L. 105–115, § 125(b)(2)(I)(ii)</ref>, struck out “, a certificate has not been issued for the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>,” before “or a license has not been issued” and “, approval of an application for certification under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>,” before “or approval of a license”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/290/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–290, § 2(a)</ref>, inserted after first sentence “A request for designation of a drug shall be made before the submission of an application under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/b">section 355(b) of this title</ref> for the drug, the submission of an application for certification of the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s357">section 357 of this title</ref>, or the submission of an application for licensing of the drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/290/s2/b">Pub. L. 100–290, § 2(b)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsecs. (b) and (c) as (c) and (d), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/91">Pub. L. 99–91</ref> struck out “or” at end of subpar. (A), struck out subpar. (B) and substituted subpars. (B) and (C), and inserted “, certification,” after “approval”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/551">Pub. L. 98–551</ref> substituted “which (A) affects less than 200,000 persons in the United States, or (B) affects more than 200,000 in the United States and for which” for “which occurs so infrequently in the United States that”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14267a79-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14267a7a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/91">Pub. L. 99–91</ref> effective <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/91/s8/b">section 8(b) of Pub. L. 99–91</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360aa">section 360aa of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
