<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id142ff037-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb–2"><num value="360bbb–2">§ 360bbb–2.</num><heading> Classification of products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142ff038-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Request</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person who submits an application or submission (including a petition, notification, and any other similar form of request) under this chapter for a product, may submit a request to the Secretary respecting the classification of the product as a drug, biological product, device, or a combination product subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s353/g">section 353(g) of this title</ref> or respecting the component of the Food and Drug Administration that will regulate the product. In submitting the request, the person shall recommend a classification for the product, or a component to regulate the product, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142ff039-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the receipt of the request described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall determine the classification of the product under subsection (a), or the component of the Food and Drug Administration that will regulate the product, and shall provide to the person a written statement that identifies such classification or such component, and the reasons for such determination. The Secretary may not modify such statement except with the written consent of the person, or for public health reasons based on scientific evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142ff03a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inaction of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary does not provide the statement within the 60-day period described in subsection (b), the recommendation made by the person under subsection (a) shall be considered to be a final determination by the Secretary of such classification of the product, or the component of the Food and Drug Administration that will regulate the product, as applicable, and may not be modified by the Secretary except with the written consent of the person, or for public health reasons based on scientific evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id142ff03b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s563">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 563</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/tIV/s416">Pub. L. 105–115, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2378">111 Stat. 2378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id142ff03c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id142ff03d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id142ff03e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s501">section 501 of Pub. L. 105–115</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1997 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
