<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id142b3585-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll"><num value="360ll">§ 360ll.</num><heading> Notification of defects in and repair or replacement of electronic products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b3586-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification; exemption</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id142b3587-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Every manufacturer of electronic products who discovers that an electronic product produced, assembled, or imported by him has a defect which relates to the safety of use of such product by reason of the emission of electronic product radiation, or that an electronic product produced, assembled, or imported by him on or after the effective date of an applicable standard prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360kk">section 360kk of this title</ref> fails to comply with such standard, shall immediately notify the Secretary of such defect or failure to comply if such product has left the place of manufacture and shall (except as authorized by paragraph (2)) with reasonable promptness furnish notification of such defect or failure to the persons (where known to the manufacturer) specified in subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id142b3588-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, in the opinion of such manufacturer, the defect or failure to comply is not such as to create a significant risk of injury, including genetic injury, to any person, he may, at the time of giving notice to the Secretary of such defect or failure to comply, apply to the Secretary for an exemption from the requirement of notice to the persons specified in subsection (b). If such application states reasonable grounds for such exemption, the Secretary shall afford such manufacturer an opportunity to present his views and evidence in support of the application, the burden of proof being on the manufacturer. If, after such presentation, the Secretary is satisfied that such defect or failure to comply is not such as to create a significant risk of injury, including genetic injury, to any person, he shall exempt such manufacturer from the requirement of notice to the persons specified in subsection (b) of this section and from the requirements of repair or replacement imposed by subsection (f) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b3589-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Method of notification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The notification (other than to the Secretary) required by paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section shall be accomplished—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id142b358a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by certified mail to the first purchaser of such product for purposes other than resale, and to any subsequent transferee of such product; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id142b358b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> by certified mail or other more expeditious means to the dealers or distributors of such manufacturer to whom such product was delivered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b358c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requisite elements of notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The notifications required by paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section shall contain a clear description of such defect or failure to comply with an applicable standard, an evaluation of the hazard reasonably related to such defect or failure to comply, and a statement of the measures to be taken to repair such defect. In the case of a notification to a person referred to in subsection (b) of this section, the notification shall also advise the person of his rights under subsection (f) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b358d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Copies to Secretary of communications by manufacturers to dealers or distributors regarding defects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every manufacturer of electronic products shall furnish to the Secretary a true or representative copy of all notices, bulletins, and other communications to the dealers or distributors of such manufacturer or to purchasers (or subsequent transferees) of electronic products of such manufacturer regarding any such defect in such product or any such failure to comply with a standard applicable to such product. The Secretary shall disclose to the public so much of the information contained in such notice or other information obtained under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360nn">section 360nn of this title</ref> as he deems will assist in carrying out the purposes of this part, but he shall not disclose any information which contains or relates to a trade secret or other matter referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref> unless he determines that it is necessary to carry out the purposes of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b358e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice from Secretary to manufacturer of defects or failure to comply with standards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If through testing, inspection, investigation, or research carried out pursuant to this part, or examination of reports submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360nn">section 360nn of this title</ref>, or otherwise, the Secretary determines that any electronic product—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id142b358f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> does not comply with an applicable standard prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360kk">section 360kk of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id142b3590-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> contains a defect which relates to the safety of use of such product by reason of the emission of electronic product radiation;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">he shall immediately notify the manufacturer of such product of such defect or failure to comply. The notice shall contain the findings of the Secretary and shall include all information upon which the findings are based. The Secretary shall afford such manufacturer an opportunity to present his views and evidence in support thereof, to establish that there is no failure of compliance or that the alleged defect does not exist or does not relate to safety of use of the product by reason of the emission of such radiation hazard. If after such presentation by the manufacturer the Secretary determines that such product does not comply with an applicable standard prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360kk">section 360kk of this title</ref>, or that it contains a defect which relates to the safety of use of such product by reason of the emission of electronic product radiation, the Secretary shall direct the manufacturer to furnish the notification specified in subsection (c) of this section to the persons specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) of this section (where known to the manufacturer), unless the manufacturer has applied for an exemption from the requirement of such notification on the ground specified in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) and the Secretary is satisfied that such noncompliance or defect is not such as to create a significant risk of injury, including genetic injury, to any person.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b3591-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Correction of defects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any electronic product is found under subsection (a) or (e) to fail to comply with an applicable standard prescribed under this part or to have a defect which relates to the safety of use of such product, and the notification specified in subsection (c) is required to be furnished on account of such failure or defect, the manufacturer of such product shall (1) without charge, bring such product into conformity with such standard or remedy such defect and provide reimbursement for any expenses for transportation of such product incurred in connection with having such product brought into conformity or having such defect remedied, (2) replace such product with a like or equivalent product which complies with each applicable standard prescribed under this part and which has no defect relating to the safety of its use, or (3) make a refund of the cost of such product. The manufacturer shall take the action required by this subsection in such manner, and with respect to such persons, as the Secretary by regulations shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id142b3592-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s360ll/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any electronic product that was manufactured before <date date="1968-10-18">October 18, 1968</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id142b3593-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s535">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 535</ref>, formerly <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIII/s535">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 535</ref>, formerly § 359, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/602/s2/3">Pub. L. 90–602, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-18">Oct. 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1180">82 Stat. 1180</ref>; renumbered § 535 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/1/B">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(C), (3), (4), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4529">104 Stat. 4529</ref>, 4530; <ref href="/us/pl/103/80/s4/a/2">Pub. L. 103–80, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-13">Aug. 13, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/779">107 Stat. 779</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id142b3594-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id142b3595-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id142b3596-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s263g">section 263g of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to renumbering by <ref href="/us/pl/101/629">Pub. L. 101–629</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id142b3597-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/80">Pub. L. 103–80</ref> amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/4">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(4)</ref>, which renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s263g">section 263g of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/2/C/i">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “section 360kk” for “section 263f”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/1/B">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(C)(ii), substituted “section 360nn” for “section 263i” and “this part” for “this subpart” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/1/B">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(C), substituted “this part” for “this subpart” and “section 360nn” for “section 263i” in introductory provisions and “section 360kk” for “section 263f” in par. (1) and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/629/s19/a/1/B">Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “this part” for “this subpart” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id142b3598-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id142b3599-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Noninterference With Other Federal Agencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enactment of this section not to be construed to supersede or limit the functions under any other provision of law of any officer or agency of the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/602/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 90–602</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360hh">section 360hh of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
