<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1443036f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374"><num value="374">§ 374.</num><heading> Inspection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14430370-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Right of agents to enter; scope of inspection; notice; promptness; exclusions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430371-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of enforcement of this chapter, officers or employees duly designated by the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials and a written notice to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, are authorized (A) to enter, at reasonable times, any factory, warehouse, or establishment in which food, drugs, devices, tobacco products, or cosmetics are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, for introduction into interstate commerce or after such introduction, or to enter any vehicle being used to transport or hold such food, drugs, devices, tobacco products, or cosmetics in interstate commerce; and (B) to inspect, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, such factory, warehouse, establishment, or vehicle and all pertinent equipment, finished and unfinished materials, containers, and labeling therein. In the case of any person (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufactures, processes, packs, transports, distributes, holds, or imports foods, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c">section 350c of this title</ref>, when the standard for records inspection under paragraph (1) or (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a">section 350c(a) of this title</ref> applies, subject to the limitations established in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d">section 350c(d) of this title</ref>. In the case of a facility (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s364">section 364 of this title</ref>) that manufactures or processes cosmetic products, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in sections 364a, 364b, and 364f of this title, when the standard for records inspection under such section applies. In the case of any factory, warehouse, establishment, or consulting laboratory in which prescription drugs, nonprescription drugs intended for human use, devices, or tobacco products are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, the inspection shall extend to all things therein (including records, files, papers, processes, controls, and facilities) bearing on whether prescription drugs, nonprescription drugs intended for human use, devices, or tobacco products which are adulterated or misbranded within the meaning of this chapter, or which may not be manufactured, introduced into interstate commerce, or sold, or offered for sale by reason of any provision of this chapter, have been or are being manufactured, processed, packed, transported, or held in any such place, or otherwise bearing on violation of this chapter. No inspection authorized by the preceding sentence or by paragraph (3) shall extend to financial data, sales data other than shipment data, pricing data, personnel data (other than data as to qualification of technical and professional personnel performing functions subject to this chapter), and research data (other than data relating to new drugs, antibiotic drugs, devices, and tobacco products and subject to reporting and inspection under regulations lawfully issued pursuant to section 355(i) or (k) of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360i">section 360i of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360j/g">section 360j(g) of this title</ref>, or subchapter IX and data relating to other drugs, devices, or tobacco products which in the case of a new drug would be subject to reporting or inspection under lawful regulations issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/j">section 355(j) of this title</ref>). A separate notice shall be given for each such inspection, but a notice shall not be required for each entry made during the period covered by the inspection. Each such inspection shall be commenced and completed with reasonable promptness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430372-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The provisions of the third sentence of paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430373-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> pharmacies which maintain establishments in conformance with any applicable local laws regulating the practice of pharmacy and medicine and which are regularly engaged in dispensing prescription drugs or devices, upon prescriptions of practitioners licensed to administer such drugs or devices to patients under the care of such practitioners in the course of their professional practice, and which do not, either through a subsidiary or otherwise, manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process drugs or devices for sale other than in the regular course of their business of dispensing or selling drugs or devices at retail;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430374-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> practitioners licensed by law to prescribe or administer drugs, or prescribe or use devices, as the case may be, and who manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process drugs, or manufacture or process devices, solely for use in the course of their professional practice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430375-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> persons who manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process drugs or manufacture or process devices, solely for use in research, teaching, or chemical analysis and not for sale;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430376-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such other classes of persons as the Secretary may by regulation exempt from the application of this section upon a finding that inspection as applied to such classes of persons in accordance with this section is not necessary for the protection of the public health.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430377-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> An officer or employee making an inspection under paragraph (1) for purposes of enforcing the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350a">section 350a of this title</ref> applicable to infant formulas shall be permitted, at all reasonable times, to have access to and to copy and verify any records—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430378-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> bearing on whether the infant formula manufactured or held in the facility inspected meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350a">section 350a of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430379-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> required to be maintained under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350a">section 350a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any records or other information that the Secretary may inspect under this section from a person that owns or operates an establishment that is engaged in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or device, or a site or facility that is subject to inspection under paragraph (5)(C), shall, upon the request of the Secretary, be provided to the Secretary by such person, in advance of or in lieu of an inspection, within a reasonable timeframe, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner, and in either electronic or physical form, at the expense of such person. The Secretary’s request shall include a sufficient description of the records or other information requested and a rationale for requesting such records or other information in advance of, or in lieu of, an inspection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Upon receipt of the records requested under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide to the person confirmation of receipt.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary may rely on any records or other information that the Secretary may inspect under this section to satisfy requirements that may pertain to a preapproval or risk-based surveillance inspection, or to resolve deficiencies identified during such inspections, if applicable and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph supplants the authority of the Secretary to conduct inspections otherwise permitted under this chapter in order to ensure compliance with this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443037f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430380-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary may, to ensure the accuracy and reliability of studies and records or other information described in subparagraph (B) and to assess compliance with applicable requirements under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], enter sites and facilities specified in subparagraph (C) in order to inspect such records or other information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430381-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An inspection under this paragraph shall extend to all records and other information related to the studies and submissions described in subparagraph (E), including records and information related to the conduct, results, and analyses of, and the protection of human and animal trial participants participating in, such studies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430382-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430383-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The sites and facilities subject to inspection by the Secretary under this paragraph are those owned or operated by a person described in clause (ii) and which are (or were) utilized by such person in connection with—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430384-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> developing an application or other submission to the Secretary under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act related to marketing authorization for a product described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430385-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> preparing, conducting, or analyzing the results of a study described in subparagraph (E); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430386-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> holding any records or other information described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430387-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> A person described in this clause is—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430388-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the sponsor of an application or submission specified in subparagraph (E);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430389-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a person engaged in any activity described in clause (i) on behalf of such a sponsor, through a contract, grant, or other business arrangement with such sponsor;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1443038a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> an institutional review board, or other individual or entity, engaged by contract, grant, or other business arrangement with a nonsponsor in preparing, collecting, or analyzing records or other information described in subparagraph (B); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1443038b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> any person not otherwise described in this clause that conducts, or has conducted, a study described in subparagraph (E) yielding records or other information described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443038c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443038d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Subject to clause (ii), an entity that owns or operates any site or facility subject to inspection under this paragraph shall provide the Secretary with access to records and other information described in subparagraph (B) that is held by or under the control of such entity, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1443038e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> permitting the Secretary to record or copy such information for purposes of this paragraph;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1443038f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> providing the Secretary with access to any electronic information system utilized by such entity to hold, process, analyze, or transfer any records or other information described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430390-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> permitting the Secretary to inspect the facilities, equipment, written procedures, processes, and conditions through which records or other information described in subparagraph (B) is or was generated, held, processed, analyzed, or transferred.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430391-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Nothing in clause (i) shall negate, supersede, or otherwise affect the applicability of provisions, under this or any other Act, preventing or limiting the disclosure of confidential commercial information or other information considered proprietary or trade secret.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430392-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An inspection under this paragraph shall be conducted at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14430393-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The studies and submissions described in this subparagraph are each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430394-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Clinical and nonclinical studies submitted to the Secretary in support of, or otherwise related to, applications and other submissions to the Secretary under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act for marketing authorization of a product described in paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430395-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Postmarket safety activities conducted under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430396-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> Any other clinical investigation of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14430397-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a drug subject to section 355 or 360b of this title or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14430398-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a device subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360j/g">section 360j(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14430399-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Any other submissions made under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act with respect to which the Secretary determines an inspection under this paragraph is warranted in the interest of public health.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443039a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> This paragraph clarifies the authority of the Secretary to conduct inspections of the type described in this paragraph and shall not be construed as a basis for inferring that, prior to <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, the Secretary lacked the authority to conduct such inspections, including under this chapter or the Public Health Service Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1443039b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Written report to owner; copy to Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443039c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon completion of any such inspection of a factory, warehouse, consulting laboratory, or other establishment, and prior to leaving the premises, the officer or employee making the inspection shall give to the owner, operator, or agent in charge a report in writing setting forth any conditions or practices observed by him which, in his judgment, indicate that any food, drug, device, tobacco product, or cosmetic in such establishment (A) consists in whole or in part of any filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance, or (B) has been prepared, packed, or held under insanitary conditions whereby it may have become contaminated with filth, or whereby it may have been rendered injurious to health. A copy of such report shall be sent promptly to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1443039d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In carrying out this subsection with respect to any establishment manufacturing a drug approved under subsection (c) or (j) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355">section 355 of this title</ref> for which a notification has been submitted in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356c">section 356c of this title</ref> is, or has been in the last 5 years, listed on the drug shortage list under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356e">section 356e of this title</ref>, or that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/j/11/A">section 355(j)(11)(A) of this title</ref>, a copy of the report shall be sent promptly to the appropriate offices of the Food and Drug Administration with expertise regarding drug shortages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1443039e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Receipt for samples taken</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the officer or employee making any such inspection of a factory, warehouse, or other establishment has obtained any sample in the course of the inspection, upon completion of the inspection and prior to leaving the premises he shall give to the owner, operator, or agent in charge a receipt describing the samples obtained.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1443039f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Analysis of samples furnished owner</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever in the course of any such inspection of a factory or other establishment where food is manufactured, processed, or packed, the officer or employee making the inspection obtains a sample of any such food, and an analysis is made of such sample for the purpose of ascertaining whether such food consists in whole or in part of any filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance, or is otherwise unfit for food, a copy of the results of such analysis shall be furnished promptly to the owner, operator, or agent in charge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id144303a0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Accessibility of records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every person required under section 360i or 360j(g) of this title to maintain records and every person who is in charge or custody of such records shall, upon request of an officer or employee designated by the Secretary, permit such officer or employee at all reasonable times to have access to, and to copy and verify, such records.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id144303a1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303a2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An accredited person described in paragraph (3) shall maintain records documenting the training qualifications of the person and the employees of the person, the procedures used by the person for handling confidential information, the compensation arrangements made by the person, and the procedures used by the person to identify and avoid conflicts of interest. Upon the request of an officer or employee designated by the Secretary, the person shall permit the officer or employee, at all reasonable times, to have access to, to copy, and to verify, the records.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303a3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Within 15 days after the receipt of a written request from the Secretary to an accredited person described in paragraph (3) for copies of records described in paragraph (1), the person shall produce the copies of the records at the place designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303a4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2), an accredited person described in this paragraph is a person who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303a5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is accredited under subsection (g); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303a6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is accredited under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360m">section 360m of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id144303a7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspections by accredited persons</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303a8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall, subject to the provisions of this subsection, accredit persons for the purpose of conducting inspections of establishments that manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process class II or class III devices, which inspections are required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref> or are inspections of such establishments required to register under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>. The owner or operator of such an establishment that is eligible under paragraph (6) may, from the list published under paragraph (4), select an accredited person to conduct such inspections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303a9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register criteria to accredit or deny accreditation to persons who request to perform the duties specified in paragraph (1). Thereafter, the Secretary shall inform those requesting accreditation, within 60 days after the receipt of such request, whether the request for accreditation is adequate for review, and the Secretary shall promptly act on the request for accreditation. Any resulting accreditation shall state that such person is accredited to conduct inspections at device establishments identified in paragraph (1). The accreditation of such person shall specify the particular activities under this subsection for which such person is accredited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303aa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> An accredited person shall, at a minimum, meet the following requirements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303ab-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Such person may not be an employee of the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303ac-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such person shall be an independent organization which is not owned or controlled by a manufacturer, supplier, or vendor of articles regulated under this chapter and which has no organizational, material, or financial affiliation (including a consultative affiliation) with such a manufacturer, supplier, or vendor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303ad-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Such person shall be a legally constituted entity permitted to conduct the activities for which it seeks accreditation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303ae-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Such person shall not engage in the design, manufacture, promotion, or sale of articles regulated under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303af-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The operations of such person shall be in accordance with generally accepted professional and ethical business practices, and such person shall agree in writing that at a minimum the person will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144303b0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> certify that reported information accurately reflects data reviewed, inspection observations made, other matters that relate to or may influence compliance with this chapter, and recommendations made during an inspection or at an inspection’s closing meeting;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144303b1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> limit work to that for which competence and capacity are available;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144303b2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> treat information received, records, reports, and recommendations as confidential commercial or financial information or trade secret information, except such information may be made available to the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144303b3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> promptly respond and attempt to resolve complaints regarding its activities for which it is accredited; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144303b4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> protect against the use, in carrying out paragraph (1), of any officer or employee of the accredited person who has a financial conflict of interest regarding any product regulated under this chapter, and annually make available to the public disclosures of the extent to which the accredited person, and the officers and employees of the person, have maintained compliance with requirements under this clause relating to financial conflicts of interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303b5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Such person shall notify the Secretary of any withdrawal, suspension, restriction, or expiration of certificate of conformance with the quality systems standard referred to in paragraph (7) for any device establishment that such person inspects under this subsection not later than 30 days after such withdrawal, suspension, restriction, or expiration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144303b6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Such person may conduct audits to establish conformance with the quality systems standard referred to in paragraph (7).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303b7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall publish on the Internet site of the Food and Drug Administration a list of persons who are accredited under paragraph (2). Such list shall be updated to ensure that the identity of each accredited person, and the particular activities for which the person is accredited, is known to the public. The updating of such list shall be no later than one month after the accreditation of a person under this subsection or the suspension or withdrawal of accreditation, or the modification of the particular activities for which the person is accredited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303b8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303b9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To ensure that persons accredited under this subsection continue to meet the standards of accreditation, the Secretary shall (i) audit the performance of such persons on a periodic basis through the review of inspection reports and inspections by persons designated by the Secretary to evaluate the compliance status of a device establishment and the performance of accredited persons, and (ii) take such additional measures as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144303ba-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may withdraw accreditation of any person accredited under paragraph (2), after providing notice and an opportunity for an informal hearing, when such person is substantially not in compliance with the standards of accreditation, poses a threat to public health, fails to act in a manner that is consistent with the purposes of this subsection, or where the Secretary determines that there is a financial conflict of interest in the relationship between the accredited person and the owner or operator of a device establishment that the accredited person has inspected under this subsection. The Secretary may suspend the accreditation of such person during the pendency of the process under the preceding sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573bb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573bc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), a device establishment is eligible for inspection by persons accredited under paragraph (2) if the following conditions are met:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573bd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary classified the results of the most recent inspection of the establishment as “no action indicated” or “voluntary action indicated”.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573be-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> With respect to inspections of the establishment to be conducted by an accredited person, the owner or operator of the establishment submits to the Secretary a notice that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144573bf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> provides the date of the last inspection of the establishment by the Secretary and the classification of that inspection;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144573c0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> states the intention of the owner or operator to use an accredited person to conduct inspections of the establishment;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144573c1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> identifies the particular accredited person the owner or operator intends to select to conduct such inspections; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id144573c2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> includes a certification that, with respect to the devices that are manufactured, prepared, propagated, compounded, or processed in the establishment—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id144573c3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> at least 1 of such devices is marketed in the United States; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id144573c4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/A/ii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> at least 1 of such devices is marketed, or is intended to be marketed, in 1 or more foreign countries, 1 of which countries certifies, accredits, or otherwise recognizes the person accredited under paragraph (2) and identified under subclause (III) as a person authorized to conduct inspections of device establishments.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573c5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573c6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Except with respect to the requirement of subparagraph (A)(i), a device establishment is deemed to have clearance to participate in the program and to use the accredited person identified in the notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) for inspections of the establishment unless the Secretary, not later than 30 days after receiving such notice, issues a response that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573c7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> denies clearance to participate as provided under subparagraph (C); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573c8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> makes a request under clause (ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573c9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may request from the owner or operator of a device establishment in response to the notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) with respect to the establishment, or from the particular accredited person identified in such notice—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573ca-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> compliance data for the establishment in accordance with clause (iii)(I); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573cb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> information concerning the relationship between the owner or operator of the establishment and the accredited person identified in such notice in accordance with clause (iii)(II).</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The owner or operator of the establishment, or such accredited person, as the case may be, shall respond to such a request not later than 60 days after receiving such request.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573cc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573cd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The compliance data to be submitted by the owner or operator of a device establishment in response to a request under clause (ii)(I) are data describing whether the quality controls of the establishment have been sufficient for ensuring consistent compliance with current good manufacturing practice within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s351/h">section 351(h) of this title</ref> and with other applicable provisions of this chapter. Such data shall include complete reports of inspectional findings regarding good manufacturing practice or other quality control audits that, during the preceding 2-year period, were conducted at the establishment by persons other than the owner or operator of the establishment, together with all other compliance data the Secretary deems necessary. Data under the preceding sentence shall demonstrate to the Secretary whether the establishment has facilitated consistent compliance by promptly correcting any compliance problems identified in such inspections.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573ce-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> A request to an accredited person under clause (ii)(II) may not seek any information that is not required to be maintained by such person in records under subsection (f)(1).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573cf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A device establishment is deemed to have clearance to participate in the program and to use the accredited person identified in the notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) for inspections of the establishment unless the Secretary, not later than 60 days after receiving the information requested under clause (ii), issues a response that denies clearance to participate as provided under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary may deny clearance to a device establishment if the Secretary has evidence that the certification under subparagraph (A)(ii)(IV) is untrue and the Secretary provides to the owner or operator of the establishment a statement summarizing such evidence.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Secretary may deny clearance to a device establishment if the Secretary determines that the establishment has failed to demonstrate consistent compliance for purposes of subparagraph (B)(iii)(I) and the Secretary provides to the owner or operator of the establishment a statement of the reasons for such determination.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The Secretary may reject the selection of the accredited person identified in the notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) if the Secretary provides to the owner or operator of the establishment a statement of the reasons for such rejection. Reasons for the rejection may include that the establishment or the accredited person, as the case may be, has failed to fully respond to the request, or that the Secretary has concerns regarding the relationship between the establishment and such accredited person.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> If the Secretary rejects the selection of an accredited person by the owner or operator of a device establishment, the owner or operator may make an additional selection of an accredited person by submitting to the Secretary a notice that identifies the additional selection. Clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B), and subclause (I) of this clause, apply to the selection of an accredited person through a notice under the preceding sentence in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to a selection of an accredited person through a notice under subparagraph (A)(ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/6/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> In the case of a device establishment that is denied clearance under clause (i) or (ii) or with respect to which the selection of the accredited person is rejected under clause (iii), the Secretary shall designate a person to review the statement of reasons, or statement summarizing such evidence, as the case may be, of the Secretary under such clause if, during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the owner or operator of the establishment receives such statement, the owner or operator requests the review. The review shall commence not later than 30 days after the owner or operator requests the review, unless the Secretary and the owner or operator otherwise agree.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Persons accredited under paragraph (2) to conduct inspections shall record in writing their inspection observations and shall present the observations to the device establishment’s designated representative and describe each observation. Additionally, such accredited person shall prepare an inspection report in a form and manner designated by the Secretary to conduct inspections, taking into consideration the goals of international harmonization of quality systems standards. Any official classification of the inspection shall be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573d9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At a minimum, an inspection report under subparagraph (A) shall identify the persons responsible for good manufacturing practice compliance at the inspected device establishment, the dates of the inspection, the scope of the inspection, and shall describe in detail each observation identified by the accredited person, identify other matters that relate to or may influence compliance with this chapter, and describe any recommendations during the inspection or at the inspection’s closing meeting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573da-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An inspection report under subparagraph (A) shall be sent to the Secretary and to the designated representative of the inspected device establishment at the same time, but under no circumstances later than three weeks after the last day of the inspection. The report to the Secretary shall be accompanied by all written inspection observations previously provided to the designated representative of the establishment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573db-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any statement or representation made by an employee or agent of a device establishment to a person accredited under paragraph (2) to conduct inspections shall be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1001">section 1001 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573dc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> If at any time during an inspection by an accredited person the accredited person discovers a condition that could cause or contribute to an unreasonable risk to the public health, the accredited person shall immediately notify the Secretary of the identification of the device establishment subject to inspection and such condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573dd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/7/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> For the purpose of setting risk-based inspectional priorities, the Secretary shall accept voluntary submissions of reports of audits assessing conformance with appropriate quality systems standards set by the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) and identified by the Secretary in public notice. If the owner or operator of an establishment elects to submit audit reports under this subparagraph, the owner or operator shall submit all such audit reports with respect to the establishment during the preceding 2-year periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573de-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Compensation for an accredited person shall be determined by agreement between the accredited person and the person who engages the services of the accredited person, and shall be paid by the person who engages such services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573df-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection affects the authority of the Secretary to inspect any device establishment pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For fiscal year 2005 and each subsequent fiscal year, no device establishment may be inspected during the fiscal year involved by a person accredited under paragraph (2) if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573e2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> of the amounts appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Food and Drug Administration for the preceding fiscal year (referred to in this subparagraph as the “first prior fiscal year”), the amount obligated by the Secretary for inspections of device establishments by the Secretary was less than the adjusted base amount applicable to such first prior fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573e3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> of the amounts appropriated for salaries and expenses of the Food and Drug Administration for the fiscal year preceding the first prior fiscal year (referred to in this subparagraph as the “second prior fiscal year”), the amount obligated by the Secretary for inspections of device establishments by the Secretary was less than the adjusted base amount applicable to such second prior fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Subject to clause (ii), the Comptroller General of the United States shall determine the amount that was obligated by the Secretary for fiscal year 2002 for compliance activities of the Food and Drug Administration with respect to devices (referred to in this subparagraph as the “compliance budget”), and of such amount, the amount that was obligated for inspections by the Secretary of device establishments (referred to in this subparagraph as the “inspection budget”).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For purposes of determinations under clause (i), the Comptroller General shall not include in the compliance budget or the inspection budget any amounts obligated for inspections of device establishments conducted as part of the process of reviewing applications under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360e">section 360e of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2003-03-31">March 31, 2003</date>, the Comptroller General shall complete the determinations required in this subparagraph and submit to the Secretary and the Congress a report describing the findings made through such determinations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573e8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573e9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The term “base amount” means the inspection budget determined under subparagraph (B) for fiscal year 2002.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573ea-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The term “adjusted base amount”, in the case of applicability to fiscal year 2003, means an amount equal to the base amount increased by 5 percent.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573eb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/10/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The term “adjusted base amount”, with respect to applicability to fiscal year 2004 or any subsequent fiscal year, means the adjusted base amount applicable to the preceding year increased by 5 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573ec-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The authority provided by this subsection terminates on <date date="2027-10-01">October 1, 2027</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573ed-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> No later than four years after <date date="2002-10-26">October 26, 2002</date>, the Comptroller General shall report to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573ee-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the number of inspections conducted by accredited persons pursuant to this subsection and the number of inspections conducted by Federal employees pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref> and of device establishments required to register under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573ef-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number of persons who sought accreditation under this subsection, as well as the number of persons who were accredited under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the reasons why persons who sought accreditation, but were denied accreditation, were denied;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the number of audits conducted by the Secretary of accredited persons, the quality of inspections conducted by accredited persons, whether accredited persons are meeting their obligations under this chapter, and whether the number of audits conducted is sufficient to permit these assessments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> whether this subsection is achieving the goal of ensuring more information about device establishment compliance is being presented to the Secretary, and whether that information is of a quality consistent with information obtained by the Secretary pursuant to inspections conducted by Federal employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> whether this subsection is advancing efforts to allow device establishments to rely upon third-party inspections for purposes of compliance with the laws of foreign governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/12/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> whether the Congress should continue, modify, or terminate the program under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573f5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The Secretary shall include in the annual report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s393/g">section 393(g) of this title</ref> the names of all accredited persons and the particular activities under this subsection for which each such person is accredited and the name of each accredited person whose accreditation has been withdrawn during the year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573f6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> Notwithstanding any provision of this subsection, this subsection does not have any legal effect on any agreement described in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s383/b">section 383(b) of this title</ref> between the Secretary and a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573f7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573f8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the Secretary may recognize auditing organizations that are recognized by organizations established by governments to facilitate international harmonization for purposes of conducting inspections of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573f9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> establishments that manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process devices (other than types of devices licensed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">section 262 of title 42</ref>), as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573fa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> establishments required to register pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573fb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Nothing in this paragraph affects—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573fc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the authority of the Secretary to inspect any device establishment pursuant to this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id144573fd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/g/15/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the authority of the Secretary to determine the official classification of an inspection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id144573fe-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Improvements to inspections process for device establishments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id144573ff-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of inspections other than for-cause inspections, the Secretary shall review processes and standards applicable to inspections of domestic and foreign device establishments in effect as of <date date="2017-08-18">August 18, 2017</date>, and update such processes and standards through the adoption of uniform processes and standards applicable to such inspections. Such uniform processes and standards shall provide for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457400-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> exceptions to such processes and standards, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457401-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> announcing the inspection of the establishment within a reasonable time before such inspection occurs, including by providing to the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment a notification regarding the type and nature of the inspection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457402-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a reasonable estimate of the timeframe for the inspection, an opportunity for advance communications between the officers or employees carrying out the inspection under subsection (a)(1) and the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment concerning appropriate working hours during the inspection, and, to the extent feasible, advance notice of some records that will be requested; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457403-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> regular communications during the inspection with the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the establishment regarding inspection status, which may be recorded by either party with advance notice and mutual consent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457404-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457405-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall, with respect to a request described in subparagraph (B), provide nonbinding feedback with respect to such request not later than 45 days after the Secretary receives such request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457406-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A request described in this subparagraph is a request for feedback—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457407-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that is made by the owner, operator, or agent in charge of such establishment in a timely manner; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457408-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to actions proposed to be taken by a device establishment in a response to a report received by such establishment pursuant to subsection (b) that involve a public health priority, that implicate systemic or major actions, or relate to emerging safety issues (as determined by the Secretary).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457409-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s374/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection affects the authority of the Secretary to conduct inspections otherwise permitted under this chapter in order to ensure compliance with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id1445740a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s704">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 704</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1057">52 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch350/s1">Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 350, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/476">67 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/781/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 87–781, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/792">76 Stat. 792</ref>, 793; <ref href="/us/pl/94/295/s6">Pub. L. 94–295, § 6</ref>, <date date="1976-05-28">May 28, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/581">90 Stat. 581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/359/s4">Pub. L. 96–359, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1193">94 Stat. 1193</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/80/s3/aa">Pub. L. 103–80, § 3(aa)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-13">Aug. 13, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/778">107 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/tI/s125/b/2/L">Pub. L. 105–115, title I, § 125(b)(2)(L)</ref>, title II, § 210(b), title IV, § 412(b), <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2326">111 Stat. 2326</ref>, 2344, 2375; <ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tIII/s306/b">Pub. L. 107–188, title III, § 306(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/670">116 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/250/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 107–250, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1602">116 Stat. 1602</ref>, 1609; <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-04-01">Apr. 1, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/573">118 Stat. 573</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/tII/s228">Pub. L. 110–85, title II, § 228</ref>, <date date="2007-09-27">Sept. 27, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/855">121 Stat. 855</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tI/s103/i">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 103(i)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1837">123 Stat. 1837</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/353/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 111–353, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3887">124 Stat. 3887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/144/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 112–144, title VI, § 612</ref>, title VII, § 706, <date date="2012-07-09">July 9, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1060">126 Stat. 1060</ref>, 1067; <ref href="/us/pl/115/52/tVII">Pub. L. 115–52, title VII</ref>, §§ 702(a), 703, 705, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1055-1057">131 Stat. 1055–1057</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3112/d">Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3112(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/362">134 Stat. 362</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/180/dF/tV/s5007">Pub. L. 117–180, div. F, title V, § 5007</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2168">136 Stat. 2168</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/229/dC/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 117–229, div. C, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2022-12-16">Dec. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2312">136 Stat. 2312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2515/a/2">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2515(a)(2)</ref>, title III, §§ 3106, 3504, 3611(a), (b)(1), 3612(a), 3613(b), <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5806">136 Stat. 5806</ref>, 5807, 5859, 5869, 5872.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1445740b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id1445740c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id1445740d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(5), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6A (§ 201 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id1445740e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3611/a">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3611(a)</ref>, substituted “devices” for “restricted devices” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3504">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3504</ref>, inserted “In the case of a facility (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s364">section 364 of this title</ref>) that manufactures or processes cosmetic products, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in sections 364a, 364b, and 364f of this title, when the standard for records inspection under such section applies.” after “limitations established in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d">section 350c(d) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3611/b/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3611(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “an establishment that is engaged in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or device, or a site or facility that is subject to inspection under paragraph (5)(C),” for “an establishment that is engaged in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug” and “records or other information requested and a rationale for requesting such records or other information in advance of, or in lieu of, an inspection.” for “records requested.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3613/b">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3613(b)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3612/a">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3612(a)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s2515/a/2">Pub. L. 117–328, § 2515(a)(2)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3112/d/1">Pub. L. 116–136, § 3112(d)(1)</ref>. See 2020 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s3106">Pub. L. 117–328, § 3106</ref>, substituted “<date date="2027-10-01">October 1, 2027</date>” for “<date date="2022-12-24">December 24, 2022</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/229">Pub. L. 117–229</ref> substituted “<date date="2022-12-24">December 24, 2022</date>” for “<date date="2022-12-17">December 17, 2022</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/180">Pub. L. 117–180</ref> substituted “December 17” for “October 1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3112/d/1">Pub. L. 116–136, § 3112(d)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s2515/a/2">Pub. L. 117–328, § 2515(a)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, of par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (g)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/115/52/s703">Pub. L. 115–52, § 703</ref>, substituted “<date date="2022-10-01">October 1, 2022</date>” for “<date date="2017-10-01">October 1, 2017</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/115/52/s705">Pub. L. 115–52, § 705</ref>, added par. (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/115/52/s702/a">Pub. L. 115–52, § 702(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/144/s706">Pub. L. 112–144, § 706</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/112/144/s612">Pub. L. 112–144, § 612</ref>, substituted “<date date="2017-10-01">October 1, 2017</date>” for “<date date="2012-10-01">October 1, 2012</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (a)(1)(B) by substituting “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c">section 350c of this title</ref>, when the standard for records inspection under paragraph (1) or (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/a">section 350c(a) of this title</ref> applies, subject to” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c">section 350c of this title</ref> when” and all that follows through “subject to”, was executed by making the substitution for “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c">section 350c of this title</ref> when the Secretary has a reasonable belief that an article of food is adulterated and presents a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals, subject to” in the sentence following subpar. (B) of subsec. (a)(1), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s103/i/1/C">Pub. L. 111–31, § 103(i)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “devices, and tobacco products and subject to reporting and inspection under regulations lawfully issued pursuant to section 355(i) or (k) of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360i">section 360i of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360j/g">section 360j(g) of this title</ref>, or subchapter IX and data relating to other drugs, devices, or tobacco products” for “and devices and subject to reporting and inspection under regulations lawfully issued pursuant to section 355(i) or (k) section 360i, or 360j(g) of this title, and data relating to other drugs or devices”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s103/i/1/B">Pub. L. 111–31, § 103(i)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “restricted devices, or tobacco products” for “or restricted devices” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s103/i/1/A">Pub. L. 111–31, § 103(i)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “devices, tobacco products, or cosmetics” for “devices, or cosmetics” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s103/i/2">Pub. L. 111–31, § 103(i)(2)</ref>, inserted “tobacco product,” after “device,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s103/i/3">Pub. L. 111–31, § 103(i)(3)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s393/g">section 393(g) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/1">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(1)</ref>, substituted “The Secretary” for “Not later than one year after <date date="2002-10-26">October 26, 2002</date>, the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/2">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(2)</ref>, substituted “The Secretary” for “Not later than 180 days after <date date="2002-10-26">October 26, 2002</date>, the Secretary” and struck out at end “In the first year following the publication in the Federal Register of criteria to accredit or deny accreditation to persons who request to perform the duties specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall accredit no more than 15 persons who request to perform duties specified in paragraph (1).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/3">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(3)</ref>, added subpars. (F) and (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/4">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(4)</ref>, amended par. (6) generally, revising and restating provisions of former subpars. (A) to (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/5/A">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(5)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “Persons accredited under paragraph (2) to conduct inspections shall record in writing their inspection observations and shall present the observations to the device establishment’s designated representative and describe each observation. Additionally, such accredited person shall prepare an inspection report (including for inspections classified as ‘no action indicated’) in a form and manner consistent with such reports prepared by employees and officials designated by the Secretary to conduct inspections.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(7)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/5/B">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(5)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(10)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/85/s228/6">Pub. L. 110–85, § 228(6)</ref>, substituted “base amount applicable” for “based amount applicable”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/A">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(A)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “conducting inspections of establishments that manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process class II or class III devices, which inspections are required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref> or are inspections of such establishments required to register under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>.” for “conducting inspections of establishments that manufacture, prepare, propagate, compound, or process class II or class III devices that are required in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref>, or inspections of such establishments required to register pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/B">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(B)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “poses a threat to public health, fails to act in a manner that is consistent with the purposes of this subsection, or where the Secretary determines that there is a financial conflict of interest in the relationship between the accredited person and the owner or operator of a device establishment that the accredited person has inspected under this subsection.” for “or poses a threat to public health or fails to act in a manner that is consistent with the purposes of this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/i">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “described in paragraph (1)” for “of the establishment pursuant to subsection (h) or (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360">section 360 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/ii/I">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “inspections” for “each inspection” and inserted “during a 2-year period” after “person” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/ii/II">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(ii)(II)</ref>, substituted “an accredited person” for “such a person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/iii/I">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(iii)(I)</ref>, substituted “and 1 or both of the following additional conditions are met:” for “and the following additional conditions are met:” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(iii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/iii/II">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(iii)(II)</ref>, substituted “(accredited under paragraph (2) and identified under clause (ii)(II)) as a person authorized to conduct such inspections of device establishments.” for “accredited under paragraph (2) and identified under subclause (II) of this clause.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/iii/III">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(iii)(III)</ref>, inserted “or by a person accredited under paragraph (2)” after “by the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(iv)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/iv">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(iv)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted “section” after “pursuant to” and substituted “inspections of the establishment during the previous 4 years” for “the two immediately preceding inspections of the establishment”, in third sentence, struck out “the petition states a commercial reason for the waiver;” after “granted only if” and inserted “not” after “the Secretary has not determined that the public health would”, and, in last sentence, substituted “granted or deemed to be granted until” for “granted until”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(iv)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/C/v">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(C)(v)</ref>, inserted “of a device establishment required to register” after “to be conducted” and “section” after “pursuant to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/D">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(D)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “and with other” for “, and data otherwise describing whether the establishment has consistently been in compliance with sections 351 and 352 of this title and other” and, in second sentence, substituted “inspectional findings” for “inspections” and inserted “relevant” after “together with all other”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/E">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(E)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subcl. (I) and added subcl. (II).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/F">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(F)</ref>, struck out “in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h">section 360(h) of this title</ref>, or has not during such period been inspected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/i">section 360(i) of this title</ref>, as applicable” after “inspected by the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(10)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/G">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(G)</ref>, substituted “a report” for “a reporting”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(12)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/H/i">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(H)(i)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “the number of inspections pursuant to subsections (h) and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360">section 360 of this title</ref> conducted by accredited persons and the number of inspections pursuant to such subsections conducted by Federal employees;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(12)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/108/214/s2/b/1/H/ii">Pub. L. 108–214, § 2(b)(1)(H)(ii)</ref>, substituted “obtained by the Secretary pursuant to inspections conducted by Federal employees;” for “obtained by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (h) or (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360">section 360 of this title</ref>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/188/s306/b/1">Pub. L. 107–188, § 306(b)(1)</ref>, inserted after first sentence “In the case of any person (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufactures, processes, packs, transports, distributes, holds, or imports foods, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c">section 350c of this title</ref> when the Secretary has a reasonable belief that an article of food is adulterated and presents a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans or animals, subject to the limitations established in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s350c/d">section 350c(d) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/188/s306/b/2">Pub. L. 107–188, § 306(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “third sentence” for “second sentence” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/250/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 107–250, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “An accredited person described in paragraph (3) shall maintain records” for “A person accredited under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360m">section 360m of this title</ref> to review reports made under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/k">section 360(k) of this title</ref> and make recommendations of initial classifications of devices to the Secretary shall maintain records”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/250/s201/b/2">Pub. L. 107–250, § 201(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “an accredited person described in paragraph (3)” for “a person accredited under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360m">section 360m of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/250/s201/b/3">Pub. L. 107–250, § 201(b)(3)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/250/s201/a">Pub. L. 107–250, § 201(a)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s412/b">Pub. L. 105–115, § 412(b)</ref>, substituted “prescription drugs, nonprescription drugs intended for human use,” for “prescription drugs” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s125/b/2/L">Pub. L. 105–115, § 125(b)(2)(L)</ref>, struck out “, section 357(d) or (g),” before “section 360i”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s210/b">Pub. L. 105–115, § 210(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/80">Pub. L. 103–80</ref> substituted a comma for semicolon after “finished and unfinished materials” and “section 355(i) or (k)” for “section 355(i) or (j)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/359/s4/1">Pub. L. 96–359, § 4(1)</ref>, (2), restructured first five sentences of former subsec. (a) as par. (1) and, as so restructured, inserted reference to paragraph (3) and substituted “(A)” and “(B)” for “(1)” and “(2)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/359/s4/3">Pub. L. 96–359, § 4(3)</ref>, redesignated sixth sentence of former subsec. (a) as par. (2) and, as so redesignated, substituted reference to second sentence of paragraph (1) for reference to former second sentence of this subsection, and “(A)”, “(B)”, “(C)”, and “(D)”, for “(1)”, “(2)”, “(3)”, and “(4)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/359/s4/4">Pub. L. 96–359, § 4(4)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/295/s6/a">Pub. L. 94–295, § 6(a)</ref>–(c), expanded existing provisions to encompass medical devices by inserting references to factories, warehouses, establishments, and consulting laboratories in which restricted devices are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, inspections relating to devices, reporting and inspection regulations issued pursuant to sections 360i and 360j(g) of this title, and the manufacture and processing of devices.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/295/s6/d">Pub. L. 94–295, § 6(d)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/781/s201/a">Pub. L. 87–781, § 201(a)</ref>, extended the inspection, where prescription drugs are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, to all things bearing on whether adulterated or misbranded drugs, or any which may not be manufactured, introduced in interstate commerce, or sold or offered for sale under any provision of this chapter, have been or are being manufactured, processed, packed, transported or held in any such place, or otherwise bearing on violation of this chapter, but excluded from such inspection, data concerning finance, sales other than shipment, pricing, personnel other than qualifications of technical and professional personnel, research other than relating to new drugs subject to reporting, provided that provisions of second sentence of this subsection shall be inapplicable to pharmacies, practitioners and other persons enumerated in pars. (1) to (4), and struck out “are held” before “after such introduction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/781/s201/b">Pub. L. 87–781, § 201(b)</ref>, inserted “consulting laboratory” after “warehouse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-08-07">Aug. 7, 1953</date>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and amended them by substituting provisions permitting entry and inspection upon presentation of appropriate credentials and a written notice to the owner, operator, or agent in charge for provisions which authorized entry and inspection only after making a request and obtaining permission from the owner, operator, or custodian, and inserting provisions requiring a separate written notice for each inspection but not for each entry made during the period covered by the inspection, and directing that the inspection shall be conducted within reasonable limits, in a reasonable manner and completed with reasonable promptness, and added subsecs. (b) to (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1445740f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14457410-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/136">Pub. L. 116–136</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3112/g">section 3112(g) of Pub. L. 116–136</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356c">section 356c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14457411-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 210(b) and 412(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/115">Pub. L. 105–115</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/s501">section 501 of Pub. L. 105–115</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14457412-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/781">Pub. L. 87–781</ref> effective <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/781/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 87–781</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s332">section 332 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457413-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/353">Pub. L. 111–353</ref> to be construed to apply to certain alcohol-related facilities, to alter jurisdiction and authorities established under certain other Acts, or in a manner inconsistent with international agreements to which the United States is a party, see sections 2206, 2251, and 2252 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457414-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Processes and Practices; Guidance for Industry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3612/b">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title III, § 3612(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5871">136 Stat. 5871</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3612/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> review processes and practices in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>] applicable to inspections of foreign and domestic sites and facilities described in subparagraph (C)(i) of section 704(a)(5) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/5">21 U.S.C. 374(a)(5)</ref>], as added by subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> evaluate whether any updates are needed to facilitate the consistency of such processes and practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall issue guidance describing the processes and practices applicable to inspections of sites and facilities described in subparagraph (C)(i) of section 704(a)(5) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a), including with respect to the types of records and information required to be provided, best practices for communication between the Food and Drug Administration and industry in advance of or during an inspection or request for records or other information, and other inspections-related conduct, to the extent not specified in existing publicly available Food and Drug Administration guides and manuals for such inspections.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, issue draft guidance under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> not later than 1 year after the close of the public comment period for such draft guidance, issue final guidance under subparagraph (A).”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457415-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Unannounced Foreign Facility Inspections Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3615">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title III, § 3615</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5873">136 Stat. 5873</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3615">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall conduct a pilot program under which the Secretary increases the conduct of unannounced surveillance inspections of foreign human drug establishments and evaluates the differences between such inspections of domestic and foreign human drug establishments, including the impact of announcing inspections to persons who own or operate foreign human drug establishments in advance of an inspection. Such pilot program shall evaluate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> differences in the number and type of violations of section 501(a)(2)(B) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s351/a/2/B">21 U.S.C. 351(a)(2)(B)</ref>) identified as a result of unannounced and announced inspections of foreign human drug establishments and any other significant differences between each type of inspection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> costs and benefits associated with conducting announced and unannounced inspections of foreign human drug establishments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> barriers to conducting unannounced inspections of foreign human drug establishments and any challenges to achieving parity between domestic and foreign human drug establishment inspections; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> approaches for mitigating any negative effects of conducting announced inspections of foreign human drug establishments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program Scope</inline>.—</heading><content>The inspections evaluated under the pilot program under this section shall be routine surveillance inspections and shall not include inspections conducted as part of the Secretary’s evaluation of a request for approval to market a drug submitted under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.) or the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program Initiation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall initiate the pilot program under this section not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall, not later than 180 days following the completion of the pilot program under this section, make available on the website of the Food and Drug Administration a final report on the pilot program under this section, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> findings and any associated recommendations with respect to the evaluation under subsection (a), including any recommendations to address identified barriers to conducting unannounced inspections of foreign human drug establishments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> findings and any associated recommendations regarding how the Secretary may achieve parity between domestic and foreign human drug inspections; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the number of unannounced inspections during the pilot program that would not be unannounced under practices in use as of the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457416-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3611/b/2">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title III, § 3611(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5869">136 Stat. 5869</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIII/s3611/b/2">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall issue or update guidance describing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> circumstances in which the Secretary intends to issue requests for records or other information in advance of, or in lieu of, an inspection under section 704(a)(4) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374/a/4">21 U.S.C. 374(a)(4)</ref>], as amended by paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> processes for responding to such requests electronically or in physical form; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> factors the Secretary intends to consider in evaluating whether such records and other information are provided within a reasonable timeframe, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner, accounting for resource and other limitations that may exist, including for small businesses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>], issue draft guidance under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> not later than 1 year after the close of the comment period for such draft guidance, issue final guidance under subparagraph (A).”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/52/tVII/s702/b">Pub. L. 115–52, title VII, § 702(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1055">131 Stat. 1055</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/52/tVII/s702/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Draft guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall issue draft guidance that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> specifies how the Food and Drug Administration will implement the processes and standards described in paragraph (1) of subsection (h) of section 704 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374">21 U.S.C. 374</ref>), as added by subsection (a), and the requirements described in paragraph (2) of such subsection (h);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provides for standardized methods for communications described in such paragraphs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> establishes, with respect to inspections of both domestic and foreign device establishments (as referred to in section 510(h)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360/h/2">21 U.S.C. 360(h)(2)</ref>], as amended by subsection (a) [of <ref href="/us/pl/115/52/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 115–52</ref>]), a standard timeframe for such inspections—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> that occurs over consecutive days; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to which each investigator conducting such an inspection shall adhere unless the investigator identifies to the establishment involved a reason that more time is needed to conduct such investigation; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> identifies practices for investigators and device establishments to facilitate the continuity of inspections of such establishments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after providing notice and opportunity for public comment on the draft guidance issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final guidance to implement subsection (h) of section 704 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374">21 U.S.C. 374</ref>), as added by subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457417-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inspections</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/52/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 115–52, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1073">131 Stat. 1073</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/52/tVIII/s806">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Within 6 months of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop and implement a protocol for expediting review of timely responses to reports of observations from an inspection under section 704 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374">21 U.S.C. 374</ref>). Such protocol shall—</p>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> apply to responses to such reports pertaining to applications submitted under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355">21 U.S.C. 355</ref>)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> for which the approval is dependent upon remediation of conditions identified in the report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> for which concerns related to observations from an inspection under such section 704 are the only barrier to approval; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> where the drug that is the subject of the application is a drug—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for which there are not more than 3 other approved applications under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s355/j">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</ref>) that reference the same listed drug and for which there are less than 6 abbreviated new drug applications tentatively approved; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> that is included on the list under section 506E of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s356e">21 U.S.C. 356e</ref>);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> address expedited re-inspection of facilities, as appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> establish a 6-month timeline for completion of review of such responses to such reports.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14457418-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of Secretary Prior to <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/87/781/tII/s201/d">Pub. L. 87–781, title II, § 201(d)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/793">76 Stat. 793</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/781/tII/s201/d">“Nothing in the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) of this section [amending this section] shall be construed to negate or derogate from any authority of the Secretary existing prior to the enactment of this Act [<date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id14457419-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id1445741a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Security Administrator to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare [now Health and Human Services], and of Food and Drug Administration in the Department of Agriculture to Federal Security Agency, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
