<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1445743e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378"><num value="378">§ 378.</num><heading> Advertising of foods</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1445743f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of misbranding; notification of Federal Trade Commission by Secretary; contents</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457440-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (c), before the Secretary may initiate any action under subchapter III—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457441-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to any food which the Secretary determines is misbranded under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s343/a/2">section 343(a)(2) of this title</ref> because of its advertising, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14457442-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to a food’s advertising which the Secretary determines causes the food to be so misbranded,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall, in accordance with paragraph (2), notify in writing the Federal Trade Commission of the action the Secretary proposes to take respecting such food or advertising.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14457443-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The notice required by paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e444-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contain (i) a description of the action the Secretary proposes to take and of the advertising which the Secretary has determined causes a food to be misbranded, (ii) a statement of the reasons for the Secretary’s determination that such advertising has caused such food to be misbranded, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e445-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be accompanied by the records, documents, and other written materials which the Secretary determines supports his determination that such food is misbranded because of such advertising.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1447e446-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Action by Federal Trade Commission precluding action by Secretary; exception</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1447e447-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary notifies the Federal Trade Commission under subsection (a) of action proposed to be taken under subchapter III with respect to a food or food advertising and the Commission notifies the Secretary in writing, within the 30-day period beginning on the date of the receipt of such notice, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e448-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> it has initiated under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] an investigation of such advertising to determine if it is prohibited by such Act or any order or rule under such Act,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e449-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> it has commenced (or intends to commence) a civil action under section 5, 13, or 19 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">15 U.S.C. 45</ref>, 53, or 57b] with respect to such advertising or the Attorney General has commenced (or intends to commence) a civil action under section 5 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">15 U.S.C. 45</ref>] with respect to such advertising,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e44a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> it has issued and served (or intends to issue and serve) a complaint under section 5(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/b">15 U.S.C. 45(b)</ref>] respecting such advertising, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e44b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> pursuant to section 16(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s56/b">15 U.S.C. 56(b)</ref>] it has made a certification to the Attorney General respecting such advertising,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary may not, except as provided by paragraph (2), initiate the action described in the Secretary’s notice to the Federal Trade Commission.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1447e44c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If, before the expiration of the 60-day period beginning on the date the Secretary receives a notice described in paragraph (1) from the Federal Trade Commission in response to a notice of the Secretary under subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e44d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Commission or the Attorney General does not commence a civil action described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection respecting the advertising described in the Secretary’s notice,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e44e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Commission does not issue and serve a complaint described in subparagraph (C) of such paragraph respecting such advertising, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1447e44f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Commission does not (as described in subparagraph (D) of such paragraph) make a certification to the Attorney General respecting such advertising, or, if the Commission does make such a certification to the Attorney General respecting such advertising, the Attorney General, before the expiration of such period, does not cause appropriate criminal proceedings to be brought against such advertising,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary may, after the expiration of such period, initiate the action described in the notice to the Commission pursuant to subsection (a). The Commission shall promptly notify the Secretary of the commencement by the Commission of such a civil action, the issuance and service by it of such a complaint, or the causing by the Attorney General of criminal proceedings to be brought against such advertising.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1447e450-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary’s determination of imminent hazard to health as suspending applicability of provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The requirements of subsections (a) and (b) do not apply with respect to action under subchapter III with respect to any food or food advertising if the Secretary determines that such action is required to eliminate an imminent hazard to health.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1447e451-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s378/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of action by Secretary with Federal Trade Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of avoiding unnecessary duplication, the Secretary shall coordinate any action taken under subchapter III because of advertising which the Secretary determines causes a food to be misbranded with any action of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] with respect to such advertising.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id1447e452-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s707">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 707</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/278/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 94–278, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-22">Apr. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/412">90 Stat. 412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1447e453-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id1447e454-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id1447e455-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
