<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1472c5ad-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s384g"><num value="384g">§ 384g.</num><heading> Restricting entrance of illicit drugs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1472c5ae-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s384g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Food and Drug Administration and U.S. Customs and Border Protection cooperation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id1472c5af-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s384g/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”), acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and in consultation with the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall develop and periodically update a mutually agreed upon list of the controlled substances that the Secretary will refer to U.S. Customs and Border Protection, unless the Secretary and U.S. Customs and Border Protection agree otherwise, when such substances are offered for import via international mail and appear to violate the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.), the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">21 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.), the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.), or any other applicable law. The Secretary shall transfer controlled substances on such list to the U.S. Customs and Border Protection. If the Secretary identifies additional packages that appear to be the same as such package containing a controlled substance, such additional packages may also be transferred to U.S. Customs and Border Protection. The U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall receive such packages consistent with the requirements of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id1472c5b0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s384g/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 9 months after <date date="2018-10-24">October 24, 2018</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall report to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate on the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id1472c5b1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tIII/s3022/a">Pub. L. 115–271, title III, § 3022(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3938">132 Stat. 3938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1472c5b2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id1472c5b3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id1472c5b4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 801 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1285">84 Stat. 1285</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter II (§ 951 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">section 951 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675">act June 25, 1938, ch. 675</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1040">52 Stat. 1040</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">section 301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1472c5b5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id1472c5b6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Stop Counterfeit Drugs by Regulating and Enhancing Enforcement Now Act, also known as the SCREEN Act, and also as part of the Substance Use–Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment for Patients and Communities Act, also known as the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act, and not as part of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
