<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14750f59-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d"><num value="387d">§ 387d.</num><heading> Submission of health information to the Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14750f5a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each tobacco product manufacturer or importer, or agents thereof, shall submit to the Secretary the following information:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14750f5b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 6 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, a listing of all ingredients, including tobacco, substances, compounds, and additives that are, as of such date, added by the manufacturer to the tobacco, paper, filter, or other part of each tobacco product by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14750f5c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of the content, delivery, and form of nicotine in each tobacco product measured in milligrams of nicotine in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333/e">section 1333(e) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1477805d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Beginning 3 years after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, a listing of all constituents, including smoke constituents as applicable, identified by the Secretary as harmful or potentially harmful to health in each tobacco product, and as applicable in the smoke of each tobacco product, by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand. Effective beginning 3 years after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, the manufacturer, importer, or agent shall comply with regulations promulgated under section 387<i>o</i> of this title in reporting information under this paragraph, where applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1477805e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Beginning 6 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, all documents developed after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date> that relate to health, toxicological, behavioral, or physiologic effects of current or future tobacco products, their constituents (including smoke constituents), ingredients, components, and additives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477805f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Data submission</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the request of the Secretary, each tobacco product manufacturer or importer of tobacco products, or agents thereof, shall submit the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14778060-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any or all documents (including underlying scientific information) relating to research activities, and research findings, conducted, supported, or possessed by the manufacturer (or agents thereof) on the health, toxicological, behavioral, or physiologic effects of tobacco products and their constituents (including smoke constituents), ingredients, components, and additives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14778061-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any or all documents (including underlying scientific information) relating to research activities, and research findings, conducted, supported, or possessed by the manufacturer (or agents thereof) that relate to the issue of whether a reduction in risk to health from tobacco products can occur upon the employment of technology available or known to the manufacturer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14778062-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any or all documents (including underlying scientific or financial information) relating to marketing research involving the use of tobacco products or marketing practices and the effectiveness of such practices used by tobacco manufacturers and distributors.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">An importer of a tobacco product not manufactured in the United States shall supply the information required of a tobacco product manufacturer under this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778063-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for submission</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778064-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At least 90 days prior to the delivery for introduction into interstate commerce of a tobacco product not on the market on <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, the manufacturer of such product shall provide the information required under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778065-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of additive</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If at any time a tobacco product manufacturer adds to its tobacco products a new tobacco additive or increases the quantity of an existing tobacco additive, the manufacturer shall, except as provided in paragraph (3), at least 90 days prior to such action so advise the Secretary in writing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778066-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of other actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If at any time a tobacco product manufacturer eliminates or decreases an existing additive, or adds or increases an additive that has by regulation been designated by the Secretary as an additive that is not a human or animal carcinogen, or otherwise harmful to health under intended conditions of use, the manufacturer shall within 60 days of such action so advise the Secretary in writing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778067-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Data list</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778068-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall publish in a format that is understandable and not misleading to a lay person, and place on public display (in a manner determined by the Secretary) the list established under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778069-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumer research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct periodic consumer research to ensure that the list published under paragraph (1) is not misleading to lay persons. Not later than 5 years after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the results of such research, together with recommendations on whether such publication should be continued or modified.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477806a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Data collection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 24 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall establish, and periodically revise as appropriate, a list of harmful and potentially harmful constituents, including smoke constituents, to health in each tobacco product by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand. The Secretary shall publish a public notice requesting the submission by interested persons of scientific and other information concerning the harmful and potentially harmful constituents in tobacco products and tobacco smoke.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id1477806b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s904">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 904</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tI/s101/b/3">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1790">123 Stat. 1790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1477806c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id1477806d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id1477806e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 904 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, was renumbered section 1004 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s394">section 394 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1477806f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14778070-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification of Deadlines for Secretarial Action</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">With respect to any time periods specified in an amendment by div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref> that begin on <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, within which the Secretary of Health and Human Services is required to carry out and complete specified activities, with certain limitations, the calculation of such time periods shall commence on the first day of the first fiscal quarter following the initial 2 consecutive fiscal quarters of fiscal year 2010 for which the Secretary has collected fees under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387s">section 387s of this title</ref>, and the Secretary may extend or reduce the duration of one or more such time periods, except that no such period shall be extended for more than 90 days, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387">section 387 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
