<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14778071-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e"><num value="387e">§ 387e.</num><heading> Annual registration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778072-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778073-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing” shall include repackaging or otherwise changing the container, wrapper, or labeling of any tobacco product package in furtherance of the distribution of the tobacco product from the original place of manufacture to the person who makes final delivery or sale to the ultimate consumer or user.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778074-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Name</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “name” shall include in the case of a partnership the name of each partner and, in the case of a corporation, the name of each corporate officer and director, and the State of incorporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778075-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration by owners and operators</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On or before December 31 of each year, every person who owns or operates any establishment in any State engaged in the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing of a tobacco product or tobacco products shall register with the Secretary the name, places of business, and all such establishments of that person. If enactment of the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act occurs in the second half of the calendar year, the Secretary shall designate a date no later than 6 months into the subsequent calendar year by which registration pursuant to this subsection shall occur.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778076-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration by new owners and operators</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every person upon first engaging in the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing of a tobacco product or tobacco products in any establishment owned or operated in any State by that person shall immediately register with the Secretary that person’s name, place of business, and such establishment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778077-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration of added establishments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every person required to register under subsection (b) or (c) shall immediately register with the Secretary any additional establishment which that person owns or operates in any State and in which that person begins the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing of a tobacco product or tobacco products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778078-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Uniform product identification system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may by regulation prescribe a uniform system for the identification of tobacco products and may require that persons who are required to list such tobacco products under subsection (i) shall list such tobacco products in accordance with such system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778079-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Public access to registration information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available for inspection, to any person so requesting, any registration filed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477807a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Biennial inspection of registered establishments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every establishment registered with the Secretary under this section shall be subject to inspection under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s374">section 374 of this title</ref> or subsection (h), and every such establishment engaged in the manufacture, compounding, or processing of a tobacco product or tobacco products shall be so inspected by 1 or more officers or employees duly designated by the Secretary at least once in the 2-year period beginning with the date of registration of such establishment under this section and at least once in every successive 2-year period thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477807b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration by foreign establishments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any establishment within any foreign country engaged in the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing of a tobacco product or tobacco products, shall register under this section under regulations promulgated by the Secretary. Such regulations shall require such establishment to provide the information required by subsection (i) and shall include provisions for registration of any such establishment upon condition that adequate and effective means are available, by arrangement with the government of such foreign country or otherwise, to enable the Secretary to determine from time to time whether tobacco products manufactured, prepared, compounded, or processed in such establishment, if imported or offered for import into the United States, shall be refused admission on any of the grounds set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s381/a">section 381(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477807c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id1477807d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Product list</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Every person who registers with the Secretary under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (h) shall, at the time of registration under any such subsection, file with the Secretary a list of all tobacco products which are being manufactured, prepared, compounded, or processed by that person for commercial distribution and which have not been included in any list of tobacco products filed by that person with the Secretary under this paragraph or paragraph (2) before such time of registration. Such list shall be prepared in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe and shall be accompanied by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id1477807e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a tobacco product contained in the applicable list with respect to which a tobacco product standard has been established under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387g">section 387g of this title</ref> or which is subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, a reference to the authority for the marketing of such tobacco product and a copy of all labeling for such tobacco product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id1477807f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of any other tobacco product contained in an applicable list, a copy of all consumer information and other labeling for such tobacco product, a representative sampling of advertisements for such tobacco product, and, upon request made by the Secretary for good cause, a copy of all advertisements for a particular tobacco product; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778080-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if the registrant filing a list has determined that a tobacco product contained in such list is not subject to a tobacco product standard established under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387g">section 387g of this title</ref>, a brief statement of the basis upon which the registrant made such determination if the Secretary requests such a statement with respect to that particular tobacco product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778081-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with respect to forms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of the Treasury in developing the forms to be used for registration under this section to minimize the burden on those persons required to register with both the Secretary and the Tax and Trade Bureau of the Department of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778082-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Biannual report of any change in product list</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each person who registers with the Secretary under this section shall report to the Secretary once during the month of June of each year and once during the month of December of each year the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778083-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A list of each tobacco product introduced by the registrant for commercial distribution which has not been included in any list previously filed by that person with the Secretary under this subparagraph or paragraph (1). A list under this subparagraph shall list a tobacco product by its established name and shall be accompanied by the other information required by paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778084-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If since the date the registrant last made a report under this paragraph that person has discontinued the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing for commercial distribution of a tobacco product included in a list filed under subparagraph (A) or paragraph (1), notice of such discontinuance, the date of such discontinuance, and the identity of its established name.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778085-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If since the date the registrant reported under subparagraph (B) a notice of discontinuance that person has resumed the manufacture, preparation, compounding, or processing for commercial distribution of the tobacco product with respect to which such notice of discontinuance was reported, notice of such resumption, the date of such resumption, the identity of such tobacco product by established name, and other information required by paragraph (1), unless the registrant has previously reported such resumption to the Secretary under this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778086-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/i/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any material change in any information previously submitted under this paragraph or paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14778087-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Report preceding introduction of certain substantially equivalent products into interstate commerce</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14778088-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each person who is required to register under this section and who proposes to begin the introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce for commercial distribution of a tobacco product intended for human use that was not commercially marketed (other than for test marketing) in the United States as of <date date="2007-02-15">February 15, 2007</date>, shall, at least 90 days prior to making such introduction or delivery, report to the Secretary (in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id14778089-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the basis for such person’s determination that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id1477808a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the tobacco product is substantially equivalent, within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, to a tobacco product commercially marketed (other than for test marketing) in the United States as of <date date="2007-02-15">February 15, 2007</date>, or to a tobacco product that the Secretary has previously determined, pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, is substantially equivalent and that is in compliance with the requirements of this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id1477808b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the tobacco product is modified within the meaning of paragraph (3), the modifications are to a product that is commercially marketed and in compliance with the requirements of this chapter, and all of the modifications are covered by exemptions granted by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (3); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id1477808c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> action taken by such person to comply with the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387g">section 387g of this title</ref> that are applicable to the tobacco product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id1477808d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to certain post–<date date="2007-02-15">February 15, 2007</date>, products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A report under this subsection for a tobacco product that was first introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce for commercial distribution in the United States after <date date="2007-02-15">February 15, 2007</date>, and prior to the date that is 21 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, shall be submitted to the Secretary not later than 21 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id1477808e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id1477808f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may exempt from the requirements of this subsection relating to the demonstration that a tobacco product is substantially equivalent within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, tobacco products that are modified by adding or deleting a tobacco additive, or increasing or decreasing the quantity of an existing tobacco additive, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14778090-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such modification would be a minor modification of a tobacco product that can be sold under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14778091-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a report under this subsection is not necessary to ensure that permitting the tobacco product to be marketed would be appropriate for protection of the public health; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14778092-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an exemption is otherwise appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14778093-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387e/j/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 15 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall issue regulations to implement this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14778094-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s905">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 905</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tI/s101/b/3">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1792">123 Stat. 1792</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14778095-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14778096-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14778097-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1776">123 Stat. 1776</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2009 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">section 301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id14778098-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 905 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, was renumbered section 1005 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s395">section 395 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14778099-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id1477809a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification of Deadlines for Secretarial Action</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">With respect to any time periods specified in an amendment by div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref> that begin on <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, within which the Secretary of Health and Human Services is required to carry out and complete specified activities, with certain limitations, the calculation of such time periods shall commence on the first day of the first fiscal quarter following the initial 2 consecutive fiscal quarters of fiscal year 2010 for which the Secretary has collected fees under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387s">section 387s of this title</ref>, and the Secretary may extend or reduce the duration of one or more such time periods, except that no such period shall be extended for more than 90 days, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387">section 387 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
