<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1477809b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f"><num value="387f">§ 387f.</num><heading> General provisions respecting control of tobacco products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477809c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title applicable to a tobacco product shall apply to such tobacco product until the applicability of the requirement to the tobacco product has been changed by action taken under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387g">section 387g of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387k">section 387k of this title</ref>, or subsection (d) of this section, and any requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title which is inconsistent with a requirement imposed on such tobacco product under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387g">section 387g of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387j">section 387j of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387k">section 387k of this title</ref>, or subsection (d) of this section shall not apply to such tobacco product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id1477809d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information on public access and comment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each notice of proposed rulemaking or other notification under section 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, or 387k of this title or under this section, any other notice which is published in the Federal Register with respect to any other action taken under any such section and which states the reasons for such action, and each publication of findings required to be made in connection with rulemaking under any such section shall set forth—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1477809e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the manner in which interested persons may examine data and other information on which the notice or findings is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002126"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “are”.</note> based; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1477809f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the period within which interested persons may present their comments on the notice or findings (including the need therefore) orally or in writing, which period shall be at least 60 days but may not exceed 90 days unless the time is extended by the Secretary by a notice published in the Federal Register stating good cause therefore.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limited confidentiality of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Secretary or the Secretary’s representative under section 387c, 387d, 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, 387k, or 374 of this title, or under subsection (e) or (f) of this section, which is exempt from disclosure under subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> by reason of subsection (b)(4) of that section shall be considered confidential and shall not be disclosed, except that the information may be disclosed to other officers or employees concerned with carrying out this subchapter, or when relevant in any proceeding under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may by regulation require restrictions on the sale and distribution of a tobacco product, including restrictions on the access to, and the advertising and promotion of, the tobacco product, if the Secretary determines that such regulation would be appropriate for the protection of the public health. The Secretary may by regulation impose restrictions on the advertising and promotion of a tobacco product consistent with and to full extent permitted by the first amendment to the Constitution. The finding as to whether such regulation would be appropriate for the protection of the public health shall be determined with respect to the risks and benefits to the population as a whole, including users and nonusers of the tobacco product, and taking into account—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id147780a3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the increased or decreased likelihood that existing users of tobacco products will stop using such products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id147780a4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the increased or decreased likelihood that those who do not use tobacco products will start using such products.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">No such regulation may require that the sale or distribution of a tobacco product be limited to the written or oral authorization of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe medical products.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Label statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The label of a tobacco product shall bear such appropriate statements of the restrictions required by a regulation under subsection (a) as the Secretary may in such regulation prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780a7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No restrictions under paragraph (1) may—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780a8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> prohibit the sale of any tobacco product in face-to-face transactions by a specific category of retail outlets; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780a9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> establish a minimum age of sale of tobacco products to any person older than 21 years of age.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780aa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Matchbooks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of any regulations issued by the Secretary, matchbooks of conventional size containing not more than 20 paper matches, and which are customarily given away for free with the purchase of tobacco products, shall be considered as adult-written publications which shall be permitted to contain advertising. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if the Secretary finds that such treatment of matchbooks is not appropriate for the protection of the public health, the Secretary may determine by regulation that matchbooks shall not be considered adult-written publications.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780ab-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Remote sales</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780ac-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780ad-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> within 18 months after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, promulgate regulations regarding the sale and distribution of tobacco products that occur through means other than a direct, face-to-face exchange between a retailer and a consumer in order to prevent the sale and distribution of tobacco products to individuals who have not attained the minimum age established by applicable law for the purchase of such products, including requirements for age verification; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780ae-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> within 2 years after <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, issue regulations to address the promotion and marketing of tobacco products that are sold or distributed through means other than a direct, face-to-face exchange between a retailer and a consumer in order to protect individuals who have not attained the minimum age established by applicable law for the purchase of such products.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780af-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to other authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph limits the authority of the Secretary to take additional actions under the other paragraphs of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780b0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum age of sale</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for any retailer to sell a tobacco product to any person younger than 21 years of age.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147780b1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Good manufacturing practice requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780b2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Methods, facilities, and controls to conform</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780b3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In applying manufacturing restrictions to tobacco, the Secretary shall, in accordance with subparagraph (B), prescribe regulations (which may differ based on the type of tobacco product involved) requiring that the methods used in, and the facilities and controls used for, the manufacture, preproduction design validation (including a process to assess the performance of a tobacco product), packing, and storage of a tobacco product conform to current good manufacturing practice, or hazard analysis and critical control point methodology, as prescribed in such regulations to assure that the public health is protected and that the tobacco product is in compliance with this subchapter. Such regulations may provide for the testing of raw tobacco for pesticide chemical residues regardless of whether a tolerance for such chemical residues has been established.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780b4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780b5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> before promulgating any regulation under subparagraph (A), afford the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee an opportunity to submit recommendations with respect to the regulation proposed to be promulgated;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780b6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> before promulgating any regulation under subparagraph (A), afford opportunity for an oral hearing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780b7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provide the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee a reasonable time to make its recommendation with respect to proposed regulations under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780b8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> in establishing the effective date of a regulation promulgated under this subsection, take into account the differences in the manner in which the different types of tobacco products have historically been produced, the financial resources of the different tobacco product manufacturers, and the state of their existing manufacturing facilities, and shall provide for a reasonable period of time for such manufacturers to conform to good manufacturing practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780b9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> not require any small tobacco product manufacturer to comply with a regulation under subparagraph (A) for at least 4 years following the effective date established by the Secretary for such regulation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780ba-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions; variances</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780bb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person subject to any requirement prescribed under paragraph (1) may petition the Secretary for a permanent or temporary exemption or variance from such requirement. Such a petition shall be submitted to the Secretary in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe and shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780bc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of a petition for an exemption from a requirement, set forth the basis for the petitioner’s determination that compliance with the requirement is not required to assure that the tobacco product will be in compliance with this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780bd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a petition for a variance from a requirement, set forth the methods proposed to be used in, and the facilities and controls proposed to be used for, the manufacture, packing, and storage of the tobacco product in lieu of the methods, facilities, and controls prescribed by the requirement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780be-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> contain such other information as the Secretary shall prescribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780bf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Referral to the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may refer to the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee any petition submitted under subparagraph (A). The Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee shall report its recommendations to the Secretary with respect to a petition referred to it within 60 days after the date of the petition’s referral. Within 60 days after—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780c0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the date the petition was submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780c1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the day after the petition was referred to the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">whichever occurs later, the Secretary shall by order either deny the petition or approve it.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780c2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may approve—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780c3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a petition for an exemption for a tobacco product from a requirement if the Secretary determines that compliance with such requirement is not required to assure that the tobacco product will be in compliance with this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id147780c4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a petition for a variance for a tobacco product from a requirement if the Secretary determines that the methods to be used in, and the facilities and controls to be used for, the manufacture, packing, and storage of the tobacco product in lieu of the methods, facilities, and controls prescribed by the requirement are sufficient to assure that the tobacco product will be in compliance with this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780c5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An order of the Secretary approving a petition for a variance shall prescribe such conditions respecting the methods used in, and the facilities and controls used for, the manufacture, packing, and storage of the tobacco product to be granted the variance under the petition as may be necessary to assure that the tobacco product will be in compliance with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147780c6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">After the issuance of an order under subparagraph (B) respecting a petition, the petitioner shall have an opportunity for an informal hearing on such order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147780c7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Compliance with requirements under this subsection shall not be required before the end of the 3-year period following <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147780c8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387f/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into contracts for research, testing, and demonstrations respecting tobacco products and may obtain tobacco products for research, testing, and demonstration purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id147780c9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s906">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 906</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tI/s101/b/3">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1795">123 Stat. 1795</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dN/tI/s603/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. N, title I, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3123">133 Stat. 3123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id147780ca-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id147780cb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id147780cc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 906 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, was renumbered section 1006 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s396">section 396 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id147780cd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (d)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s603/a/1">Pub. L. 116–94, § 603(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “21 years” for “18 years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s603/a/2">Pub. L. 116–94, § 603(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id147780ce-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id147780cf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dN/tI/s603/b">Pub. L. 116–94, div. N, title I, § 603(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3123">133 Stat. 3123</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dN/tI/s603/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) shall publish in the Federal Register a final rule to update the regulations issued under chapter IX of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387">21 U.S.C. 387</ref> et seq.) as appropriate, only to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section], including to update all references to persons younger than 18 years of age in subpart B of part 1140 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, and to update the relevant age verification requirements under such part 1140 to require age verification for individuals under the age of 30. Such final rule shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> take full effect not later than 90 days after the date on which such final rule is published; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> be deemed to be in compliance with all applicable provisions of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code[,] and all other provisions of law relating to rulemaking procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Prior to making amendments to part 1140 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations[,] other than the amendments described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promulgate a proposed rule in accordance with chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id147780d0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification of Deadlines for Secretarial Action</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">With respect to any time periods specified in an amendment by div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref> that begin on <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, within which the Secretary of Health and Human Services is required to carry out and complete specified activities, with certain limitations, the calculation of such time periods shall commence on the first day of the first fiscal quarter following the initial 2 consecutive fiscal quarters of fiscal year 2010 for which the Secretary has collected fees under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387s">section 387s of this title</ref>, and the Secretary may extend or reduce the duration of one or more such time periods, except that no such period shall be extended for more than 90 days, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387">section 387 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
