<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id147c3b33-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p"><num value="387p">§ 387p.</num><heading> Preservation of State and local authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b34-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b35-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Preservation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(A), nothing in this subchapter, or rules promulgated under this subchapter, shall be construed to limit the authority of a Federal agency (including the Armed Forces), a State or political subdivision of a State, or the government of an Indian tribe to enact, adopt, promulgate, and enforce any law, rule, regulation, or other measure with respect to tobacco products that is in addition to, or more stringent than, requirements established under this subchapter, including a law, rule, regulation, or other measure relating to or prohibiting the sale, distribution, possession, exposure to, access to, advertising and promotion of, or use of tobacco products by individuals of any age, information reporting to the State, or measures relating to fire safety standards for tobacco products. No provision of this subchapter shall limit or otherwise affect any State, tribal, or local taxation of tobacco products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b36-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Preemption of certain State and local requirements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b37-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No State or political subdivision of a State may establish or continue in effect with respect to a tobacco product any requirement which is different from, or in addition to, any requirement under the provisions of this subchapter relating to tobacco product standards, premarket review, adulteration, misbranding, labeling, registration, good manufacturing standards, or modified risk tobacco products.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b38-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) does not apply to requirements relating to the sale, distribution, possession, information reporting to the State, exposure to, access to, the advertising and promotion of, or use of, tobacco products by individuals of any age, or relating to fire safety standards for tobacco products. Information disclosed to a State under subparagraph (A) that is exempt from disclosure under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/4">section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> shall be treated as a trade secret and confidential information by the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id147c3b39-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s387p/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction regarding product liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision of this subchapter relating to a tobacco product shall be construed to modify or otherwise affect any action or the liability of any person under the product liability law of any State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id147c3b3a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s916">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 916</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tI/s101/b/3">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1823">123 Stat. 1823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
