<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14811ddc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d"><num value="399d">§ 399d.</num><heading> Employee protections</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14811ddd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No entity engaged in the manufacture, processing, packing, transporting, distribution, reception, holding, or importation of food may discharge an employee or otherwise discriminate against an employee with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment because the employee, whether at the employee’s initiative or in the ordinary course of the employee’s duties (or any person acting pursuant to a request of the employee)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14811dde-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provided, caused to be provided, or is about to provide or cause to be provided to the employer, the Federal Government, or the attorney general of a State information relating to any violation of, or any act or omission the employee reasonably believes to be a violation of any provision of this chapter or any order, rule, regulation, standard, or ban under this chapter, or any order, rule, regulation, standard, or ban under this chapter; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002129">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002129"><num>1</num> So in original.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14811ddf-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> testified or is about to testify in a proceeding concerning such violation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14811de0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assisted or participated or is about to assist or participate in such a proceeding; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14811de1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> objected to, or refused to participate in, any activity, policy, practice, or assigned task that the employee (or other such person) reasonably believed to be in violation of any provision of this chapter, or any order, rule, regulation, standard, or ban under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person who believes that he or she has been discharged or otherwise discriminated against by any person in violation of subsection (a) may, not later than 180 days after the date on which such violation occurs, file (or have any person file on his or her behalf) a complaint with the Secretary of Labor (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) alleging such discharge or discrimination and identifying the person responsible for such act. Upon receipt of such a complaint, the Secretary shall notify, in writing, the person named in the complaint of the filing of the complaint, of the allegations contained in the complaint, of the substance of evidence supporting the complaint, and of the opportunities that will be afforded to such person under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a complaint filed under paragraph (1) and after affording the complainant and the person named in the complaint an opportunity to submit to the Secretary a written response to the complaint and an opportunity to meet with a representative of the Secretary to present statements from witnesses, the Secretary shall initiate an investigation and determine whether there is reasonable cause to believe that the complaint has merit and notify, in writing, the complainant and the person alleged to have committed a violation of subsection (a) of the Secretary’s findings.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasonable cause found; preliminary order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary concludes that there is reasonable cause to believe that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Secretary shall accompany the Secretary’s findings with a preliminary order providing the relief prescribed by paragraph (3)(B). Not later than 30 days after the date of notification of findings under this paragraph, the person alleged to have committed the violation or the complainant may file objections to the findings or preliminary order, or both, and request a hearing on the record. The filing of such objections shall not operate to stay any reinstatement remedy contained in the preliminary order. Any such hearing shall be conducted expeditiously. If a hearing is not requested in such 30-day period, the preliminary order shall be deemed a final order that is not subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Dismissal of complaint</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard for complainant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall dismiss a complaint filed under this subsection and shall not conduct an investigation otherwise required under subparagraph (A) unless the complainant makes a prima facie showing that any behavior described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) was a contributing factor in the unfavorable personnel action alleged in the complaint.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id14811de9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard for employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding a finding by the Secretary that the complainant has made the showing required under clause (i), no investigation otherwise required under subparagraph (A) shall be conducted if the employer demonstrates, by clear and convincing evidence, that the employer would have taken the same unfavorable personnel action in the absence of that behavior.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dea-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Violation standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary may determine that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred only if the complainant demonstrates that any behavior described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) was a contributing factor in the unfavorable personnel action alleged in the complaint.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id14811deb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/2/C/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Relief standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Relief may not be ordered under subparagraph (A) if the employer demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that the employer would have taken the same unfavorable personnel action in the absence of that behavior.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dec-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Final order</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811ded-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 120 days after the date of conclusion of any hearing under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall issue a final order providing the relief prescribed by this paragraph or denying the complaint. At any time before issuance of a final order, a proceeding under this subsection may be terminated on the basis of a settlement agreement entered into by the Secretary, the complainant, and the person alleged to have committed the violation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dee-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If, in response to a complaint filed under paragraph (1), the Secretary determines that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Secretary shall order the person who committed such violation—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811def-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to take affirmative action to abate the violation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811df0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to reinstate the complainant to his or her former position together with compensation (including back pay) and restore the terms, conditions, and privileges associated with his or her employment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811df1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to provide compensatory damages to the complainant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811df2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If such an order is issued under this paragraph, the Secretary, at the request of the complainant, shall assess against the person against whom the order is issued a sum equal to the aggregate amount of all costs and expenses (including attorneys’ and expert witness fees) reasonably incurred, as determined by the Secretary, by the complainant for, or in connection with, the bringing of the complaint upon which the order was issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811df3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Bad faith claim</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary finds that a complaint under paragraph (1) is frivolous or has been brought in bad faith, the Secretary may award to the prevailing employer a reasonable attorneys’ fee, not exceeding $1,000, to be paid by the complainant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811df4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Action in court</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811df5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary has not issued a final decision within 210 days after the filing of the complaint, or within 90 days after receiving a written determination, the complainant may bring an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States with jurisdiction, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy, and which action shall, at the request of either party to such action, be tried by the court with a jury. The proceedings shall be governed by the same legal burdens of proof specified in paragraph (2)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811df6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Relief</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The court shall have jurisdiction to grant all relief necessary to make the employee whole, including injunctive relief and compensatory damages, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811df7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> reinstatement with the same seniority status that the employee would have had, but for the discharge or discrimination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811df8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount of back pay, with interest; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id14811df9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discharge or discrimination, including litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dfa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dfb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Unless the complainant brings an action under paragraph (4), any person adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order issued under paragraph (3) may obtain review of the order in the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the violation, with respect to which the order was issued, allegedly occurred or the circuit in which the complainant resided on the date of such violation. The petition for review must be filed not later than 60 days after the date of the issuance of the final order of the Secretary. Review shall conform to chapter 7 of title 5. The commencement of proceedings under this subparagraph shall not, unless ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dfc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> No judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An order of the Secretary with respect to which review could have been obtained under subparagraph (A) shall not be subject to judicial review in any criminal or other civil proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dfd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever any person has failed to comply with an order issued under paragraph (3), the Secretary may file a civil action in the United States district court for the district in which the violation was found to occur, or in the United States district court for the District of Columbia, to enforce such order. In actions brought under this paragraph, the district courts shall have jurisdiction to grant all appropriate relief including, but not limited to, injunctive relief and compensatory damages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dfe-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil action to require compliance</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811dff-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person on whose behalf an order was issued under paragraph (3) may commence a civil action against the person to whom such order was issued to require compliance with such order. The appropriate United States district court shall have jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties, to enforce such order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e00-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/b/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Award</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The court, in issuing any final order under this paragraph, may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorneys’ and expert witness fees) to any party whenever the court determines such award is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e01-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of section</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e02-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section preempts or diminishes any other safeguards against discrimination, demotion, discharge, suspension, threats, harassment, reprimand, retaliation, or any other manner of discrimination provided by Federal or State law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e03-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights of employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any employee under any Federal or State law or under any collective bargaining agreement. The rights and remedies in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e04-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any nondiscretionary duty imposed by this section shall be enforceable in a mandamus proceeding brought under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1361">section 1361 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14811e05-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s399d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an employee of an entity engaged in the manufacture, processing, packing, transporting, distribution, reception, holding, or importation of food who, acting without direction from such entity (or such entity’s agent), deliberately causes a violation of any requirement relating to any violation or alleged violation of any order, rule, regulation, standard, or ban under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14811e06-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675/s1013">June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1013</ref>, formerly § 1012, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/353/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 111–353, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3968">124 Stat. 3968</ref>; renumbered § 1013, <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIII/s3073/b/1">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title III, § 3073(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1137">130 Stat. 1137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14811e07-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14811e08-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14811e09-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in this section to be construed to alter jurisdiction and authorities established under certain other Acts or in a manner inconsistent with international agreements to which the United States is a party, see sections 2251 and 2252 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
