<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id148367ed-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s455"><num value="455">§ 455.</num><heading> Inspection in official establishments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id148367ee-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s455/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Ante mortem inspection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of preventing the entry into or flow or movement in commerce of, or the burdening of commerce by, any poultry product which is capable of use as human food and is adulterated, the Secretary shall, where and to the extent considered by him necessary, cause to be made by inspectors ante mortem inspection of poultry in each official establishment processing poultry or poultry products for commerce or otherwise subject to inspection under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id148367ef-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s455/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Post mortem inspection; quarantine, segregation, and reinspection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, whenever processing operations are being conducted, shall cause to be made by inspectors post mortem inspection of the carcass of each bird processed, and at any time such quarantine, segregation, and reinspection as he deems necessary of poultry and poultry products capable of use as human food in each official establishment processing such poultry or poultry products for commerce or otherwise subject to inspection under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id148367f0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s455/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Condemnation; appeal; reprocessing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All poultry carcasses and parts thereof and other poultry products found to be adulterated shall be condemned and shall, if no appeal be taken from such determination of condemnation, be destroyed for human food purposes under the supervision of an inspector: <i>Provided</i>, That carcasses, parts, and products, which may by reprocessing be made not adulterated, need not be so condemned and destroyed if so reprocessed under the supervision of an inspector and thereafter found to be not adulterated. If an appeal be taken from such determination, the carcasses, parts, or products shall be appropriately marked and segregated pending completion of an appeal inspection, which appeal shall be at the cost of the appellant if the Secretary determines that the appeal is frivolous. If the determination of condemnation is sustained the carcasses, parts, and products shall be destroyed for human food purposes under the supervision of an inspector.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id148367f1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/172/s6">Pub. L. 85–172, § 6</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/443">71 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s6">Pub. L. 90–492, § 6</ref>, <date date="1968-08-18">Aug. 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/798">82 Stat. 798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id148367f2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id148367f3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id148367f4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Par. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s6/a">Pub. L. 90–492, § 6(a)</ref>, substituted “of, or the burdening of commerce by, any poultry product which is capable of use as human food and is adulterated,” for “or a designated major consuming area of any poultry product which is unwholesome or adulterated,” “each official establishment” for “any official establishment”, and “otherwise subject to inspection under this chapter” for “in, or for marketing in a designated city or area”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s6/b">Pub. L. 90–492, § 6(b)</ref>, substituted “segregation, and reinspection” for “segregation, reinspection”, and “otherwise subject to inspection under this chapter” for “in, or for marketing in a designated city or area”, and inserted “capable of use as human food” after “necessary of poultry and poultry products”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s6/c">Pub. L. 90–492, § 6(c)</ref>, inserted “other” before “poultry products”, and substituted “to be adulterated” for “to be unwholesome or adulterated”, “made not adulterated” for “made not unwholesome and not adulterated”, and “to be not adulterated” for “to be not unwholesome and not adulterated”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id148367f5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id148367f6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/492">Pub. L. 90–492</ref> effective <date date="1968-08-18">Aug. 18, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s20">section 20 of Pub. L. 90–492</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">section 451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id148367f7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Chapter Requirements to Birds of the Order Ratitae</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/387/s1/a/tVII/s752">Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VII, § 752]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1549">114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–41, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/387/s1/a/tVII/s752">“Effective 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>] and continuing for the remainder of fiscal year 2001 and each subsequent fiscal year, establishments in the United States that slaughter or process birds of the order Ratitae, such as ostriches, emus and rheas, and squab, for distribution in commerce as human food shall be subject to the ante mortem and post mortem inspection, reinspection, and sanitation requirements of the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">21 U.S.C. 451</ref> et seq.) rather than the voluntary poultry inspection program of the Department of Agriculture under section 203 of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1622">7 U.S.C. 1622</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
