<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id148821ab-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s467d"><num value="467d">§ 467d.</num><heading> Administration and enforcement; applicability of penalty provisions; conduct of inquiries; power and jurisdiction of courts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the efficient administration and enforcement of this chapter, the provision (including penalties) of sections 46, 48, 49 and 50 of title 15 (except paragraphs (c) through (h) of section 46 and the last paragraph of section 49 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002131">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002131"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 15), and the provisions of section 409(<i>l</i>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002131">1</ref> of title 47, are made applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Secretary in administering and enforcing the provisions of this chapter and to any person with respect to whom such authority is exercised. The Secretary, in person or by such agents as he may designate, may prosecute any inquiry necessary to his duties under this chapter in any part of the United States, and the powers conferred by said sections 49 and 50 of title 15 on the district courts of the United States may be exercised for the purposes of this chapter by any court designated in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s467c">section 467c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id148821ac-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/172/s22">Pub. L. 85–172, § 22</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/492/s17">Pub. L. 90–492, § 17</ref>, <date date="1968-08-18">Aug. 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/807">82 Stat. 807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id148821ad-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id148821ae-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id148821af-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The last paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s49">section 49 of title 15</ref>, and the provisions of section 409(<i>l</i>) of title 47, referred to in text, which related to immunity of witnesses, were repealed by sections 211 and 242, respectively, of <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, title II, <ref href="/us/stat/84/929">84 Stat. 929</ref>, 930. For provisions relating to immunity of witnesses, see section 6001 et seq. of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
