<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id148d0496-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s641"><num value="641">§ 641.</num><heading> Prohibition of subchapter I inspection of articles not intended for use as human food; de­naturation or other identification prior to distribution in commerce; inedible articles</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Inspection shall not be provided under subchapter I of this chapter at any establishment for the slaughter of cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, or other equines, or the preparation of any carcasses or parts or products of such animals, which are not intended for use as human food, but such articles shall, prior to their offer for sale or transportation in commerce, unless naturally inedible by humans, be denatured or otherwise identified as prescribed by regulations of the Secretary to deter their use for human food. No person, firm, or corporation shall buy, sell, transport, or offer for sale or transportation, or receive for transportation, in commerce, or import, any carcasses, parts thereof, meat or meat food products of any such animals, which are not intended for use as human food unless they are denatured or otherwise identified as required by the regulations of the Secretary or are naturally inedible by humans.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id148d0497-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, title II, § 201, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/201/s14">Pub. L. 90–201, § 14</ref>, <date date="1967-12-15">Dec. 15, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/593">81 Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id148d0498-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id148d0499-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id148d049a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter effective <date date="1967-12-15">Dec. 15, 1967</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/201/s20">section 20 of Pub. L. 90–201</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s601">section 601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
