<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14a01734-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824"><num value="824">§ 824.</num><heading> Denial, revocation, or suspension of registration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a01735-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grounds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A registration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823">section 823 of this title</ref> to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance or a list I chemical may be suspended or revoked by the Attorney General upon a finding that the registrant—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01736-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has materially falsified any application filed pursuant to or required by this subchapter or subchapter II;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01737-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has been convicted of a felony under this subchapter or subchapter II or any other law of the United States, or of any State, relating to any substance defined in this subchapter as a controlled substance or a list I chemical;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01738-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has had his State license or registration suspended, revoked, or denied by competent State authority and is no longer authorized by State law to engage in the manufacturing, distribution, or dispensing of controlled substances or list I chemicals or has had the suspension, revocation, or denial of his registration recommended by competent State authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01739-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> has committed such acts as would render his registration under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823">section 823 of this title</ref> inconsistent with the public interest as determined under such section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a0173a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> has been excluded (or directed to be excluded) from participation in a program pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7/a">section 1320a–7(a) of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A registration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/h">section 823(h) of this title</ref> to dispense a narcotic drug for maintenance treatment or detoxification treatment may be suspended or revoked by the Attorney General upon a finding that the registrant has failed to comply with any standard referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/h">section 823(h) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a0173b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limits of revocation or suspension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may limit revocation or suspension of a registration to the particular controlled substance or list I chemical with respect to which grounds for revocation or suspension exist.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a0173c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Service of show cause order; proceedings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a0173d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before taking action pursuant to this section, or pursuant to a denial of registration under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823">section 823 of this title</ref>, the Attorney General shall serve upon the applicant or registrant an order to show cause why registration should not be denied, revoked, or suspended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a0173e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An order to show cause under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a0173f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contain a statement of the basis for the denial, revocation, or suspension, including specific citations to any laws or regulations alleged to be violated by the applicant or registrant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01740-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> direct the applicant or registrant to appear before the Attorney General at a time and place stated in the order, but not less than 30 days after the date of receipt of the order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a01741-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notify the applicant or registrant of the opportunity to submit a corrective action plan on or before the date of appearance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a01742-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon review of any corrective action plan submitted by an applicant or registrant pursuant to paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall determine whether denial, revocation, or suspension proceedings should be discontinued, or deferred for the purposes of modification, amendment, or clarification to such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a01743-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Proceedings to deny, revoke, or suspend shall be conducted pursuant to this section in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. Such proceedings shall be independent of, and not in lieu of, criminal prosecutions or other proceedings under this subchapter or any other law of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a01744-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to the issuance of an immediate suspension order under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a01745-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of registration in cases of imminent danger</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a01746-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Attorney General may, in his discretion, suspend any registration simultaneously with the institution of proceedings under this section, in cases where he finds that there is an imminent danger to the public health or safety. A failure to comply with a standard referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/h">section 823(h) of this title</ref> may be treated under this subsection as grounds for immediate suspension of a registration granted under such section. A suspension under this subsection shall continue in effect until the conclusion of such proceedings, including judicial review thereof, unless sooner withdrawn by the Attorney General or dissolved by a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a01747-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In this subsection, the phrase “imminent danger to the public health or safety” means that, due to the failure of the registrant to maintain effective controls against diversion or otherwise comply with the obligations of a registrant under this subchapter or subchapter II, there is a substantial likelihood of an immediate threat that death, serious bodily harm, or abuse of a controlled substance will occur in the absence of an immediate suspension of the registration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a01748-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension and revocation of quotas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The suspension or revocation of a registration under this section shall operate to suspend or revoke any quota applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s826">section 826 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a01749-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Disposition of controlled substances or list I chemicals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event the Attorney General suspends or revokes a registration granted under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823">section 823 of this title</ref>, all controlled substances or list I chemicals owned or possessed by the registrant pursuant to such registration at the time of suspension or the effective date of the revocation order, as the case may be, may, in the discretion of the Attorney General, be placed under seal. No disposition may be made of any controlled substances or list I chemicals under seal until the time for taking an appeal has elapsed or until all appeals have been concluded except that a court, upon application therefor, may at any time order the sale of perishable controlled substances or list I chemicals. Any such order shall require the deposit of the proceeds of the sale with the court. Upon a revocation order becoming final, all such controlled substances or list I chemicals (or proceeds of sale deposited in court) shall be forfeited to the United States; and the Attorney General shall dispose of such controlled substances or list I chemicals in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s881/e">section 881(e) of this title</ref>. All right, title, and interest in such controlled substances or list I chemicals shall vest in the United States upon a revocation order becoming final.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a0174a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Seizure or placement under seal of controlled substances or list I chemicals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may, in his discretion, seize or place under seal any controlled substances or list I chemicals owned or possessed by a registrant whose registration has expired or who has ceased to practice or do business in the manner contemplated by his registration. Such controlled substances or list I chemicals shall be held for the benefit of the registrant, or his successor in interest. The Attorney General shall notify a registrant, or his successor in interest, who has any controlled substance or list I chemical seized or placed under seal of the procedures to be followed to secure the return of the controlled substance or list I chemical and the conditions under which it will be returned. The Attorney General may not dispose of any controlled substance or list I chemical seized or placed under seal under this subsection until the expiration of one hundred and eighty days from the date such substance or chemical was seized or placed under seal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a0174b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Order to prohibit registration based on prior history</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may issue an order to prohibit, conditionally or unconditionally, and permanently or for such period as the Attorney General may determine, any person from being registered under this subchapter to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance or a list I chemical, if the Attorney General finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a0174c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such person meets or has met any of the conditions for suspension or revocation of registration under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14a0174d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s824/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such person has a history of prior suspensions or revocations of registration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14a0174e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/513/tII/s304">Pub. L. 91–513, title II, § 304</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1255">84 Stat. 1255</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/281/s4">Pub. L. 93–281, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/125">88 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII">Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 304, 512, 513, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2050">98 Stat. 2050</ref>, 2073; <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s8/j">Pub. L. 100–93, § 8(j)</ref>, <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/695">101 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s3/d">Pub. L. 103–200, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2337">107 Stat. 2337</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXXIII/s330024/e">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330024(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2151">108 Stat. 2151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXV/s3502/b">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXV, § 3502(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1227">114 Stat. 1227</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/145/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 114–145, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="2016-04-19">Apr. 19, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/354">130 Stat. 354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/36/s2">Pub. L. 117–36, § 2</ref>, <date date="2021-08-06">Aug. 6, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/328">135 Stat. 328</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/215/tI/s103/b/1/C">Pub. L. 117–215, title I, § 103(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-02">Dec. 2, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2263">136 Stat. 2263</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tI/s1262/b/1">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title I, § 1262(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5682">136 Stat. 5682</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/26/s4/2/B/i">Pub. L. 119–26, § 4(2)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), <date date="2025-07-16">July 16, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/416">139 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14a0174f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14a01750-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14a01751-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (2), (c)(4), (d)(2), and (h), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, and is popularly known as the “Controlled Substances Act”. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see second paragraph of Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter II, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (2) and (d)(2), was in the original “title III”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1285">84 Stat. 1285</ref>. Part A of title III comprises subchapter II of this chapter. For classification of Part B, consisting of sections 1101 to 1105 of title III, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id14a01752-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsecs. (a), (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/26/s4/2/B/i">Pub. L. 119–26, § 4(2)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1262/b/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1262(b)(1)</ref>. See 2022 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1262/b/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1262(b)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/26/s4/2/B/i">Pub. L. 119–26, § 4(2)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), in concluding provisions, substituted “823(h)” for “823(h)(1)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/215">Pub. L. 117–215</ref>, in concluding provisions, substituted “823(h)(1)” for “823(g)(1)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1262/b/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1262(b)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/26/s4/2/B/i">Pub. L. 119–26, § 4(2)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), substituted “823(h)” for “823(h)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/215">Pub. L. 117–215</ref> substituted “823(h)(1)” for “823(g)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/117/36">Pub. L. 117–36</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/145/s2/b">Pub. L. 114–145, § 2(b)</ref>, struck out “The order to show cause shall contain a statement of the basis thereof and shall call upon the applicant or registrant to appear before the Attorney General at a time and place stated in the order, but in no event less than thirty days after the date of receipt of the order. Proceedings to deny, revoke, or suspend shall be conducted pursuant to this section in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. Such proceedings shall be independent of, and not in lieu of, criminal prosecutions or other proceedings under this subchapter or any other law of the United States.” after “denied, revoked, or suspended.”, designated existing provisions as par. (1), and added pars. (2) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/145/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 114–145, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/s3502/b/1">Pub. L. 106–310, § 3502(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/g/1">section 823(g)(1) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/g">section 823(g) of this title</ref>” in two places in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/s3502/b/2">Pub. L. 106–310, § 3502(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/g/1">section 823(g)(1) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/g">section 823(g) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> inserted “or chemical” after “such substance” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s3/d/1">Pub. L. 103–200, § 3(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “or a list I chemical” after “controlled substance” in introductory provisions and par. (2) and inserted “or list I chemicals” after “controlled substances” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s3/d/2">Pub. L. 103–200, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, inserted “or list I chemical” after “controlled substance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s3/d/3">Pub. L. 103–200, § 3(d)(3)</ref>, inserted “or list I chemicals” after “controlled substances” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s3/d/4">Pub. L. 103–200, § 3(d)(4)</ref>, inserted “or list I chemicals” after “controlled substances” in two places and “or list I chemical” after “controlled substance” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/93">Pub. L. 100–93</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s512/1">Pub. L. 98–473, § 512(1)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to suspension, etc., recommended by competent State authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s512/2">Pub. L. 98–473, § 512(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s304">Pub. L. 98–473, § 304</ref>, inserted provisions relating to vesting of right, title, and interest in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s513">Pub. L. 98–473, § 513</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/281/s4/a">Pub. L. 93–281, § 4(a)</ref>, provided for revocation or suspension of a registration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s823/g">section 823(g) of this title</ref> for failure of a registrant to comply with standards referred to in such section 823(g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/281/s4/b">Pub. L. 93–281, § 4(b)</ref>, substituted “A suspension under this subsection” for “Such suspension” in third sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14a01753-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14a01754-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/119/26/s4">Pub. L. 119–26, § 4</ref>, <date date="2025-07-16">July 16, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/416">139 Stat. 416</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 4(2)(B)(i), (ii) is effective as if included in the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/117/328">Pub. L. 117–328</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14a01755-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s330024/f">section 330024(f) of Pub. L. 103–322</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802">section 802 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14a01756-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/200">Pub. L. 103–200</ref> effective on date that is 120 days after <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/200/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 103–200</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802">section 802 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id14a01757-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/93">Pub. L. 100–93</ref> effective at end of fourteen-day period beginning <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, and inapplicable to administrative proceedings commenced before end of such period, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 100–93</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7">section 1320a–7 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id14a01758-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on first day of seventh calendar month that begins after <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/s704">section 704 of Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id14a01759-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Provisional Registration</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Applicability of this section to provisional registrations, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/s703">section 703 of Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s822">section 822 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
