<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14a98cef-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851"><num value="851">§ 851.</num><heading> Proceedings to establish prior convictions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a98cf0-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Information filed by United States Attorney</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a98cf1-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No person who stands convicted of an offense under this part shall be sentenced to increased punishment by reason of one or more prior convictions, unless before trial, or before entry of a plea of guilty, the United States attorney files an information with the court (and serves a copy of such information on the person or counsel for the person) stating in writing the previous convictions to be relied upon. Upon a showing by the United States attorney that facts regarding prior convictions could not with due diligence be obtained prior to trial or before entry of a plea of guilty, the court may postpone the trial or the taking of the plea of guilty for a reasonable period for the purpose of obtaining such facts. Clerical mistakes in the information may be amended at any time prior to the pronouncement of sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a98cf2-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An information may not be filed under this section if the increased punishment which may be imposed is imprisonment for a term in excess of three years unless the person either waived or was afforded prosecution by indictment for the offense for which such increased punishment may be imposed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a98cf3-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Affirmation or denial of previous conviction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the United States attorney files an information under this section, the court shall after conviction but before pronouncement of sentence inquire of the person with respect to whom the information was filed whether he affirms or denies that he has been previously convicted as alleged in the information, and shall inform him that any challenge to a prior conviction which is not made before sentence is imposed may not thereafter be raised to attack the sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14a98cf4-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial; written response; hearing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a98cf5-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the person denies any allegation of the information of prior conviction, or claims that any conviction alleged is invalid, he shall file a written response to the information. A copy of the response shall be served upon the United States attorney. The court shall hold a hearing to determine any issues raised by the response which would except the person from increased punishment. The failure of the United States attorney to include in the information the complete criminal record of the person or any facts in addition to the convictions to be relied upon shall not constitute grounds for invalidating the notice given in the information required by subsection (a)(1). The hearing shall be before the court without a jury and either party may introduce evidence. Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the United States attorney shall have the burden of proof beyond a reasonable doubt on any issue of fact. At the request of either party, the court shall enter findings of fact and conclusions of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14a98cf6-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person claiming that a conviction alleged in the information was obtained in violation of the Constitution of the United States shall set forth his claim, and the factual basis therefor, with particularity in his response to the information. The person shall have the burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence on any issue of fact raised by the response. Any challenge to a prior conviction, not raised by response to the information before an increased sentence is imposed in reliance thereon, shall be waived unless good cause be shown for failure to make a timely challenge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14abfdf7-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Imposition of sentence</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14abfdf8-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the person files no response to the information, or if the court determines, after hearing, that the person is subject to increased punishment by reason of prior convictions, the court shall proceed to impose sentence upon him as provided by this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id14abfdf9-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the court determines that the person has not been convicted as alleged in the information, that a conviction alleged in the information is invalid, or that the person is otherwise not subject to an increased sentence as a matter of law, the court shall, at the request of the United States attorney, postpone sentence to allow an appeal from that determination. If no such request is made, the court shall impose sentence as provided by this part. The person may appeal from an order postponing sentence as if sentence had been pronounced and a final judgment of conviction entered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14abfdfa-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s851/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Statute of limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person who stands convicted of an offense under this part may challenge the validity of any prior conviction alleged under this section which occurred more than five years before the date of the information alleging such prior conviction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14abfdfb-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/513/tII/s411">Pub. L. 91–513, title II, § 411</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1269">84 Stat. 1269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14abfdfc-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id14abfdfd-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id14abfdfe-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on first day of seventh calendar month that begins after <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/s704">section 704 of Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
