<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id14b0b926-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865"><num value="865">§ 865.</num><heading> Smuggling methamphetamine or methamphetamine precursor chemicals into the United States while using facilitated entry programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14b0b927-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Enhanced prison sentence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sentence of imprisonment imposed on a person convicted of an offense under the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.) or the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">21 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.), involving methamphetamine or any listed chemical that is defined in section 102(33) of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802/33">21 U.S.C. 802(33)</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002160">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002160"><num>1</num> So in original. A second closing parenthesis probably should precede the comma.</note> shall, if the offense is committed under the circumstance described in subsection (b), be increased by a consecutive term of imprisonment of not more than 15 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14b0b928-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Circumstances</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the circumstance described in this subsection is that the offense described in subsection (a) was committed by a person who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14b0b929-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> was enrolled in, or who was acting on behalf of any person or entity enrolled in, any dedicated commuter lane, alternative or accelerated inspection system, or other facilitated entry program administered or approved by the Federal Government for use in entering the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id14b0b92a-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> committed the offense while entering the United States, using such lane, system, or program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id14b0b92b-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d" identifier="/us/usc/t21/s865/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent ineligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person whose term of imprisonment is increased under subsection (a) shall be permanently and irrevocably barred from being eligible for or using any lane, system, or program described in subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id14b0b92c-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tVII/s731">Pub. L. 109–177, title VII, § 731</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/270">120 Stat. 270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id14b0b92d-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id14b0b92e-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id14b0b92f-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1285">84 Stat. 1285</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter II (§ 951 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">section 951 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id14b0b930-3a70-11f1-b089-c1e1e512a22d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and also as part of the Combat Methamphetamine Epidemic Act of 2005, and not as part of the Controlled Substances Act which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
