<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id122ecb6d-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s1909"><num value="1909">§ 1909.</num><heading> Requirements of depository libraries; reports on conditions; investigations; termination; replacement</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Only a library able to provide custody and service for depository materials and located in an area where it can best serve the public need, and within an area not already adequately served by existing depository libraries may be designated by Senators, Representatives, the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, the Commissioner of the District of Columbia,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002013"><num>1</num> See Transfer of Functions note below.</note> or the Governors of Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands as a depository of Government publications. The designated depository libraries shall report to the Superintendent of Documents at least every two years concerning their condition.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Superintendent of Documents shall make firsthand investigation of conditions for which need is indicated and include the results of investigations in his annual report. When he ascertains that the number of books in a depository library is below ten thousand, other than Government publications, or it has ceased to be maintained so as to be accessible to the public, or that the Government publications which have been furnished the library have not been properly maintained, he shall delete the library from the list of depository libraries if the library fails to correct the unsatisfactory conditions within six months. The Representative or the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico in whose area the library is located or the Senator who made the designation, or a successor of the Senator, and, in the case of a library in the District of Columbia, the Commissioner of the District of Columbia, and, in the case of a library in Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands, the Governor, shall be notified and shall then be authorized to designate another library within the area served by him, which shall meet the conditions herein required, but which may not be in excess of the number of depository libraries authorized by laws within the State, district, territory, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, as the case may be.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id122ecb6e-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1285">82 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id122ecb6f-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id122ecb70-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 86 (<ref href="/us/act/1895-01-12/ch23/s70">Jan. 12, 1895, ch. 23, § 70</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/612">28 Stat. 612</ref>; <date date="1962-08-09">Aug. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/579/s6">Pub. L. 87–579, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/354">76 Stat. 354</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id122ecb71-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id122ecb72-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Commissioner of District of Columbia, as established under Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1967, eff. <date date="1967-11-03">Nov. 3, 1967</date> (in part), 32 F.R. 11669, <ref href="/us/stat/81/948">81 Stat. 948</ref>, abolished as of noon <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/93/198/tVII/s711">Pub. L. 93–198, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="1973-12-24">Dec. 24, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/818">87 Stat. 818</ref>, and replaced by office of Mayor of District of Columbia by <ref href="/us/pl/93/198/s421">section 421 of Pub. L. 93–198</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
