<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1238681d-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2111"><num value="2111">§ 2111.</num><heading> Material accepted for deposit</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1238681e-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2111/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>When the Archivist considers it to be in the public interest the Archivist may accept for deposit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1238681f-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2111/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the papers and other historical materials of a President or former President of the United States, or other official or former official of the Government, and other papers relating to and contemporary with a President or former President of the United States, subject to restrictions agreeable to the Archivist as to their use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id12386820-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2111/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> recorded information (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3301/a/2">section 3301(a)(2) of this title</ref>) from private sources that are appropriate for preservation by the Government as evidence of its organization, functions, policies, decisions, procedures, and transactions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id12386821-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2111/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall not apply in the case of any Presidential records which are subject to the provisions of chapter 22 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id12386822-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1288">82 Stat. 1288</ref>, § 2107; <ref href="/us/pl/95/591/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 95–591, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2528">92 Stat. 2528</ref>; renumbered § 2111 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/tI">Pub. L. 98–497, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(5), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2280">98 Stat. 2280</ref>, 2286; <ref href="/us/pl/113/187/s3/b">Pub. L. 113–187, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2008">128 Stat. 2008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id12386823-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id12386824-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on 44 U.S. Code 1964 ed., § 397(e) (<ref href="/us/act/1949-06-30/ch288">June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title V, § 507, as added <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-05/ch849/s6/d">Sept. 5, 1950, ch. 849, § 6(d)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/583">64 Stat. 583</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-12/ch703/s1/p">July 12, 1952, ch. 703, § 1(p)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/594">66 Stat. 594</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-12/ch329">July 12, 1955, ch. 329</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/297">69 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-12/ch859">Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 859</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/695">69 Stat. 695</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id12386825-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id12386826-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2111 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2115">section 2115 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id12386827-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/187">Pub. L. 113–187</ref> amended section generally, substituting subsecs. (a) and (b) for similar provisions contained in pars. (1) and (2) and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/497/s107/a/5">Pub. L. 98–497, § 107(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “Archivist” for “Administrator of General Services” in provisions preceding par. (1), and substituted “Archivist” for “Administrator” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/591">Pub. L. 95–591</ref> inserted provision excluding Presidential records which are subject to provisions of chapter 22 of this title from application of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id12386828-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id12386829-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/497">Pub. L. 98–497</ref> effective <date date="1985-04-01">Apr. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/s301">section 301 of Pub. L. 98–497</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id1238682a-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/591">Pub. L. 95–591</ref> effective with respect to Presidential records created during a term of office of President beginning on or after <date date="1981-01-20">Jan. 20, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/591/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 95–591</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id1238682b-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/526/tI">Pub. L. 93–526, title I</ref>, §§ 101–106, <date date="1974-12-19">Dec. 19, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1695-1698">88 Stat. 1695–1698</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/tI/s107/c">Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2291">98 Stat. 2291</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dF/tV/s543/a">Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/346">118 Stat. 346</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/199/dF/tV/s543/a">
<inline>“That this Act [enacting this note, former sections 3315 to 3324 of this title, and provisions set out as a note under former <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3315">section 3315 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act’.</inline>
<title style="-uslm-lc:I74"><num value="I">“Title I—</num><heading class="centered small-caps">Preservation of Presidential Recordings and Materials</heading><level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“delivery and retention of certain presidential materials</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="101">“Sec. 101.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other law or any agreement or understanding made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2111">section 2111 of title 44</ref>, United States Code any Federal employee in possession shall deliver, and the Archivist of the United States (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Archivist’) shall receive, obtain, or retain, complete possession and control of all original tape recordings of conversations which were recorded or caused to be recorded by any officer or employee of the Federal Government and which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> involve former President Richard M. Nixon or other individuals who, at the time of the conversation, were employed by the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> were recorded in the White House or in the office of the President in the Executive Office Buildings located in Washington, District of Columbia; Camp David, Maryland; Key Biscayne, Florida; or San Clemente, California; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> were recorded during the period beginning <date date="1969-01-20">January 20, 1969</date>, and ending <date date="1974-08-09">August 9, 1974</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other law or any agreement or understanding made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2111">section 2111 of title 44</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist shall receive, retain, or make reasonable efforts to obtain, complete possession and control of all papers, documents, memorandums, transcripts, and other objects and materials which constitute the Presidential historical materials of Richard M. Nixon, covering the period beginning <date date="1969-01-20">January 20, 1969</date>, and ending <date date="1974-08-09">August 9, 1974</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘historical materials’ has the meaning given it by <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2101">section 2101 of title 44</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“availability of certain presidential materials</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="102">“Sec. 102.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> None of the tape recordings or other materials referred to in section 101 shall be destroyed, except as hereafter may be provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, any other law, or any agreement or understanding made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2111">section 2111 of title 44</ref>, United States Code, the tape recordings and other materials referred to in section 101 shall, immediately upon the date of enactment of this title, be made available, subject to any rights, defenses, or privileges which the Federal Government or any person may invoke, for use in any judicial proceeding or otherwise subject to court subpena or other legal process. Any request by the Office of Watergate Special Prosecution Force, whether by court subpena or other lawful process, for access to such recordings or materials shall at all times have priority over any other request for such recordings or materials.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Richard M. Nixon, or any person whom he may designate in writing, shall at all times have access to the tape recordings and other materials referred to in section 101 for any purpose which is consistent with the provisions of this title, subsequent and subject to the regulations which the Archivist shall issue pursuant to section 103.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> Any agency or department in the executive branch of the Federal Government shall at all times have access to the tape recordings and other materials referred to in section 101 for lawful Government use, subject to the regulations which the Archivist shall issue pursuant to section 103.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“regulations to protect certain tape recordings and other materials</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="103">“Sec. 103.</num><content> The Archivist shall issue at the earliest possible date such regulations as may be necessary to assure the protection of the tape recordings and other materials referred to in section 101 from loss or destruction, and to prevent access to such recordings and materials by unauthorized persons. The Archivist may transfer such recordings and materials to a Presidential archival depository in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2112">section 2112 of title 44</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“regulations relating to public access</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="104">“Sec. 104.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> The Archivist shall, within ninety days after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="1974-12-19">Dec. 19, 1974</date>], submit to each House of the Congress a report proposing and explaining regulations that would provide public access to the tape recordings and other materials referred to in section 101. Such regulations shall take into account the following factors:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the need to provide the public with the full truth, at the earliest reasonable date, of the abuses of governmental power popularly identified under the generic term ‘Watergate’;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the need to make such recordings and materials available for use in judicial proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the need to prevent general access, except in accordance with appropriate procedures established for use in judicial proceedings to information relating to the Nation’s security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the need to protect every individual’s right to a fair and impartial trial;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the need to protect any party’s opportunity to assert any legally or constitutionally based right or privilege which would prevent or otherwise limit access to such recordings and materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the need to provide public access to those materials which have general historical significance, and which are not likely to be related to the need described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the need to give to Richard M. Nixon, or his heirs, for his sole custody and use, tape recordings and other materials which are not likely to be related to the need described in paragraph (1) and are not otherwise of general historical significance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The regulations proposed by the Archivist in the report required by subsection (a) shall not take effect until the expiration of the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of the Congress after the date of the submission of such regulations to each House of the Congress. For the purposes of this subsection, continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die, but the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain are excluded.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The provisions of this title shall not apply, on and after the date upon which regulations proposed by the Administrator take effect under subsection (b), to any tape recordings or other materials given to Richard M. Nixon, or his heirs, pursuant to subsection (a)(7).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The provisions of this title shall not in any way affect the rights, limitations or exemptions applicable under the Freedom of Information Act, 5 U.S.C. § 552 et seq.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“judicial review</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="105">“Sec. 105.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear challenges to the legal or constitutional validity of this title or of any regulation issued under the authority granted by this title, and any action or proceeding involving the question of title, ownership, custody, possession, or control of any tape recording or material referred to in section 101 or involving payment of any just compensation which may be due in connection therewith. Any such challenge shall be treated by the court as a matter requiring immediate consideration and resolution, and such challenge shall have priority on the docket of such court over other cases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> If, under the procedures established by subsection (a), a judicial decision is rendered that a particular provision of this title, or a particular regulation issued under the authority granted by this title, is unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, such decision shall not affect in any way the validity or enforcement of any other provision of this title or any regulation issued under the authority granted by this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> If a final decision of such court holds that any provision of this title has deprived an individual of private property without just compensation, then there shall be paid out of the general fund of the Treasury of the United States such amount or amounts as may be adjudged just by that Court.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“authorization of appropriations</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="106">“Sec. 106.</num><content> There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this title.”</content>
</section>
</level>
</title>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dF/tV/s543/b">Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title V, § 543(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/346">118 Stat. 346</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/199/dF/tV/s543/b">“Nothing in section 103 of the Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act (<ref href="/us/pl/93/526">Public Law 93–526</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2111">44 U.S.C. 2111</ref> note), as amended by subsection (a), may be construed as affecting public access to the recordings and materials referred to in that section as provided in regulations promulgated pursuant to section 104 of such Act.]”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id1238682c-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id1238682d-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Classified National Security Information</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions authorizing Archivist to review, downgrade, and declassify information of former Presidents under control of Archivist pursuant to this section or provisions set out as a note under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 13526, § 3.5(b), <date date="2009-12-29">Dec. 29, 2009</date>, 75 F.R. 718, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
