<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id123f93a2-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s2307"><num value="2307">§ 2307.</num><heading> Trust fund account; disbursements; sales of publications and releases</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The income from trust funds held by the Board and the proceeds from the sale of securities and other personal property, as and when collected, shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States in a trust fund account to be known as the National Archives Trust Fund, subject to disbursement on the basis of certified vouchers of the Archivist of the United States (or his designee) for activities approved by the Board and in the interest of the national archival and records activities administered by the National Archives and Records Administration, including but not restricted to the preparation and publication of special works, and collections of sources and the preparation, duplication, editing, and release of historical photographic materials and sound recordings. The Archivist may sell publications and releases authorized by this section and paid for out of the income derived from trust funds at a price which will cover their cost, plus 10 percent, and moneys received from these sales shall be paid into, administered, and expended as part of the National Archives Trust Fund.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id123f93a3-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1293">82 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 98–497, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2294">98 Stat. 2294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id123f93a4-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id123f93a5-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 300ee (<ref href="/us/act/1941-07-09/ch284/s5">July 9, 1941, ch. 284, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/581">55 Stat. 581</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id123f93a6-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id123f93a7-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/497">Pub. L. 98–497</ref> substituted “on the basis of certified vouchers of the Archivist of the United States (or his designee) for activities approved by the Board and in the interest of the national archival and records activities administered by the National Archives and Records Administration” for “by the Division of Disbursement, Treasury Department, on the basis of certified vouchers of the Chairman or his authorized agent, unless otherwise restricted by the instrument of gift or bequest, for and in the interest of the national archival and records activities administered by the General Services Administration” and “Archivist” for “Chairman” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id123f93a8-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id123f93a9-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/497">Pub. L. 98–497</ref> effective <date date="1985-04-01">Apr. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/s301">section 301 of Pub. L. 98–497</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id123f93aa-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id123f93ab-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Division of Disbursement of Treasury Department consolidated into Fiscal Service of Treasury Department by section 1(a)(1) of Reorg. Plan No. III of 1940, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2107, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1231">54 Stat. 1231</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. See <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s306">section 306 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
