<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1216fd62-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s303"><num value="303">§ 303.</num><heading> Director of the Government Publishing Office and Deputy Director of the Government Publishing Office: pay</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The annual rate of pay for the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level II of the Executive Schedule under subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5. The annual rate of pay for the Deputy Director of the Government Publishing Office shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level III of such Executive Schedule.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id1216fd63-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1239">82 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/82/tII/s204/c/1">Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 204(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/421">89 Stat. 421</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tII/s209">Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2274">104 Stat. 2274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s1301/a">Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1033">117 Stat. 1033</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dH/tI/s1301/c">Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)</ref>, (e), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2537">128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1216fd64-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id1216fd65-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 39a (<ref href="/us/pl/88/426/tII/s203/c">Pub. L. 88–426, title II, § 203(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/415">78 Stat. 415</ref>, as amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/206/tII/s219/2">Pub. L. 90–206, title II, § 219(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/639">81 Stat. 639</ref>.)</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id1216fd66-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id1216fd67-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Levels II and III of the Executive Schedule, referred to in text, are set out in sections 5313 and 5314, respectively, of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id1216fd68-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/e">Pub. L. 113–235, § 1301(e)</ref>, substituted “Deputy Director of the Government Publishing Office” for “Deputy Public Printer” in section catchline and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/c">Pub. L. 113–235, § 1301(c)</ref>, substituted “Director of the Government Publishing Office” for “Public Printer” in section catchline and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/83">Pub. L. 108–83</ref> reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The annual rate of pay for the Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level III of the Executive Schedule of subchapter II of chapter 53 of Title 5. The annual rate of pay for the Deputy Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level IV of such Executive Schedule.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/520">Pub. L. 101–520</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The annual rate of pay for the Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5. The annual rate of pay for the Deputy Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level V of such Executive Schedule.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/94/82">Pub. L. 94–82</ref> substituted “pay” for “compensation” in section catchline, and substituted provisions setting the rate of pay for the Public Printer at a rate equal to the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule and the rate of pay for Deputy Public Printer at a rate equal to the rate for level V of such Schedule for provisions setting the compensation of the Public Printer and the Deputy Public Printer at the rate of $28,750 and $27,500 per annum, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1216fd69-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id1216fd6a-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s1301/b">Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1033">117 Stat. 1033</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s1301/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id1216fd6b-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Salary Increases</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Salaries of Public Printer and Deputy Public Printer increased respectively to $77,500 and $72,500 per annum, on recommendation of the President of the United States, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s358">section 358 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Salaries of the Public Printer and Deputy Public Printer increased respectively to $50,000 and $47,500 per annum, on recommendation of the President of the United States, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s358">section 358 of Title 2</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Salaries of the Public Printer and Deputy Public Printer increased respectively from $28,750 and $27,500 to $38,000 and $36,000 per annum, commencing on the first day of the pay period which begins after <date date="1969-02-14">Feb. 14, 1969</date>, on recommendation of the President of the United States, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s358">section 358 of Title 2</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
