<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id121bb8d6-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s317"><num value="317">§ 317.</num><heading> Special policemen</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Government Publishing Office or a delegate of the Director may designate employees of the Government Publishing Office to serve as special policemen to protect persons and property in premises and adjacent areas occupied by or under the control of the Government Publishing Office. Under regulations to be prescribed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office, employees designated as special policemen are authorized to bear and use arms in the performance of their duties; make arrest for violations of laws of the United States, the several States, and the District of Columbia; and enforce the regulations of the Director of the Government Publishing Office, including the removal from Government Publishing Office premises of individuals who violate such regulations. The jurisdiction of special policemen in premises occupied by or under the control of the Government Publishing Office and adjacent areas shall be concurrent with the jurisdiction of the respective law enforcement agencies where the premises are located.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id121bb8d7-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/91/359/s1/a">Pub. L. 91–359, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-07-31">July 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/668">84 Stat. 668</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dH/tI/s1301/b">Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, (c)(1), (i)(9), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2537">128 Stat. 2537</ref>, 2539.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id121bb8d8-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id121bb8d9-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id121bb8da-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/i/9">Pub. L. 113–235, § 1301(i)(9)</ref>, substituted “a delegate of the Director” for “his delegate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/c/1">Pub. L. 113–235, § 1301(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Director of the Government Publishing Office” for “Public Printer” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id121bb8db-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id121bb8dc-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Government Publishing Office” substituted for “Government Printing Office” in text on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/b">section 1301(b) of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
