<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id1259d320-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562"><num value="3562">§ 3562.</num><heading> Coordination and oversight of policies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1259d321-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director shall coordinate and oversee the confidentiality and disclosure policies established by this subchapter. The Director may promulgate rules or provide other guidance to ensure consistent interpretation of this subchapter by the affected agencies. The Director shall develop a process by which the Director designates agencies or organizational units as statistical agencies and units. The Director shall promulgate guidance to implement such process, which shall include specific criteria for such designation and methods by which the Director will ensure transparency in the process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1259d322-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agency Rules</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsection (c), agencies may promulgate rules to implement this subchapter. Rules governing disclosures of information that are authorized by this subchapter shall be promulgated by the agency that originally collected the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1259d323-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review and Approval of Rules</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director shall review any rules proposed by an agency pursuant to this subchapter for consistency with the provisions of this chapter and such rules shall be subject to the approval of the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id1259d324-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1259d325-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The head of each agency shall provide to the Director such reports and other information as the Director requests.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1259d326-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each Designated Statistical Agency (as defined in section 3576(e)) shall report annually to the Director, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the actions it has taken to implement section 3576. The report shall include copies of each written agreement entered into pursuant to section 3576(c)(1) for the applicable year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id1259d327-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3562/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director shall include a summary of reports submitted to the Director under this subsection and actions taken by the Director to advance the purposes of this subchapter in the annual report to Congress on statistical programs prepared under section 3504(e)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id1259d328-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/435/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5546">132 Stat. 5546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id1259d329-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id1259d32a-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id1259d32b-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id1259d32c-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 180 days after <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/435/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 115–435</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2019 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s306">section 306 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
