<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id125c1c60-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575"><num value="3575">§ 3575.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c61-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Federal statistics are an important source of information for public and private decision-makers such as policymakers, consumers, businesses, investors, and workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c62-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Federal statistical agencies should continuously seek to improve their efficiency. Statutory constraints limit the ability of these agencies to share data and thus to achieve higher efficiency for Federal statistical programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c63-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The quality of Federal statistics depends on the willingness of businesses to respond to statistical surveys. Reducing reporting burdens will increase response rates, and therefore lead to more accurate characterizations of the economy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c64-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Enhanced sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics for exclusively statistical purposes will improve their ability to track more accurately the large and rapidly changing nature of United States business. In particular, the statistical agencies will be able to better ensure that businesses are consistently classified in appropriate industries, resolve data anomalies, produce statistical samples that are consistently adjusted for the entry and exit of new businesses in a timely manner, and correct faulty reporting errors quickly and efficiently.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c65-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Congress enacted the International Investment and Trade in Services Survey Act (<ref href="/us/pl/94/472">Public Law 94–472</ref>), which allowed the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics to share data on foreign-owned companies. The Act not only expanded detailed industry coverage from 135 industries to over 800 industries with no increase in the data collected from respondents but also demonstrated how data sharing can result in the creation of valuable data products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id125c1c66-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s3575/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> With part B of this subchapter, the sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics continues to ensure the highest level of confidentiality for respondents to statistical surveys.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id125c1c67-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/435/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 115–435, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5549">132 Stat. 5549</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id125c1c68-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id125c1c69-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id125c1c6a-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The International Investment and Trade in Services Survey Act, referred to in par. (5), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/472">Pub. L. 94–472</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2059">90 Stat. 2059</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 46 (§ 3101 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3101">section 3101 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id125c1c6b-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id125c1c6c-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 180 days after <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/435/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 115–435</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2019 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s306">section 306 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
