<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id122099f1-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s723"><num value="723">§ 723.</num><heading> Memorial addresses: preparation; distribution</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the final adjournment of each session of Congress, there shall be compiled, prepared, printed with illustrations, and bound in cloth in one volume, in the style, form, and manner directed by the Joint Committee on Printing, without extra compensation to any employee, the legislative proceedings of Congress and the exercises at the general memorial services held in the House of Representatives during each session relative to the death of a Member of Congress or a former Member of Congress who served as Speaker, together with all relevant memorial addresses and eulogies published in the Congressional Record during the same session of Congress, and any other matter the Joint Committee considers relevant; and there shall be printed as many copies as needed to supply the total quantity provided for by this section, of which fifty copies, bound in full morocco, with gilt edges, suitably lettered as may be requested, shall be delivered to the family of the deceased, and the remaining copies shall be distributed as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">of all eulogies on deceased Members of Congress to the Vice President and each Senator, Representative, and Resident Commissioner in Congress, one copy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">of the eulogies on deceased Senators there shall be furnished two hundred and fifty copies for each Senator of the State represented by the deceased and twenty copies for each Representative from that State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">of the eulogies on a deceased Representative and Resident Commissioner two hundred and fifty copies for his successor in office; twenty copies for each of the other Representatives, or Resident Commissioner of the State, or insular possession represented by the deceased; and twenty copies for each Senator from that State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The “usual number” of memorial addresses may not be printed.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id122099f2-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1251">82 Stat. 1251</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/51/s101/c">Pub. L. 97–51, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/959">95 Stat. 959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id122099f3-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id122099f4-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on 44 U.S. Code, 1964, ed., § 151 (<ref href="/us/act/1894-08-23/ch307">Aug. 23, 1894, ch. 307</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/447">28 Stat. 447</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1895-01-12/ch23/s73">Jan. 12, 1895, ch. 23, § 73</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/616">28 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-20/ch630">June 20, 1936, ch. 630</ref>, title I, § 1, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1545">49 Stat. 1545</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id122099f5-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id122099f6-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The 1981 amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/51">Pub. L. 97–51</ref> is based on section 4 of House Resolution 23, Ninety–seventh Congress, <date date="1981-03-10">Mar. 10, 1981</date>, as enacted into permanent law by H.R. 4120, as reported <date date="1981-07-09">July 9, 1981</date>, and incorporated by reference in <ref href="/us/pl/97/51/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 97–51</ref>, to be effective as if enacted into law.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id122099f7-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/51">Pub. L. 97–51</ref> inserted “or a former Member of Congress who served as Speaker” after “relative to the death of a Member of Congress”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id122099f8-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id122099f9-e3ef-11ef-8e9f-f6e47fd25777"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Restriction on Number of Bound Eulogies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/59/tVIII">Pub. L. 94–59, title VIII</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/296">89 Stat. 296</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/59/tVIII">“Hereafter, appropriations for authorized printing and binding for Congress shall not be available under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s723">section 723 of title 44</ref> of the United States Code for the printing, publication, and distribution of more than fifty bound eulogies to be delivered to the family of the deceased, and in the case of a deceased Senator or deceased Representative (including Delegates to Congress and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico), there shall be furnished to his successor in office two hundred and fifty copies.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
