<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7468a5ba-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003"><num value="1003">§ 1003.</num><heading> Obligation to make royalty payments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7468a5bb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Importation and Manufacture</inline>.—</heading><content>No person shall import into and distribute, or manufacture and distribute, any digital audio recording device or digital audio recording medium unless such person records the notice specified by this section and subsequently deposits the statements of account and applicable royalty payments for such device or medium specified in section 1004.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7468a5bc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Filing of Notice</inline>.—</heading><content>The importer or manufacturer of any digital audio recording device or digital audio recording medium, within a product category or utilizing a technology with respect to which such manufacturer or importer has not previously filed a notice under this subsection, shall file with the Register of Copyrights a notice with respect to such device or medium, in such form and content as the Register shall prescribe by regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7468a5bd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Filing of Quarterly and Annual Statements of Account.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7468a5be-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Generally</inline>.—</heading><content>Any importer or manufacturer that distributes any digital audio recording device or digital audio recording medium that it manufactured or imported shall file with the Register of Copyrights, in such form and content as the Register shall prescribe by regulation, such quarterly and annual statements of account with respect to such distribution as the Register shall prescribe by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7468a5bf-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification, verification, and confidentiality</inline>.—</heading><content>Each such statement shall be certified as accurate by an authorized officer or principal of the importer or manufacturer. The Register shall issue regulations to provide for the verification and audit of such statements and to protect the confidentiality of the information contained in such statements. Such regulations shall provide for the disclosure, in confidence, of such statements to interested copyright parties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7468a5c0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1003/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Royalty payments</inline>.—</heading><content>Each such statement shall be accompanied by the royalty payments specified in section 1004.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7468a5c1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/563/s2">Pub. L. 102–563, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4240">106 Stat. 4240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
