<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7419e912-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A"><num value="104A">§ 104A.</num><heading> Copyright in restored works</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7419e913-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Automatic Protection and Term.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e914-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e915-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Copyright subsists, in accordance with this section, in restored works, and vests automatically on the date of restoration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e916-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any work in which copyright is restored under this section shall subsist for the remainder of the term of copyright that the work would have otherwise been granted in the United States if the work never entered the public domain in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e917-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>Any work in which the copyright was ever owned or administered by the Alien Property Custodian and in which the restored copyright would be owned by a government or instrumentality thereof, is not a restored work.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7419e918-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ownership of Restored Copyright</inline>.—</heading><content>A restored work vests initially in the author or initial rightholder of the work as determined by the law of the source country of the work.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7419e919-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Filing of Notice of Intent to Enforce Restored Copyright Against Reliance Parties</inline>.—</heading><content>On or after the date of restoration, any person who owns a copyright in a restored work or an exclusive right therein may file with the Copyright Office a notice of intent to enforce that person’s copyright or exclusive right or may serve such a notice directly on a reliance party. Acceptance of a notice by the Copyright Office is effective as to any reliance parties but shall not create a presumption of the validity of any of the facts stated therein. Service on a reliance party is effective as to that reliance party and any other reliance parties with actual knowledge of such service and of the contents of that notice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7419e91a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Remedies for Infringement of Restored Copyrights.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e91b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of copyright in restored works in the absence of a reliance party</inline>.—</heading><content>As against any party who is not a reliance party, the remedies provided in chapter 5 of this title shall be available on or after the date of restoration of a restored copyright with respect to an act of infringement of the restored copyright that is commenced on or after the date of restoration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e91c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of copyright in restored works as against reliance parties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As against a reliance party, except to the extent provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), the remedies provided in chapter 5 of this title shall be available, with respect to an act of infringement of a restored copyright, on or after the date of restoration of the restored copyright if the requirements of either of the following subparagraphs are met:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e91d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e91e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The owner of the restored copyright (or such owner’s agent) or the owner of an exclusive right therein (or such owner’s agent) files with the Copyright Office, during the 24-month period beginning on the date of restoration, a notice of intent to enforce the restored copyright; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e91f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e920-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the act of infringement commenced after the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date of publication of the notice in the Federal Register;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e921-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the act of infringement commenced before the end of the 12-month period described in subclause (I) and continued after the end of that 12-month period, in which case remedies shall be available only for infringement occurring after the end of that 12-month period; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e922-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> copies or phonorecords of a work in which copyright has been restored under this section are made after publication of the notice of intent in the Federal Register.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e923-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e924-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The owner of the restored copyright (or such owner’s agent) or the owner of an exclusive right therein (or such owner’s agent) serves upon a reliance party a notice of intent to enforce a restored copyright; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e925-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e926-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the act of infringement commenced after the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date the notice of intent is received;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e927-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the act of infringement commenced before the end of the 12-month period described in subclause (I) and continued after the end of that 12-month period, in which case remedies shall be available only for the infringement occurring after the end of that 12-month period; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e928-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> copies or phonorecords of a work in which copyright has been restored under this section are made after receipt of the notice of intent.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In the event that notice is provided under both subparagraphs (A) and (B), the 12-month period referred to in such subparagraphs shall run from the earlier of publication or service of notice.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e929-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Existing derivative works</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e92a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In the case of a derivative work that is based upon a restored work and is created—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e92b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> before the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, if the source country of the restored work is an eligible country on such date, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7419e92c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> before the date on which the source country of the restored work becomes an eligible country, if that country is not an eligible country on such date of enactment,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">a reliance party may continue to exploit that derivative work for the duration of the restored copyright if the reliance party pays to the owner of the restored copyright reasonable compensation for conduct which would be subject to a remedy for infringement but for the provisions of this paragraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e92d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the absence of an agreement between the parties, the amount of such compensation shall be determined by an action in United States district court, and shall reflect any harm to the actual or potential market for or value of the restored work from the reliance party’s continued exploitation of the work, as well as compensation for the relative contributions of expression of the author of the restored work and the reliance party to the derivative work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e92e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commencement of infringement for reliance parties</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of section 412, in the case of reliance parties, infringement shall be deemed to have commenced before registration when acts which would have constituted infringement had the restored work been subject to copyright were commenced before the date of restoration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7419e92f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notices of Intent To Enforce a Restored Copyright.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e930-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notices of intent filed with the copyright office</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e931-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e932-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A notice of intent filed with the Copyright Office to enforce a restored copyright shall be signed by the owner of the restored copyright or the owner of an exclusive right therein, who files the notice under subsection (d)(2)(A)(i) (hereafter in this paragraph referred to as the “owner”), or by the owner’s agent, shall identify the title of the restored work, and shall include an English translation of the title and any other alternative titles known to the owner by which the restored work may be identified, and an address and telephone number at which the owner may be contacted. If the notice is signed by an agent, the agency relationship must have been constituted in a writing signed by the owner before the filing of the notice. The Copyright Office may specifically require in regulations other information to be included in the notice, but failure to provide such other information shall not invalidate the notice or be a basis for refusal to list the restored work in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e933-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If a work in which copyright is restored has no formal title, it shall be described in the notice of intent in detail sufficient to identify it.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e934-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Minor errors or omissions may be corrected by further notice at any time after the notice of intent is filed. Notices of corrections for such minor errors or omissions shall be accepted after the period established in subsection (d)(2)(A)(i). Notices shall be published in the Federal Register pursuant to subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e935-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e936-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Register of Copyrights shall publish in the Federal Register, commencing not later than 4 months after the date of restoration for a particular nation and every 4 months thereafter for a period of 2 years, lists identifying restored works and the ownership thereof if a notice of intent to enforce a restored copyright has been filed.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e937-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Not less than 1 list containing all notices of intent to enforce shall be maintained in the Public Information Office of the Copyright Office and shall be available for public inspection and copying during regular business hours pursuant to sections 705 and 708.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7419e938-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Register of Copyrights is authorized to fix reasonable fees based on the costs of receipt, processing, recording, and publication of notices of intent to enforce a restored copyright and corrections thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a39-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than 90 days before the date the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property referred to in section 101(d)(15) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act enters into force with respect to the United States, the Copyright Office shall issue and publish in the Federal Register regulations governing the filing under this subsection of notices of intent to enforce a restored copyright.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Such regulations shall permit owners of restored copyrights to file simultaneously for registration of the restored copyright.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notices of intent served on a reliance party</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notices of intent to enforce a restored copyright may be served on a reliance party at any time after the date of restoration of the restored copyright.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notices of intent to enforce a restored copyright served on a reliance party shall be signed by the owner or the owner’s agent, shall identify the restored work and the work in which the restored work is used, if any, in detail sufficient to identify them, and shall include an English translation of the title, any other alternative titles known to the owner by which the work may be identified, the use or uses to which the owner objects, and an address and telephone number at which the reliance party may contact the owner. If the notice is signed by an agent, the agency relationship must have been constituted in writing and signed by the owner before service of the notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a3f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of material false statements</inline>.—</heading><content>Any material false statement knowingly made with respect to any restored copyright identified in any notice of intent shall make void all claims and assertions made with respect to such restored copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id741c5a40-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Immunity From Warranty and Related Liability.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a41-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any person who warrants, promises, or guarantees that a work does not violate an exclusive right granted in section 106 shall not be liable for legal, equitable, arbitral, or administrative relief if the warranty, promise, or guarantee is breached by virtue of the restoration of copyright under this section, if such warranty, promise, or guarantee is made before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a42-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Performances</inline>.—</heading><content>No person shall be required to perform any act if such performance is made infringing by virtue of the restoration of copyright under the provisions of this section, if the obligation to perform was undertaken before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id741c5a43-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Proclamation of Copyright Restoration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Whenever the President finds that a particular foreign nation extends, to works by authors who are nationals or domiciliaries of the United States, restored copyright protection on substantially the same basis as provided under this section, the President may by proclamation extend restored protection provided under this section to any work—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a44-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> of which one or more of the authors is, on the date of first publication, a national, domiciliary, or sovereign authority of that nation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a45-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> which was first published in that nation.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The President may revise, suspend, or revoke any such proclamation or impose any conditions or limitations on protection under such a proclamation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id741c5a46-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section and section 109(a):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a47-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “date of adherence or proclamation” means the earlier of the date on which a foreign nation which, as of the date the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States, is not a nation adhering to the Berne Convention or a WTO member country, becomes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a48-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a nation adhering to the Berne Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a49-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a WTO member country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a4a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a nation adhering to the WIPO Copyright Treaty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a4b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a nation adhering to the WIPO Performances and Phonograms Treaty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a4c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> subject to a Presidential proclamation under subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a4d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The “date of restoration” of a restored copyright is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a4e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, if the source country of the restored work is a nation adhering to the Berne Convention or a WTO member country on such date, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a4f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the date of adherence or proclamation, in the case of any other source country of the restored work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a50-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The term “eligible country” means a nation, other than the United States, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a51-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> becomes a WTO member country after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a52-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on such date of enactment is, or after such date of enactment becomes, a nation adhering to the Berne Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a53-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> adheres to the WIPO Copyright Treaty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a54-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> adheres to the WIPO Performances and Phonograms Treaty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a55-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> after such date of enactment becomes subject to a proclamation under subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a56-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The term “reliance party” means any person who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a57-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to a particular work, engages in acts, before the source country of that work becomes an eligible country, which would have violated section 106 if the restored work had been subject to copyright protection, and who, after the source country becomes an eligible country, continues to engage in such acts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a58-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> before the source country of a particular work becomes an eligible country, makes or acquires 1 or more copies or phonorecords of that work; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a59-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> as the result of the sale or other disposition of a derivative work covered under subsection (d)(3), or significant assets of a person described in subparagraph (A) or (B), is a successor, assignee, or licensee of that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a5a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “restored copyright” means copyright in a restored work under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a5b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The term “restored work” means an original work of authorship that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a5c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is protected under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a5d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not in the public domain in its source country through expiration of term of protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a5e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> is in the public domain in the United States due to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a5f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> noncompliance with formalities imposed at any time by United States copyright law, including failure of renewal, lack of proper notice, or failure to comply with any manufacturing requirements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a60-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> lack of subject matter protection in the case of sound recordings fixed before <date date="1972-02-15">February 15, 1972</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a61-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> lack of national eligibility;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a62-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> has at least one author or rightholder who was, at the time the work was created, a national or domiciliary of an eligible country, and if published, was first published in an eligible country and not published in the United States during the 30-day period following publication in such eligible country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a63-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/6/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> if the source country for the work is an eligible country solely by virtue of its adherence to the WIPO Performances and Phonograms Treaty, is a sound recording.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a64-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> The term “rightholder” means the person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a65-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who, with respect to a sound recording, first fixes a sound recording with authorization, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a66-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who has acquired rights from the person described in subparagraph (A) by means of any conveyance or by operation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id741c5a67-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> The “source country” of a restored work is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a68-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a nation other than the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a69-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> in the case of an unpublished work—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a6a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the eligible country in which the author or rightholder is a national or domiciliary, or, if a restored work has more than 1 author or rightholder, of which the majority of foreign authors or rightholders are nationals or domiciliaries; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a6b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the majority of authors or rightholders are not foreign, the nation other than the United States which has the most significant contacts with the work; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id741c5a6c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> in the case of a published work—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a6d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the eligible country in which the work is first published, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id741c5a6e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s104A/h/8/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the restored work is published on the same day in 2 or more eligible countries, the eligible country which has the most significant contacts with the work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id741c5a6f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tIII/s334/a">Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 334(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2115">107 Stat. 2115</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s514/a">Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4976">108 Stat. 4976</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/295/s20/e/2">Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3529">110 Stat. 3529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 2</ref>, <date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1530">111 Stat. 1530</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/tI/s102/c">Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 102(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2862">112 Stat. 2862</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id741c5a70-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id741c5a71-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id741c5a72-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, referred to in subsecs. (d)(3)(A) and (h)(3), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, which was approved <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 101(d)(15) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, referred to in subsec. (e)(1)(D)(i), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511/d/15">section 3511(d)(15) of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id741c5a73-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (h)(1)(A) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/1">Pub. L. 105–304, § 102(c)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (A) to (E) and struck out former subpars. (A) and (B) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) a nation adhering to the Berne Convention or a WTO member country; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) subject to a Presidential proclamation under subsection (g).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/2">Pub. L. 105–304, § 102(c)(2)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “The term ‘eligible country’ means a nation, other than the United States, that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) becomes a WTO member country after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) on such date of enactment is, or after such date of enactment becomes, a member of the Berne Convention; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) after such date of enactment becomes subject to a proclamation under subsection (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this section, a nation that is a member of the Berne Convention on the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall be construed to become an eligible country on such date of enactment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(6)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/3">Pub. L. 105–304, § 102(c)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(8)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/4">Pub. L. 105–304, § 102(c)(4)</ref>, inserted “of which” before “the majority” and struck out “of eligible countries” after “domiciliaries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/5">Pub. L. 105–304, § 102(c)(5)</ref>, struck out par. (9) which read as follows: “The terms ‘WTO Agreement’ and ‘WTO member country’ have the meanings given those terms in paragraphs (9) and (10), respectively, of section 2 of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s2/1">Pub. L. 105–80, § 2(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “In the case of a derivative work that is based upon a restored work and is created—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) before the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, if the source country of the derivative work is an eligible country on such date, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) before the date of adherence or proclamation, if the source country of the derivative work is not an eligible country on such date of enactment,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">a reliance party may continue to exploit that work for the duration of the restored copyright if the reliance party pays to the owner of the restored copyright reasonable compensation for conduct which would be subject to a remedy for infringement but for the provisions of this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s2/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 2(2)</ref>, struck out at end “Such list shall also be published in the Federal Register on an annual basis for the first 2 years after the applicable date of restoration.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s2/3">Pub. L. 105–80, § 2(3)</ref>, (4), amended pars. (2) and (3) generally. Prior to amendment, pars. (2) and (3) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) The ‘date of restoration’ of a restored copyright is the later of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the date on which the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property referred to in section 101(d)(15) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act enters into force with respect to the United States, if the source country of the restored work is a nation adhering to the Berne Convention or a WTO member country on such date; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the date of adherence or proclamation, in the case of any other source country of the restored work.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) The term ‘eligible country’ means a nation, other than the United States, that is a WTO member country, adheres to the Berne Convention, or is subject to a proclamation under subsection (g).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/295">Pub. L. 104–295</ref> substituted “subsection (g)” for “section 104A(g)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> substituted “Copyright in restored works” for “Copyright in certain motion pictures” as section catchline and amended text generally, substituting present provisions for provisions restoring copyright in certain motion pictures and providing for effective date of protection as well as use of previously owned copies.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id741c5a74-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id741c5a75-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A), (B), (E), (3)(A), (B), (E) of this section and amendment by section 102(c)(4), (5) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/304">Pub. L. 105–304</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, except as otherwise provided, subsec. (h)(1)(C), (3)(C) of this section effective <date date="2002-03-06">Mar. 6, 2002</date>, and subsec. (h)(1)(D), (3)(D) of this section and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s102/c/3">section 102(c)(3) of Pub. L. 105–304</ref> effective <date date="2002-05-20">May 20, 2002</date>, see section 105(a), (b)(1)(C), (D), (2)(D)–(F) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/304">Pub. L. 105–304</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id741c5a76-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date the North American Free Trade Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States (<date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s335/a">section 335(a) of Pub. L. 103–182</ref>, formerly set out in an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1052">section 1052 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id741c5a77-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id741c5a78-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Uruguay Round Agreements: Entry Into Force</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Uruguay Round Agreements, including the World Trade Organization Agreement and agreements annexed to that Agreement, as referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511/d">section 3511(d) of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, entered into force with respect to the United States on <date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>. See note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511">section 3511 of Title 19</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
