<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id74427f84-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117"><num value="117">§ 117.</num><heading> Limitations on exclusive rights: Computer programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id74427f85-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Making of Additional Copy or Adaptation by Owner of Copy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 106, it is not an infringement for the owner of a copy of a computer program to make or authorize the making of another copy or adaptation of that computer program provided:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f86-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that such a new copy or adaptation is created as an essential step in the utilization of the computer program in conjunction with a machine and that it is used in no other manner, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f87-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that such new copy or adaptation is for archival purposes only and that all archival copies are destroyed in the event that continued possession of the computer program should cease to be rightful.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id74427f88-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lease, Sale, or Other Transfer of Additional Copy or Adaptation</inline>.—</heading><content>Any exact copies prepared in accordance with the provisions of this section may be leased, sold, or otherwise transferred, along with the copy from which such copies were prepared, only as part of the lease, sale, or other transfer of all rights in the program. Adaptations so prepared may be transferred only with the authorization of the copyright owner.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id74427f89-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Machine Maintenance or Repair</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 106, it is not an infringement for the owner or lessee of a machine to make or authorize the making of a copy of a computer program if such copy is made solely by virtue of the activation of a machine that lawfully contains an authorized copy of the computer program, for purposes only of maintenance or repair of that machine, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f8a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such new copy is used in no other manner and is destroyed immediately after the maintenance or repair is completed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f8b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to any computer program or part thereof that is not necessary for that machine to be activated, such program or part thereof is not accessed or used other than to make such new copy by virtue of the activation of the machine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id74427f8c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f8d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the “maintenance” of a machine is the servicing of the machine in order to make it work in accordance with its original specifications and any changes to those specifications authorized for that machine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74427f8e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s117/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the “repair” of a machine is the restoring of the machine to the state of working in accordance with its original specifications and any changes to those specifications authorized for that machine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id74427f8f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/553/tI/s101">Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2565">90 Stat. 2565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/517/s10/b">Pub. L. 96–517, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3028">94 Stat. 3028</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 105–304, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2887">112 Stat. 2887</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id74427f90-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id74427f91-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74427f92-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 94–1476</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">As the program for general revision of the copyright law has evolved, it has become increasingly apparent that in one major area the problems are not sufficiently developed for a definitive legislative solution. This is the area of computer uses of copyrighted works: the use of a work “in conjunction with automatic systems capable of storing, processing, retrieving, or transferring information.” The Commission on New Technological Uses is, among other things, now engaged in making a thorough study of the emerging patterns in this field and it will, on the basis of its findings, recommend definitive copyright provisions to deal with the situation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Since it would be premature to change existing law on computer uses at present, the purpose of section 117 is to preserve the status quo. It is intended neither to cut off any rights that may now exist, nor to create new rights that might be denied under the Act of 1909 or under common law principles currently applicable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provision deals only with the exclusive rights of a copyright owner with respect to computer uses, that is, the bundle of rights specified for other types of uses in section 106 and qualified in sections 107 through 116 and 118. With respect to the copyright-ability of computer programs, the ownership of copyrights in them, the term of protection, and the formal requirements of the remainder of the bill, the new statute would apply.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Under section 117, an action for infringement of a copyrighted work by means of a computer would necessarily be a federal action brought under the new title 17. The court, in deciding the scope of exclusive rights in the computer area, would first need to determine the applicable law, whether State statutory or common law or the Act of 1909. Having determined what law was applicable, its decision would depend upon its interpretation of what that law was on the point on the day before the effective date of the new statute.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id74427f93-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id74427f94-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/304">Pub. L. 105–304</ref> designated existing provisions as subsecs. (a) and (b), inserted headings, and added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/517">Pub. L. 96–517</ref> substituted provision respecting limitations on exclusive rights in connection with computer programs for prior provision enunciating scope of exclusive rights and use of the work in conjunction with computers and similar information systems and declaring owner of copyright in a work without any greater or lesser rights with respect to the use of the work in conjunction with automatic systems capable of storing, processing, retrieving, or transferring information, or in conjunction with any similar device, machine, or process, than those afforded to works under the law, whether this title or the common law or statutes of a State, in effect on <date date="1977-12-31">Dec. 31, 1977</date>, as held applicable and construed by the court in an action brought under this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
