<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7444c99e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119"><num value="119">§ 119.</num><heading> Limitations on exclusive rights: Secondary transmissions of distant television programming by satellite</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444c99f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secondary Transmissions by Satellite Carriers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9a0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-network stations</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (3), (4), and (6) of this subsection and section 114(d), secondary transmissions of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a non-network station shall be subject to statutory licensing under this section if the secondary transmission is made by a satellite carrier to the public for private home viewing or for viewing in a commercial establishment, with regard to secondary transmissions the satellite carrier is in compliance with the rules, regulations, or authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission governing the carriage of television broadcast station signals, and the carrier makes a direct or indirect charge for each retransmission service to each subscriber receiving the secondary transmission or to a distributor that has contracted with the carrier for direct or indirect delivery of the secondary transmission to the public for private home viewing or for viewing in a commercial establishment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9a1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Network stations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9a2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection and section 114(d), secondary transmissions of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a network station shall be subject to statutory licensing under this section if the secondary transmission is made by a satellite carrier to the public for private home viewing, with regard to secondary transmissions the satellite carrier is in compliance with the rules, regulations, or authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission governing the carriage of television broadcast station signals, the carrier makes a direct or indirect charge for such retransmission service to each subscriber receiving the secondary transmission, and the carrier provides local-into-local service to all DMAs. Failure to reach an agreement with a network station to retransmit the signals of the station shall not be construed to affect compliance with providing local-into-local service to all DMAs if the satellite carrier has the capability to retransmit such signals when an agreement is reached.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9a3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secondary transmissions to unserved households.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9a4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The statutory license provided for in subparagraph (A) shall be limited to secondary transmissions of the signals of no more than two network stations in a single day for each television network to persons who reside in unserved households.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9a5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short markets</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of secondary transmissions to households located in short markets, subject to clause (i), the statutory license shall be further limited to secondary transmissions of only those primary transmissions of network stations that embody the programming of networks not offered on the primary stream or the multicast stream transmitted by any network station in that market.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9a6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of subscriber lists to networks.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9a7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial lists</inline>.—</heading><content>A satellite carrier that makes secondary transmissions of a primary transmission made by a network station pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall, not later than 90 days after commencing such secondary transmissions, submit to the network that owns or is affiliated with the network station a list identifying (by name and address, including street or rural route number, city, State, and 9-digit zip code) all subscribers to which the satellite carrier makes secondary transmissions of that primary transmission to subscribers in unserved households.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9a8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Monthly lists</inline>.—</heading><content>After the submission of the initial lists under clause (i), the satellite carrier shall, not later than the 15th of each month, submit to the network a list, aggregated by designated market area, identifying (by name and address, including street or rural route number, city, State, and 9-digit zip code) any persons who have been added or dropped as subscribers under clause (i) since the last submission under this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9a9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of subscriber information</inline>.—</heading><content>Subscriber information submitted by a satellite carrier under this subparagraph may be used only for purposes of monitoring compliance by the satellite carrier with this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9aa-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>The submission requirements of this subparagraph shall apply to a satellite carrier only if the network to which the submissions are to be made places on file with the Register of Copyrights a document identifying the name and address of the person to whom such submissions are to be made. The Register shall maintain for public inspection a file of all such documents.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ab-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Noncompliance with reporting and payment requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2), the willful or repeated secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier of a primary transmission made by a non-network station or a network station and embodying a performance or display of a work is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506, where the satellite carrier has not deposited the statement of account and royalty fee required by subsection (b), or has failed to make the submissions to networks required by paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ac-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Willful alterations</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2), the secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a non-network station or a network station is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506 and section 510, if the content of the particular program in which the performance or display is embodied, or any commercial advertising or station announcement transmitted by the primary transmitter during, or immediately before or after, the transmission of such program, is in any way willfully altered by the satellite carrier through changes, deletions, or additions, or is combined with programming from any other broadcast signal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ad-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Violation of territorial restrictions on statutory license for network stations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9ae-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individual violations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The willful or repeated secondary transmission by a satellite carrier of a primary transmission made by a network station and embodying a performance or display of a work to a subscriber who is not eligible to receive the transmission under this section is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501 and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506, except that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9af-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no damages shall be awarded for such act of infringement if the satellite carrier took corrective action by promptly withdrawing service from the ineligible subscriber, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9b0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any statutory damages shall not exceed $250 for such subscriber for each month during which the violation occurred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9b1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pattern of violations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a satellite carrier engages in a willful or repeated pattern or practice of delivering a primary transmission made by a network station and embodying a performance or display of a work to subscribers who are not eligible to receive the transmission under this section, then in addition to the remedies set forth in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9b2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if the pattern or practice has been carried out on a substantially nationwide basis, the court shall order a permanent injunction barring the secondary transmission by the satellite carrier, for private home viewing, of the primary transmissions of any primary network station affiliated with the same network, and the court may order statutory damages of not to exceed $2,500,000 for each 3-month period during which the pattern or practice was carried out; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9b3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the pattern or practice has been carried out on a local or regional basis, the court shall order a permanent injunction barring the secondary transmission, for private home viewing in that locality or region, by the satellite carrier of the primary transmissions of any primary network station affiliated with the same network, and the court may order statutory damages of not to exceed $2,500,000 for each 6-month period during which the pattern or practice was carried out.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9b4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Previous subscribers excluded</inline>.—</heading><content>Subparagraphs (A) and (B) do not apply to secondary transmissions by a satellite carrier to persons who subscribed to receive such secondary transmissions from the satellite carrier or a distributor before <date date="1988-11-16">November 16, 1988</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9b5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burden of proof</inline>.—</heading><content>In any action brought under this paragraph, the satellite carrier shall have the burden of proving that its secondary transmission of a primary transmission by a network station is to a subscriber who is eligible to receive the secondary transmission under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The court shall direct one half of any statutory damages ordered under clause (i) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002006"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably means subpar. (B)(i).</note> to be deposited with the Register of Copyrights for distribution to copyright owners pursuant to subsection (b). The Copyright Royalty Judges shall issue regulations establishing procedures for distributing such funds, on a proportional basis, to copyright owners whose works were included in the secondary transmissions that were the subject of the statutory damages.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9b6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discrimination by a satellite carrier</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1), the willful or repeated secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a non-network station or a network station is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506, if the satellite carrier unlawfully discriminates against a distributor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9b7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Geographic limitation on secondary transmissions</inline>.—</heading><content>The statutory license created by this section shall apply only to secondary transmissions to households located in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9b8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service to recreational vehicles and commercial trucks.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9b9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9ba-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, and subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the term “unserved household” shall include—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9bb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> recreational vehicles as defined in regulations of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under section 3282.8 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9bc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> commercial trucks that qualify as commercial motor vehicles under regulations of the Secretary of Transportation under section 383.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9bd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Clause (i) shall apply only to a recreational vehicle or commercial truck if any satellite carrier that proposes to make a secondary transmission of a network station to the operator of such a recreational vehicle or commercial truck complies with the documentation requirements under subparagraphs (B) and (C).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9be-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subparagraph, the terms “recreational vehicle” and “commercial truck” shall not include any fixed dwelling, whether a mobile home or otherwise.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9bf-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Documentation requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A recreational vehicle or commercial truck shall be deemed to be an unserved household beginning 10 days after the relevant satellite carrier provides to the network that owns or is affiliated with the network station that will be secondarily transmitted to the recreational vehicle or commercial truck the following documents:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9c0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Declaration</inline>.—</heading><content>A signed declaration by the operator of the recreational vehicle or commercial truck that the satellite dish is permanently attached to the recreational vehicle or commercial truck, and will not be used to receive satellite programming at any fixed dwelling.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9c1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Registration</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a recreational vehicle, a copy of the current State vehicle registration for the recreational vehicle.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9c2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Registration and license</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a commercial truck, a copy of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9c3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the current State vehicle registration for the truck; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9c4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a copy of a valid, current commercial driver’s license, as defined in regulations of the Secretary of Transportation under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s383">section 383 of title 49</ref>, Code of Federal Regulations, issued to the operator.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9c5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updated documentation requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>If a satellite carrier wishes to continue to make secondary transmissions to a recreational vehicle or commercial truck for more than a 2-year period, that carrier shall provide each network, upon request, with updated documentation in the form described under subparagraph (B) during the 90 days before expiration of that 2-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9c6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statutory license contingent on compliance with fcc rules and remedial steps</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the willful or repeated secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier of a primary transmission embodying a performance or display of a work made by a broadcast station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506, if, at the time of such transmission, the satellite carrier is not in compliance with the rules, regulations, and authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission concerning the carriage of television broadcast station signals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9c7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restricted transmission of out-of-state distant network signals into certain markets.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9c8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Out-of-state network affiliates</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the statutory license in this subsection and subsection (b) shall not apply to any secondary transmission of the primary transmission of a network station located outside of the State of Alaska to any subscriber in that State to whom the secondary transmission of the primary transmission of a television station located in that State is made available by the satellite carrier pursuant to section 122.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9c9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The limitation in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the secondary transmission of the primary transmission of a digital signal of a network station located outside of the State of Alaska if at the time that the secondary transmission is made, no television station licensed to a community in the State and affiliated with the same network makes primary transmissions of a digital signal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444c9ca-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deposit of Statements and Fees; Verification Procedures.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9cb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deposits with the register of copyrights</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A satellite carrier whose secondary transmissions are subject to statutory licensing under subsection (a) shall, on a semiannual basis, deposit with the Register of Copyrights, in accordance with requirements that the Register shall prescribe by regulation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9cc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a statement of account, covering the preceding 6-month period, specifying the names and locations of all non-network stations and network stations whose signals were retransmitted, at any time during that period, to subscribers as described in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2), the total number of subscribers that received such retransmissions, and such other data as the Register of Copyrights may from time to time prescribe by regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9cd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a royalty fee payable to copyright owners pursuant to paragraph (4) for that 6-month period, computed by multiplying the total number of subscribers receiving each secondary transmission of a primary stream or multicast stream of each non-network station or network station during each calendar year month by the appropriate rate in effect under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9ce-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a filing fee, as determined by the Register of Copyrights pursuant to section 708(a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9cf-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Verification of accounts and fee payments</inline>.—</heading><content>The Register of Copyrights shall issue regulations to permit interested parties to verify and audit the statements of account and royalty fees submitted by satellite carriers under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9d0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Investment of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The Register of Copyrights shall receive all fees (including the filing fee specified in paragraph (1)(C)) deposited under this section and, after deducting the reasonable costs incurred by the Copyright Office under this section (other than the costs deducted under paragraph (5)), shall deposit the balance in the Treasury of the United States, in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury directs. All funds held by the Secretary of the Treasury shall be invested in interest-bearing securities of the United States for later distribution with interest by the Librarian of Congress as provided by this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9d1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Persons to whom fees are distributed</inline>.—</heading><content>The royalty fees deposited under paragraph (3) shall, in accordance with the procedures provided by paragraph (5), be distributed to those copyright owners whose works were included in a secondary transmission made by a satellite carrier during the applicable 6-month accounting period and who file a claim with the Copyright Royalty Judges under paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9d2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures for distribution</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The royalty fees deposited under paragraph (3) shall be distributed in accordance with the following procedures:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9d3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Filing of claims for fees</inline>.—</heading><content>During the month of July in each year, each person claiming to be entitled to statutory license fees for secondary transmissions shall file a claim with the Copyright Royalty Judges, in accordance with requirements that the Copyright Royalty Judges shall prescribe by regulation. For purposes of this paragraph, any claimants may agree among themselves as to the proportionate division of statutory license fees among them, may lump their claims together and file them jointly or as a single claim, or may designate a common agent to receive payment on their behalf.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9d4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of controversy; distributions</inline>.—</heading><content>After the first day of August of each year, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall determine whether there exists a controversy concerning the distribution of royalty fees. If the Copyright Royalty Judges determine that no such controversy exists, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall authorize the Librarian of Congress to proceed to distribute such fees to the copyright owners entitled to receive them, or to their designated agents, subject to the deduction of reasonable administrative costs under this section. If the Copyright Royalty Judges find the existence of a controversy, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall, pursuant to chapter 8 of this title, conduct a proceeding to determine the distribution of royalty fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9d5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Withholding of fees during controversy</inline>.—</heading><content>During the pendency of any proceeding under this subsection, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall have the discretion to authorize the Librarian of Congress to proceed to distribute any amounts that are not in controversy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444c9d6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment of Royalty Fees.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9d7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability and determination of royalty fees for signals.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9d8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial fee</inline>.—</heading><content>The appropriate fee for purposes of determining the royalty fee under subsection (b)(1)(B) for the secondary transmission of the primary transmissions of network stations and non-network stations shall be the appropriate fee set forth in part 258 of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="2009-07-01">July 1, 2009</date>, as modified under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9d9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fee set by voluntary negotiation</inline>.—</heading><content>On or before <date date="2010-06-01">June 1, 2010</date>, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall cause to be published in the Federal Register of the initiation of voluntary negotiation proceedings for the purpose of determining the royalty fee to be paid by satellite carriers for the secondary transmission of the primary transmissions of network stations and non-network stations under subsection (b)(1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9da-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Negotiations</inline>.—</heading><content>Satellite carriers, distributors, and copyright owners entitled to royalty fees under this section shall negotiate in good faith in an effort to reach a voluntary agreement or agreements for the payment of royalty fees. Any such satellite carriers, distributors and copyright owners may at any time negotiate and agree to the royalty fee, and may designate common agents to negotiate, agree to, or pay such fees. If the parties fail to identify common agents, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall do so, after requesting recommendations from the parties to the negotiation proceeding. The parties to each negotiation proceeding shall bear the cost thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9db-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreements binding on parties; filing of agreements; public notice</inline>.—</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9dc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Voluntary agreements; filing</inline>.—</heading><content>Voluntary agreements negotiated at any time in accordance with this paragraph shall be binding upon all satellite carriers, distributors, and copyright owners that are parties thereto. Copies of such agreements shall be filed with the Copyright Office within 30 days after execution in accordance with regulations that the Register of Copyrights shall prescribe.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9dd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedure for adoption of fees.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9de-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication of notice</inline>.—</heading><content>Within 10 days after publication in the Federal Register of a notice of the initiation of voluntary negotiation proceedings, parties who have reached a voluntary agreement may request that the royalty fees in that agreement be applied to all satellite carriers, distributors, and copyright owners without convening a proceeding under subparagraph (F).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9df-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public notice of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon receiving a request under subclause (I), the Copyright Royalty Judges shall immediately provide public notice of the royalty fees from the voluntary agreement and afford parties an opportunity to state that they object to those fees.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/D/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adoption of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The Copyright Royalty Judges shall adopt the royalty fees from the voluntary agreement for all satellite carriers, distributors, and copyright owners without convening the proceeding under subparagraph (F) unless a party with an intent to participate in that proceeding and a significant interest in the outcome of that proceeding objects under subclause (II).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9e1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period agreement is in effect</inline>.—</heading><content>The obligation to pay the royalty fees established under a voluntary agreement which has been filed with the Copyright Royalty Judges in accordance with this paragraph shall become effective on the date specified in the agreement and shall remain in effect in accordance with the terms of the agreement until the subscriber for which the royalty is payable is no longer eligible to receive a secondary transmission pursuant to the license under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9e2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fee set by copyright royalty judges proceeding.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9e3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of initiation of the proceeding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>On or before <date date="2010-09-01">September 1, 2010</date>, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall cause notice to be published in the Federal Register of the initiation of a proceeding for the purpose of determining the royalty fees to be paid for the secondary transmission of the primary transmissions of network stations and non-network stations under subsection (b)(1)(B) by satellite carriers and distributors—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the absence of a voluntary agreement filed in accordance with subparagraph (D) that establishes royalty fees to be paid by all satellite carriers and distributors; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if an objection to the fees from a voluntary agreement submitted for adoption by the Copyright Royalty Judges to apply to all satellite carriers, distributors, and copyright owners is received under subparagraph (D) from a party with an intent to participate in the proceeding and a significant interest in the outcome of that proceeding.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> Such proceeding shall be conducted under chapter 8.</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9e6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of royalty fees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining royalty fees under this subparagraph, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall establish fees for the secondary transmissions of the primary transmissions of network stations and non-network stations that most clearly represent the fair market value of secondary transmissions, except that the Copyright Royalty Judges shall adjust royalty fees to account for the obligations of the parties under any applicable voluntary agreement filed with the Copyright Royalty Judges in accordance with subparagraph (D). In determining the fair market value, the Judges shall base their decision on economic, competitive, and programming information presented by the parties, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the competitive environment in which such programming is distributed, the cost of similar signals in similar private and compulsory license marketplaces, and any special features and conditions of the retransmission marketplace;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the economic impact of such fees on copyright owners and satellite carriers; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444c9e9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the impact on the continued availability of secondary transmissions to the public.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9ea-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date for decision of copyright royalty judges</inline>.—</heading><content>The obligation to pay the royalty fees established under a determination that is made by the Copyright Royalty Judges in a proceeding under this paragraph shall be effective as of <date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444c9eb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/1/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Persons subject to royalty fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The royalty fees referred to in clause (iii) shall be binding on all satellite carriers, distributors and copyright owners, who are not party to a voluntary agreement filed with the Copyright Office under subparagraph (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ec-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual royalty fee adjustment</inline>.—</heading><content>Effective January 1 of each year, the royalty fee payable under subsection (b)(1)(B) for the secondary transmission of the primary transmissions of network stations and non-network stations shall be adjusted by the Copyright Royalty Judges to reflect any changes occurring in the cost of living as determined by the most recent Consumer Price Index (for all consumers and for all items) published by the Secretary of Labor before December 1 of the preceding year. Notification of the adjusted fees shall be published in the Federal Register at least 25 days before January 1.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444c9ed-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ee-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Distributor</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “distributor” means an entity that contracts to distribute secondary transmissions from a satellite carrier and, either as a single channel or in a package with other programming, provides the secondary transmission either directly to individual subscribers or indirectly through other program distribution entities in accordance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ef-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Network station</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “network station” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9f0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission, including any translator station or terrestrial satellite station that rebroadcasts all or substantially all of the programming broadcast by a network station, that is owned or operated by, or affiliated with, one or more of the television networks in the United States that offer an interconnected program service on a regular basis for 15 or more hours per week to at least 25 of its affiliated television licensees in 10 or more States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9f1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a noncommercial educational broadcast station (as defined in section 397 of the Communications Act of 1934);</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that the term does not include the signal of the Alaska Rural Communications Service, or any successor entity to that service.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary network station</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “primary network station” means a network station that broadcasts or rebroadcasts the basic programming service of a particular national network.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary transmission</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “primary transmission” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111/f">section 111(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private home viewing</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “private home viewing” means the viewing, for private use in a household by means of satellite reception equipment that is operated by an individual in that household and that serves only such household, of a secondary transmission delivered by a satellite carrier of a primary transmission of a television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Satellite carrier</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “satellite carrier” means an entity that uses the facilities of a satellite or satellite service licensed by the Federal Communications Commission and operates in the Fixed-Satellite Service under part 25 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or the Direct Broadcast Satellite Service under part 100 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to establish and operate a channel of communications for point-to-multipoint distribution of television station signals, and that owns or leases a capacity or service on a satellite in order to provide such point-to-multipoint distribution, except to the extent that such entity provides such distribution pursuant to tariff under the Communications Act of 1934, other than for private home viewing pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secondary transmission</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “secondary transmission” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111/f">section 111(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9f7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subscriber; subscribe.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9f8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subscriber</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “subscriber” means a person or entity that receives a secondary transmission service from a satellite carrier and pays a fee for the service, directly or indirectly, to the satellite carrier or to a distributor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9f9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subscribe</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “subscribe” means to elect to become a subscriber.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9fa-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-network station</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “non-network station” means a television station, other than a network station, licensed by the Federal Communications Commission, that is secondarily transmitted by a satellite carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9fb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Unserved household</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “unserved household”, with respect to a particular television network, means a household that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9fc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is a subscriber to whom subsection (a)(8) applies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444c9fd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is a subscriber located in a short market.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9fe-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local market</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “local market” has the meaning given such term under section 122(j).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444c9ff-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commercial establishment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “commercial establishment”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca00-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> means an establishment used for commercial purposes, such as a bar, restaurant, private office, fitness club, oil rig, retail store, bank or other financial institution, supermarket, automobile or boat dealership, or any other establishment with a common business area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca01-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include a multi-unit permanent or temporary dwelling where private home viewing occurs, such as a hotel, dormitory, hospital, apartment, condominium, or prison.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca02-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Multicast stream</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “multicast stream” means a digital stream containing programming and program-related material affiliated with a television network, other than the primary stream.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca03-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary stream</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “primary stream” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca04-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/14/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the single digital stream of programming as to which a television broadcast station has the right to mandatory carriage with a satellite carrier under the rules of the Federal Communications Commission in effect on <date date="2009-07-01">July 1, 2009</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca05-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/14/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> if there is no stream described in subparagraph (A), then either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca06-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/14/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the single digital stream of programming associated with the network last transmitted by the station as an analog signal; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca07-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/14/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if there is no stream described in clause (i), then the single digital stream of programming affiliated with the network that, as of <date date="2009-07-01">July 1, 2009</date>, had been offered by the television broadcast station for the longest period of time.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca08-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local-into-local service to all dmas</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “local-into-local service to all DMAs” has the meaning given such term in subsection (f)(7).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca09-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/d/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short market</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “short market” means a local market in which programming of one or more of the four most widely viewed television networks nationwide is not offered on either the primary stream or multicast stream transmitted by any network station in that market or is temporarily or permanently unavailable as a result of an act of god <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002007"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> or other force majeure event beyond the control of the carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444ca0a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited Consideration by Justice Department of Voluntary Agreements to Provide Satellite Secondary Transmissions to Local Markets.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca0b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In a case in which no satellite carrier makes available, to subscribers located in a local market, as defined in section 122(j)(2), the secondary transmission into that market of a primary transmission of one or more television broadcast stations licensed by the Federal Communications Commission, and two or more satellite carriers request a business review letter in accordance with section 50.6 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>), in order to assess the legality under the antitrust laws of proposed business conduct to make or carry out an agreement to provide such secondary transmission into such local market, the appropriate official of the Department of Justice shall respond to the request no later than 90 days after the date on which the request is received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca0c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, the term “antitrust laws”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca0d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has the meaning given that term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12/a">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</ref>), except that such term includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">15 U.S.C. 45</ref>) to the extent such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca0e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes any State law similar to the laws referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7444ca0f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Waivers Granted to Providers of Local-into-local Service to All DMAs.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca10-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Injunction waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>A court that issued an injunction pursuant to subsection (a)(5)(B) before the date of the enactment of this subsection shall waive such injunction if the court recognizes the entity against which the injunction was issued as a qualified carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca11-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limited temporary waiver.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca12-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon a request made by a satellite carrier, a court that issued an injunction against such carrier under subsection (a)(5)(B) before the date of the enactment of this subsection shall waive such injunction with respect to the statutory license provided under subsection (a)(2) to the extent necessary to allow such carrier to make secondary transmissions of primary transmissions made by a network station to unserved households located in short markets in which such carrier was not providing local service pursuant to the license under section 122 as of <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca13-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expiration of temporary waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>A temporary waiver of an injunction under subparagraph (A) shall expire after the end of the 120-day period beginning on the date such temporary waiver is issued unless extended for good cause by the court making the temporary waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca14-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to provide local-into-local service to all dmas.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca15-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to act reasonably and in good faith</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the court issuing a temporary waiver under subparagraph (A) determines that the satellite carrier that made the request for such waiver has failed to act reasonably or has failed to make a good faith effort to provide local-into-local service to all DMAs, such failure—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca16-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501 and the court may in its discretion impose the remedies provided for in sections 502 through 506 and subsection (a)(6)(B) of this section; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002008"><num>3</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca17-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> shall result in the termination of the waiver issued under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca18-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to provide local-into-local service</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the court issuing a temporary waiver under subparagraph (A) determines that the satellite carrier that made the request for such waiver has failed to provide local-into-local service to all DMAs, but determines that the carrier acted reasonably and in good faith, the court may in its discretion impose financial penalties that reflect—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca19-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the degree of control the carrier had over the circumstances that resulted in the failure;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca1a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the quality of the carrier’s efforts to remedy the failure; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca1b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the severity and duration of any service interruption.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca1c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Single temporary waiver available</inline>.—</heading><content>An entity may only receive one temporary waiver under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca1d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short market defined</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, the term “short market” means a local market in which programming of one or more of the four most widely viewed television networks nationwide as measured on the date of the enactment of this subsection is not offered on the primary stream transmitted by any local television broadcast station.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca1e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of qualified carrier recognition.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca1f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An entity seeking to be recognized as a qualified carrier under this subsection shall file a statement of eligibility with the court that imposed the injunction. A statement of eligibility must include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca20-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an affidavit that the entity is providing local-into-local service to all DMAs;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca21-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a motion for a waiver of the injunction;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca22-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a motion that the court appoint a special master under Rule 53 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca23-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> an agreement by the carrier to pay all expenses incurred by the special master under paragraph (4)(B)(ii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca24-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> a certification issued pursuant to section 342(a) of Communications Act of 1934.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca25-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grant of recognition as a qualified carrier</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon receipt of a statement of eligibility, the court shall recognize the entity as a qualified carrier and issue the waiver under paragraph (1). Upon motion pursuant to subparagraph (A)(iii), the court shall appoint a special master to conduct the examination and provide a report to the court as provided in paragraph (4)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca26-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Voluntary termination</inline>.—</heading><content>At any time, an entity recognized as a qualified carrier may file a statement of voluntary termination with the court certifying that it no longer wishes to be recognized as a qualified carrier. Upon receipt of such statement, the court shall reinstate the injunction waived under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca27-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loss of recognition prevents future recognition</inline>.—</heading><content>No entity may be recognized as a qualified carrier if such entity had previously been recognized as a qualified carrier and subsequently lost such recognition or voluntarily terminated such recognition under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7444ca28-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified carrier obligations and compliance.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca29-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuing obligations.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca2a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>An entity recognized as a qualified carrier shall continue to provide local-into-local service to all DMAs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca2b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation with compliance examination</inline>.—</heading><content>An entity recognized as a qualified carrier shall fully cooperate with the special master appointed by the court under paragraph (3)(B) in an examination set forth in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7444ca2c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified carrier compliance examination.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca2d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Examination and report</inline>.—</heading><content>A special master appointed by the court under paragraph (3)(B) shall conduct an examination of, and file a report on, the qualified carrier’s compliance with the royalty payment and household eligibility requirements of the license under this section. The report shall address the qualified carrier’s conduct during the period beginning on the date on which the qualified carrier is recognized as such under paragraph (3)(B) and ending on <date date="2012-04-30">April 30, 2012</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7444ca2e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records of qualified carrier</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning on the date that is one year after the date on which the qualified carrier is recognized as such under paragraph (3)(B), but not later than <date date="2011-12-01">December 1, 2011</date>, the qualified carrier shall provide the special master with all records that the special master considers to be directly pertinent to the following requirements under this section:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7444ca2f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Proper calculation and payment of royalties under the statutory license under this section.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id74473a30-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Provision of service under this license to eligible subscribers only.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a31-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of report</inline>.—</heading><content>The special master shall file the report required by clause (i) not later than <date date="2012-07-24">July 24, 2012</date>, with the court referred to in paragraph (1) that issued the injunction, and the court shall transmit a copy of the report to the Register of Copyrights, the Committees on the Judiciary and on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on the Judiciary and on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a32-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evidence of infringement</inline>.—</heading><content>The special master shall include in the report a statement of whether the examination by the special master indicated that there is substantial evidence that a copyright holder could bring a successful action under this section against the qualified carrier for infringement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a33-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsequent examination</inline>.—</heading><content>If the special master’s report includes a statement that its examination indicated the existence of substantial evidence that a copyright holder could bring a successful action under this section against the qualified carrier for infringement, the special master shall, not later than 6 months after the report under clause (i) is filed, initiate another examination of the qualified carrier’s compliance with the royalty payment and household eligibility requirements of the license under this section since the last report was filed under clause (iii). The special master shall file a report on the results of the examination conducted under this clause with the court referred to in paragraph (1) that issued the injunction, and the court shall transmit a copy to the Register of Copyrights, the Committees on the Judiciary and on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on the Judiciary and on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate. The report shall include a statement described in clause (iv).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a34-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon motion filed by an aggrieved copyright owner, the court recognizing an entity as a qualified carrier shall terminate such designation upon finding that the entity has failed to cooperate with an examination required by this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a35-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Oversight</inline>.—</heading><content>During the period of time that the special master is conducting an examination under this subparagraph, the Comptroller General shall monitor the degree to which the entity seeking to be recognized or recognized as a qualified carrier under paragraph (3) is complying with the special master’s examination. The qualified carrier shall make available to the Comptroller General all records and individuals that the Comptroller General considers necessary to meet the Comptroller General’s obligations under this clause. The Comptroller General shall report the results of the monitoring required by this clause to the Committees on the Judiciary and on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on the Judiciary and on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate at intervals of not less than six months during such period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a36-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affirmation</inline>.—</heading><content>A qualified carrier shall file an affidavit with the district court and the Register of Copyrights 30 months after such status was granted stating that, to the best of the affiant’s knowledge, it is in compliance with the requirements for a qualified carrier. The qualified carrier shall attach to its affidavit copies of all reports or orders issued by the court, the special master, and the Comptroller General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a37-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance determination</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon the motion of an aggrieved television broadcast station, the court recognizing an entity as a qualified carrier may make a determination of whether the entity is providing local-into-local service to all DMAs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a38-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pleading requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>In any motion brought under subparagraph (D), the party making such motion shall specify one or more designated market areas (as such term is defined in section 122(j)(2)(C)) for which the failure to provide service is being alleged, and, for each such designated market area, shall plead with particularity the circumstances of the alleged failure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a39-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burden of proof</inline>.—</heading><content>In any proceeding to make a determination under subparagraph (D), and with respect to a designated market area for which failure to provide service is alleged, the entity recognized as a qualified carrier shall have the burden of proving that the entity provided local-into-local service with a good quality satellite signal to at least 90 percent of the households in such designated market area (based on the most recent census data released by the United States Census Bureau) at the time and place alleged.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74473a3a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to provide service.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a3b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the court recognizing an entity as a qualified carrier finds that such entity has willfully failed to provide local-into-local service to all DMAs, such finding shall result in the loss of recognition of the entity as a qualified carrier and the termination of the waiver provided under paragraph (1), and the court may, in its discretion—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a3c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> treat such failure as an act of infringement under section 501, and subject such infringement to the remedies provided for in sections 502 through 506 and subsection (a)(6)(B) of this section; <sup>3</sup> and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a3d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> impose a fine of not less than $250,000 and not more than $5,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a3e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for nonwillful violation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the court determines that the failure to provide local-into-local service to all DMAs is nonwillful, the court may in its discretion impose financial penalties for noncompliance that reflect—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a3f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the degree of control the entity had over the circumstances that resulted in the failure;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a40-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the quality of the entity’s efforts to remedy the failure and restore service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id74473a41-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the severity and duration of any service interruption.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74473a42-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalties for violations of license</inline>.—</heading><content>A court that finds, under subsection (a)(6)(A),<sup>3</sup> that an entity recognized as a qualified carrier has willfully made a secondary transmission of a primary transmission made by a network station and embodying a performance or display of a work to a subscriber who is not eligible to receive the transmission under this section shall reinstate the injunction waived under paragraph (1), and the court may order statutory damages of not more than $2,500,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id74473a43-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local-into-local service to all dmas defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a44-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>An entity provides “local-into-local service to all DMAs” if the entity provides local service in all designated market areas (as such term is defined in section 122(j)(2)(C)) pursuant to the license under section 122, except for designated market areas where the entity is temporarily or permanently unable to provide local service as a result of an act of god <sup>2</sup> or other force majeure event beyond the control of the entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a45-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Household coverage</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of subparagraph (A), an entity that makes available local-into-local service with a good quality satellite signal to at least 90 percent of the households in a designated market area based on the most recent census data released by the United States Census Bureau shall be considered to be providing local service to such designated market area.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id74473a46-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s119/f/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good quality satellite signal defined</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “good quality satellite signal” has the meaning given such term under section 342(e)(2) of Communications <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002009"><num>4</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”.</note> Act of 1934.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id74473a47-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/tII/s202/2">Pub. L. 100–667, title II, § 202(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3949">102 Stat. 3949</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2310">107 Stat. 2310</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-10-18">Oct. 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3477">108 Stat. 3477</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/39/s5/c">Pub. L. 104–39, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-01">Nov. 1, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/348">109 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/80">Pub. L. 105–80</ref>, §§ 1, 12(a)(8), <date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1529">111 Stat. 1529</ref>, 1535; <ref href="/us/pl/106/44/s1/g/4">Pub. L. 106–44, § 1(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/222">113 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tI/s1004–100">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, §§ 1004–1007, 1008(b), 1011(b)(2), (c)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–527 to 1501A–531, 1501A–537, 1501A–543, 1501A–544; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13209, 13210(1), (8), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1908">116 Stat. 1908</ref>, 1909; <ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/g">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(g)</ref>, (h), <date date="2004-11-30">Nov. 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2367">118 Stat. 2367</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dJ/tIX">Pub. L. 108–447, div. J, title IX</ref> [title I, §§ 101(b)–105, 107(a), 108, 111(a)], <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3394-3408">118 Stat. 3394–3408</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/e">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(e)</ref>, (g), <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1482">120 Stat. 1482</ref>, 1483; <ref href="/us/pl/110/403/tII/s209/a/4">Pub. L. 110–403, title II, § 209(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4264">122 Stat. 4264</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/118/dB/s1003/a/1">Pub. L. 111–118, div. B, § 1003(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-19">Dec. 19, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3469">123 Stat. 3469</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/144/s10/a/1">Pub. L. 111–144, § 10(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-02">Mar. 2, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/47">124 Stat. 47</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/151/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 111–151, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-26">Mar. 26, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1027">124 Stat. 1027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/157/s9/a/1">Pub. L. 111–157, § 9(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-04-15">Apr. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1118">124 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/tI">Pub. L. 111–175, title I</ref>, §§ 102(a)(1), (b)–(k), 105, <date date="2010-05-27">May 27, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1219-1226">124 Stat. 1219–1226</ref>, 1239; <ref href="/us/pl/111/295/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–295, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3181">124 Stat. 3181</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/200/tII">Pub. L. 113–200, title II</ref>, §§ 201(2), 202(a), <date date="2014-12-04">Dec. 4, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2066">128 Stat. 2066</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tXI/s1102/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XI, § 1102(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3201">133 Stat. 3201</ref>, 3203.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id74473a48-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id74473a49-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id74473a4a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Communications Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (d)(6), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 5 (§ 151 et seq.) of Title 47, Telecommunications. Sections 342 and 397 of the Act are classified to sections 342 and 397, respectively, of Title 47. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of Title 47</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), (2)(A), (E), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/111/175">Pub. L. 111–175</ref>, which shall be deemed to refer to <date date="2010-02-27">Feb. 27, 2010</date>. See <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s307/a">section 307(a) of Pub. L. 111–175</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2010 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a)(6) of this section, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(C)(i)(I), (5)(A)(i), (6), was redesignated subsec. (a)(5) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tXI/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XI, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3202">133 Stat. 3202</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsec. (f)(3)(A)(iii), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id74473a4b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/c/1/A/i">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(c)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (3), (4), and (6)” for “paragraphs (4), (5), and (7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/A/i">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, (c)(1)(A)(ii), substituted “paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6)” for “paragraphs (4), (5), (6), and (7)” and “signals,” for “signals, and”, inserted “, and the carrier provides local-into-local service to all DMAs” after “receiving the secondary transmission”, and inserted at end “Failure to reach an agreement with a network station to retransmit the signals of the station shall not be construed to affect compliance with providing local-into-local service to all DMAs if the satellite carrier has the capability to retransmit such signals when an agreement is reached.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(ii), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out former cls. (ii) and (iii) which related to accurate determinations of eligibility and C-band exemption to unserved households, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (4) as (3) and struck out former par. (3) which related to statutory license where retransmissions into local market available.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated pars. (5) and (6) as (4) and (5), respectively. Former par. (4) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated par. (7) as (6). Former par. (6) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out subpar. (E). Text read as follows: “The secondary transmission by a satellite carrier of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a network station to subscribers who do not reside in unserved households shall not be an act of infringement if—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the station on <date date="1991-05-01">May 1, 1991</date>, was retransmitted by a satellite carrier and was not on that date owned or operated by or affiliated with a television network that offered interconnected program service on a regular basis for 15 or more hours per week to at least 25 affiliated television licensees in 10 or more States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) as of <date date="1998-07-01">July 1, 1998</date>, such station was retransmitted by a satellite carrier under the statutory license of this section; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) the station is not owned or operated by or affiliated with a television network that, as of <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, offered interconnected program service on a regular basis for 15 or more hours per week to at least 25 affiliated television licensees in 10 or more States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated pars. (8) and (11) as (7) and (8), respectively. Former par. (7) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (12) as (9) and struck out former par. (9). Prior to amendment, text of par. (9) read as follows: “In any civil action filed relating to the eligibility of subscribing households as unserved households—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) a network station challenging such eligibility shall, within 60 days after receipt of the measurement results and a statement of such costs, reimburse the satellite carrier for any signal intensity measurement that is conducted by that carrier in response to a challenge by the network station and that establishes the household is an unserved household; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) a satellite carrier shall, within 60 days after receipt of the measurement results and a statement of such costs, reimburse the network station challenging such eligibility for any signal intensity measurement that is conducted by that station and that establishes the household is not an unserved household.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (14) as (10) and struck out former par. (10). Prior to amendment, text of par. (10) read as follows: “If a network station makes a reasonable attempt to conduct a site measurement of its signal at a subscriber’s household and is denied access for the purpose of conducting the measurement, and is otherwise unable to conduct a measurement, the satellite carrier shall within 60 days notice thereof, terminate service of the station’s network to that household.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11), (12). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated pars. (11) and (12) as (8) and (9), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (13). Text read as follows: “A subscriber who is denied the secondary transmission of a signal of a network station under subsection (a)(2)(B) may request a waiver from such denial by submitting a request, through the subscriber’s satellite carrier, to the network station asserting that the secondary transmission is prohibited. The network station shall accept or reject a subscriber’s request for a waiver within 30 days after receipt of the request. If a television network station fails to accept or reject a subscriber’s request for a waiver within the 30-day period after receipt of the request, that station shall be deemed to agree to the waiver request and have filed such written waiver. Unless specifically stated by the network station, a waiver that was granted before the date of the enactment of the Satellite Home Viewer Extension and Reauthorization Act of 2004 under section 339(c)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934, and that was in effect on such date of enactment, shall constitute a waiver for purposes of this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/1/C">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated par. (14) as (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/2">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “in the agreement and shall remain in effect in accordance with the terms of the agreement until the subscriber for which the royalty is payable is no longer eligible to receive a secondary transmission pursuant to the license under this section.” for “in the agreement, and shall remain in effect until <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>, or in accordance with the terms of the agreement, whichever is later.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/3/A">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(3)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (A) and substituted “subsection (a)(8)” for “subsection (a)(11)”, added subpar. (B), and struck out former subpars. (A) to (C) and (E) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) cannot receive, through the use of an antenna, an over-the-air signal containing the primary stream, or, on or after the qualifying date, the multicast stream, originating in that household’s local market and affiliated with that network of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) if the signal originates as an analog signal, Grade B intensity as defined by the Federal Communications Commission in section 73.683(a) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) if the signal originates as a digital signal, intensity defined in the values for the digital television noise-limited service contour, as defined in regulations issued by the Federal Communications Commission (section 73.622(e) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations), as such regulations may be amended from time to time;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) is subject to a waiver that meets the standards of subsection (a)(13), whether or not the waiver was granted before the date of the enactment of the Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act of 2010;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) is a subscriber to whom subsection (e) applies;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(E) is a subscriber to whom the exemption under subsection (a)(2)(B)(iii) applies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(13) to (16). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/3/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(3)(B)</ref>–(D), redesignated pars. (14) and (15) as (13) and (14), respectively, added pars. (15) and (16), and struck out former par. (13) which defined the term “qualifying date” for purposes of former subsec. (d)(10)(A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/4">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(4)</ref>, (6), redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and struck out former subsec. (e). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (e) read as follows: “Until <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>, a subscriber who does not receive a signal of Grade A intensity (as defined in the regulations of the Federal Communications Commission under section 73.683(a) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, or predicted by the Federal Communications Commission using the Individual Location Longley-Rice methodology described by the Federal Communications Commission in Docket No. 98–201) of a local network television broadcast station shall remain eligible to receive signals of network stations affiliated with the same network, if that subscriber had satellite service of such network signal terminated after <date date="1998-07-11">July 11, 1998</date>, and before <date date="1999-10-31">October 31, 1999</date>, as required by this section, or received such service on <date date="1999-10-31">October 31, 1999</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/6">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(6)</ref>, (c)(1)(B), redesignated subsec. (g) as (f) and substituted “subsection (a)(5)(B)” for “subsection (a)(7)(B)” in pars. (1) and (2)(A). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/6">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(6)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/5">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “, except for designated market areas where the entity is temporarily or permanently unable to provide local service as a result of an act of god or other force majeure event beyond the control of the entity” after “section 122”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s1102/a/4">Pub. L. 116–94, § 1102(a)(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h). Text read as follows: “This section shall cease to be effective on <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/113/200/s201/2/A">Pub. L. 113–200, § 201(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “2019” for “2014”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/200/s201/2/B">Pub. L. 113–200, § 201(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “2019” for “2014”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/113/200/s202/a">Pub. L. 113–200, § 202(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/a/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “distant television programming by satellite” for “superstations and network stations for private home viewing” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/1/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated pars. (4) to (14) and (16) as (3) to (13) and (14), respectively, and struck out former pars. (3) and (15) which related to secondary transmissions of significantly viewed signals and carriage of low power television stations, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/A/i">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “(4), (5), and (7)” for “(5), (6), and (8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(2)</ref>, which directed amendment of section by substituting “non-network stations” for “superstations” wherever appearing in headings, was executed by substituting “<inline class="small-caps">Non-network stations</inline>” for “<inline class="small-caps">Superstations</inline>” in par. (1) heading, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “non-network station” for “superstation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/A/ii/I">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(A)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and paragraphs (4), (5), (6), and (7)” for “subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph and paragraphs (5), (6), (7), and (8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/A/ii/II">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(A)(ii)(II)</ref>, struck out “The limitation in this clause shall not apply to secondary transmissions under paragraph (3).” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(ii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(1)</ref>, added subcl. (III).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/5">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(5)</ref>, (k)(1), substituted “In this clause,” for “In this clause” and “, Code of Federal Regulations” for “of the Code of Federal Regulations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/1/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (C) and struck out former subpar. (C), which related to exceptions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C)(i), (ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/A/ii/III">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(A)(ii)(III)</ref>, added cls. (i) and (ii) and struck out former cls. (i) and (ii) which related to initial lists and monthly lists, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/1/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/2/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “analog” after “subscribers to” in subpar. heading, substituted “distant” for “distant analog” and “primary” for “primary analog” wherever appearing in headings and text, and struck out “analog” after “receive such local” in cl. (i)(I)(bb).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/2/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpars. (B) and (C) which related to rules for other subscribers and future applicability, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/2/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subpar. (E) as (D) and struck out former subpar. (D) which related to special rules for distant digital signals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/2/C">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(2)(C)</ref>, (D), redesignated subpar. (F) as (E) and substituted “(B) or (C)” for “(C) or (D)”. Former subpar. (E) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, struck out “under paragraph (3) or” after “transmissions” and substituted “paragraph (11)” for “paragraph (12)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/2/C">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(2)(C)</ref>, (E), redesignated subpar. (G) as (F) and inserted “9-digit” before “zip code”. Former subpar. (F) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/4">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(4)</ref>, struck out “and 509” after “506”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “non-network station” for “superstation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/3/C">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(3)(C)</ref>, inserted concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “non-network station” for “superstation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/3/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “$250” for “$5”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/3/B/i">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(3)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “$2,500,000 for each 3-month period” for “$250,000 for each 6-month period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/i/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(i)(3)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “$2,500,000” for “$250,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “non-network station” for “superstation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11)(A)(i)(I), (II), (B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/k/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(k)(1)</ref>, substituted “, Code of Federal Regulations” for “of the Code of Federal Regulations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(1)</ref>, amended heading generally. Prior to amendment, heading read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Statutory License for Secondary Transmissions for Private Home Viewing.—”.</inline></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/h/2/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(h)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out concluding provisions which read as follows: “Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (B), a satellite carrier whose secondary transmissions are subject to statutory licensing under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall have no royalty obligation for secondary transmissions to a subscriber under paragraph (3) of such subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “non-network stations” for “superstations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “a royalty fee for that 6-month period, computed by multiplying the total number of subscribers receiving each secondary transmission of each superstation or network station during each calendar month by the appropriate rate in effect under this section; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/c">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(c)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/4">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(4)</ref>, added par. (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/3">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(3)</ref>, (5), redesignated par. (2) as (3), inserted “(including the filing fee specified in paragraph (1)(C))” after “shall receive all fees”, and substituted “paragraph (5)” for “paragraph (4)”. Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/3">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(3)</ref>, (6), redesignated par. (3) as (4), substituted “paragraph (3)” for “paragraph (2)”, and substituted “paragraph (5)” for “paragraph (4)” in two places. Former par. (4) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/d/3">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(d)(3)</ref>, (7), redesignated par. (4) as (5) and substituted “paragraph (3)” for “paragraph (2)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “analog” after “fees for” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(B)</ref>, (g)(2), substituted “primary transmissions” for “primary analog transmissions”, “non-network stations” for “superstations”, and “<date date="2009-07-01">July 1, 2009</date>” for “<date date="2004-07-01">July 1, 2004</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/C">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(C)</ref>, (g)(2), substituted “<date date="2010-06-01">June 1, 2010</date>, the Copyright Royalty Judges” for “<date date="2005-01-02">January 2, 2005</date>, the Librarian of Congress”, “primary transmissions” for “primary analog transmission”, and “non-network stations” for “superstations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/D">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Librarian of Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/E/i">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(E)(i)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “that are parties” for “that a parties”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/E/ii/I">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(E)(ii)(I)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/E/ii/I">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(E)(ii)(I)</ref>, (II), inserted heading and substituted “a proceeding under subparagraph (F)” for “an arbitration proceeding pursuant to subparagraph (E)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/E/ii/III">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(E)(ii)(III)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “Upon receiving a request under subclause (I), the Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Upon receiving a request under subclause (I), the Librarian of Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D)(ii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/E/ii/IV">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(E)(ii)(IV)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “The Copyright Royalty Judges” for “The Librarian”, “the proceeding under subparagraph (F)” for “an arbitration proceeding”, and “that proceeding” for “the arbitration proceeding”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/F">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Copyright Office” and “<date date="2014-12-31">December 31, 2014</date>” for “<date date="2010-05-31">May 31, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/157/s9/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–157, § 9(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-05-31">May 31, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-04-30">April 30, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/151/s2/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–151, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-04-30">April 30, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-03-28">March 28, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/144/s10/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–144, § 10(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-03-28">March 28, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-02-28">February 28, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/i">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(i)</ref>, substituted “copyright royalty judges proceeding” for “compulsory arbitration” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/ii/I">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(ii)(I)</ref>, (II), (IV), (g)(2), in heading, substituted “the proceeding” for “proceedings”, in introductory provisions, substituted “<date date="2010-09-01">September 1, 2010</date>, the Copyright Royalty Judges” for “<date date="2005-05-01">May 1, 2005</date>, the Librarian of Congress”, “a proceeding” for “arbitration proceedings”, “fees to be paid” for “fee to be paid”, “the primary transmissions” for “primary analog transmission”, “non-network stations” for “superstations”, and “distributors—” for “distributors”, and amended concluding provisions generally. Prior to amendment, concluding provisions read as follows: “Such arbitration proceeding shall be conducted under chapter 8 as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Copyright Royalty and Distribution Act of 2004.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/ii/III">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(ii)(III)</ref>, substituted “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Librarian of Congress” and struck out “arbitration” after “participate in the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/iii">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(iii)</ref>, amended introductory provisions generally. Prior to amendment, introductory provisions read as follows: “In determining royalty fees under this subparagraph, the copyright arbitration royalty panel appointed under chapter 8, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Copyright Royalty and Distribution Act of 2004 shall establish fees for the secondary transmissions of the primary analog transmission of network stations and superstations that most clearly represent the fair market value of secondary transmissions, except that the Librarian of Congress and any copyright arbitration royalty panel shall adjust those fees to account for the obligations of the parties under any applicable voluntary agreement filed with the Copyright Office pursuant to subparagraph (D). In determining the fair market value, the panel shall base its decision on economic, competitive, and programming information presented by the parties, including—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/iv">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(iv)</ref>, amended cl. (iii) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The obligation to pay the royalty fee established under a determination which—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) is made by a copyright arbitration royalty panel in an arbitration proceeding under this paragraph and is adopted by the Librarian of Congress under section 802(f), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Copyright Royalty and Distribution Act of 2004; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) is established by the Librarian under section 802(f) as in effect on the day before such date of enactment shall be effective as of <date date="2005-01-01">January 1, 2005</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/1/G/v">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(1)(G)(v)</ref>, substituted “fees” for “fee” in heading and substituted “fees referred to in clause (iii)” for “fee referred to in (iii)” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/e/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(e)(2)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) related to applicability and determination of royalty fees for digital signals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/6">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(6)</ref>, substituted “that contracts” for “which contracts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/6">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(6)</ref>, substituted “that offer” for “which offer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/6">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(6)</ref>, substituted “that is operated” for “which is operated” and “that serves” for “which serves”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/k">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(k)</ref>, substituted “, Code of Federal Regulations, or the Direct Broadcast Satellite Service under part 100 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations” for “of the Code of Federal Regulations or the Direct Broadcast Satellite Service under part 100 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(1)</ref>, amended par. (8) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘subscriber’ means an individual or entity that receives a secondary transmission service by means of a secondary transmission from a satellite carrier and pays a fee for the service, directly or indirectly, to the satellite carrier or to a distributor in accordance with the provisions of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, which directed amendment of section by substituting “non-network station” for “superstation” wherever appearing in headings, was executed by substituting “<inline class="small-caps">Non-network station</inline>” for “<inline class="small-caps">Superstation</inline>” in par. (9) heading, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/g/1">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “non-network station” for “superstation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/b/1/A">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “cannot receive, through the use of a conventional, stationary, outdoor rooftop receiving antenna, an over-the-air signal of a primary network station affiliated with that network of Grade B intensity as defined by the Federal Communications Commission under section 73.683(a) of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/b/1/B">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a)(13),” for “subsection (a)(14)” and “Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act of 2010” for “Satellite Home Viewer Extension and Reauthorization Act of 2004”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/b/1/C">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(b)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “(a)(11)” for “(a)(12)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(2)</ref>, amended par. (11) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘local market’ has the meaning given such term under section 122(j), except that with respect to a low power television station, the term ‘local market’ means the designated market area in which the station is located.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(12), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/3">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(3)</ref>, redesignated pars. (13) and (14) as (12) and (13), respectively, and struck out former par. (12). Text read as follows: “The term ‘low power television station’ means a low power television as defined under section 74.701(f) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on <date date="2004-06-01">June 1, 2004</date>. For purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘low power television station’ includes a low power television station that has been accorded primary status as a Class A television licensee under section 73.6001(a) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/4">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(4)</ref>, added par. (14). Former par. (14) redesignated (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/b/2">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (14).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/f/5">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(f)(5)</ref>, added par. (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s102/j">Pub. L. 111–175, § 102(j)</ref>, (k)(1), substituted “<date date="2014-12-31">December 31, 2014</date>” for “<date date="2010-05-31">May 31, 2010</date>” and “, Code of Federal Regulations” for “of the Code of Federal Regulations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/157/s9/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–157, § 9(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-05-31">May 31, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-04-30">April 30, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/151/s2/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–151, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-04-30">April 30, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-03-28">March 28, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/144/s10/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–144, § 10(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-03-28">March 28, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2010-02-28">February 28, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s105">Pub. L. 111–175, § 105</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/111/295">Pub. L. 111–295</ref> substituted “an examination” for “the examinations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsecs. (c)(1)(E), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/118">Pub. L. 111–118</ref> substituted “<date date="2010-02-28">February 28, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/403/s209/a/4/A">Pub. L. 110–403, § 209(a)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 510” for “sections 509 and 510”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/403/s209/a/4/B">Pub. L. 110–403, § 209(a)(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “and 509” after “506” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/110/403/s209/a/4/C">Pub. L. 110–403, § 209(a)(4)(C)</ref>, (D), struck out “and 509” after “506”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/e/1/A">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(e)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted second sentence for former second sentence which read as follows: “If the Copyright Royalty Judges determine that no such controversy exists, the Librarian of Congress shall, after deducting reasonable administrative costs under this paragraph, distribute such fees to the copyright owners entitled to receive them, or to their designated agents.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/e/1/B">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(e)(1)(B)</ref>, amended subpar. (C) generally. Prior to amendment, text of subpar. (C) read as follows: “During the pendency of any proceeding under this subsection, the Copyright Royalty Judges shall withhold from distribution an amount sufficient to satisfy all claims with respect to which a controversy exists, but shall have the discretion to proceed to distribute any amounts that are not in controversy.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/g">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(g)</ref>, deemed amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/h">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(h)</ref>, never to have been enacted. See 2004 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/e/2">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “arbitration” for “arbitrary” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/1">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “or for viewing in a commercial establishment” after “for private home viewing” in two places and substituted “subscriber” for “household”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/1">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(1)</ref>, struck out “and pbs satellite feed” after “Superstations” in heading, substituted “paragraphs (5), (6), and (8)” for “paragraphs (3), (4), and (6)” and struck out “or by the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed” after “primary transmission made by a superstation” in first sentence, and struck out at end “In the case of the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed, the statutory license shall be effective until <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/2/A">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (5), (6), (7), and (8)” for “paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/7">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(7)</ref>, inserted at end “The limitation in this clause shall not apply to secondary transmissions under paragraph (3).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/2/B">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(2)(B)</ref>, added subpars. (C) and (D) and struck out heading and text of former subpar. (C). Text read as follows: “A satellite carrier that makes secondary transmissions of a primary transmission made by a network station pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall, 90 days after commencing such secondary transmissions, submit to the network that owns or is affiliated with the network station a list identifying (by name and street address, including county and zip code) all subscribers to which the satellite carrier makes secondary transmissions of that primary transmission. Thereafter, on the 15th of each month, the satellite carrier shall submit to the network a list identifying (by name and street address, including county and zip code) any persons who have been added or dropped as such subscribers since the last submission under this subparagraph. Such subscriber information submitted by a satellite carrier may be used only for purposes of monitoring compliance by the satellite carrier with this subsection. The submission requirements of this subparagraph shall apply to a satellite carrier only if the network to whom the submissions are to be made places on file with the Register of Copyrights a document identifying the name and address of the person to whom such submissions are to be made. The Register shall maintain for public inspection a file of all such documents.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref>, §§ 102(5), (6), 103(1), added pars. (3) and (4) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (5) and (6), respectively. Former pars. (5) and (6) redesignated (7) and (8), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/5">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(5)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (7). Former par. (7) redesignated (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/6/A">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “who is not eligible to receive the transmission under this section” for “who does not reside in an unserved household” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/6/B">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(6)(B)</ref>, substituted “who are not eligible to receive the transmission under this section” for “who do not reside in unserved households” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/6/C">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(6)(C)</ref>, substituted “is to a subscriber who is eligible to receive the secondary transmission under this section” for “is for private home viewing to an unserved household”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/3">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(3)</ref>, (5), redesignated par. (6) as (8) and struck out former par. (8) which related to transitional signal intensity measurement procedures.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9) to (13). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s102/4">Pub. L. 108–447, § 102(4)</ref>, (5), redesignated pars. (7) and (9) to (12) as (9) and (10) to (13), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(2)</ref>, added par. (14).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s104">Pub. L. 108–447, § 104</ref>, added par. (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s111/a">Pub. L. 108–447, § 111(a)</ref>, added par. (16).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/4">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(4)</ref>, inserted at end: “Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (B), a satellite carrier whose secondary transmissions are subject to statutory licensing under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall have no royalty obligation for secondary transmissions to a subscriber under paragraph (3) of such subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “for private home viewing” after “to subscribers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/3">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(3)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “a royalty fee for that 6-month period, computed by—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) multiplying the total number of subscribers receiving each secondary transmission of a superstation during each calendar month by 17.5 cents per subscriber in the case of superstations that as retransmitted by the satellite carrier include any program which, if delivered by any cable system in the United States, would be subject to the syndicated exclusivity rules of the Federal Communications Commission, and 14 cents per subscriber in the case of superstations that are syndex-proof as defined in section 258.2 of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) multiplying the number of subscribers receiving each secondary transmission of a network station or the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed during each calendar month by 6 cents; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) adding together the totals computed under clauses (i) and (ii).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “for private home viewing” after “secondary transmission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/g/1">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Librarian of Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “for private home viewing” after “secondary transmissions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/g/2/A">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(g)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Librarian of Congress” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/g/2/B">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(g)(2)(B)</ref>, reenacted headings without change and amended text generally, substituting provisions relating to duties of Copyright Royalty Judges concerning determination of royalty fee controversies and distribution of royalty fees for provisions relating to duties of Librarian of Congress relating to such determination and distribution.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s103/5">Pub. L. 108–447, § 103(5)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text related to adjustment, determination, arbitration, and reduction of royalty fees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s5/h">Pub. L. 108–419, § 5(h)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (c) by substituting “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “Librarian of Congress” in par. (2)(B), “Copyright Royalty Judges shall prescribe as provided in section 803(b)(6)” for “Register of Copyrights shall prescribe” in par. (2)(C), “proceedings” for “arbitration proceedings” and for “arbitration proceeding” in par. (3)(A), “Copyright Royalty Judges” for “copyright arbitration royalty panel appointed under chapter 8” and “Copyright Royalty Judges shall base their determination” for “panel shall base its decision” in par. (3)(B), “determination under chapter 8” for “decision of arbitration panel or order of librarian” in heading of par. (3)(C), and “(i) is made by the Copyright Royalty Judges pursuant to this paragraph and becomes final, or” and “(ii) is made by the court on appeal under section 803(d)(3),” for cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, of par. (3)(C), was deemed never to have been enacted by Pub L. 109–303, § 4(g). See Removal of Inconsistent Provisions note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/3">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(3)</ref>, struck out “for private home viewing” after “individual subscribers” and inserted “in accordance with the provisions of this section” before the period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s105/1">Pub. L. 108–447, § 105(1)</ref>, substituted “a television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission” for “a television broadcast station”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/4">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “pursuant to this section” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s107/a/5">Pub. L. 108–447, § 107(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “or entity that” for “who”, struck out “for private home viewing” after “transmission service”, and inserted “in accordance with the provisions of this section” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s105/2">Pub. L. 108–447, § 105(2)</ref>, amended heading and text of par. (9) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘superstation’—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) means a television broadcast station, other than a network station, licensed by the Federal Communications Commission that is secondarily transmitted by a satellite carrier; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) except for purposes of computing the royalty fee, includes the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s105/3/A">Pub. L. 108–447, § 105(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “that meets the standards of subsection (a)(14) whether or not the waiver was granted before the date of the enactment of the Satellite Home Viewer Extension and Reauthorization Act of 2004” for “granted under regulations established under section 339(c)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s105/3/B">Pub. L. 108–447, § 105(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “(a)(12)” for “(a)(11)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11) to (13). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s105/4">Pub. L. 108–447, § 105(4)</ref>, added pars. (11) to (13) and struck out former pars. (11) and (12) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(11) <inline class="small-caps">Local market</inline>.—The term ‘local market’ has the meaning given such term under section 122(j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(12) <inline class="small-caps">Public broadcasting service satellite feed</inline>.—The term ‘Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed’ means the national satellite feed distributed and designated for purposes of this section by the Public Broadcasting Service consisting of educational and informational programming intended for private home viewing, to which the Public Broadcasting Service holds national terrestrial broadcast rights.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s101/b">Pub. L. 108–447, § 101(b)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>” for “<date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s108">Pub. L. 108–447, § 108</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/3/B">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(3)(B)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/b/2/A">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(b)(2)(A)]</ref>. See 1999 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/3/A">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(3)(A)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/a">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(a)]</ref>. See 1999 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/1/A">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(1)(A)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1007/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1007(2)]</ref>. See 1999 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13210/1">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13210(1)</ref>, substituted “of a performance” for “of performance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/1/B">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(1)(B)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1007/3">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1007(3)]</ref>. See 1999 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13210/8">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13210(8)</ref>, substituted “retransmitted” for “transmitted” and “retransmissions” for “transmissions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/2">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(2)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(b)]</ref>. See 1999 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/b/2/A">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(b)(2)(A)]</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/3/B">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a superstation or by the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed” for “primary transmission made by a superstation and embodying a performance or display of a work”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1007/1">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1007(1)]</ref>, inserted “with regard to secondary transmissions the satellite carrier is in compliance with the rules, regulations, or authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission governing the carriage of television broadcast station signals,” after “satellite carrier to the public for private home viewing,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/a">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(a)]</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/3/A">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(3)(A)</ref>, in heading substituted “Superstations and pbs satellite feed” for “Superstations” and in text inserted “In the case of the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed, the statutory license shall be effective until <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>.” at end. <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, which repealed <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/a/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(a)(2)]</ref>, was executed by striking out “or by the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed” which had been inserted by section 1006(a)(2) after “of a primary transmission made by a superstation”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/b/2/A">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(b)(2)(A)]</ref>, substituted “a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by a network station” for “programming contained in a primary transmission made by a network station and embodying a performance or display of a work”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1007/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1007(2)]</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/1/A">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “with regard to secondary transmissions the satellite carrier is in compliance with the rules, regulations, or authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission governing the carriage of television broadcast station signals,” after “satellite carrier to the public for private home viewing,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/a/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(a)(2)]</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The statutory license provided for in subparagraph (A) shall be limited to secondary transmissions to persons who reside in unserved households.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/c">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(c)]</ref>, struck out “currently” after “all subscribers to which the satellite carrier” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/b/2/C">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(b)(2)(C)]</ref>, inserted “a performance or display of a work embodied in” after “by a satellite carrier of” and struck out “and embodying a performance or display of a work” after “network station”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(b)]</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1011/b/2/D">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1011(b)(2)(D)]</ref>, inserted “performance or display of a work embodied in” after “by a satellite carrier of” and struck out “and embodying a performance or display of a work” after “network station”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/106/44">Pub. L. 106–44</ref> substituted “within the network station’s” for “within the network’s station” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/d">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(d)]</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1007/3">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1007(3)]</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/1/B">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(b)]</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13209/2">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13209(2)</ref>, inserted “or the Public Broadcasting Service satellite feed” after “network station”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1004">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1004]</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1008/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1008(b)]</ref>, substituted a semicolon for the period at end of subpar. (B) and inserted concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/c/1">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(c)(1)]</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘superstation’ means a television broadcast station, other than a network station, licensed by the Federal Communications Commission that is secondarily transmitted by a satellite carrier.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/a/1">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(a)(1)]</ref>, added par. (10) and struck out heading and text of former par. (10). Text read as follows: “The term ‘unserved household’, with respect to a particular television network, means a household that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) cannot receive, through the use of a conventional outdoor rooftop receiving antenna, an over-the-air signal of grade B intensity (as defined by the Federal Communications Commission) of a primary network station affiliated with that network, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) has not, within 90 days before the date on which that household subscribes, either initially or on renewal, to receive secondary transmissions by a satellite carrier of a network station affiliated with that network, subscribed to a cable system that provides the signal of a primary network station affiliated with that network.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/e">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(e)]</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘local market’ means the area encompassed within a network station’s predicted Grade B contour as that contour is defined by the Federal Communications Commission.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1006/c/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1006(c)(2)]</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tI/s1005/c">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1005(c)]</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “No provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref> or any other law (other than this section) shall be construed to contain any authorization, exemption, or license through which secondary transmissions by satellite carrier for private home viewing of programming contained in a primary transmission made by a superstation or a network station may be made without obtaining the consent of the copyright owner.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/3">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(3)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/5/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(5)(A)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/1">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(1)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/3/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(3)(A)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s12/a/8">Pub. L. 105–80, § 12(a)(8)</ref>, which directed substitution of “unless” for “until unless” before “a royalty fee”, could not be executed because “until” did not appear subsequent to amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(A)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A), (D), (3)(A)–(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(1), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/39">Pub. L. 104–39</ref> inserted “and section 114(d)” after “of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/1">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(1)</ref>, struck out “90 days after the effective date of the Satellite Home Viewer Act of 1988, or” before “90 days after commencing”, “whichever is later,” before “submit to the network that owns”, and “, on or after the effective date of the Satellite Home Viewer Act of 1988,” after “Register of Copyrights”, and inserted “name and” after “identifying (by” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/5/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(5)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/3">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(3)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1988-11-16">November 16, 1988</date>” for “the date of the enactment of the Satellite Home Viewer Act of 1988”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/2">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(2)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/5/B">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(5)(B)</ref>, added pars. (8) to (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/3/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(3)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/1">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “17.5 cents per subscriber in the case of superstations that as retransmitted by the satellite carrier include any program which, if delivered by any cable system in the United States, would be subject to the syndicated exclusivity rules of the Federal Communications Commission, and 14 cents per subscriber in the case of superstations that are syndex-proof as defined in section 258.2 of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations” for “12 cents”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/3/B">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “6 cents” for “3 cents”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, struck out “until <date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>,” before “unless a royalty fee”, substituted “paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection” for “paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of this subsection”, and struck out at end “After that date, the fee shall be determined either in accordance with the voluntary negotiation procedure specified in paragraph (2) or in accordance with the compulsory arbitration procedure specified in paragraphs (3) and (4).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/B/i">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(B)(i)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1996-07-01">July 1, 1996</date>” for “<date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/B/ii">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(B)(ii)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, or in accordance with the terms of the agreement, whichever is later” for “<date date="1994-12-31">December 31, 1994</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/C/i">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(C)(i)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>” for “<date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/C/ii">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(C)(ii)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Factors for determining royalty fees</inline>.—In determining royalty fees under this paragraph, the copyright arbitration royalty panel appointed under chapter 8 shall consider the approximate average cost to a cable system for the right to secondarily transmit to the public a primary transmission made by a broadcast station, the fee established under any voluntary agreement filed with the Copyright Office in accordance with paragraph (2), and the last fee proposed by the parties, before proceedings under this paragraph, for the secondary transmission of superstations or network stations for private home viewing. The fee shall also be calculated to achieve the following objectives:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) To maximize the availability of creative works to the public.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) To afford the copyright owner a fair return for his or her creative work and the copyright user a fair income under existing economic conditions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) To reflect the relative roles of the copyright owner and the copyright user in the product made available to the public with respect to relative creative contribution, technological contribution, capital investment, cost, risk, and contribution to the opening of new markets for creative expression and media for their communication.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iv) To minimize any disruptive impact on the structure of the industries involved and on generally prevailing industry practices.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/4/C/iii">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(4)(C)(iii)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s1/2">Pub. L. 105–80, § 1(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end “or <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, whichever is later”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/6/A">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(6)(A)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Network station</inline>.—The term ‘network station’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111/f">section 111(f) of this title</ref>, and includes any translator station or terrestrial satellite station that rebroadcasts all or substantially all of the programming broadcast by a network station.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/6/B">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(6)(B)</ref>, inserted “and operates in the Fixed-Satellite Service under part 25 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations or the Direct Broadcast Satellite Service under part 100 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations” after “Federal Communications Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s2/6/C">Pub. L. 103–369, § 2(6)(C)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/1/A">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “, after consultation with the Copyright Royalty Tribunal,” in introductory provisions after “Register shall” and in subpar. (A) after “Copyrights may”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/1/B">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(1)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/1/D">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(1)(D)</ref>, in subpar. (A), substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal” after “claim with the” and for “Tribunal” after “requirements that the”, in subpar. (B), substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal” before “shall determine” and for “Tribunal” wherever else appearing, and substituted “convene a copyright arbitration royalty panel” for “conduct a proceeding”, and in subpar. (C), substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/A">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Adjustment” for “Determination” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/B">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/C/i">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “Librarian of Congress” for “Copyright Royalty Tribunal” and substituted last sentence for former last sentence which read as follows: “Such notice shall include the names and qualifications of potential arbitrators chosen by the Tribunal from a list of available arbitrators obtained from the American Arbitration Association or such similar organization as the Tribunal shall select.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, (iii), redesignated subpar. (D) as (B), substituted “copyright arbitration royalty panel appointed under chapter 8” for “Arbitration Panel” in introductory provisions, and struck out former subpar. (B) which provided for the selection of an Arbitration Panel.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, (v), redesignated subpar. (G) as (C), amended subpar. generally, substituting provisions relating to period during which decision of arbitration panel or order of Librarian of Congress becomes effective for provisions relating to period during which decision of Arbitration Panel or order of Copyright Royalty Tribunal became effective, and struck out former subpar. (C) which related to proceedings in arbitration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/C/vi">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(C)(vi)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (H) as (D) and substituted “referred to in subparagraph (C)” for “adopted or ordered under subparagraph (F)”. Former subpar. (D) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(E) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/C/iv">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(C)(iv)</ref>–(vi)(I), struck out subpar. (E) which required the Arbitration Panel to report to the Copyright Royalty Tribunal not later than 60 days after publication of notice initiating an arbitration proceeding, struck out subpar. (F) which required action by the Tribunal within 60 days after receiving the report by the Panel, and redesignated subpars. (G) and (H) as (C) and (D), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/198/s5/2/D">Pub. L. 103–198, § 5(2)(D)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which established procedures for judicial review of decisions of the Copyright Royalty Tribunal.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7449843c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7449843d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/175">Pub. L. 111–175</ref> effective <date date="2010-02-27">Feb. 27, 2010</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/s307/a">section 307(a) of Pub. L. 111–175</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7449843e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/303">Pub. L. 109–303</ref> effective as if included in the Copyright Royalty and Distribution Reform Act of 2004, <ref href="/us/pl/108/419">Pub. L. 108–419</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 109–303</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7449843f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/419">Pub. L. 108–419</ref> effective 6 months after <date date="2004-11-30">Nov. 30, 2004</date>, subject to transition provisions, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/419/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 108–419</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id74498440-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1000(a)(9) [title I, §§ 1004, 1006] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective <date date="1999-07-01">July 1, 1999</date>, and amendment by section 1000(a)(9) [title I, §§ 1005, 1007, 1008(b), 1011(b)(2), (c)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, see section 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1012] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id74498441-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/80/s13">Pub. L. 105–80, § 13</ref>, <date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1536">111 Stat. 1536</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/80/s13">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), the amendments made by this Act [amending this section, sections 101, 104A, 108 to 110, 114 to 116, 303, 304, 405, 407, 411, 504, 509, 601, 708, 801 to 803, 909, 910, 1006, and 1007 of this title, and <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2319">section 2319 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s914">section 914 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Satellite Home Viewer Act</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by section 1 [amending this section] shall be effective as if enacted as part of the Satellite Home Viewer Act of 1994 (<ref href="/us/pl/103/369">Public Law 103–369</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Technical Amendment</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by section 12(b)(1) [amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s914">section 914 of this title</ref>] shall be effective as if enacted on <date date="1987-11-09">November 9, 1987</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id74498442-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/39">Pub. L. 104–39</ref> effective 3 months after <date date="1995-11-01">Nov. 1, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/39/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 104–39</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id74498443-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s6">Pub. L. 103–369, § 6</ref>, <date date="1994-10-18">Oct. 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3481">108 Stat. 3481</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/369/s6">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (d), this Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as a note under this section] and the amendments made by this Act take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-18">Oct. 18, 1994</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burden of Proof Provisions</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/5/D">section 119(a)(5)(D) of title 17</ref>, United States Code (as added by section 2(2) of this Act) relating to the burden of proof of satellite carriers, shall take effect on <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, with respect to civil actions relating to the eligibility of subscribers who subscribed to service as an unserved household before the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional Signal Intensity Measurement Procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119/a/8">section 119(a)(8) of title 17</ref>, United States Code (as added by section 2(5) of this Act), relating to transitional signal intensity measurements, shall cease to be effective on <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local Service Area of a Primary Transmitter</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by section 3(b) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>], relating to the definition of the local service area of a primary transmitter, shall take effect on <date date="1994-07-01">July 1, 1994</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id74498444-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/667/tII/s206">Pub. L. 100–667, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3960">102 Stat. 3960</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/667/tII/s206">“This title and the amendments made by this title [enacting this section and sections 612 and 613 of Title 47, Telecommunications, amending sections 111, 501, 801, and 804 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s605">section 605 of Title 47</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>] take effect on <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>, except that the authority of the Register of Copyrights to issue regulations pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119/b/1">section 119(b)(1) of title 17</ref>, United States Code, as added by section 202 of this Act, takes effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/667/tII/s207">Pub. L. 100–667, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3960">102 Stat. 3960</ref>, provided that this title and the amendments made by this title (other than the amendments made by section 205 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s605">section 605 of Title 47</ref>]) cease to be effective on <date date="1994-12-31">Dec. 31, 1994</date>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s4/b">Pub. L. 103–369, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-18">Oct. 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3481">108 Stat. 3481</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74498445-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/175/tI/s107/a">Pub. L. 111–175, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-05-27">May 27, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1245">124 Stat. 1245</ref>, which provided that this section would cease to be effective on <date date="2014-12-31">Dec. 31, 2014</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/200/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 113–200, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-04">Dec. 4, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2066">128 Stat. 2066</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/118/dB/s1003/a/2/A">Pub. L. 111–118, div. B, § 1003(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-19">Dec. 19, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3469">123 Stat. 3469</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/144/s10/a/2">Pub. L. 111–144, § 10(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-02">Mar. 2, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/47">124 Stat. 47</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/151/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 111–151, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-26">Mar. 26, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1027">124 Stat. 1027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/157/s9/a/2">Pub. L. 111–157, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-04-15">Apr. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1119">124 Stat. 1119</ref>, which provided that this section would cease to be effective on <date date="2010-05-31">May 31, 2010</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/111/175/tI/s107/b">Pub. L. 111–175, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-05-27">May 27, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1245">124 Stat. 1245</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s4/a">Pub. L. 103–369, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-18">Oct. 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3481">108 Stat. 3481</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tI/s1003">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title I, § 1003]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–527; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dJ/tIX">Pub. L. 108–447, div. J, title IX</ref> [title I, § 101(a)], <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3394">118 Stat. 3394</ref>, which provided that this section would cease to be effective on <date date="2009-12-31">Dec. 31, 2009</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/111/118/dB/s1003/a/2/B">Pub. L. 111–118, div. B, § 1003(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-19">Dec. 19, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3469">123 Stat. 3469</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74498446-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Previously Covered Subscribers Under the STELA Reauthorization Act of 2014</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tXI/s1102/b">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XI, § 1102(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3203">133 Stat. 3203</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tXI/s1102/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A subscriber of a satellite carrier who receives the secondary transmission of a network station under the statutory license in <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119">section 119 of title 17</ref>, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], and to whom subsection (a)(2)(B) of such section, as amended by subsection (a), does not apply, shall continue to be eligible to receive that secondary transmission from such carrier under such license, and at the royalty rate established for such license by the Copyright Royalty Board or voluntary agreement, as applicable, until the date that is the earlier of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> <date date="2020-05-31">May 31, 2020</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date on which such carrier provides local-into-local service to all DMAs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the terms ‘satellite carrier’, ‘subscriber’, ‘secondary transmission’, ‘network station’, and ‘local-into-local service to all DMAs’ have the meaning given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119">section 119 of title 17</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74498447-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Removal of Inconsistent Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/303/s4/g">Pub. L. 109–303, § 4(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1483">120 Stat. 1483</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/303/s4/g">“The amendments contained in subsection (h) of section 5 of the Copyright Royalty and Distribution Reform Act of 2004 [<ref href="/us/pl/108/419">Pub. L. 108–419</ref>, amending this section] shall be deemed never to have been enacted.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74498448-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Certain Proceedings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dJ/tIX">Pub. L. 108–447, div. J, title IX</ref> [title I, § 106], <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3406">118 Stat. 3406</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/447/dJ/tIX">“Nothing in this title [see Short Title of 2004 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>] shall modify any remedy imposed on a party that is required by the judgment of a court in any action that was brought before <date date="2004-05-01">May 1, 2004</date>, against that party for a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119">section 119 of title 17</ref>, United States Code.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id74498449-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/369/s5">Pub. L. 103–369, § 5</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3481">108 Stat. 3481</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/369/s5">“The amendments made by this section apply only to <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s119">section 119 of title 17</ref>, United States Code.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
