<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id746aef23-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201"><num value="1201">§ 1201.</num><heading> Circumvention of copyright protection systems</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef24-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Violations Regarding Circumvention of Technological Measures</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef25-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef26-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No person shall circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title. The prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall take effect at the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef27-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The prohibition contained in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to persons who are users of a copyrighted work which is in a particular class of works, if such persons are, or are likely to be in the succeeding 3-year period, adversely affected by virtue of such prohibition in their ability to make noninfringing uses of that particular class of works under this title, as determined under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef28-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> During the 2-year period described in subparagraph (A), and during each succeeding 3-year period, the Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, who shall consult with the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce and report and comment on his or her views in making such recommendation, shall make the determination in a rulemaking proceeding for purposes of subparagraph (B) of whether persons who are users of a copyrighted work are, or are likely to be in the succeeding 3-year period, adversely affected by the prohibition under subparagraph (A) in their ability to make noninfringing uses under this title of a particular class of copyrighted works. In conducting such rulemaking, the Librarian shall examine—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef29-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the availability for use of copyrighted works;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef2a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the availability for use of works for nonprofit archival, preservation, and educational purposes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef2b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the impact that the prohibition on the circumvention of technological measures applied to copyrighted works has on criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, or research;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef2c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the effect of circumvention of technological measures on the market for or value of copyrighted works; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef2d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> such other factors as the Librarian considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef2e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Librarian shall publish any class of copyrighted works for which the Librarian has determined, pursuant to the rulemaking conducted under subparagraph (C), that noninfringing uses by persons who are users of a copyrighted work are, or are likely to be, adversely affected, and the prohibition contained in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to such users with respect to such class of works for the ensuing 3-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef2f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Neither the exception under subparagraph (B) from the applicability of the prohibition contained in subparagraph (A), nor any determination made in a rulemaking conducted under subparagraph (C), may be used as a defense in any action to enforce any provision of this title other than this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef30-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> No person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef31-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef32-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef33-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is marketed by that person or another acting in concert with that person with that person’s knowledge for use in circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef34-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef35-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to “circumvent a technological measure” means to descramble a scrambled work, to decrypt an encrypted work, or otherwise to avoid, bypass, remove, deactivate, or impair a technological measure, without the authority of the copyright owner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef36-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a technological measure “effectively controls access to a work” if the measure, in the ordinary course of its operation, requires the application of information, or a process or a treatment, with the authority of the copyright owner, to gain access to the work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef37-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Violations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef38-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> No person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef39-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef3a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef3b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is marketed by that person or another acting in concert with that person with that person’s knowledge for use in circumventing protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title in a work or a portion thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef3c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef3d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to “circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure” means avoiding, bypassing, removing, deactivating, or otherwise impairing a technological measure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef3e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a technological measure “effectively protects a right of a copyright owner under this title” if the measure, in the ordinary course of its operation, prevents, restricts, or otherwise limits the exercise of a right of a copyright owner under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef3f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Rights, Etc., Not Affected</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef40-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall affect rights, remedies, limitations, or defenses to copyright infringement, including fair use, under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef41-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall enlarge or diminish vicarious or contributory liability for copyright infringement in connection with any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef42-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall require that the design of, or design and selection of parts and components for, a consumer electronics, telecommunications, or computing product provide for a response to any particular technological measure, so long as such part or component, or the product in which such part or component is integrated, does not otherwise fall within the prohibitions of subsection (a)(2) or (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef43-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall enlarge or diminish any rights of free speech or the press for activities using consumer electronics, telecommunications, or computing products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef44-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption for Nonprofit Libraries, Archives, and Educational Institutions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef45-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution which gains access to a commercially exploited copyrighted work solely in order to make a good faith determination of whether to acquire a copy of that work for the sole purpose of engaging in conduct permitted under this title shall not be in violation of subsection (a)(1)(A). A copy of a work to which access has been gained under this paragraph—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef46-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may not be retained longer than necessary to make such good faith determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef47-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may not be used for any other purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef48-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The exemption made available under paragraph (1) shall only apply with respect to a work when an identical copy of that work is not reasonably available in another form.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef49-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution that willfully for the purpose of commercial advantage or financial gain violates paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef4a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall, for the first offense, be subject to the civil remedies under section 1203; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef4b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall, for repeated or subsequent offenses, in addition to the civil remedies under section 1203, forfeit the exemption provided under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef4c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection may not be used as a defense to a claim under subsection (a)(2) or (b), nor may this subsection permit a nonprofit library, archives, or educational institution to manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, component, or part thereof, which circumvents a technological measure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef4d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> In order for a library or archives to qualify for the exemption under this subsection, the collections of that library or archives shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef4e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> open to the public; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef4f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> available not only to researchers affiliated with the library or archives or with the institution of which it is a part, but also to other persons doing research in a specialized field.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef50-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Law Enforcement, Intelligence, and Other Government Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>This section does not prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, information security, or intelligence activity of an officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or a person acting pursuant to a contract with the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State. For purposes of this subsection, the term “information security” means activities carried out in order to identify and address the vulnerabilities of a government computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef51-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reverse Engineering</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef52-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), a person who has lawfully obtained the right to use a copy of a computer program may circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a particular portion of that program for the sole purpose of identifying and analyzing those elements of the program that are necessary to achieve interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, and that have not previously been readily available to the person engaging in the circumvention, to the extent any such acts of identification and analysis do not constitute infringement under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef53-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a)(2) and (b), a person may develop and employ technological means to circumvent a technological measure, or to circumvent protection afforded by a technological measure, in order to enable the identification and analysis under paragraph (1), or for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, if such means are necessary to achieve such interoperability, to the extent that doing so does not constitute infringement under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef54-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The information acquired through the acts permitted under paragraph (1), and the means permitted under paragraph (2), may be made available to others if the person referred to in paragraph (1) or (2), as the case may be, provides such information or means solely for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs, and to the extent that doing so does not constitute infringement under this title or violate applicable law other than this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef55-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “interoperability” means the ability of computer programs to exchange information, and of such programs mutually to use the information which has been exchanged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef56-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Encryption Research.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef57-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef58-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “encryption research” means activities necessary to identify and analyze flaws and vulnerabilities of encryption technologies applied to copyrighted works, if these activities are conducted to advance the state of knowledge in the field of encryption technology or to assist in the development of encryption products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef59-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “encryption technology” means the scrambling and descrambling of information using mathematical formulas or algorithms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef5a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Permissible acts of encryption research</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to circumvent a technological measure as applied to a copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of a published work in the course of an act of good faith encryption research if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef5b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the person lawfully obtained the encrypted copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of the published work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef5c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such act is necessary to conduct such encryption research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef5d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the person made a good faith effort to obtain authorization before the circumvention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef5e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such act does not constitute infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1030">section 1030 of title 18</ref> and those provisions of title 18 amended by the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef5f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors in determining exemption</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining whether a person qualifies for the exemption under paragraph (2), the factors to be considered shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef60-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whether the information derived from the encryption research was disseminated, and if so, whether it was disseminated in a manner reasonably calculated to advance the state of knowledge or development of encryption technology, versus whether it was disseminated in a manner that facilitates infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including a violation of privacy or breach of security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef61-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whether the person is engaged in a legitimate course of study, is employed, or is appropriately trained or experienced, in the field of encryption technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef62-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whether the person provides the copyright owner of the work to which the technological measure is applied with notice of the findings and documentation of the research, and the time when such notice is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef63-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of technological means for research activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef64-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> develop and employ technological means to circumvent a technological measure for the sole purpose of that person performing the acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef65-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide the technological means to another person with whom he or she is working collaboratively for the purpose of conducting the acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2) or for the purpose of having that other person verify his or her acts of good faith encryption research described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef66-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this chapter, the Register of Copyrights and the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce shall jointly report to the Congress on the effect this subsection has had on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef67-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> encryption research and the development of encryption technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef68-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the adequacy and effectiveness of technological measures designed to protect copyrighted works; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef69-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/g/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> protection of copyright owners against the unauthorized access to their encrypted copyrighted works.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The report shall include legislative recommendations, if any.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef6a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions Regarding Minors</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In applying subsection (a) to a component or part, the court may consider the necessity for its intended and actual incorporation in a technology, product, service, or device, which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef6b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> does not itself violate the provisions of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef6c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has the sole purpose to prevent the access of minors to material on the Internet.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef6d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection of Personally Identifying Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef6e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Circumvention permitted</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under this title, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef6f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the technological measure, or the work it protects, contains the capability of collecting or disseminating personally identifying information reflecting the online activities of a natural person who seeks to gain access to the work protected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef70-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the normal course of its operation, the technological measure, or the work it protects, collects or disseminates personally identifying information about the person who seeks to gain access to the work protected, without providing conspicuous notice of such collection or dissemination to such person, and without providing such person with the capability to prevent or restrict such collection or dissemination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef71-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the act of circumvention has the sole effect of identifying and disabling the capability described in subparagraph (A), and has no other effect on the ability of any person to gain access to any work; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef72-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the act of circumvention is carried out solely for the purpose of preventing the collection or dissemination of personally identifying information about a natural person who seeks to gain access to the work protected, and is not in violation of any other law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef73-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to certain technological measures</inline>.—</heading><content>This subsection does not apply to a technological measure, or a work it protects, that does not collect or disseminate personally identifying information and that is disclosed to a user as not having or using such capability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef74-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security Testing.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef75-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subsection, the term “security testing” means accessing a computer, computer system, or computer network, solely for the purpose of good faith testing, investigating, or correcting, a security flaw or vulnerability, with the authorization of the owner or operator of such computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef76-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Permissible acts of security testing</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(1)(A), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to engage in an act of security testing, if such act does not constitute infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1030">section 1030 of title 18</ref> and those provisions of title 18 amended by the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef77-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors in determining exemption</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining whether a person qualifies for the exemption under paragraph (2), the factors to be considered shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef78-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whether the information derived from the security testing was used solely to promote the security of the owner or operator of such computer, computer system or computer network, or shared directly with the developer of such computer, computer system, or computer network; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef79-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whether the information derived from the security testing was used or maintained in a manner that does not facilitate infringement under this title or a violation of applicable law other than this section, including a violation of privacy or breach of security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef7a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of technological means for security testing</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2), it is not a violation of that subsection for a person to develop, produce, distribute or employ technological means for the sole purpose of performing the acts of security testing described in subsection (2),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002018"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be subsection “(a)(2),”.</note> provided such technological means does not otherwise violate section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002019"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746aef7b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Analog Devices and Certain Technological Measures.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef7c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain analog devices.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef7d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Effective 18 months after the date of the enactment of this chapter, no person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide or otherwise traffic in any—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef7e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> VHS format analog video cassette recorder unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef7f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 8mm format analog video cassette camcorder unless such camcorder conforms to the automatic gain control technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef80-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Beta format analog video cassette recorder, unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology, except that this requirement shall not apply until there are 1,000 Beta format analog video cassette recorders sold in the United States in any one calendar year after the date of the enactment of this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef81-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> 8mm format analog video cassette recorder that is not an analog video cassette camcorder, unless such recorder conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology, except that this requirement shall not apply until there are 20,000 such recorders sold in the United States in any one calendar year after the date of the enactment of this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef82-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> analog video cassette recorder that records using an NTSC format video input and that is not otherwise covered under clauses (i) through (iv), unless such device conforms to the automatic gain control copy control technology.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef83-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Effective on the date of the enactment of this chapter, no person shall manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide or otherwise traffic in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef84-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any VHS format analog video cassette recorder or any 8mm format analog video cassette recorder if the design of the model of such recorder has been modified after such date of enactment so that a model of recorder that previously conformed to the automatic gain control copy control technology no longer conforms to such technology; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef85-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any VHS format analog video cassette recorder, or any 8mm format analog video cassette recorder that is not an 8mm analog video cassette camcorder, if the design of the model of such recorder has been modified after such date of enactment so that a model of recorder that previously conformed to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology no longer conforms to such technology.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Manufacturers that have not previously manufactured or sold a VHS format analog video cassette recorder, or an 8mm format analog cassette recorder, shall be required to conform to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology in the initial model of any such recorder manufactured after the date of the enactment of this chapter, and thereafter to continue conforming to the four-line colorstripe copy control technology. For purposes of this subparagraph, an analog video cassette recorder “conforms to” the four-line colorstripe copy control technology if it records a signal that, when played back by the playback function of that recorder in the normal viewing mode, exhibits, on a reference display device, a display containing distracting visible lines through portions of the viewable picture.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef86-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain encoding restrictions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No person shall apply the automatic gain control copy control technology or colorstripe copy control technology to prevent or limit consumer copying except such copying—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef87-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> of a single transmission, or specified group of transmissions, of live events or of audiovisual works for which a member of the public has exercised choice in selecting the transmissions, including the content of the transmissions or the time of receipt of such transmissions, or both, and as to which such member is charged a separate fee for each such transmission or specified group of transmissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef88-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> from a copy of a transmission of a live event or an audiovisual work if such transmission is provided by a channel or service where payment is made by a member of the public for such channel or service in the form of a subscription fee that entitles the member of the public to receive all of the programming contained in such channel or service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef89-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> from a physical medium containing one or more prerecorded audiovisual works; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef8a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> from a copy of a transmission described in subparagraph (A) or from a copy made from a physical medium described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In the event that a transmission meets both the conditions set forth in subparagraph (A) and those set forth in subparagraph (B), the transmission shall be treated as a transmission described in subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef8b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subsection shall not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef8c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require any analog video cassette camcorder to conform to the automatic gain control copy control technology with respect to any video signal received through a camera lens;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef8d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> apply to the manufacture, importation, offer for sale, provision of, or other trafficking in, any professional analog video cassette recorder; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef8e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> apply to the offer for sale or provision of, or other trafficking in, any previously owned analog video cassette recorder, if such recorder was legally manufactured and sold when new and not subsequently modified in violation of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef8f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef90-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An “analog video cassette recorder” means a device that records, or a device that includes a function that records, on electromagnetic tape in an analog format the electronic impulses produced by the video and audio portions of a television program, motion picture, or other form of audiovisual work.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef91-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An “analog video cassette camcorder” means an analog video cassette recorder that contains a recording function that operates through a camera lens and through a video input that may be connected with a television or other video playback device.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef92-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> An analog video cassette recorder “conforms” to the automatic gain control copy control technology if it—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef93-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> detects one or more of the elements of such technology and does not record the motion picture or transmission protected by such technology; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746aef94-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> records a signal that, when played back, exhibits a meaningfully distorted or degraded display.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef95-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The term “professional analog video cassette recorder” means an analog video cassette recorder that is designed, manufactured, marketed, and intended for use by a person who regularly employs such a device for a lawful business or industrial use, including making, performing, displaying, distributing, or transmitting copies of motion pictures on a commercial scale.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746aef96-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The terms “VHS format”, “8mm format”, “Beta format”, “automatic gain control copy control technology”, “colorstripe copy control technology”, “four-line version of the colorstripe copy control technology”, and “NTSC” have the meanings that are commonly understood in the consumer electronics and motion picture industries as of the date of the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746aef97-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1201/k/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Violations</inline>.—</heading><content>Any violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be treated as a violation of subsection (b)(1) of this section. Any violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be deemed an “act of circumvention” for the purposes of section 1203(c)(3)(A) of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id746aef98-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2863">112 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tV/s5006">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title V, § 5006]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–594.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id746aef99-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id746aef9a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id746aef9b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of this chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(A), (g)(5), and (k)(1), (4)(E), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/105/304">Pub. L. 105–304</ref>, which was approved <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986, referred to in subsecs. (g)(2)(D) and (j)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/474">Pub. L. 99–474</ref>, <date date="1986-10-16">Oct. 16, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1213">100 Stat. 1213</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1030">section 1030 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1001">section 1001 of Title 18</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1986 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1001">section 1001 of Title 18</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id746aef9c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> struck out “on the record” after “determination in a rulemaking proceeding” in first sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id746aef9d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id746aef9e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/144">Pub. L. 113–144</ref>, <date date="2014-08-01">Aug. 1, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1751">128 Stat. 1751</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/144">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> REPEAL OF EXISTING RULE AND ADDITIONAL RULEMAKING BY LIBRARIAN OF CONGRESS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repeal and Replace</inline>.—</heading><content>As of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-08-01">Aug. 1, 2014</date>], paragraph (3) of section 201.40(b) of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations, as amended and revised by the Librarian of Congress on <date date="2012-10-28">October 28, 2012</date>, pursuant to the Librarian’s authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a">section 1201(a) of title 17</ref>, United States Code, shall have no force and effect, and such paragraph shall read, and shall be in effect, as such paragraph was in effect on <date date="2010-07-27">July 27, 2010</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><content>The Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, who shall consult with the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce and report and comment on his or her views in making such recommendation, shall determine, consistent with the requirements set forth under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1">section 1201(a)(1) of title 17</ref>, United States Code, whether to extend the exemption for the class of works described in section 201.40(b)(3) of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations, as amended by subsection (a), to include any other category of wireless devices in addition to wireless telephone handsets. The determination shall be made in the first rulemaking under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C">section 1201(a)(1)(C) of title 17</ref>, United States Code, that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Unlocking at Direction of Owner</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Circumvention of a technological measure that restricts wireless telephone handsets or other wireless devices from connecting to a wireless telecommunications network—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as authorized by paragraph (3) of section 201.40(b) of title 37, Code of Federal Regulations, as made effective by subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> as may be extended to other wireless devices pursuant to a determination in the rulemaking conducted under subsection (b); or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> as authorized by an exemption adopted by the Librarian of Congress pursuant to a determination made on or after the date of enactment of this Act under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1/C">section 1201(a)(1)(C) of title 17</ref>, United States Code,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may be initiated by the owner of any such handset or other device, by another person at the direction of the owner, or by a provider of a commercial mobile radio service or a commercial mobile data service at the direction of such owner or other person, solely in order to enable such owner or a family member of such owner to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when such connection is authorized by the operator of such network.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as expressly provided herein, nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter the scope of any party’s rights under existing law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Librarian of congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this Act alters, or shall be construed to alter, the authority of the Librarian of Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s1201/a/1">section 1201(a)(1) of title 17</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commercial mobile data service; commercial mobile radio service</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘commercial mobile data service’ and ‘commercial mobile radio service’ have the respective meanings given those terms in section 20.3 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Wireless telecommunications network</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘wireless telecommunications network’ means a network used to provide a commercial mobile radio service or a commercial mobile data service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Wireless telephone handsets; wireless devices</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘wireless telephone handset’ and ‘wireless device’ mean a handset or other device that operates on a wireless telecommunications network.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
