<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id746d5f9f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202"><num value="1202">§ 1202.</num><heading> Integrity of copyright management information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d5fa0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">False Copyright Management Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No person shall knowingly and with the intent to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide copyright management information that is false, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> distribute or import for distribution copyright management information that is false.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d5fa3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Removal or Alteration of Copyright Management Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No person shall, without the authority of the copyright owner or the law—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> intentionally remove or alter any copyright management information,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> distribute or import for distribution copyright management information knowing that the copyright management information has been removed or altered without authority of the copyright owner or the law, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> distribute, import for distribution, or publicly perform works, copies of works, or phonorecords, knowing that copyright management information has been removed or altered without authority of the copyright owner or the law,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">knowing, or, with respect to civil remedies under section 1203, having reasonable grounds to know, that it will induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal an infringement of any right under this title.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d5fa7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this section, the term “copyright management information” means any of the following information conveyed in connection with copies or phonorecords of a work or performances or displays of a work, including in digital form, except that such term does not include any personally identifying information about a user of a work or of a copy, phonorecord, performance, or display of a work:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The title and other information identifying the work, including the information set forth on a notice of copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fa9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The name of, and other identifying information about, the author of a work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5faa-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The name of, and other identifying information about, the copyright owner of the work, including the information set forth in a notice of copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fab-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> With the exception of public performances of works by radio and television broadcast stations, the name of, and other identifying information about, a performer whose performance is fixed in a work other than an audiovisual work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fac-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> With the exception of public performances of works by radio and television broadcast stations, in the case of an audiovisual work, the name of, and other identifying information about, a writer, performer, or director who is credited in the audiovisual work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fad-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Terms and conditions for use of the work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fae-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Identifying numbers or symbols referring to such information or links to such information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5faf-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Such other information as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation, except that the Register of Copyrights may not require the provision of any information concerning the user of a copyrighted work.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d5fb0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Law Enforcement, Intelligence, and Other Government Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>This section does not prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, information security, or intelligence activity of an officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or a person acting pursuant to a contract with the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State. For purposes of this subsection, the term “information security” means activities carried out in order to identify and address the vulnerabilities of a government computer, computer system, or computer network.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d5fb1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Liability.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fb2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Analog transmissions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of an analog transmission, a person who is making transmissions in its capacity as a broadcast station, or as a cable system, or someone who provides programming to such station or system, shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fb3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> avoiding the activity that constitutes such violation is not technically feasible or would create an undue financial hardship on such person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fb4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such person did not intend, by engaging in such activity, to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fb5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Digital transmissions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fb6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If a digital transmission standard for the placement of copyright management information for a category of works is set in a voluntary, consensus standard-setting process involving a representative cross-section of broadcast stations or cable systems and copyright owners of a category of works that are intended for public performance by such stations or systems, a person identified in paragraph (1) shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) with respect to the particular copyright management information addressed by such standard if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746d5fb7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the placement of such information by someone other than such person is not in accordance with such standard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746d5fb8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the activity that constitutes such violation is not intended to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fb9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Until a digital transmission standard has been set pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to the placement of copyright management information for a category of works, a person identified in paragraph (1) shall not be liable for a violation of subsection (b) with respect to such copyright management information, if the activity that constitutes such violation is not intended to induce, enable, facilitate, or conceal infringement of a right under this title, and if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746d5fba-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the transmission of such information by such person would result in a perceptible visual or aural degradation of the digital signal; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id746d5fbb-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the transmission of such information by such person would conflict with—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id746d5fbc-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an applicable government regulation relating to transmission of information in a digital signal;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id746d5fbd-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an applicable industry-wide standard relating to the transmission of information in a digital signal that was adopted by a voluntary consensus standards body prior to the effective date of this chapter; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id746d5fbe-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> an applicable industry-wide standard relating to the transmission of information in a digital signal that was adopted in a voluntary, consensus standards-setting process open to participation by a representative cross-section of broadcast stations or cable systems and copyright owners of a category of works that are intended for public performance by such stations or systems.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d5fbf-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fc0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “broadcast station” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s153">47 U.S.C. 153</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id746d5fc1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1202/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “cable system” has the meaning given that term in section 602 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s522">47 U.S.C. 522</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id746d5fc2-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 105–304, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2872">112 Stat. 2872</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/44/s1/e">Pub. L. 106–44, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/222">113 Stat. 222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id746d5fc3-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id746d5fc4-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id746d5fc5-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(B)(ii)(II), is <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>. See <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/s105">section 105 of Pub. L. 105–304</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1998 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id746d5fc6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/106/44">Pub. L. 106–44</ref> substituted “category of works” for “category or works” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
