<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id746d602b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309"><num value="1309">§ 1309.</num><heading> Infringement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d602c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acts of Infringement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), it shall be infringement of the exclusive rights in a design protected under this chapter for any person, without the consent of the owner of the design, within the United States and during the term of such protection, to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d602d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> make, have made, or import, for sale or for use in trade, any infringing article as defined in subsection (e); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d602e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> sell or distribute for sale or for use in trade any such infringing article.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d602f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acts of Sellers and Distributors</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A seller or distributor of an infringing article who did not make or import the article shall be deemed to have infringed on a design protected under this chapter only if that person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d6030-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> induced or acted in collusion with a manufacturer to make, or an importer to import such article, except that merely purchasing or giving an order to purchase such article in the ordinary course of business shall not of itself constitute such inducement or collusion; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id746d6031-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> refused or failed, upon the request of the owner of the design, to make a prompt and full disclosure of that person’s source of such article, and that person orders or reorders such article after receiving notice by registered or certified mail of the protection subsisting in the design.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d6032-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acts Without Knowledge</inline>.—</heading><content>It shall not be infringement under this section to make, have made, import, sell, or distribute, any article embodying a design which was created without knowledge that a design was protected under this chapter and was copied from such protected design.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d6033-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acts in Ordinary Course of Business</inline>.—</heading><content>A person who incorporates into that person’s product of manufacture an infringing article acquired from others in the ordinary course of business, or who, without knowledge of the protected design embodied in an infringing article, makes or processes the infringing article for the account of another person in the ordinary course of business, shall not be deemed to have infringed the rights in that design under this chapter except under a condition contained in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b). Accepting an order or reorder from the source of the infringing article shall be deemed ordering or reordering within the meaning of subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d6034-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Infringing Article Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in this section, an “infringing article” is any article the design of which has been copied from a design protected under this chapter, without the consent of the owner of the protected design. An infringing article is not an illustration or picture of a protected design in an advertisement, book, periodical, newspaper, photograph, broadcast, motion picture, or similar medium. A design shall not be deemed to have been copied from a protected design if it is original and not substantially similar in appearance to a protected design.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d6035-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishing Originality</inline>.—</heading><content>The party to any action or proceeding under this chapter who alleges rights under this chapter in a design shall have the burden of establishing the design’s originality whenever the opposing party introduces an earlier work which is identical to such design, or so similar as to make prima facie showing that such design was copied from such work.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id746d6036-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s1309/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reproduction for Teaching or Analysis</inline>.—</heading><content>It is not an infringement of the exclusive rights of a design owner for a person to reproduce the design in a useful article or in any other form solely for the purpose of teaching, analyzing, or evaluating the appearance, concepts, or techniques embodied in the design, or the function of the useful article embodying the design.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id746d6037-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/304/tV/s502">Pub. L. 105–304, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2908">112 Stat. 2908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
