<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id745592a6-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s403"><num value="403">§ 403.</num><heading> Notice of copyright: Publications incorporating United States Government works</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Sections 401(d) and 402(d) shall not apply to a work published in copies or phonorecords consisting predominantly of one or more works of the United States Government unless the notice of copyright appearing on the published copies or phonorecords to which a defendant in the copyright infringement suit had access includes a statement identifying, either affirmatively or negatively, those portions of the copies or phonorecords embodying any work or works protected under this title.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id745592a7-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/553/tI/s101">Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2577">90 Stat. 2577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/568/s7/c">Pub. L. 100–568, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2858">102 Stat. 2858</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id745592a8-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id745592a9-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id745592aa-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 94–1476</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 403 is aimed at a publishing practice that, while technically justified under the present law, has been the object of considerable criticism. In cases where a Government work is published or republished commercially, it has frequently been the practice to add some “new matter” in the form of an introduction, editing, illustrations, etc., and to include a general copyright notice in the name of the commercial publisher. This in no way suggests to the public that the bulk of the work is uncopyrightable and therefore free for use.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">To make the notice meaningful rather than misleading, section 403 requires that, when the copies or phonorecords consist “preponderantly of one or more works of the United States Government,” the copyright notice (if any) identify those parts of the work in which copyright is claimed. A failure to meet this requirement would be treated as an omission of the notice, subject to the provisions of section 405.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id745592ab-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id745592ac-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/568">Pub. L. 100–568</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “Whenever a work is published in copies or phonorecords consisting preponderantly of one or more works of the United States Government, the notice of copyright provided by sections 401 or 402 shall also include a statement identifying, either affirmatively or negatively, those portions of the copies or phonorecords embodying any work or works protected under this title.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id745592ad-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id745592ae-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/568">Pub. L. 100–568</ref> effective <date date="1989-03-01">Mar. 1, 1989</date>, with any cause of action arising under this title before such date being governed by provisions in effect when cause of action arose, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/568/s13">section 13 of Pub. L. 100–568</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
