<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id745c9844-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513"><num value="513">§ 513.</num><heading> Determination of reasonable license fees for individual proprietors</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any performing rights society subject to a consent decree which provides for the determination of reasonable license rates or fees to be charged by the performing rights society, notwithstanding the provisions of that consent decree, an individual proprietor who owns or operates fewer than 7 non-publicly traded establishments in which nondramatic musical works are performed publicly and who claims that any license agreement offered by that performing rights society is unreasonable in its license rate or fee as to that individual proprietor, shall be entitled to determination of a reasonable license rate or fee as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745c9845-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The individual proprietor may commence such proceeding for determination of a reasonable license rate or fee by filing an application in the applicable district court under paragraph (2) that a rate disagreement exists and by serving a copy of the application on the performing rights society. Such proceeding shall commence in the applicable district court within 90 days after the service of such copy, except that such 90-day requirement shall be subject to the administrative requirements of the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745c9846-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The proceeding under paragraph (1) shall be held, at the individual proprietor’s election, in the judicial district of the district court with jurisdiction over the applicable consent decree or in that place of holding court of a district court that is the seat of the Federal circuit (other than the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit) in which the proprietor’s establishment is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745c9847-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Such proceeding shall be held before the judge of the court with jurisdiction over the consent decree governing the performing rights society. At the discretion of the court, the proceeding shall be held before a special master or magistrate judge appointed by such judge. Should that consent decree provide for the appointment of an advisor or advisors to the court for any purpose, any such advisor shall be the special master so named by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745c9848-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any such proceeding, the industry rate shall be presumed to have been reasonable at the time it was agreed to or determined by the court. Such presumption shall in no way affect a determination of whether the rate is being correctly applied to the individual proprietor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745c9849-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Pending the completion of such proceeding, the individual proprietor shall have the right to perform publicly the copyrighted musical compositions in the repertoire of the performing rights society by paying an interim license rate or fee into an interest bearing escrow account with the clerk of the court, subject to retroactive adjustment when a final rate or fee has been determined, in an amount equal to the industry rate, or, in the absence of an industry rate, the amount of the most recent license rate or fee agreed to by the parties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745f084a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Any decision rendered in such proceeding by a special master or magistrate judge named under paragraph (3) shall be reviewed by the judge of the court with jurisdiction over the consent decree governing the performing rights society. Such proceeding, including such review, shall be concluded within 6 months after its commencement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745f084b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any such final determination shall be binding only as to the individual proprietor commencing the proceeding, and shall not be applicable to any other proprietor or any other performing rights society, and the performing rights society shall be relieved of any obligation of nondiscrimination among similarly situated music users that may be imposed by the consent decree governing its operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745f084c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> An individual proprietor may not bring more than one proceeding provided for in this section for the determination of a reasonable license rate or fee under any license agreement with respect to any one performing rights society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id745f084d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s513/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the term “industry rate” means the license fee a performing rights society has agreed to with, or which has been determined by the court for, a significant segment of the music user industry to which the individual proprietor belongs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id745f084e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/298/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 105–298, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2831">112 Stat. 2831</ref>, § 512; renumbered § 513, <ref href="/us/pl/106/44/s1/c/1">Pub. L. 106–44, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/221">113 Stat. 221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id745f084f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id745f0850-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id745f0851-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/44">Pub. L. 106–44</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s512">section 512 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id745f0852-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id745f0853-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/298/s207">section 207 of Pub. L. 105–298</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1998 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
