<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id745f0896-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704"><num value="704">§ 704.</num><heading> Retention and disposition of articles deposited in Copyright Office</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id745f0897-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Upon their deposit in the Copyright Office under sections 407 and 408, all copies, phonorecords, and identifying material, including those deposited in connection with claims that have been refused registration, are the property of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id745f0898-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In the case of published works, all copies, phonorecords, and identifying material deposited are available to the Library of Congress for its collections, or for exchange or transfer to any other library. In the case of unpublished works, the Library is entitled, under regulations that the Register of Copyrights shall prescribe, to select any deposits for its collections or for transfer to the National Archives of the United States or to a Federal records center, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2901">section 2901 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id745f0899-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Register of Copyrights is authorized, for specific or general categories of works, to make a facsimile reproduction of all or any part of the material deposited under section 408, and to make such reproduction a part of the Copyright Office records of the registration, before transferring such material to the Library of Congress as provided by subsection (b), or before destroying or otherwise disposing of such material as provided by subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id745f089a-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Deposits not selected by the Library under subsection (b), or identifying portions or reproductions of them, shall be retained under the control of the Copyright Office, including retention in Government storage facilities, for the longest period considered practicable and desirable by the Register of Copyrights and the Librarian of Congress. After that period it is within the joint discretion of the Register and the Librarian to order their destruction or other disposition; but, in the case of unpublished works, no deposit shall be knowingly or intentionally destroyed or otherwise disposed of during its term of copyright unless a facsimile reproduction of the entire deposit has been made a part of the Copyright Office records as provided by subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id745f089b-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b" identifier="/us/usc/t17/s704/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The depositor of copies, phonorecords, or identifying material under section 408, or the copyright owner of record, may request retention, under the control of the Copyright Office, of one or more of such articles for the full term of copyright in the work. The Register of Copyrights shall prescribe, by regulation, the conditions under which such requests are to be made and granted, and shall fix the fee to be charged under section 708(a) if the request is granted.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id745f089c-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/553/tI/s101">Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2591">90 Stat. 2591</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/318/s2/c">Pub. L. 101–318, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-07-03">July 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/288">104 Stat. 288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/295/s6/e">Pub. L. 111–295, § 6(e)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-09">Dec. 9, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3181">124 Stat. 3181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id745f089d-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id745f089e-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id745f089f-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/295">Pub. L. 111–295</ref> substituted “section 708(a)” for “section 708(a)(10)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/318">Pub. L. 101–318</ref> substituted “708(a)(10)” for “708(a)(11)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id745f08a0-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id745f08a1-2930-11f1-b33a-a9dcf95eef0b"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/318">Pub. L. 101–318</ref> effective 6 months after <date date="1990-07-03">July 3, 1990</date>, and applicable to (A) claims to original, supplementary, and renewal copyright received for registration, and to items received for recordation in Copyright Office, on or after such effective date, and (B) other requests for services received on or after such effective date, or received before such effective date for services not yet rendered as of such date, and with claims to original, supplementary, and renewal copyright received for registration and items received for recordation in acceptable form in Copyright Office before such effective date, and requests for services which are rendered before such effective date, to be governed by <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s708">section 708 of this title</ref> as in effect before such effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/318/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 101–318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s708">section 708 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
