<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a17248b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104"><num value="104">§ 104.</num><heading> Enumeration of specific acts not subject to restraining orders or injunctions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No court of the United States shall have jurisdiction to issue any restraining order or temporary or permanent injunction in any case involving or growing out of any labor dispute to prohibit any person or persons participating or interested in such dispute (as these terms are herein defined) from doing, whether singly or in concert, any of the following acts:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a17248c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Ceasing or refusing to perform any work or to remain in any relation of employment;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a17248d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Becoming or remaining a member of any labor organization or of any employer organization, regardless of any such undertaking or promise as is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s103">section 103 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a17248e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Paying or giving to, or withholding from, any person participating or interested in such labor dispute, any strike or unemployment benefits or insurance, or other moneys or things of value;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a17248f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> By all lawful means aiding any person participating or interested in any labor dispute who is being proceeded against in, or is prosecuting, any action or suit in any court of the United States or of any State;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a172490-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Giving publicity to the existence of, or the facts involved in, any labor dispute, whether by advertising, speaking, patrolling, or by any other method not involving fraud or violence;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a172491-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Assembling peaceably to act or to organize to act in promotion of their interests in a labor dispute;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a172492-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Advising or notifying any person of an intention to do any of the acts heretofore specified;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a172493-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> Agreeing with other persons to do or not to do any of the acts heretofore specified; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a172494-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s104/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Advising, urging, or otherwise causing or inducing without fraud or violence the acts heretofore specified, regardless of any such undertaking or promise as is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s103">section 103 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a172495-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1932-03-23/ch90/s4">Mar. 23, 1932, ch. 90, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/70">47 Stat. 70</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
