<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5add0c74-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059"><num value="1059">§ 1059.</num><heading> Recordkeeping and reporting requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5add0c75-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5add0c76-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided by paragraph (2) every employer shall, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, maintain records with respect to each of his employees sufficient to determine the benefits due or which may become due to such employees. The plan administrator shall make a report, in such manner and at such time as may be provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to each employee who is a participant under the plan and who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5add0c77-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> requests such report, in such manner and at such time as may be provided in such regulations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5add0c78-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> terminates his service with the employer, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5add0c79-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has a 1-year break in service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1053/b/3/A">section 1053(b)(3)(A) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The employer shall furnish to the plan administrator the information necessary for the administrator to make the reports required by the preceding sentence. Not more than one report shall be required under subparagraph (A) in any 12-month period. Not more than one report shall be required under subparagraph (C) with respect to consecutive 1-year breaks in service. The report required under this paragraph shall be in the same form, and contain the same information, as periodic benefit statements under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1025/a">section 1025(a) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5add0c7a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If more than one employer adopts a plan, each such employer shall furnish to the plan administrator the information necessary for the administrator to maintain the records, and make the reports, required by paragraph (1). Such administrator shall maintain the records, and make the reports, required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5add0c7b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1059/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If any person who is required, under subsection (a), to furnish information or maintain records for any plan year fails to comply with such requirement, he shall pay to the Secretary a civil penalty of $10 for each employee with respect to whom such failure occurs, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5add0c7c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tI/s209">Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 209</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/865">88 Stat. 865</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/tI/s105/f">Pub. L. 110–458, title I, § 105(f)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5105">122 Stat. 5105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5add0c7d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5add0c7e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5add0c7f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s105/f/1">Pub. L. 110–458, § 105(f)(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe” for “regulations prescribed by the Secretary” and, in concluding provisions, inserted last sentence and struck out former last sentence which read as follows: “The report required under this paragraph shall be sufficient to inform the employee of his accrued benefits under the plan and the percentage of such benefits which are nonforfeitable under the plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s105/f/2">Pub. L. 110–458, § 105(f)(2)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “If more than one employer adopts a plan, each such employer shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, furnish to the plan administrator the information necessary for the administrator to maintain the records and make the reports required by paragraph (1). Such administrator shall maintain the records and, to the extent provided under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, make the reports, required by paragraph (1).”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5add0c80-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5add0c81-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/458">Pub. L. 110–458</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> to which the amendment relates, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s112">section 112 of Pub. L. 110–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5add0c82-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary authorized, effective <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, to promulgate regulations wherever provisions of this subchapter call for the promulgation of regulations, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
