<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5af9bbf7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108"><num value="1108">§ 1108.</num><heading> Exemptions from prohibited transactions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5af9bbf8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant of exemptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an exemption procedure for purposes of this subsection. Pursuant to such procedure, he may grant a conditional or unconditional exemption of any fiduciary or transaction, or class of fiduciaries or transactions, from all or part of the restrictions imposed by sections 1106 and 1107(a) of this title. Action under this subsection may be taken only after consultation and coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury. An exemption granted under this section shall not relieve a fiduciary from any other applicable provision of this chapter. The Secretary may not grant an exemption under this subsection unless he finds that such exemption is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbf9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> administratively feasible,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbfa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the interests of the plan and of its participants and beneficiaries, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbfb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> protective of the rights of participants and beneficiaries of such plan.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Before granting an exemption under this subsection from section 1106(a) or 1107(a) of this title, the Secretary shall publish notice in the Federal Register of the pendency of the exemption, shall require that adequate notice be given to interested persons, and shall afford interested persons opportunity to present views. The Secretary may not grant an exemption under this subsection from <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/b">section 1106(b) of this title</ref> unless he affords an opportunity for a hearing and makes a determination on the record with respect to the findings required by paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5af9bbfc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enumeration of transactions exempted from section 1106 prohibitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The prohibitions provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106">section 1106 of this title</ref> shall not apply to any of the following transactions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbfd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any loans made by the plan to parties in interest who are participants or beneficiaries of the plan if such loans (A) are available to all such participants and beneficiaries on a reasonably equivalent basis, (B) are not made available to highly compensated employees (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414/q">section 414(q) of title 26</ref>) in an amount greater than the amount made available to other employees, (C) are made in accordance with specific provisions regarding such loans set forth in the plan, (D) bear a reasonable rate of interest, and (E) are adequately secured. A loan made by a plan shall not fail to meet the requirements of the preceding sentence by reason of a loan repayment suspension described under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414/u/4">section 414(u)(4) of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbfe-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bbff-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Contracting or making reasonable arrangements with a party in interest for office space, or legal, accounting, or other services necessary for the establishment or operation of the plan, if no more than reasonable compensation is paid therefor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc00-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc01-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> No contract or arrangement for services between a covered plan and a covered service provider, and no extension or renewal of such a contract or arrangement, is reasonable within the meaning of this paragraph unless the requirements of this subparagraph are met. For purposes of applying <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a/1/C">section 1106(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref> with respect to a transaction described under this subparagraph or subparagraph (C), a contract or arrangement for services between a covered plan and an entity providing services to the plan, including a health insurance issuer providing health insurance coverage in connection with the covered plan, in which such entity contracts, in connection with such plan, with a service provider for pharmacy benefit management services, shall be considered an indirect furnishing of goods, services, or facilities between the covered plan and the service provider for pharmacy benefit management services acting as the party in interest.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc02-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc03-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subparagraph:</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc04-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The term “covered plan” means a group health plan as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b/a">section 1191b(a) of this title</ref> and the terms “health insurance coverage” and “health insurance issuer” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b/b">section 1191b(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc05-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><chapeau> The term “covered service provider” means a service provider that enters into a contract or arrangement with the covered plan and reasonably expects $1,000 (or such amount as the Secretary may establish in regulations to account for inflation since <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, as appropriate) or more in compensation, direct or indirect, to be received in connection with providing one or more of the following services, pursuant to the contract or arrangement, regardless of whether such services will be performed, or such compensation received, by the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor:</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5af9bc06-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> Services (including brokerage services), for which the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive indirect compensation or direct compensation described in item (dd), provided to a covered plan with respect to selection of insurance products (including vision and dental), recordkeeping services, medical management vendor, benefits administration (including vision and dental), stop-loss insurance, pharmacy benefit management services, wellness services, transparency tools and vendors, group purchasing organization preferred vendor panels, disease management vendors and products, compliance services, employee assistance programs, or third party administration services.</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5af9bc07-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> Other services, for which the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive indirect compensation or direct compensation described in item (dd), including any of the following: plan design, insurance or insurance product selection (including vision and dental), recordkeeping, medical management, benefits administration selection (including vision and dental), stop-loss insurance, pharmacy benefit management services, wellness design and management services, transparency tools, group purchasing organization agreements and services, participation in and services from preferred vendor panels, disease management, compliance services, employee assistance programs, or third-party administration services, or consulting services related to any such services.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc08-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> The term “affiliate”, with respect to a covered service provider, means an entity that directly or indirectly (through one or more intermediaries) controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, such provider, or is an officer, director, or employee of, or partner in, such provider.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc09-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc0a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/dd/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> The term “compensation” means anything of monetary value, but does not include non-monetary compensation valued at $250 (or such amount as the Secretary may establish in regulations to account for inflation since <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, as appropriate) or less, in the aggregate, during the term of the contract or arrangement.</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc0b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/dd/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> The term “direct compensation” means compensation received directly from a covered plan.</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc0c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/dd/CC"><num value="CC">(CC)</num><content> The term “indirect compensation” means compensation received from any source other than the covered plan, the plan sponsor, the covered service provider, or an affiliate. Compensation received from a subcontractor is indirect compensation, unless it is received in connection with services performed under a contract or arrangement with a subcontractor.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc0d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><content> The term “responsible plan fiduciary” means a fiduciary with authority to cause the covered plan to enter into, or extend or renew, the contract or arrangement.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc0e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/I/ff"><num value="ff">(ff)</num><content> The term “subcontractor” means any person or entity (or an affiliate of such person or entity) that is not an affiliate of the covered service provider and that, pursuant to a contract or arrangement with the covered service provider or an affiliate, reasonably expects to receive $1,000 (or such amount as the Secretary may establish in regulations to account for inflation since <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, as appropriate) or more in compensation for performing one or more services described in item (bb) under a contract or arrangement with the covered plan.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc0f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> For purposes of this subparagraph, a description of compensation or cost may be expressed as a monetary amount, formula, or a per capita charge for each enrollee or, if the compensation or cost cannot reasonably be expressed in such terms, by any other reasonable method, including a disclosure that additional compensation may be earned but may not be calculated at the time of contract if such a disclosure includes a description of the circumstances under which the additional compensation may be earned and a reasonable and good faith estimate if the covered service provider cannot otherwise readily describe compensation or cost and explains the methodology and assumptions used to prepare such estimate. Any such description shall contain sufficient information to permit evaluation of the reasonableness of the compensation or cost.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc10-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> No person or entity is a “covered service provider” within the meaning of subclause (I)(bb) solely on the basis of providing services as an affiliate or a subcontractor that is performing one or more of the services described in subitem (AA) or (BB) of such subclause under the contract or arrangement with the covered plan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc11-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> A covered service provider shall disclose to a responsible plan fiduciary, in writing, the following (in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary addressing time, manner, and content of such disclosures):</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc12-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A description of the services to be provided to the covered plan pursuant to the contract or arrangement.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc13-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> If applicable, a statement that the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor will provide, or reasonably expects to provide, services pursuant to the contract or arrangement directly to the covered plan as a fiduciary (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21">section 1002(21) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc14-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> A description of all direct compensation, either in the aggregate or by service, that the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive in connection with the services described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc15-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc16-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><chapeau> A description of all indirect compensation that the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive in connection with the services described in subclause (I)—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5af9bc17-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/aa/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> including compensation from a vendor to a brokerage firm based on a structure of incentives not solely related to the contract with the covered plan; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5af9bc18-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/aa/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> not including compensation received by an employee from an employer on account of work performed by the employee.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc19-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> A description of the arrangement between the payer and the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor, as applicable, pursuant to which such indirect compensation is paid.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc1a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> Identification of the services for which the indirect compensation will be received, if applicable.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc1b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/IV/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> Identification of the payer of the indirect compensation.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc1c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> A description of any compensation that will be paid among the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor, in connection with the services described in subclause (I) if such compensation is set on a transaction basis (such as commissions, finder’s fees, or other similar incentive compensation based on business placed or retained), including identification of the services for which such compensation will be paid and identification of the payers and recipients of such compensation (including the status of a payer or recipient as an affiliate or a subcontractor), regardless of whether such compensation also is disclosed pursuant to subclause (III) or (IV).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc1d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> A description of any compensation that the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive in connection with termination of the contract or arrangement, and how any prepaid amounts will be calculated and refunded upon such termination.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc1e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A covered service provider shall disclose to a responsible plan fiduciary, in writing a description of the manner in which the compensation described in clause (iii), as applicable, will be received.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc1f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc20-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/v/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A covered service provider shall disclose the information required under clauses (iii) and (iv) to the responsible plan fiduciary not later than the date that is reasonably in advance of the date on which the contract or arrangement is entered into, and extended or renewed.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc21-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/v/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> A covered service provider shall disclose any change to the information required under clause (iii) and (iv) as soon as practicable, but not later than 60 days from the date on which the covered service provider is informed of such change, unless such disclosure is precluded due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the covered service provider’s control, in which case the information shall be disclosed as soon as practicable.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc22-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc23-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/vi/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Upon the written request of the responsible plan fiduciary or covered plan administrator, a covered service provider shall furnish any other information relating to the compensation received in connection with the contract or arrangement that is required for the covered plan to comply with the reporting and disclosure requirements under this chapter.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc24-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/vi/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The covered service provider shall disclose the information required under clause (iii)(I) reasonably in advance of the date upon which such responsible plan fiduciary or covered plan administrator states that it is required to comply with the applicable reporting or disclosure requirement, unless such disclosure is precluded due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the covered service provider’s control, in which case the information shall be disclosed as soon as practicable.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc25-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> No contract or arrangement will fail to be reasonable under this subparagraph solely because the covered service provider, acting in good faith and with reasonable diligence, makes an error or omission in disclosing the information required pursuant to clause (iii) (or a change to such information disclosed pursuant to clause (v)(II)) or clause (vi), provided that the covered service provider discloses the correct information to the responsible plan fiduciary as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days from the date on which the covered service provider knows of such error or omission.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc26-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc27-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> Pursuant to subsection (a), subparagraphs (C) and (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a/1">section 1106(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall not apply to a responsible plan fiduciary, notwithstanding any failure by a covered service provider to disclose information required under clause (iii), if the following conditions are met:</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc28-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The responsible plan fiduciary did not know that the covered service provider failed or would fail to make required disclosures and reasonably believed that the covered service provider disclosed the information required to be disclosed.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc29-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> The responsible plan fiduciary, upon discovering that the covered service provider failed to disclose the required information, requests in writing that the covered service provider furnish such information.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc2a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> If the covered service provider fails to comply with a written request described in subclause (III) within 90 days of the request, the responsible plan fiduciary notifies the Secretary of the covered service provider’s failure, in accordance with subclauses (III) and (IV).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc2b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> Pursuant to subsection (a), subparagraphs (C) and (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a/1">section 1106(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall not apply to a responsible plan fiduciary, notwithstanding any failure to remit required amounts under subparagraph (C)(i), if the following conditions are met:</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc2c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The responsible plan fiduciary did not know that the covered service provider failed or would fail to make required remittances and reasonably believed that the covered service provider remitted such required amounts.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc2d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> The responsible plan fiduciary, upon discovering that the covered service provider failed to remit the required amounts, requests in writing that the covered service provider remit such amounts.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc2e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> If the covered service provider fails to comply with a written request described in subclause (III) within 90 days of the request, the responsible plan fiduciary notifies the Secretary of the covered service provider’s failure, in accordance with subclauses (III) and (IV).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5af9bc2f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><chapeau> A notice described in subclause (I)(cc) shall contain—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc30-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the name of the covered plan;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5af9bc31-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the plan number used for the annual report on the covered plan;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0522-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> the plan sponsor’s name, address, and employer identification number;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0523-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> the name, address, and telephone number of the responsible plan fiduciary;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0524-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><content> the name, address, phone number, and, if known, employer identification number of the covered service provider;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0525-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/ff"><num value="ff">(ff)</num><content> a description of the services provided to the covered plan;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0526-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/gg"><num value="gg">(gg)</num><content> a description of the information that the covered service provider failed to disclose;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0527-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/hh"><num value="hh">(hh)</num><content> the date on which such information was requested in writing from the covered service provider; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0528-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/III/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a statement as to whether the covered service provider continues to provide services to the plan.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0529-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> A notice described in subclause (I)(cc) shall be filed with the Department not later than 30 days following the earlier of—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc052a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The covered service provider’s refusal to furnish the information requested by the written request described in subclause (I)(bb); or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc052b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> 90 days after the written request referred to in subclause (I)(cc) is made.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc052c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> If the covered service provider fails to comply with the written request under subclause (I)(bb) within 90 days of such request, the responsible plan fiduciary shall determine whether to terminate or continue the contract or arrangement under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1104">section 1104 of this title</ref>. If the requested information relates to future services and is not disclosed promptly after the end of the 90-day period, the responsible plan fiduciary shall terminate the contract or arrangement as expeditiously as possible, consistent with such duty of prudence.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc052d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to supersede any provision of State law that governs disclosures by parties that provide the services described in this section, except to the extent that such law prevents the application of a requirement of this section.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc052e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> A service provider for pharmacy benefit management services that is considered to indirectly furnish goods, services, or facilities to a covered plan, as described in clause (i)(I), is entitled to relief with respect to a violation of this section provided the conditions for receiving such relief are satisfied.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc052f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0530-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0531-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> For plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after <date date="2026-02-03">February 3, 2026</date>, (referred to in this clause as the “effective date”), no contract or arrangement or renewal or extension of a contract or arrangement, entered into on or after the effective date, for services between a covered plan and a covered service provider (or between a sponsor of a covered plan and a covered service provider), through a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, a third-party administrator, an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, or other entity, for pharmacy benefit management services, is reasonable within the meaning of this paragraph unless such entity providing pharmacy benefit management services—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0532-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/i/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> remits 100 percent of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration received from any applicable entity that are related to utilization of drugs or drug spending under such health plan or health insurance coverage, to the group health plan or, in the case of a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, to the health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage on behalf of the plan; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0533-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/i/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> does not enter into any contract for pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or coverage, with an applicable entity unless 100 percent of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration received under such contract that are related to the utilization of drugs or drug spending under such group health plan or health insurance coverage are remitted to the group health plan or, in the case of a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, to the health insurance issuer on behalf of the plan by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0534-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Nothing in subclause (I) shall be construed to affect the term of a contract or arrangement, as in effect on the effective date (as described in such subclause), except that such subclause shall apply to any renewal or extension of such a contract or arrangement entered into on or after such effective date, as so described.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0535-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> With respect to such rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0536-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> the rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration under clause (i)(I) shall be—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0537-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><chapeau> remitted—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5afc0538-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I/aa/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> on a quarterly basis, to the group health plan or, in the case of a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, to the group health insurance issuer on behalf of the plan, not later than 90 days after the end of each quarter; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5afc0539-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I/aa/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> in the case of an underpayment in a remittance for a prior quarter, as soon as practicable, but not later than 90 days after notice of the underpayment is first given;</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc053a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> fully disclosed and enumerated to the group health plan or health insurance issuer; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc053b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> returned to the covered service provider for pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the group health plan if any audit by a plan sponsor, issuer or a third party designated by a plan sponsor, indicates that the amounts received are in excess of correct amounts after such amounts have been paid to the group health plan, in the amount of such excess;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc053c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> the Secretary may issue regulations governing—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc053d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> procedures for the remittance of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration under subclause (I)(aa);</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc053e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> any audit pursuant to this subparagraph; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc053f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> the timing, manner, and content of the disclosure of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration under subclause (I)(bb) as well as any other information the Secretary determines necessary for the responsible plan fiduciary to consider the reasonableness of the contract or arrangement (provided that such information does not include personally identifiable health information or protected health information subject to established individual privacy and nondiscrimination requirements under law); and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0540-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the records of such rebates, fees, alternative discounts, other remuneration, and disclosures, shall be available for audit by the plan (or the plan sponsor, issuer, or a third party designated by a plan sponsor on behalf of the plan), not less than once per plan year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0541-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> To ensure that an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services is able to meet the requirements of clause (ii)(I), a rebate aggregator (or other purchasing entity designed to aggregate rebates) and an applicable group purchasing organization shall remit such rebates to the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services not later than 45 days after the end of each quarter.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0542-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A third-party administrator of a group health plan, a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, or a covered service provider for pharmacy benefit management services under such health plan or health insurance coverage shall make rebate contracts with rebate aggregators or drug manufacturers available for audit by such plan, subject to reasonable restrictions (as determined by the Secretary) on confidentiality to prevent re-disclosure of such contracts or use of such information in audits for purposes unrelated to this section.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0543-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Audits carried out under clauses (ii)(III) and (iv) shall be performed by an auditor selected by the responsible plan fiduciary. Payment for such auditors shall not be made, whether directly or indirectly, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0544-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><chapeau> Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0545-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> prohibit reasonable payments to entities offering pharmacy benefit management services for bona fide services using a fee structure not described in this subparagraph, provided that such fees are transparent and quantifiable to group health plans and health insurance issuers;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0546-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> require a third-party administrator of a group health plan or covered service provider for pharmacy benefit management services under such health plan or health insurance coverage to remit bona fide service fees to the group health plan;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0547-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> limit the ability of a group health plan or health insurance issuer to pass through rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration to the participant or beneficiary;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0548-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> modify the requirements for the creation, receipt, maintenance, or transmission of protected health information under the privacy regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 in part 160 and subparts A and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0549-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vi/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> limit any requirement under subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc054a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subparagraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc054b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the terms “applicable entity” and “applicable group purchasing organization” have the meanings given such terms in section 1185<i>o</i>(e) of this title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc054c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the terms “covered plan”, “covered service provider”, and “responsible plan fiduciary” have the meanings given such terms in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc054d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/C/vii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the terms “group health insurance coverage”, “health insurance coverage”, and “health insurance issuer” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b">section 1191b of this title</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc054e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A loan to an employee stock ownership plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/6">section 1107(d)(6) of this title</ref>), if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc054f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such loan is primarily for the benefit of participants and beneficiaries of the plan, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0550-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such loan is at an interest rate which is not in excess of a reasonable rate.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If the plan gives collateral to a party in interest for such loan, such collateral may consist only of qualifying employer securities (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/5">section 1107(d)(5) of this title</ref>).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0551-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The investment of all or part of a plan’s assets in deposits which bear a reasonable interest rate in a bank or similar financial institution supervised by the United States or a State, if such bank or other institution is a fiduciary of such plan and if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0552-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the plan covers only employees of such bank or other institution and employees of affiliates of such bank or other institution, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0553-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such investment is expressly authorized by a provision of the plan or by a fiduciary (other than such bank or institution or affiliate thereof) who is expressly empowered by the plan to so instruct the trustee with respect to such investment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0554-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Any contract for life insurance, health insurance, or annuities with one or more insurers which are qualified to do business in a State, if the plan pays no more than adequate consideration, and if each such insurer or insurers is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0555-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the employer maintaining the plan, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0556-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a party in interest which is wholly owned (directly or indirectly) by the employer maintaining the plan, or by any person which is a party in interest with respect to the plan, but only if the total premiums and annuity considerations written by such insurers for life insurance, health insurance, or annuities for all plans (and their employers) with respect to which such insurers are parties in interest (not including premiums or annuity considerations written by the employer maintaining the plan) do not exceed 5 percent of the total premiums and annuity considerations written for all lines of insurance in that year by such insurers (not including premiums or annuity considerations written by the employer maintaining the plan).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0557-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The providing of any ancillary service by a bank or similar financial institution supervised by the United States or a State, if such bank or other institution is a fiduciary of such plan, and if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0558-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such bank or similar financial institution has adopted adequate internal safeguards which assure that the providing of such ancillary service is consistent with sound banking and financial practice, as determined by Federal or State supervisory authority, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0559-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the extent to which such ancillary service is provided is subject to specific guidelines issued by such bank or similar financial institution (as determined by the Secretary after consultation with Federal and State supervisory authority), and adherence to such guidelines would reasonably preclude such bank or similar financial institution from providing such ancillary service (i) in an excessive or unreasonable manner, and (ii) in a manner that would be inconsistent with the best interests of participants and beneficiaries of employee benefit plans.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such ancillary services shall not be provided at more than reasonable compensation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc055a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The exercise of a privilege to convert securities, to the extent provided in regulations of the Secretary, but only if the plan receives no less than adequate consideration pursuant to such conversion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc055b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> Any transaction between a plan and (i) a common or collective trust fund or pooled investment fund maintained by a party in interest which is a bank or trust company supervised by a State or Federal agency or (ii) a pooled investment fund of an insurance company qualified to do business in a State, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc055c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transaction is a sale or purchase of an interest in the fund,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc055d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the bank, trust company, or insurance company receives not more than reasonable compensation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc055e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such transaction is expressly permitted by the instrument under which the plan is maintained, or by a fiduciary (other than the bank, trust company, or insurance company, or an affiliate thereof) who has authority to manage and control the assets of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc055f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The making by a fiduciary of a distribution of the assets of the plan in accordance with the terms of the plan if such assets are distributed in the same manner as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> (relating to allocation of assets).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0560-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Any transaction required or permitted under part 1 of subtitle E of subchapter III.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0561-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> A merger of multiemployer plans, or the transfer of assets or liabilities between multiemployer plans, determined by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0562-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> The sale by a plan to a party in interest on or after <date date="1987-12-18">December 18, 1987</date>, of any stock, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0563-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) are met with respect to such stock,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0564-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on the later of the date on which the stock was acquired by the plan, or <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, such stock constituted a qualifying employer security (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/5">section 1107(d)(5) of this title</ref> as then in effect), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0565-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such stock does not constitute a qualifying employer security (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/5">section 1107(d)(5) of this title</ref> as in effect at the time of the sale).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0566-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> Any transfer made before <date date="2033-01-01">January 1, 2033</date>, of excess pension assets from a defined benefit plan to a retiree health account in a qualified transfer permitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s420">section 420 of title 26</ref> (as in effect on <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0567-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><chapeau> Any transaction in connection with the provision of investment advice described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> to a participant or beneficiary of an individual account plan that permits such participant or beneficiary to direct the investment of assets in their individual account, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0568-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the transaction is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0569-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the provision of the investment advice to the participant or beneficiary of the plan with respect to a security or other property available as an investment under the plan,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc056a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the acquisition, holding, or sale of a security or other property available as an investment under the plan pursuant to the investment advice, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc056b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the direct or indirect receipt of fees or other compensation by the fiduciary adviser or an affiliate thereof (or any employee, agent, or registered representative of the fiduciary adviser or affiliate) in connection with the provision of the advice or in connection with an acquisition, holding, or sale of a security or other property available as an investment under the plan pursuant to the investment advice; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc056c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/14/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the requirements of subsection (g) are met.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc056d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc056e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Any transaction involving the purchase or sale of securities, or other property (as determined by the Secretary), between a plan and a party in interest (other than a fiduciary described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A">section 1002(21)(A) of this title</ref>) with respect to a plan if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc056f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the transaction involves a block trade,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0570-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at the time of the transaction, the interest of the plan (together with the interests of any other plans maintained by the same plan sponsor), does not exceed 10 percent of the aggregate size of the block trade,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0571-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the terms of the transaction, including the price, are at least as favorable to the plan as an arm’s length <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002107"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “arm’s-length”.</note> transaction, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0572-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the compensation associated with the purchase and sale is not greater than the compensation associated with an arm’s length <sup>3</sup> transaction with an unrelated party.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0573-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “block trade” means any trade of at least 10,000 shares or with a market value of at least $200,000 which will be allocated across two or more unrelated client accounts of a fiduciary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0574-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><chapeau> Any transaction involving the purchase or sale of securities, or other property (as determined by the Secretary), between a plan and a party in interest if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0575-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the transaction is executed through an electronic communication network, alternative trading system, or similar execution system or trading venue subject to regulation and oversight by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0576-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the applicable Federal regulating entity, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0577-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such foreign regulatory entity as the Secretary may determine by regulation,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0578-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0579-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the transaction is effected pursuant to rules designed to match purchases and sales at the best price available through the execution system in accordance with applicable rules of the Securities and Exchange Commission or other relevant governmental authority, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc057a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> neither the execution system nor the parties to the transaction take into account the identity of the parties in the execution of trades,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc057b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the price and compensation associated with the purchase and sale are not greater than the price and compensation associated with an arm’s length <sup>3</sup> transaction with an unrelated party,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc057c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> if the party in interest has an ownership interest in the system or venue described in subparagraph (A), the system or venue has been authorized by the plan sponsor or other independent fiduciary for transactions described in this paragraph, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc057d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/16/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> not less than 30 days prior to the initial transaction described in this paragraph executed through any system or venue described in subparagraph (A), a plan fiduciary is provided written or electronic notice of the execution of such transaction through such system or venue.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc057e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc057f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Transactions described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a/1">section 1106(a)(1) of this title</ref> between a plan and a person that is a party in interest other than a fiduciary (or an affiliate) who has or exercises any discretionary authority or control with respect to the investment of the plan assets involved in the transaction or renders investment advice (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>) with respect to those assets, solely by reason of providing services to the plan or solely by reason of a relationship to such a service provider described in subparagraph (F), (G), (H), or (I) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/14">section 1002(14) of this title</ref>, or both, but only if in connection with such transaction the plan receives no less, nor pays no more, than adequate consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0580-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “adequate consideration” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0581-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of a security for which there is a generally recognized market—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0582-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the price of the security prevailing on a national securities exchange which is registered under section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</ref>], taking into account factors such as the size of the transaction and marketability of the security, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc0583-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if the security is not traded on such a national securities exchange, a price not less favorable to the plan than the offering price for the security as established by the current bid and asked prices quoted by persons independent of the issuer and of the party in interest, taking into account factors such as the size of the transaction and marketability of the security, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0584-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/17/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an asset other than a security for which there is a generally recognized market, the fair market value of the asset as determined in good faith by a fiduciary or fiduciaries in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0585-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign exchange transactions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any foreign exchange transactions, between a bank or broker-dealer (or any affiliate of either), and a plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/3">section 1002(3) of this title</ref>) with respect to which such bank or broker-dealer (or affiliate) is a trustee, custodian, fiduciary, or other party in interest, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0586-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/18/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transaction is in connection with the purchase, holding, or sale of securities or other investment assets (other than a foreign exchange transaction unrelated to any other investment in securities or other investment assets),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0587-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/18/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at the time the foreign exchange transaction is entered into, the terms of the transaction are not less favorable to the plan than the terms generally available in comparable arm’s length <sup>3</sup> foreign exchange transactions between unrelated parties, or the terms afforded by the bank or broker-dealer (or any affiliate of either) in comparable arm’s-length foreign exchange transactions involving unrelated parties,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0588-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/18/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the exchange rate used by such bank or broker-dealer (or affiliate) for a particular foreign exchange transaction does not deviate by more than 3 percent from the interbank bid and asked rates for transactions of comparable size and maturity at the time of the transaction as displayed on an independent service that reports rates of exchange in the foreign currency market for such currency, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0589-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/18/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the bank or broker-dealer (or any affiliate of either) does not have investment discretion, or provide investment advice, with respect to the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc058a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cross trading</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any transaction described in sections 1106(a)(1)(A) and 1106(b)(2) of this title involving the purchase and sale of a security between a plan and any other account managed by the same investment manager, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc058b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transaction is a purchase or sale, for no consideration other than cash payment against prompt delivery of a security for which market quotations are readily available,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc058c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the transaction is effected at the independent current market price of the security (within the meaning of section 270.17a–7(b) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc058d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> no brokerage commission, fee (except for customary transfer fees, the fact of which is disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (D)), or other remuneration is paid in connection with the transaction,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc058e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a fiduciary (other than the investment manager engaging in the cross-trades or any affiliate) for each plan participating in the transaction authorizes in advance of any cross-trades (in a document that is separate from any other written agreement of the parties) the investment manager to engage in cross trades at the investment manager’s discretion, after such fiduciary has received disclosure regarding the conditions under which cross trades may take place (but only if such disclosure is separate from any other agreement or disclosure involving the asset management relationship), including the written policies and procedures of the investment manager described in subparagraph (H),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc058f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> each plan participating in the transaction has assets of at least $100,000,000, except that if the assets of a plan are invested in a master trust containing the assets of plans maintained by employers in the same controlled group (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/7">section 1107(d)(7) of this title</ref>), the master trust has assets of at least $100,000,000,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0590-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the investment manager provides to the plan fiduciary who authorized cross trading under subparagraph (D) a quarterly report detailing all cross trades executed by the investment manager in which the plan participated during such quarter, including the following information, as applicable: (i) the identity of each security bought or sold; (ii) the number of shares or units traded; (iii) the parties involved in the cross-trade; and (iv) trade price and the method used to establish the trade price,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0591-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the investment manager does not base its fee schedule on the plan’s consent to cross trading, and no other service (other than the investment opportunities and cost savings available through a cross trade) is conditioned on the plan’s consent to cross trading,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0592-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> the investment manager has adopted, and cross-trades are effected in accordance with, written cross-trading policies and procedures that are fair and equitable to all accounts participating in the cross-trading program, and that include a description of the manager’s pricing policies and procedures, and the manager’s policies and procedures for allocating cross trades in an objective manner among accounts participating in the cross-trading program, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc0593-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the investment manager has designated an individual responsible for periodically reviewing such purchases and sales to ensure compliance with the written policies and procedures described in subparagraph (H), and following such review, the individual shall issue an annual written report no later than 90 days following the period to which it relates signed under penalty of perjury to the plan fiduciary who authorized cross trading under subparagraph (D) describing the steps performed during the course of the review, the level of compliance, and any specific instances of non-compliance.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The written report under subparagraph (I) shall also notify the plan fiduciary of the plan’s right to terminate participation in the investment manager’s cross-trading program at any time.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0594-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0595-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), a transaction described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a">section 1106(a) of this title</ref> in connection with the acquisition, holding, or disposition of any security or commodity, if the transaction is corrected before the end of the correction period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0596-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) does not apply to any transaction between a plan and a plan sponsor or its affiliates that involves the acquisition or sale of an employer security (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/1">section 1107(d)(1) of this title</ref>) or the acquisition, sale, or lease of employer real property (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/2">section 1107(d)(2) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0597-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of any fiduciary or other party in interest (or any other person knowingly participating in such transaction), subparagraph (A) does not apply to any transaction if, at the time the transaction occurs, such fiduciary or party in interest (or other person) knew (or reasonably should have known) that the transaction would (without regard to this paragraph) constitute a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a">section 1106(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0598-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “correction period” means, in connection with a fiduciary or party in interest (or other person knowingly participating in the transaction), the 14-day period beginning on the date on which such fiduciary or party in interest (or other person) discovers, or reasonably should have discovered, that the transaction would (without regard to this paragraph) constitute a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a">section 1106(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc0599-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc059a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The term “security” has the meaning given such term by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s475/c/2">section 475(c)(2) of title 26</ref> (without regard to subparagraph (F)(iii) and the last sentence thereof).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc059b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The term “commodity” has the meaning given such term by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s475/e/2">section 475(e)(2) of title 26</ref> (without regard to subparagraph (D)(iii) thereof).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc059c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> The term “correct” means, with respect to a transaction—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc059d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> to undo the transaction to the extent possible and in any case to make good to the plan or affected account any losses resulting from the transaction, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afc059e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/20/E/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> to restore to the plan or affected account any profits made through the use of assets of the plan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc059f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content> The provision of a de minimis financial incentive described in section 401(k)(4)(A) or <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s403/b/12/A">section 403(b)(12)(A) of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05a0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Fiduciary benefits and compensation not prohibited by section 1106</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106">section 1106 of this title</ref> shall be construed to prohibit any fiduciary from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> receiving any benefit to which he may be entitled as a participant or beneficiary in the plan, so long as the benefit is computed and paid on a basis which is consistent with the terms of the plan as applied to all other participants and beneficiaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> receiving any reasonable compensation for services rendered, or for the reimbursement of expenses properly and actually incurred, in the performance of his duties with the plan; except that no person so serving who already receives full time pay from an employer or an association of employers, whose employees are participants in the plan, or from an employee organization whose members are participants in such plan shall receive compensation from such plan, except for reimbursement of expenses properly and actually incurred; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> serving as a fiduciary in addition to being an officer, employee, agent, or other representative of a party in interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05a4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Owner-employees; family members; shareholder employees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05a5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/b">Section 1107(b) of this title</ref> and subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section shall not apply to a transaction in which a plan directly or indirectly—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> lends any part of the corpus or income of the plan to,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pays any compensation for personal services rendered to the plan to, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05a8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> acquires for the plan any property from, or sells any property to,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">any person who is with respect to the plan an owner-employee (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401/c/3">section 401(c)(3) of title 26</ref>), a member of the family (as defined in section 267(c)(4) of such title) of any such owner-employee, or any corporation in which any such owner-employee owns, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote or 50 percent or more of the total value of shares of all classes of stock of the corporation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05a9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05aa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the following shall be treated as owner-employees:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05ab-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A shareholder-employee.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05ac-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> A participant or beneficiary of an individual retirement plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/37">section 7701(a)(37) of title 26</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05ad-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An employer or association of employees which establishes such an individual retirement plan under section 408(c) of such title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05ae-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Paragraph (1)(C) shall not apply to a transaction which consists of a sale of employer securities to an employee stock ownership plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/6">section 1107(d)(6) of this title</ref>) by a shareholder-employee, a member of the family (as defined in section 267(c)(4) of such title) of any such owner-employee, or a corporation in which such a shareholder-employee owns stock representing a 50 percent or greater interest described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05af-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term “owner-employee” shall only include a person described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5afc05b0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (2), the term “shareholder-employee” means an employee or officer of an S corporation (as defined in section 1361(a)(1) of such title) who owns (or is considered as owning within the meaning of section 318(a)(1) of such title) more than 5 percent of the outstanding stock of the corporation on any day during the taxable year of such corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05b1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition or sale by plan of qualifying employer securities; acquisition, sale, or lease by plan of qualifying employer real property</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Sections 1106 and 1107 of this title shall not apply to the acquisition or sale by a plan of qualifying employer securities (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/5">section 1107(d)(5) of this title</ref>) or acquisition, sale or lease by a plan of qualifying employer real property (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/4">section 1107(d)(4) of this title</ref>)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05b2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if such acquisition, sale, or lease is for adequate consideration (or in the case of a marketable obligation, at a price not less favorable to the plan than the price determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/e/1">section 1107(e)(1) of this title</ref>),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05b3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if no commission is charged with respect thereto, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5afc05b4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc05b5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the plan is an eligible individual account plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/d/3">section 1107(d)(3) of this title</ref>), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc05b6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of an acquisition or lease of qualifying employer real property by a plan which is not an eligible individual account plan, or of an acquisition of qualifying employer securities by such a plan, the lease or acquisition is not prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1107/a">section 1107(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05b7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of statutory prohibitions to mergers or transfers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/b/2">Section 1106(b)(2) of this title</ref> shall not apply to any merger or transfer described in subsection (b)(11).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05b8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of investment advice to participant and beneficiaries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05b9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The prohibitions provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106">section 1106 of this title</ref> shall not apply to transactions described in subsection (b)(14) if the investment advice provided by a fiduciary adviser is provided under an eligible investment advice arrangement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afc05ba-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible investment advice arrangement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “eligible investment advice arrangement” means an arrangement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afc05bb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> which either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76bc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> provides that any fees (including any commission or other compensation) received by the fiduciary adviser for investment advice or with respect to the sale, holding, or acquisition of any security or other property for purposes of investment of plan assets do not vary depending on the basis of any investment option selected, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76bd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> uses a computer model under an investment advice program meeting the requirements of paragraph (3) in connection with the provision of investment advice by a fiduciary adviser to a participant or beneficiary, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76be-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to which the requirements of paragraph (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), and (9) are met.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76bf-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment advice program using computer model</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76c0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An investment advice program meets the requirements of this paragraph if the requirements of subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) are met.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76c1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Computer model</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements of this subparagraph are met if the investment advice provided under the investment advice program is provided pursuant to a computer model that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76c2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> applies generally accepted investment theories that take into account the historic returns of different asset classes over defined periods of time,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76c3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> utilizes relevant information about the participant, which may include age, life expectancy, retirement age, risk tolerance, other assets or sources of income, and preferences as to certain types of investments,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76c4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> utilizes prescribed objective criteria to provide asset allocation portfolios comprised of investment options available under the plan,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76c5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> operates in a manner that is not biased in favor of investments offered by the fiduciary adviser or a person with a material affiliation or contractual relationship with the fiduciary adviser, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76c6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> takes into account all investment options under the plan in specifying how a participant’s account balance should be invested and is not inappropriately weighted with respect to any investment option.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76c7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76c8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any investment advice program if an eligible investment expert certifies, prior to the utilization of the computer model and in accordance with rules prescribed by the Secretary, that the computer model meets the requirements of subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76c9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Renewal of certifications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, there are material modifications to a computer model, the requirements of this subparagraph are met only if a certification described in clause (i) is obtained with respect to the computer model as so modified.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76ca-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible investment expert</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “eligible investment expert” means any person—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5afe76cb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> which meets such requirements as the Secretary may provide, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5afe76cc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> does not bear any material affiliation or contractual relationship with any investment adviser or a related person thereof (or any employee, agent, or registered representative of the investment adviser or related person).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76cd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusivity of recommendation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any investment advice program if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76ce-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the only investment advice provided under the program is the advice generated by the computer model described in subparagraph (B), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76cf-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any transaction described in subsection (b)(14)(A)(ii) occurs solely at the direction of the participant or beneficiary.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Nothing in the preceding sentence shall preclude the participant or beneficiary from requesting investment advice other than that described in subparagraph (A), but only if such request has not been solicited by any person connected with carrying out the arrangement.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76d0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Express authorization by separate fiduciary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met with respect to an arrangement if the arrangement is expressly authorized by a plan fiduciary other than the person offering the investment advice program, any person providing investment options under the plan, or any affiliate of either.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76d1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual audit</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if an independent auditor, who has appropriate technical training or experience and proficiency and so represents in writing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76d2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conducts an annual audit of the arrangement for compliance with the requirements of this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76d3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> following completion of the annual audit, issues a written report to the fiduciary who authorized use of the arrangement which presents its specific findings regarding compliance of the arrangement with the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, an auditor is considered independent if it is not related to the person offering the arrangement to the plan and is not related to any person providing investment options under the plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76d4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76d5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the fiduciary adviser provides to a participant or a beneficiary before the initial provision of the investment advice with regard to any security or other property offered as an investment option, a written notification (which may consist of notification by means of electronic communication)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76d6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> of the role of any party that has a material affiliation or contractual relationship with the fiduciary adviser in the development of the investment advice program and in the selection of investment options available under the plan,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76d7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> of the past performance and historical rates of return of the investment options available under the plan,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76d8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> of all fees or other compensation relating to the advice that the fiduciary adviser or any affiliate thereof is to receive (including compensation provided by any third party) in connection with the provision of the advice or in connection with the sale, acquisition, or holding of the security or other property,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76d9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> of any material affiliation or contractual relationship of the fiduciary adviser or affiliates thereof in the security or other property,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76da-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002108">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002108"><num>4</num> So in original. The word “of” probably should appear.</note> the manner, and under what circumstances, any participant or beneficiary information provided under the arrangement will be used or disclosed,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76db-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> of the types of services provided by the fiduciary adviser in connection with the provision of investment advice by the fiduciary adviser,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76dc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> that the adviser is acting as a fiduciary of the plan in connection with the provision of the advice, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76dd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> that a recipient of the advice may separately arrange for the provision of advice by another adviser, that could have no material affiliation with and receive no fees or other compensation in connection with the security or other property, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76de-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> at all times during the provision of advisory services to the participant or beneficiary, the fiduciary adviser—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76df-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> maintains the information described in subparagraph (A) in accurate form and in the manner described in paragraph (8),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76e0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provides, without charge, accurate information to the recipient of the advice no less frequently than annually,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76e1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provides, without charge, accurate information to the recipient of the advice upon request of the recipient, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76e2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> provides, without charge, accurate information to the recipient of the advice concerning any material change to the information required to be provided to the recipient of the advice at a time reasonably contemporaneous to the change in information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76e3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Other conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76e4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the fiduciary adviser provides appropriate disclosure, in connection with the sale, acquisition, or holding of the security or other property, in accordance with all applicable securities laws,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76e5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the sale, acquisition, or holding occurs solely at the direction of the recipient of the advice,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76e6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the compensation received by the fiduciary adviser and affiliates thereof in connection with the sale, acquisition, or holding of the security or other property is reasonable, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76e7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the terms of the sale, acquisition, or holding of the security or other property are at least as favorable to the plan as an arm’s length <sup>3</sup> transaction would be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76e8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards for presentation of information</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76e9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements of this paragraph are met if the notification required to be provided to participants and beneficiaries under paragraph (6)(A) is written in a clear and conspicuous manner and in a manner calculated to be understood by the average plan participant and is sufficiently accurate and comprehensive to reasonably apprise such participants and beneficiaries of the information required to be provided in the notification.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76ea-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Model form for disclosure of fees and other compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue a model form for the disclosure of fees and other compensation required in paragraph (6)(A)(iii) which meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76eb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance for 6 years of evidence of compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if a fiduciary adviser who has provided advice referred to in paragraph (1) maintains, for a period of not less than 6 years after the provision of the advice, any records necessary for determining whether the requirements of the preceding provisions of this subsection and of subsection (b)(14) have been met. A transaction prohibited under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106">section 1106 of this title</ref> shall not be considered to have occurred solely because the records are lost or destroyed prior to the end of the 6-year period due to circumstances beyond the control of the fiduciary adviser.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76ec-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption for plan sponsor and certain other fiduciaries</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76ed-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), a plan sponsor or other person who is a fiduciary (other than a fiduciary adviser) shall not be treated as failing to meet the requirements of this part solely by reason of the provision of investment advice referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> (or solely by reason of contracting for or otherwise arranging for the provision of the advice), if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76ee-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the advice is provided by a fiduciary adviser pursuant to an eligible investment advice arrangement between the plan sponsor or other fiduciary and the fiduciary adviser for the provision by the fiduciary adviser of investment advice referred to in such section,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76ef-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the terms of the eligible investment advice arrangement require compliance by the fiduciary adviser with the requirements of this subsection, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the terms of the eligible investment advice arrangement include a written acknowledgment by the fiduciary adviser that the fiduciary adviser is a fiduciary of the plan with respect to the provision of the advice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76f1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued duty of prudent selection of adviser and periodic review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to exempt a plan sponsor or other person who is a fiduciary from any requirement of this part for the prudent selection and periodic review of a fiduciary adviser with whom the plan sponsor or other person enters into an eligible investment advice arrangement for the provision of investment advice referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>. The plan sponsor or other person who is a fiduciary has no duty under this part to monitor the specific investment advice given by the fiduciary adviser to any particular recipient of the advice.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76f2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/10/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of plan assets for payment for advice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this part shall be construed to preclude the use of plan assets to pay for reasonable expenses in providing investment advice referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76f3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection and subsection (b)(14)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76f4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Fiduciary adviser</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “fiduciary adviser” means, with respect to a plan, a person who is a fiduciary of the plan by reason of the provision of investment advice referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> by the person to a participant or beneficiary of the plan and who is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> registered as an investment adviser under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–1">15 U.S.C. 80b–1</ref> et seq.) or under the laws of the State in which the fiduciary maintains its principal office and place of business,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a bank or similar financial institution referred to in subsection (b)(4) or a savings association (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/b/1">section 1813(b)(1) of title 12</ref>), but only if the advice is provided through a trust department of the bank or similar financial institution or savings association which is subject to periodic examination and review by Federal or State banking authorities,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an insurance company qualified to do business under the laws of a State,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a person registered as a broker or dealer under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76f9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> an affiliate of a person described in any of clauses (i) through (iv), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5afe76fa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> an employee, agent, or registered representative of a person described in clauses (i) through (v) who satisfies the requirements of applicable insurance, banking, and securities laws relating to the provision of the advice.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of this part, a person who develops the computer model described in paragraph (3)(B) or markets the investment advice program or computer model shall be treated as a person who is a fiduciary of the plan by reason of the provision of investment advice referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">section 1002(21)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> to a participant or beneficiary and shall be treated as a fiduciary adviser for purposes of this subsection and subsection (b)(14), except that the Secretary may prescribe rules under which only 1 fiduciary adviser may elect to be treated as a fiduciary with respect to the plan.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76fb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Affiliate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “affiliate” of another entity means an affiliated person of the entity (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–2/a/3">section 80a–2(a)(3) of title 15</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76fc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/g/11/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Registered representative</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “registered representative” of another entity means a person described in section 3(a)(18) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c/a/18">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(18)</ref>) (substituting the entity for the broker or dealer referred to in such section) or a person described in section 202(a)(17) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–2/a/17">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)(17)</ref>) (substituting the entity for the investment adviser referred to in such section).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76fd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of pharmacy benefit services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe76fe-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Provided that all of the conditions described in paragraph (2) are met, the restrictions imposed by subsections (a), (b)(1), and (b)(2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106">section 1106 of this title</ref> shall not apply to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe76ff-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the offering of pharmacy benefit services to a group health plan that is sponsored by an entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/37/G/vi">section 1002(37)(G)(vi) of this title</ref> or to any other group health plan that is sponsored by a regional council, local union, or other labor organization affiliated with such entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7700-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the purchase of pharmacy benefit services by plan participants and beneficiaries of a group health plan that is sponsored by an entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/37/G/vi">section 1002(37)(G)(vi) of this title</ref> or of any other group health plan that is sponsored by a regional council, local union, or other labor organization affiliated with such entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7701-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the operation or implementation of pharmacy benefit services by an entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/37/G/vi">section 1002(37)(G)(vi) of this title</ref> or by any other group health plan that is sponsored by a regional council, local union, or other labor organization affiliated with such entity,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">in any arrangement where such entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/37/G/vi">section 1002(37)(G)(vi) of this title</ref> or any related organization or subsidiary of such entity provides pharmacy benefit services that include prior authorization and appeals, a retail pharmacy network, pharmacy benefit administration, mail order fulfillment, formulary support, manufacturer payments, audits, and specialty pharmacy and goods, to any such group health plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe7702-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The conditions described in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7703-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The terms of the arrangement are at least as favorable to the group health plan as such group health plan could obtain in a similar arm’s length arrangement with an unrelated third party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7704-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At least 50 percent of the providers participating in the pharmacy benefit services offered by the arrangement are unrelated to the contributing employers or any other party in interest with respect to the group health plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7705-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The group health plan retains an independent fiduciary who will be responsible for monitoring the group health plan’s consultants, contractors, subcontractors, and other service providers for purposes of pharmacy benefit services described in paragraph (1) offered by such entity or any of its related organizations or subsidiaries and monitors the transactions of such entity and any of its related organizations or subsidiaries to ensure that all conditions of this exemption are satisfied during each plan year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7706-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any decisions regarding the provision of pharmacy benefit services described in paragraph (1) are made by the group health plan’s independent fiduciary, based on objective standards developed by the independent fiduciary in reliance on information provided by the arrangement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7707-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The independent fiduciary of the group health plan provides an annual report to the Secretary and the congressional committees of jurisdiction attesting that the conditions described in subparagraphs (C) and (D) have been met for the applicable plan year, together with a statement that use of the arrangement’s services are in the best interest of the participants and beneficiaries in the aggregate for that plan year compared to other similar arrangements the group health plan could have obtained in transactions with an unrelated third party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5afe7708-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The arrangement is not designed to benefit any party in interest with respect to the group health plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe7709-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the event an entity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/37/G/vi">section 1002(37)(G)(vi) of this title</ref> or any affiliate of such entity violates any of the conditions of such exemption, such exemption shall not apply with respect to such entity or affiliate and all enforcement and claims available under this chapter shall apply with respect to such entity or affiliate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe770a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to modify any obligation of a group health plan otherwise set forth in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5afe770b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1108/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Group health plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “group health plan” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b/a">section 1191b(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5afe770c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tI/s408">Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 408</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/883">88 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 96–364, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1295">94 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/354/s5/a/43">Pub. L. 97–354, § 5(a)(43)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1697">96 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1114/b/15/B">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1114(b)(15)(B)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1898(i)(1), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2452">100 Stat. 2452</ref>, 2957; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7881(<i>l</i>)(5), 7891(a), 7894(e)(4)(A), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2443">103 Stat. 2443</ref>, 2445, 2450; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXII/s12012/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title XII, § 12012(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-571">104 Stat. 1388–571</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tVII/s731/c/4/C">Pub. L. 103–465, title VII, § 731(c)(4)(C)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/5004">108 Stat. 5004</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1704/n/2">Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1704(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1886">110 Stat. 1886</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXV/s1506/b/2">Pub. L. 105–34, title XV, § 1506(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1066">111 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tV/s535/a/2/C">Pub. L. 106–170, title V, § 535(a)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1934">113 Stat. 1934</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s612/b">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 612(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/100">115 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/218/tII/s204/b/3">Pub. L. 108–218, title II, § 204(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-04-10">Apr. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/609">118 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVII/s709/a/3">Pub. L. 108–357, title VII, § 709(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1551">118 Stat. 1551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tI/s108/a/11">Pub. L. 109–280, title I, § 108(a)(11)</ref>, formerly § 107(a)(11), title VI, §§ 601(a)(1), (2), 611(a)(1), (c)(1), (d)(1), (e)(1), (g)(1), 612(a), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/819">120 Stat. 819</ref>, 952, 953, 967–969, 971, 972, 975, renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/111/192/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 111–192, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-06-25">June 25, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1297">124 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/tI/s106/a/1">Pub. L. 110–458, title I, § 106(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5106">122 Stat. 5106</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dD/tII/s40241/b">Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title II, § 40241(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/859">126 Stat. 859</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/41/tII/s2007/b">Pub. L. 114–41, title II, § 2007(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-07-31">July 31, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/459">129 Stat. 459</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tXIII/s1302/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIII, § 1302(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3204">133 Stat. 3204</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2894">134 Stat. 2894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dT/tI/s113/d">Pub. L. 117–328, div. T, title I, § 113(d)</ref>, title VI, § 606(b)(3), <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5296">136 Stat. 5296</ref>, 5397; <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dJ/tVII/s6702/a">Pub. L. 119–75, div. J, title VII, § 6702(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/733">140 Stat. 733</ref>, 736.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5afe770d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5afe770e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5afe770f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b)(2)(B)(vi)(I), and (h)(3), (4), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, known as the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974. Titles I, III, and IV of such Act are classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(C)(vi)(IV), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1936">110 Stat. 1936</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1996 Amendments note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Investment Advisers Act of 1940, referred to in subsec. (g)(11)(A)(i), is title II of <ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">act Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/847">54 Stat. 847</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 80b–1 et seq.) of chapter 2D of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–20">section 80b–20 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (g)(11)(A)(iv), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5afe7710-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2026–Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/2/A">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “requirements of this subparagraph” for “requirements of this clause” and inserted at end “For purposes of applying <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1106/a/1/C">section 1106(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref> with respect to a transaction described under this subparagraph or subparagraph (C), a contract or arrangement for services between a covered plan and an entity providing services to the plan, including a health insurance issuer providing health insurance coverage in connection with the covered plan, in which such entity contracts, in connection with such plan, with a service provider for pharmacy benefit management services, shall be considered an indirect furnishing of goods, services, or facilities between the covered plan and the service provider for pharmacy benefit management services acting as the party in interest.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(aa). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/2/C">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(2)(C)</ref>, (D), inserted “in” after “defined” and “and the terms ‘health insurance coverage’ and ‘health insurance issuer’ have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b/b">section 1191b(b) of this title</ref>” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)(AA). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Services (including brokerage services),” for “Brokerage services,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)(BB). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/1/B">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Other services,” for “Consulting,” and “including any of the following: plan design, insurance or insurance product selection (including vision and dental), recordkeeping, medical management, benefits administration selection (including vision and dental), stop-loss insurance, pharmacy benefit management services, wellness design and management services, transparency tools, group purchasing organization agreements and services, participation in and services from preferred vendor panels, disease management, compliance services, employee assistance programs, or third-party administration services, or consulting services related to any such services.” for “related to the development or implementation of plan design, insurance or insurance product selection (including vision and dental), recordkeeping, medical management, benefits administration selection (including vision and dental), stop-loss insurance, pharmacy benefit management services, wellness design and management services, transparency tools, group purchasing organization agreements and services, participation in and services from preferred vendor panels, disease management, compliance services, employee assistance programs, or third party administration services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/2/E">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(2)(E)</ref>, inserted “(in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary addressing time, manner, and content of such disclosures)” after “following” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(viii)(I)(cc). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/a/1/B">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “subclause (III)” for “subclause (II)” and “subclauses (III) and (IV)” for “subclauses (II) and (III)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(viii)(II) to (V). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/a/1/A">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (C), added subcl. (II) and redesignated former subcls. (II) to (IV) as (III) to (V), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(x). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/c/2/B">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(c)(2)(B)</ref>, added cl. (x).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/s6702/a/2">Pub. L. 119–75, § 6702(a)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s606/b/3">Pub. L. 117–328, § 606(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2033-01-01">January 1, 2033</date>” for “<date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>” and “(as in effect on <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>)” for “(as in effect on <date date="2015-07-31">July 31, 2015</date>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(21). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s113/d">Pub. L. 117–328, § 113(d)</ref>, added par. (21).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/114/41">Pub. L. 114–41</ref> substituted “<date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>” for “<date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>” and “<date date="2015-07-31">July 31, 2015</date>” for “<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>”. The latter substitution was executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress notwithstanding an extra closing quotation mark in the directory language.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> substituted “<date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>” for “<date date="2014-01-01">January 1, 2014</date>” and “<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>” for “<date date="2006-08-17">August 17, 2006</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(18)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s106/b/1">Pub. L. 110–458, § 106(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “or less” after “deviate by more”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3)(D)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s106/a/1/A">Pub. L. 110–458, § 106(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(14)(A)(ii)” for “subsection (b)(14)(B)(ii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s106/a/1/B">Pub. L. 110–458, § 106(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “fiduciary adviser” for “financial adviser”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(11)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s106/a/1/C">Pub. L. 110–458, § 106(a)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “a participant” for “the participant” in introductory and concluding provisions and “subsection (b)(4)” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/4">section 1108(b)(4) of this title</ref>” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s108/a/11">Pub. L. 109–280, § 108(a)(11)</ref>, formerly § 107(a)(11), as renumbered by <ref href="/us/pl/111/192">Pub. L. 111–192</ref>, substituted “<date date="2006-08-17">August 17, 2006</date>” for “<date date="2004-10-22">October 22, 2004</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s601/a/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (14).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15) to (19). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s611/a/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 611(a)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), (d)(1), (e)(1), (g)(1), added pars. (15) to (19).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(20). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s612/a">Pub. L. 109–280, § 612(a)</ref>, added par. (20).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s601/a/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 601(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> substituted “<date date="2004-10-22">October 22, 2004</date>” for “<date date="2004-04-10">April 10, 2004</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/218">Pub. L. 108–218</ref> substituted “<date date="2014-01-01">January 1, 2014</date>” for “<date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>” and “<date date="2004-04-10">April 10, 2004</date>” for “<date date="1999-12-17">December 17, 1999</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16">Pub. L. 107–16</ref> added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170">Pub. L. 106–170</ref> substituted “made before <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>” for “in a taxable year beginning before <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>” and “<date date="1999-12-17">December 17, 1999</date>” for “<date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions exempting transactions involving an owner-employee, a member of the family, or a corporation controlled by any such owner-employee through the ownership, directly or indirectly, of 50 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote or 50 percent or more of the total value of shares of all classes of stock of the corporation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> inserted at end “A loan made by a plan shall not fail to meet the requirements of the preceding sentence by reason of a loan repayment suspension described under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414/u/4">section 414(u)(4) of title 26</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> substituted “2001” for “1996” and “1995” for “1991”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7881">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7881</ref>(<i>l</i>)(5), added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7891/a/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7891(a)(1)</ref>, in last sentence, substituted “section 401(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “section 401(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401/c/3">section 401(c)(3) of title 26</ref>” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7891/a/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7891(a)(2)</ref>, in last sentence, substituted “section 408 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “section 408 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954” and “section 408(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “section 408(c) of such Code” which for purposes of codification were translated as “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408">section 408 of title 26</ref>” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408/c">section 408(c) of title 26</ref>”, respectively, thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7894/e/4/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7894(e)(4)(A)</ref>, in last sentence, substituted “individual retirement account or individual retirement annuity described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408">section 408 of title 26</ref> or a retirement bond described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s409">section 409 of title 26</ref> (as effective for obligations issued before <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>)” for “individual retirement account, individual retirement annuity, or an individual retirement bond (as defined in section 408 or 409 of title 26)” and “section 408(c) of such Code” for “section 408(c) of such code”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408/c">section 408(c) of title 26</ref>” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1114/b/15/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1114(b)(15)(B)</ref>, substituted “highly compensated employees (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414/q">section 414(q) of title 26</ref>)” for “highly compensated employees, officers, or shareholders”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1898/i/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1898(i)(1)</ref>, struck out “(a),” before “(b),” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/354">Pub. L. 97–354</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1379">section 1379 of title 26</ref> as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1379">section 1379 of title 26</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/s308/a">Pub. L. 96–364, § 308(a)</ref>, added pars. (10) and (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/s308/b">Pub. L. 96–364, § 308(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5afe7711-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7712-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s113/d">section 113(d) of Pub. L. 117–328</ref> applicable with respect to plan years beginning after <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s113/e">section 113(e) of Pub. L. 117–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s606/b/3">section 606(b)(3) of Pub. L. 117–328</ref> applicable to transfers made after <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s606/c">section 606(c) of Pub. L. 117–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s420">section 420 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7713-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/e">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title II, § 202(e)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2900">134 Stat. 2900</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/e">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (c) [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–46">section 300gg–46 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and amending this section] shall apply beginning 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7714-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/458">Pub. L. 110–458</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> to which the amendment relates, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s112">section 112 of Pub. L. 110–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7715-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s108/a/11">section 108(a)(11) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref> applicable to plan years beginning after 2007, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s108/e">section 108(e) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVI/s601/a/3">Pub. L. 109–280, title VI, § 601(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/958">120 Stat. 958</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tVI/s601/a/3">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply with respect to advice referred to in section 3(21)(A)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/21/A/ii">29 U.S.C. 1002(21)(A)(ii)</ref>] provided after <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 611(a)(1), (c)(1), (d)(1), (e)(1), (g)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> applicable to transactions occurring after <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s611/h/1">section 611(h)(1) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975">section 4975 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s612/a">section 612(a) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref> applicable to any transaction which the fiduciary or disqualified person discovers, or reasonably should have discovered, after <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, constitutes a prohibited transaction, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s612/c">section 612(c) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975">section 4975 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7716-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/16">Pub. L. 107–16</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">Dec. 31, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s612/c">section 612(c) of Pub. L. 107–16</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975">section 4975 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7717-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/170">Pub. L. 106–170</ref> applicable to qualified transfers occurring after <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s535/c/1">section 535(c)(1) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s420">section 420 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7718-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1997-12-31">Dec. 31, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1506/c">section 1506(c) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s409">section 409 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe7719-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> effective as of <date date="1994-12-12">Dec. 12, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/n/3">section 1704(n)(3) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414">section 414 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe771a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to qualified transfers under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s420">section 420 of title 26</ref> made after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s12012/e">section 12012(e) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe771b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 7881(<i>l</i>)(5) of <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Pension Protection Act, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, §§ 9302–9346, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7882">section 7882 of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7891/a">section 7891(a) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7891/f">section 7891(f) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002">section 1002 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7894/e/4/B">Section 7894(e)(4)(B) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/s7894/e/4/B">“The amendments made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall take effect as if originally included in section 491(b) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe771c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1114/b/15/B">section 1114(b)(15)(B) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1114/c/3">section 1114(c)(3) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414">section 414 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1898/i/2">Section 1898(i)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s1898/i/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to transactions after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe771d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/354">Pub. L. 97–354</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/354/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 97–354</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1361">section 1361 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5afe771e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/364">Pub. L. 96–364</ref> effective <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, except as specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1461/e">section 1461(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5afe771f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVI/s611/g/3">Pub. L. 109–280, title VI, § 611(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/975">120 Stat. 975</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tVI/s611/g/3">“No later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>], the Secretary of Labor, after consultation with the Securities and Exchange Commission, shall issue regulations regarding the content of policies and procedures required to be adopted by an investment manager under section 408(b)(19) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/19">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(19)</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate to issue before <date date="1988-02-01">Feb. 1, 1988</date>, final regulations to carry out amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1114">section 1114 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1141">section 1141 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary authorized, effective <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, to promulgate regulations wherever provisions of this part call for the promulgation of regulations, see sections 1031 and 1114 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5afe7720-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dJ/tVII/s6702/b">Pub. L. 119–75, div. J, title VII, § 6702(b)</ref>, <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/736">140 Stat. 736</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/75/dJ/tVII/s6702/b">“Subclause (II)(aa) of section 408(b)(2)(B)(viii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/viii">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(viii)</ref>), as amended by subsection (a), shall not be construed to relieve or limit a responsible plan fiduciary from the duty to monitor the practices of any covered service provider that contracts with the applicable covered plan, including for the purposes of ensuring the reasonableness of compensation. For purposes of this subsection, the terms ‘covered plan’, ‘covered service provider’, and ‘responsible plan fiduciary’ have the meanings given such terms in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e721-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Existing Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2899">134 Stat. 2899</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/b">“Nothing in the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall be construed to affect the applicability of section 2550.408b–2 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), with respect to any applicable entity other than a covered plan or a covered service provider (as defined in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B/ii">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>], as amended by subsection (a)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e722-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transition Rule</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/d">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title II, § 202(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2900">134 Stat. 2900</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tII/s202/d">“No contract executed prior to the effective date described in subsection (e) [see Effective Date of 2020 Amendment note above] by a group health plan subject to the requirements of section 408(b)(2)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1108/b/2/B">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)</ref>] (as amended by subsection (a)) or by a health insurance issuer subject to the requirements of section 2746 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–46">42 U.S.C. 300gg–46</ref>] (as added by subsection (c)) shall be subject to the requirements of such section 408(b)(2)(B) or such section 2746, as applicable.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e723-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">With respect to a group health plan subject to subsec. (h) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975/c">section 4975(c) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, as amended by section 1302(a), (b) of div. P of <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref>, beginning at the end of the fifth plan year of such group health plan that begins after <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, subsec. (h) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975/c">section 4975(c) of Title 26</ref> to have no force or effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/s1302/c">section 1302(c) of div. P of Pub. L. 116–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975">section 4975 of Title 26</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e724-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Amendments by Subtitles A and B of Title I of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For special rules on applicability of amendments by subtitles A (§§ 101–108) and B (§§ 111–116) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> to certain eligible cooperative plans, PBGC settlement plans, and eligible government contractor plans, see sections 104, 105, and 106 of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e725-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of 2006 Amendment With Existing Exemptions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any exemption under subsec. (b) of this section provided by amendment by section 601(a)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> not to alter existing individual or class exemptions provided by statute or administrative action, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s601/c">section 601(c) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4975">section 4975 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b00e726-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
