<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b05a319-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1136"><num value="1136">§ 1136.</num><heading> Coordination and responsibility of agencies enforcing this subchapter and related Federal laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b05a31a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1136/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other agencies and departments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to avoid unnecessary expense and duplication of functions among Government agencies, the Secretary may make such arrangements or agreements for cooperation or mutual assistance in the performance of his functions under this subchapter and the functions of any such agency as he may find to be practicable and consistent with law. The Secretary may utilize, on a reimbursable or other basis, the facilities or services of any department, agency, or establishment of the United States or of any State or political subdivision of a State, including the services of any of its employees, with the lawful consent of such department, agency, or establishment; and each department, agency, or establishment of the United States is authorized and directed to cooperate with the Secretary and, to the extent permitted by law, to provide such information and facilities as he may request for his assistance in the performance of his functions under this subchapter. The Attorney General or his representative shall receive from the Secretary for appropriate action such evidence developed in the performance of his functions under this subchapter as may be found to warrant consideration for criminal prosecution under the provisions of this subchapter or other Federal law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b05a31b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1136/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility for detecting and investigating civil and criminal violations of this subchapter and related Federal laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall have the responsibility and authority to detect and investigate and refer, where appropriate, civil and criminal violations related to the provisions of this subchapter and other related Federal laws, including the detection, investigation, and appropriate referrals of related violations of title 18. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude other appropriate Federal agencies from detecting and investigating civil and criminal violations of this subchapter and other related Federal laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b05a31c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1136/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of enforcement with States with respect to certain arrangements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State may enter into an agreement with the Secretary for delegation to the State of some or all of the Secretary’s authority under sections 1132 and 1134 of this title to enforce the requirements under part 7 in connection with multiple employer welfare arrangements, providing medical care (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b/a/2">section 1191b(a)(2) of this title</ref>), which are not group health plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b05a31d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tI/s506">Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 506</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/894">88 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s805">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 805</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2134">98 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tI/s101/e/3">Pub. L. 104–191, title I, § 101(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1953">110 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/204/tVI/s603/b/3/F">Pub. L. 104–204, title VI, § 603(b)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-26">Sept. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2938">110 Stat. 2938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b05a31e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5b05a31f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5b05a320-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/204">Pub. L. 104–204</ref> made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1191b">section 1191b of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), added subsec. (b), and amended section catchline.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b05a321-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b05a322-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/204">Pub. L. 104–204</ref> applicable with respect to group health plans for plan years beginning on or after <date date="1998-01-01">Jan. 1, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/204/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 104–204</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1003">section 1003 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref> applicable with respect to group health plans for plan years beginning after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s101/g">section 101(g) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1181">section 1181 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b05a323-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary authorized, effective <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, to promulgate regulations wherever provisions of this subchapter call for the promulgation of regulations, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1031">section 1031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b05a324-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Relation of Subtitle E of Title II of <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref> to ERISA Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s250">Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 250</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2021">110 Stat. 2021</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s250">“Nothing in this subtitle [subtitle E (§§ 241–250) of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, enacting sections 24, 669, 1035, 1347, 1518, and 3486 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, amending sections 982, 1345, 1510, and 1956 of Title 18, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">section 1395i of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of Labor under section 506(b) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1136/b">29 U.S.C. 1136(b)</ref>], including the Secretary’s authority with respect to violations of title 18, United States Code (as amended by this subtitle).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
