<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b0a5e34-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1150"><num value="1150">§ 1150.</num><heading> Applicability of State law to combat fraud and abuse</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may, for the purpose of identifying, preventing, or prosecuting fraud and abuse, adopt regulatory standards establishing, or issue an order relating to a specific person establishing, that a person engaged in the business of providing insurance through a multiple employer welfare arrangement described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/40">section 1002(40) of this title</ref> is subject to the laws of the States in which such person operates which regulate insurance in such State, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1144/b/6">section 1144(b)(6) of this title</ref> or the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3901">15 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.], and regardless of whether the law of the State is otherwise preempted under any of such provisions. This section shall not apply to any plan or arrangement that does not fall within the meaning of the term “multiple employer welfare arrangement” under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/40/A">section 1002(40)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5b0a5e35-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tI/s520">Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 520</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tVI/s6604/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title VI, § 6604(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/780">124 Stat. 780</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b0a5e36-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5b0a5e37-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5b0a5e38-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/97/45">Pub. L. 97–45</ref>, <date date="1981-09-25">Sept. 25, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/949">95 Stat. 949</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 65 (§ 3901 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3901">section 3901 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
