<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b0f18f8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169"><num value="1169">§ 1169.</num><heading> Additional standards for group health plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f18f9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Group health plan coverage pursuant to medical child support orders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f18fa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each group health plan shall provide benefits in accordance with the applicable requirements of any qualified medical child support order. A qualified medical child support order with respect to any participant or beneficiary shall be deemed to apply to each group health plan which has received such order, from which the participant or beneficiary is eligible to receive benefits, and with respect to which the requirements of paragraph (4) are met.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f18fb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f18fc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified medical child support order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “qualified medical child support order” means a medical child support order—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f18fd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> which creates or recognizes the existence of an alternate recipient’s right to, or assigns to an alternate recipient the right to, receive benefits for which a participant or beneficiary is eligible under a group health plan, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f18fe-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to which the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) are met.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f18ff-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical child support order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “medical child support order” means any judgment, decree, or order (including approval of a settlement agreement) which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f1900-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> provides for child support with respect to a child of a participant under a group health plan or provides for health benefit coverage to such a child, is made pursuant to a State domestic relations law (including a community property law), and relates to benefits under such plan, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f1901-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is made pursuant to a law relating to medical child support described in section 1908 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396g–1">42 U.S.C. 1396g–1</ref>] (as added by section 13822 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002125"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be section “13623”.</note> of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993) with respect to a group health plan,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">if such judgment, decree, or order (I) is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction or (II) is issued through an administrative process established under State law and has the force and effect of law under applicable State law. For purposes of this subparagraph, an administrative notice which is issued pursuant to an administrative process referred to in subclause (II) of the preceding sentence and which has the effect of an order described in clause (i) or (ii) of the preceding sentence shall be treated as such an order.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1902-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternate recipient</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “alternate recipient” means any child of a participant who is recognized under a medical child support order as having a right to enrollment under a group health plan with respect to such participant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1903-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Child</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “child” includes any child adopted by, or placed for adoption with, a participant of a group health plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1904-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be included in qualified order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A medical child support order meets the requirements of this paragraph only if such order clearly specifies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b0f1905-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the name and the last known mailing address (if any) of the participant and the name and mailing address of each alternate recipient covered by the order, except that, to the extent provided in the order, the name and mailing address of an official of a State or a political subdivision thereof may be substituted for the mailing address of any such alternate recipient,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b0f1906-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a reasonable description of the type of coverage to be provided to each such alternate recipient, or the manner in which such type of coverage is to be determined, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b0f1907-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the period to which such order applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1908-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on new types or forms of benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A medical child support order meets the requirements of this paragraph only if such order does not require a plan to provide any type or form of benefit, or any option, not otherwise provided under the plan, except to the extent necessary to meet the requirements of a law relating to medical child support described in section 1908 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396g–1">42 U.S.C. 1396g–1</ref>] (as added by section 13822 <sup>1</sup> of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1909-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f190a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Timely notifications and determinations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any medical child support order received by a group health plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f190b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the plan administrator shall promptly notify the participant and each alternate recipient of the receipt of such order and the plan’s procedures for determining whether medical child support orders are qualified medical child support orders, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f190c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> within a reasonable period after receipt of such order, the plan administrator shall determine whether such order is a qualified medical child support order and notify the participant and each alternate recipient of such determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f190d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of procedures for determining qualified status of orders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each group health plan shall establish reasonable procedures to determine whether medical child support orders are qualified medical child support orders and to administer the provision of benefits under such qualified orders. Such procedures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f190e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be in writing,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f190f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall provide for the notification of each person specified in a medical child support order as eligible to receive benefits under the plan (at the address included in the medical child support order) of such procedures promptly upon receipt by the plan of the medical child support order, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id5b0f1910-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> shall permit an alternate recipient to designate a representative for receipt of copies of notices that are sent to the alternate recipient with respect to a medical child support order.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1911-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> National Medical Support Notice deemed to be a qualified medical child support order</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1912-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the plan administrator of a group health plan which is maintained by the employer of a noncustodial parent of a child or to which such an employer contributes receives an appropriately completed National Medical Support Notice promulgated pursuant to section 401(b) of the Child Support Performance and Incentive Act of 1998 in the case of such child, and the Notice meets the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4), the Notice shall be deemed to be a qualified medical child support order in the case of such child.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1913-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Enrollment of child in plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In any case in which an appropriately completed National Medical Support Notice is issued in the case of a child of a participant under a group health plan who is a noncustodial parent of the child, and the Notice is deemed under clause (i) to be a qualified medical child support order, the plan administrator, within 40 business days after the date of the Notice, shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5b0f1914-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> notify the State agency issuing the Notice with respect to such child whether coverage of the child is available under the terms of the plan and, if so, whether such child is covered under the plan and either the effective date of the coverage or, if necessary, any steps to be taken by the custodial parent (or by the official of a State or political subdivision thereof substituted for the name of such child pursuant to paragraph (3)(A)) to effectuate the coverage; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id5b0f1915-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provide to the custodial parent (or such substituted official) a description of the coverage available and any forms or documents necessary to effectuate such coverage.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1916-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/5/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as requiring a group health plan, upon receipt of a National Medical Support Notice, to provide benefits under the plan (or eligibility for such benefits) in addition to benefits (or eligibility for benefits) provided under the terms of the plan as of immediately before receipt of such Notice.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1917-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions taken by fiduciaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a plan fiduciary acts in accordance with part 4 of this subtitle in treating a medical child support order as being (or not being) a qualified medical child support order, then the plan’s obligation to the participant and each alternate recipient shall be discharged to the extent of any payment made pursuant to such act of the fiduciary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1918-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of alternate recipients</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1919-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment as beneficiary generally</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person who is an alternate recipient under a qualified medical child support order shall be considered a beneficiary under the plan for purposes of any provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment as participant for purposes of reporting and disclosure requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person who is an alternate recipient under any medical child support order shall be considered a participant under the plan for purposes of the reporting and disclosure requirements of part 1 of this subtitle.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct provision of benefits provided to alternate recipients</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any payment for benefits made by a group health plan pursuant to a medical child support order in reimbursement for expenses paid by an alternate recipient or an alternate recipient’s custodial parent or legal guardian shall be made to the alternate recipient or the alternate recipient’s custodial parent or legal guardian.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment to State official treated as satisfaction of plan’s obligation to make payment to alternate recipient</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Payment of benefits by a group health plan to an official of a State or a political subdivision thereof whose name and address have been substituted for the address of an alternate recipient in a qualified medical child support order, pursuant to paragraph (3)(A), shall be treated, for purposes of this subchapter, as payment of benefits to the alternate recipient.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights of States with respect to group health plans where participants or beneficiaries thereunder are eligible for medicaid benefits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance by plans with assignment of rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A group health plan shall provide that payment for benefits with respect to a participant under the plan will be made in accordance with any assignment of rights made by or on behalf of such participant or a beneficiary of the participant as required by a State plan for medical assistance approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] pursuant to section 1912(a)(1)(A) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396k/a/1/A">42 U.S.C. 1396k(a)(1)(A)</ref>] (as in effect on <date date="1993-08-10">August 10, 1993</date>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f191f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Enrollment and provision of benefits without regard to medicaid eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A group health plan shall provide that, in enrolling an individual as a participant or beneficiary or in determining or making any payments for benefits of an individual as a participant or beneficiary, the fact that the individual is eligible for or is provided medical assistance under a State plan for medical assistance approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] will not be taken into account.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1920-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition by States of rights of third parties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A group health plan shall provide that, to the extent that payment has been made under a State plan for medical assistance approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] in any case in which a group health plan has a legal liability to make payment for items or services constituting such assistance, payment for benefits under the plan will be made in accordance with any State law which provides that the State has acquired the rights with respect to a participant to such payment for such items or services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1921-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Group health plan coverage of dependent children in cases of adoption</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1922-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Coverage effective upon placement for adoption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any case in which a group health plan provides coverage for dependent children of participants or beneficiaries, such plan shall provide benefits to dependent children placed with participants or beneficiaries for adoption under the same terms and conditions as apply in the case of dependent children who are natural children of participants or beneficiaries under the plan, irrespective of whether the adoption has become final.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1923-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions based on preexisting conditions at time of placement for adoption prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A group health plan may not restrict coverage under the plan of any dependent child adopted by a participant or beneficiary, or placed with a participant or beneficiary for adoption, solely on the basis of a preexisting condition of such child at the time that such child would otherwise become eligible for coverage under the plan, if the adoption or placement for adoption occurs while the participant or beneficiary is eligible for coverage under the plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1924-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1925-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Child</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “child” means, in connection with any adoption, or placement for adoption, of the child, an individual who has not attained age 18 as of the date of such adoption or placement for adoption.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1926-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Placement for adoption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “placement”, or being “placed”, for adoption, in connection with any placement for adoption of a child with any person, means the assumption and retention by such person of a legal obligation for total or partial support of such child in anticipation of adoption of such child. The child’s placement with such person terminates upon the termination of such legal obligation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1927-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued coverage of costs of a pediatric vaccine under group health plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A group health plan may not reduce its coverage of the costs of pediatric vaccines (as defined under section 1928(h)(6) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396s/h/6">42 U.S.C. 1396s(h)(6)</ref>] as amended by section 13830 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002126"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be section “13631”.</note> of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993) below the coverage it provided as of <date date="1993-05-01">May 1, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b0f1928-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1169/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any regulations prescribed under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b0f1929-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tI/s609">Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 609</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tIV/s4301/a">Pub. L. 103–66, title IV, § 4301(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/371">107 Stat. 371</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tIII/s381/a">Pub. L. 104–193, title III, § 381(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2257">110 Stat. 2257</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV">Pub. L. 105–33, title V</ref>, §§ 5611(a), (b), 5612(a), 5613(a), (b), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/647">111 Stat. 647</ref>, 648; <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/tIV/s401/d">Pub. L. 105–200, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, (h)(2)(A)(iii), (B), (3)(A), <date date="1998-07-16">July 16, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/662">112 Stat. 662</ref>, 668.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b0f192a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5b0f192b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5b0f192c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 401(b) of the Child Support Performance and Incentive Act of 1998, referred to in subsec. (a)(5)(C)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/b">section 401(b) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">section 651 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(7)(A), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, known as the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974. Titles I, III, and IV of such Act are classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title XIX of the Act is classified generally to subchapter XIX (§ 1396 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5b0f192d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/h/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 105–200, § 401(h)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, substituted “is made pursuant to” for “enforces”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/h/2/B">Pub. L. 105–200, § 401(h)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/d">Pub. L. 105–200, § 401(d)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/h/3/A">Pub. L. 105–200, § 401(h)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “the address of an alternate recipient” for “the name and address of an alternate recipient”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5613/b">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5613(b)</ref>, inserted at end “A qualified medical child support order with respect to any participant or beneficiary shall be deemed to apply to each group health plan which has received such order, from which the participant or beneficiary is eligible to receive benefits, and with respect to which the requirements of paragraph (4) are met.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5612/a">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5612(a)</ref>, inserted at end of concluding provisions “For purposes of this subparagraph, an administrative notice which is issued pursuant to an administrative process referred to in subclause (II) of the preceding sentence and which has the effect of an order described in clause (i) or (ii) of the preceding sentence shall be treated as such an order.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5611/a">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5611(a)</ref>, inserted at end “except that, to the extent provided in the order, the name and mailing address of an official of a State or a political subdivision thereof may be substituted for the mailing address of any such alternate recipient,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5613/a/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5613(a)(1)</ref>, (2), struck out “by the plan” after “to be provided” and inserted “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5613/a/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5613(a)(3)</ref>, substituted a period for “, and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5613/a/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5613(a)(4)</ref>, struck out subpar. (D) which read as follows: “each plan to which such order applies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5611/b">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5611(b)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> substituted “which—” for “issued by a court of competent jurisdiction which—” in introductory provisions, substituted a comma for a period at end of cl. (ii), and inserted concluding provisions after cl. (ii).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b0f192e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b0f192f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/h/2/A/iii">section 401(h)(2)(A)(iii) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of section 4301(c)(4)(A) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/h/2/C">section 401(h)(2)(C) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1144">section 1144 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/200/tIV/s401/h/3/B">Pub. L. 105–200, title IV, § 401(h)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-16">July 16, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/668">112 Stat. 668</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/200/tIV/s401/h/3/B">“The amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall be effective as if included in the enactment of section 5611(b) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 [<ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b0f1930-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5611/c">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5611(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/647">111 Stat. 647</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5611/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to medical child support orders issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5612/b">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5612(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/647">111 Stat. 647</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5612/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall be effective as if included in the enactment of section 381 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Public Law 104–193</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/110/2257">110 Stat. 2257</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5613/c">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5613(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/648">111 Stat. 648</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5613/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to medical child support orders issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b0f1931-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tIII/s381/b">Pub. L. 104–193, title III, § 381(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2257">110 Stat. 2257</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/193/tIII/s381/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan amendments not required until <date date="1997-01-01">january 1, 1997</date></inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any amendment to a plan required to be made by an amendment made by this section shall not be required to be made before the 1st plan year beginning on or after <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> during the period after the date before the date of the enactment of this Act and before such 1st plan year, the plan is operated in accordance with the requirements of the amendments made by this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such plan amendment applies retroactively to the period after the date before the date of the enactment of this Act and before such 1st plan year.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A plan shall not be treated as failing to be operated in accordance with the provisions of the plan merely because it operates in accordance with this paragraph.”</continuation>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For provisions relating to effective date of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, see section 395(a)–(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s654">section 654 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b0f1932-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Medical Support Notices for Health Plans; Qualified Medical Child Support Orders</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/200/tIV/s401/e">Pub. L. 105–200, title IV, § 401(e)</ref>–(g), <date date="1998-07-16">July 16, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/663-668">112 Stat. 663–668</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tVII/s7307/a/2/B">Pub. L. 109–171, title VII, § 7307(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/146">120 Stat. 146</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/171/tVII/s7307/a/2/B">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Medical Support Notices for State or Local Governmental Group Health Plans.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Each State or local governmental group health plan shall provide benefits in accordance with the applicable requirements of any National Medical Support Notice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enrollment of child in plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In any case in which an appropriately completed National Medical Support Notice is issued in the case of a child of a participant under a State or local governmental group health plan, the plan administrator, within 40 business days after the date of the Notice, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> notify the State agency issuing the Notice with respect to such child whether coverage of the child is available under the terms of the plan and, if so, whether such child is covered under the plan and either the effective date of the coverage or any steps necessary to be taken by the custodial parent (or by any official of a State or political subdivision thereof substituted in the Notice for the name of such child in accordance with procedures appliable [sic] under subsection (b)(2) of this section [<ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/b/2">section 401(b)(2) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> note]) to effectuate the coverage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provide to the custodial parent (or such substituted official) a description of the coverage available and any forms or documents necessary to effectuate such coverage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as requiring a State or local governmental group health plan, upon receipt of a National Medical Support Notice, to provide benefits under the plan (or eligibility for such benefits) in addition to benefits (or eligibility for benefits) provided under the terms of the plan as of immediately before receipt of such Notice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State or local governmental group health plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State or local governmental group health plan’ means a group health plan which is established or maintained for its employees by the government of any State, any political subdivision of a State, or any agency or instrumentality of either of the foregoing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternate recipient</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘alternate recipient’ means any child of a participant who is recognized under a National Medical Support Notice as having a right to enrollment under a State or local governmental group health plan with respect to such participant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Group health plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘group health plan’ has the meaning provided in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1167/1">29 U.S.C. 1167(1)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other terms</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘participant’ and ‘administrator’ shall have the meanings provided such terms, respectively, by paragraphs (7) and (16) of section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this subsection shall take effect on the date of the issuance of interim regulations pursuant to subsection (b)(4) of this section [<ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/b/4">section 401(b)(4) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> note].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified Medical Child Support Orders and National Medical Support Notices for Church Plans.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Each church group health plan shall provide benefits in accordance with the applicable requirements of any qualified medical child support order. A qualified medical child support order with respect to any participant or beneficiary shall be deemed to apply to each such group health plan which has received such order, from which the participant or beneficiary is eligible to receive benefits, and with respect to which the requirements of paragraph (4) are met.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Church group health plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘church group health plan’ means a group health plan which is a church plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified medical child support order</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified medical child support order’ means a medical child support order—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> which creates or recognizes the existence of an alternate recipient’s right to, or assigns to an alternate recipient the right to, receive benefits for which a participant or beneficiary is eligible under a church group health plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> with respect to which the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) are met.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medical child support order</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘medical child support order’ means any judgment, decree, or order (including approval of a settlement agreement) which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> provides for child support with respect to a child of a participant under a church group health plan or provides for health benefit coverage to such a child, is made pursuant to a State domestic relations law (including a community property law), and relates to benefits under such plan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> is made pursuant to a law relating to medical child support described in section 1908 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396g–1">42 U.S.C. 1396g–1</ref>] (as added by section 13822 [13623] of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 [<ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref>]) with respect to a church group health plan,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  if such judgment, decree, or order: (I) is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction; or (II) is issued through an administrative process established under State law and has the force and effect of law under applicable State law. For purposes of this paragraph, an administrative notice which is issued pursuant to an administrative process referred to in subclause (II) of the preceding sentence and which has the effect of an order described in clause (i) or (ii) of the preceding sentence shall be treated as such an order.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternate recipient</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘alternate recipient’ means any child of a participant who is recognized under a medical child support order as having a right to enrollment under a church group health plan with respect to such participant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Group health plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘group health plan’ has the meaning provided in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1167/1">29 U.S.C. 1167(1)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other terms</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘participant’, ‘beneficiary’, ‘administrator’, and ‘church plan’ shall have the meanings provided such terms, respectively, by paragraphs (7), (8), (16), and (33) of section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1102">29 U.S.C. 1102</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information to be included in qualified order</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A medical child support order meets the requirements of this paragraph only if such order clearly specifies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the name and the last known mailing address (if any) of the participant and the name and mailing address of each alternate recipient covered by the order, except that, to the extent provided in the order, the name and mailing address of an official of a State or a political subdivision thereof may be substituted for the mailing address of any such alternate recipient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a reasonable description of the type of coverage to be provided to each such alternate recipient, or the manner in which such type of coverage is to be determined; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the period to which such order applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restriction on new types or forms of benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>A medical child support order meets the requirements of this paragraph only if such order does not require a church group health plan to provide any type or form of benefit, or any option, not otherwise provided under the plan, except to the extent necessary to meet the requirements of a law relating to medical child support described in section 1908 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396g–1">42 U.S.C. 1396g–1</ref>] (as added by section 13822 [13623] of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 [<ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref>]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedural requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timely notifications and determinations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of any medical child support order received by a church group health plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the plan administrator shall promptly notify the participant and each alternate recipient of the receipt of such order and the plan’s procedures for determining whether medical child support orders are qualified medical child support orders; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> within a reasonable period after receipt of such order, the plan administrator shall determine whether such order is a qualified medical child support order and notify the participant and each alternate recipient of such determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of procedures for determining qualified status of orders</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each church group health plan shall establish reasonable procedures to determine whether medical child support orders are qualified medical child support orders and to administer the provision of benefits under such qualified orders. Such procedures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> shall be in writing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> shall provide for the notification of each person specified in a medical child support order as eligible to receive benefits under the plan (at the address included in the medical child support order) of such procedures promptly upon receipt by the plan of the medical child support order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> shall permit an alternate recipient to designate a representative for receipt of copies of notices that are sent to the alternate recipient with respect to a medical child support order.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National medical support notice deemed to be a qualified medical child support order.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If the plan administrator of any church group health plan which is maintained by the employer of a parent of a child or to which such an employer contributes receives an appropriately completed National Medical Support Notice promulgated pursuant to subsection (b) of this section [<ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/b">section 401(b) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> note] in the case of such child, and the Notice meets the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the Notice shall be deemed to be a qualified medical child support order in the case of such child.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enrollment of child in plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In any case in which an appropriately completed National Medical Support Notice is issued in the case of a child of a participant under a church group health plan who is a parent of the child, and the Notice is deemed under clause (i) to be a qualified medical child support order, the plan administrator, within 40 business days after the date of the Notice, shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> notify the State agency issuing the Notice with respect to such child whether coverage of the child is available under the terms of the plan and, if so, whether such child is covered under the plan and either the effective date of the coverage or any steps necessary to be taken by the custodial parent (or by the official of a State or political subdivision thereof substituted for the name of such child pursuant to paragraph (3)(A)) to effectuate the coverage; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> provide to the custodial parent (or such substituted official) a description of the coverage available and any forms or documents necessary to effectuate such coverage.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as requiring a church group health plan, upon receipt of a National Medical Support Notice, to provide benefits under the plan (or eligibility for such benefits) in addition to benefits (or eligibility for benefits) provided under the terms of the plan as of immediately before receipt of such Notice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Direct provision of benefits provided to alternate recipients</inline>.—</heading><content>Any payment for benefits made by a church group health plan pursuant to a medical child support order in reimbursement for expenses paid by an alternate recipient or an alternate recipient’s custodial parent or legal guardian shall be made to the alternate recipient or the alternate recipient’s custodial parent or legal guardian.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment to state official treated as satisfaction of plan’s obligation to make payment to alternate recipient</inline>.—</heading><content>Payment of benefits by a church group health plan to an official of a State or a political subdivision thereof whose name and address have been substituted for the address of an alternate recipient in a medical child support order, pursuant to paragraph (3)(A), shall be treated, for purposes of this subsection and part D of title IV of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.], as payment of benefits to the alternate recipient.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this subsection shall take effect on the date of the issuance of interim regulations pursuant to subsection (b)(4) of this section [<ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/b/4">section 401(b)(4) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> note].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and Recommendations Regarding the Enforcement of Qualified Medical Child Support Orders</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 8 months after the issuance of the report to the Congress pursuant to subsection (a)(5) [<ref href="/us/pl/105/200/s401/a/5">section 401(a)(5) of Pub. L. 105–200</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">42 U.S.C. 651</ref> note], the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor shall jointly submit to each House of the Congress a report containing recommendations for appropriate legislation to improve the effectiveness of, and enforcement of, qualified medical child support orders under the provisions of subsection (f) of this section and section 609(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1169/a">29 U.S.C. 1169(a)</ref>).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b118933-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1994</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions setting forth circumstances under which any amendment to a plan required to be made by an amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s4301/d">section 4301(d) of Pub. L. 103–66</ref> shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s4301/d">section 4301(d) of Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
