<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b412588-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1364"><num value="1364">§ 1364.</num><heading> Liability on termination of single-employer plans under multiple controlled groups</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b412589-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1364/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> This section applies to all contributing sponsors of a single-employer plan which has two or more contributing sponsors at least two of whom are not under common control at the time such plan is terminated under section 1341(c) or 1342 of this title, or who, at any time within the 5 plan years preceding the date of termination, made contributions under the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b41258a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1364/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The corporation shall determine the liability with respect to each contributing sponsor and each member of its controlled group in a manner consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362">section 1362 of this title</ref>, except that the amount of liability determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1">section 1362(b)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the entire plan shall be allocated to each controlled group by multiplying such amount by a fraction—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b41258b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1364/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the numerator of which is the amount required to be contributed to the plan for the last 5 plan years ending prior to the termination date by persons in such controlled group as contributing sponsors, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b41258c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1364/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the denominator of which is the total amount required to be contributed to the plan for such last 5 plan years by all persons as contributing sponsors,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1368/a">section 1368(a) of this title</ref> shall be applied separately with respect to each controlled group. The corporation may also determine the liability of each such contributing sponsor and member of its controlled group on any other equitable basis prescribed by the corporation in regulations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b41258d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tIV/s4064">Pub. L. 93–406, title IV, § 4064</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1031">88 Stat. 1031</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/tIV/s403/i">Pub. L. 96–364, title IV, § 403(i)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1301">94 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXI/s11016/a/5/B">Pub. L. 99–272, title XI, § 11016(a)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/270">100 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9312/b/2/C/i">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9312(b)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-361">101 Stat. 1330–361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7881/f/3/A">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7881(f)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2440">103 Stat. 2440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b41258e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5b41258f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5b412590-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> substituted “section 1368(a)” for “clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of section 1362(b)(1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “The corporation shall determine the liability with respect to each contributing sponsor and each member of its controlled group in a manner consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362">section 1362 of this title</ref>, except that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the amount of the liability determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1">section 1362(b)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the entire plan—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) shall be determined without regard to clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1/A">section 1362(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) shall be allocated to each controlled group by multiplying such amount by a fraction—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(i) the numerator of which is the amount required to be contributed to the plan for the last 5 plan years ending prior to the termination date by persons in such controlled group as contributing sponsors, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(ii) the denominator of which is the total amount required to be contributed to the plan for such last 5 plan years by all persons as contributing sponsors,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">and clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1/A">section 1362(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref> shall be applied separately with respect to each such controlled group, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the amount of the liability determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/c/1">section 1362(c)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the entire plan shall be allocated to each controlled group by multiplying such amount by the fraction described in paragraph (1)(B) in connection with such controlled group.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11016/a/5/B/iii">Pub. L. 99–272, § 11016(a)(5)(B)(iii)</ref>, substituted “on termination of single-employer plans under multiple controlled groups” for “of employers on termination of plan maintained by more than one employer” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11016/a/5/B/i">Pub. L. 99–272, § 11016(a)(5)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “all contributing sponsors of a single-employer plan which has two or more contributing sponsors at least two of whom are not under common control” for “all employers who maintain a plan under which more than one employer makes contributions (other than a multiemployer plan)” and inserted “under section 1341(c) or 1342 of this title” after “terminated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11016/a/5/B/ii">Pub. L. 99–272, § 11016(a)(5)(B)(ii)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally, substituting reference to each contributing sponsor and each member of its controlled group for reference to each employer of a plan maintained by more than one employer and inserted provisions that liability determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1">section 1362(b)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the entire plan be determined without regard to cls. (i)(II) and (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/b/1/A">section 1362(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref> and that the amount of liability determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1362/c/1">section 1362(c)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the entire plan be allocated to each controlled group by multiplying such amount by the fraction described in par. (1)(B) in connection with such controlled group.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/364">Pub. L. 96–364</ref> inserted provisions excepting a multiemployer plan.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b412591-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b412592-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Pension Protection Act, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, §§ 9302–9346, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7882">section 7882 of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b412593-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> applicable with respect to plan terminations under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref> with respect to which notices of intent to terminate are provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1341/a/2">section 1341(a)(2) of this title</ref> after <date date="1987-12-17">Dec. 17, 1987</date>, and plan terminations with respect to which proceedings are instituted by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1342">section 1342 of this title</ref> after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s9312/d/1">section 9312(d)(1) of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b412594-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> effective <date date="1986-01-01">Jan. 1, 1986</date>, with certain exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11019">section 11019 of Pub. L. 99–272</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5b412595-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/364">Pub. L. 96–364</ref> effective <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, except as specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1461/e">section 1461(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
