<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a230ac1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s172"><num value="172">§ 172.</num><heading> Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230ac2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s172/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Creation; appointment of Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is created an independent agency to be known as the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (herein referred to as the “Service”, except that for sixty days after <date date="1947-06-23">June 23, 1947</date>, such term shall refer to the Conciliation Service of the Department of Labor). The Service shall be under the direction of a Federal Mediation and Conciliation Director (hereinafter referred to as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director shall not engage in any other business, vocation, or employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230ac3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s172/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of officers and employees; expenditures for supplies, facilities, and services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director is authorized, subject to the civil service laws, to appoint such clerical and other personnel as may be necessary for the execution of the functions of the Service, and shall fix their compensation in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, and may, without regard to the provisions of the civil service laws, appoint such conciliators and mediators as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Service. The Director is authorized to make such expenditures for supplies, facilities, and services as he deems necessary. Such expenditures shall be allowed and paid upon presentation of itemized vouchers therefor approved by the Director or by any employee designated by him for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230ac4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s172/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Principal and regional offices; delegation of authority by Director; annual report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The principal office of the Service shall be in the District of Columbia, but the Director may establish regional offices convenient to localities in which labor controversies are likely to arise. The Director may by order, subject to revocation at any time, delegate any authority and discretion conferred upon him by this chapter to any regional director, or other officer or employee of the Service. The Director may establish suitable procedures for cooperation with State and local mediation agencies. The Director shall make an annual report in writing to Congress at the end of the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230ac5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s172/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of all mediation and conciliation services to Service; effective date; pending proceedings unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All mediation and conciliation functions of the Secretary of Labor or the United States Conciliation Service under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s51">section 51 of this title</ref>, and all functions of the United States Conciliation Service under any other law are transferred to the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, together with the personnel and records of the United States Conciliation Service. Such transfer shall take effect upon the sixtieth day after <date date="1947-06-23">June 23, 1947</date>. Such transfer shall not affect any proceedings pending before the United States Conciliation Service or any certification, order, rule, or regulation theretofore made by it or by the Secretary of Labor. The Director and the Service shall not be subject in any way to the jurisdiction or authority of the Secretary of Labor or any official or division of the Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a230ac6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, title II, § 202, <ref href="/us/stat/61/153">61 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a230ac7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a230ac8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a230ac9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s51">Section 51 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/642">80 Stat. 642</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5a230aca-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of subsec. (a) which prescribed the basic annual compensation of the Director were omitted to conform to the provisions of the Executive Schedule. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5314">section 5314 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b), “chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of subsec. (b) that authorized the Director to fix the compensation of conciliators and mediators without regard to the Classification Act of 1923, as amended, have been omitted as obsolete. Sections 1202 and 1204 of the Classification Act of 1949, <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>, 973, repealed the Classification Act of 1923 and all other laws or parts of laws inconsistent with the 1949 Act. While section 1106(a) of the 1949 Act provided that references in other laws to the 1923 Act should be held and considered to mean the 1949 Act, it did not have the effect of continuing the exceptions contained in this section because of section 1106(b) which provided that the application of the 1949 Act to any position, officer, or employee shall not be affected by section 1106(a). The Classification Act of 1949 was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8(a), <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref> (of which section 1 revised and enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, into law). <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5102">Section 5102 of Title 5</ref> contains the applicability provisions of the 1949 Act, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5103">section 5103 of Title 5</ref> authorizes the Office of Personnel Management to determine the applicability to specific positions and employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a230acb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a230acc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id5a230acd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed (subject to a savings clause) by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, 655.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a230ace-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (c) requiring the Director to make an annual report in writing to Congress at the end of the fiscal year, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 171 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
