<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a230ae7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a"><num value="175a">§ 175a.</num><heading> Assistance to plant, area, and industrywide labor management committees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230ae8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment and operation of plant, area, and industrywide committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a230ae9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Service is authorized and directed to provide assistance in the establishment and operation of plant, area and industrywide labor management committees which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a230aea-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> have been organized jointly by employers and labor organizations representing employees in that plant, area, or industry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a230aeb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> are established for the purpose of improving labor management relationships, job security, organizational effectiveness, enhancing economic development or involving workers in decisions affecting their jobs including improving communication with respect to subjects of mutual interest and concern.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a230aec-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Service is authorized and directed to enter into contracts and to make grants, where necessary or appropriate, to fulfill its responsibilities under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230aed-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on grants, contracts, or other assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a230aee-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No grant may be made, no contract may be entered into and no other assistance may be provided under the provisions of this section to a plant labor management committee unless the employees in that plant are represented by a labor organization and there is in effect at that plant a collective bargaining agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a230aef-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No grant may be made, no contract may be entered into and no other assistance may be provided under the provisions of this section to an area or industrywide labor management committee unless its participants include any labor organizations certified or recognized as the representative of the employees of an employer participating in such committee. Nothing in this clause shall prohibit participation in an area or industrywide committee by an employer whose employees are not represented by a labor organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a230af0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No grant may be made under the provisions of this section to any labor management committee which the Service finds to have as one of its purposes the discouragement of the exercise of rights contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s157">section 157 of this title</ref>, or the interference with collective bargaining in any plant, or industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230af1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Service shall carry out the provisions of this section through an office established for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a230af2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s175a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $10,000,000 for the fiscal year 1979, and such sums as may be necessary thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a230af3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, title II, § 205A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/524/s6/c/2">Pub. L. 95–524, § 6(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2020">92 Stat. 2020</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a230af4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a230af5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id5a230af6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of <ref href="/us/pl/95/524/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 95–524</ref> as the Labor Management Cooperation Act of 1978, see Short Title of 1978 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a230af7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Statement of Purpose</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/524/s6/b">Pub. L. 95–524, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2020">92 Stat. 2020</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/524/s6/b">
<inline>“It is the purpose of this section [enacting this section and amending sections 173 and 186 of this title]—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to improve communication between representatives of labor and management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide workers and employers with opportunities to study and explore new and innovative joint approaches to achieving organizational effectiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to assist workers and employers in solving problems of mutual concern not susceptible to resolution within the collective bargaining process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> to study and explore ways of eliminating potential problems which reduce the competitiveness and inhibit the economic development of the plant, area or industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> to enhance the involvement of workers in making decisions that affect their working lives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> to expand and improve working relationships between workers and managers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> to encourage free collective bargaining by establishing continuing mechanisms for communication between employers and their employees through Federal assistance to the formation and operation of labor management committees.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a230af8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability to Collective Bargaining Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/524/s6/e">Pub. L. 95–524, § 6(e)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2021">92 Stat. 2021</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/524/s6/e">“Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section [enacting this section, amending sections 173 and 186 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] shall affect the terms and conditions of any collective bargaining agreement whether in effect prior to or entered into after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
