<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a257c1d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183"><num value="183">§ 183.</num><heading> Conciliation of labor disputes in the health care industry</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c1e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of Boards of Inquiry; membership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, in the opinion of the Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, a threatened or actual strike or lockout affecting a health care institution will, if permitted to occur or to continue, substantially interrupt the delivery of health care in the locality concerned, the Director may further assist in the resolution of the impasse by establishing within 30 days after the notice to the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service under clause (A) of the last sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s158/d">section 158(d) of this title</ref> (which is required by clause (3) of such <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s158/d">section 158(d) of this title</ref>), or within 10 days after the notice under clause (B), an impartial Board of Inquiry to investigate the issues involved in the dispute and to make a written report thereon to the parties within fifteen (15) days after the establishment of such a Board. The written report shall contain the findings of fact together with the Board’s recommendations for settling the dispute, with the objective of achieving a prompt, peaceful and just settlement of the dispute. Each such Board shall be composed of such number of individuals as the Director may deem desirable. No member appointed under this section shall have any interest or involvement in the health care institutions or the employee organizations involved in the dispute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c1f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation of members of Boards of Inquiry</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a257c20-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Members of any board established under this section who are otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in carrying out its duties under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a257c21-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Members of any board established under this section who are not subject to paragraph (1) shall receive compensation at a rate prescribed by the Director but not to exceed the daily rate prescribed for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, including travel for each day they are engaged in the performance of their duties under this section and shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in carrying out their duties under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c22-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of status quo</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the establishment of a board under subsection (a) of this section and for 15 days after any such board has issued its report, no change in the status quo in effect prior to the expiration of the contract in the case of negotiations for a contract renewal, or in effect prior to the time of the impasse in the case of an initial bargaining negotiation, except by agreement, shall be made by the parties to the controversy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c23-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s183/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a257c24-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, title II, § 213, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/360/s2">Pub. L. 93–360, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-07-26">July 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/396">88 Stat. 396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a257c25-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a257c26-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id5a257c27-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on thirtieth day after <date date="1974-07-26">July 26, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/360/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 93–360</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s169">section 169 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a257c28-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
