<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a257c2a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185"><num value="185">§ 185.</num><heading> Suits by and against labor organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c2b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Venue, amount, and citizenship</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Suits for violation of contracts between an employer and a labor organization representing employees in an industry affecting commerce as defined in this chapter, or between any such labor organizations, may be brought in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the parties, without respect to the amount in controversy or without regard to the citizenship of the parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c2c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility for acts of agent; entity for purposes of suit; enforcement of money judgments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any labor organization which represents employees in an industry affecting commerce as defined in this chapter and any employer whose activities affect commerce as defined in this chapter shall be bound by the acts of its agents. Any such labor organization may sue or be sued as an entity and in behalf of the employees whom it represents in the courts of the United States. Any money judgment against a labor organization in a district court of the United States shall be enforceable only against the organization as an entity and against its assets, and shall not be enforceable against any individual member or his assets.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c2d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of actions and proceedings by or against labor organizations in the district courts of the United States, district courts shall be deemed to have jurisdiction of a labor organization (1) in the district in which such organization maintains its principal office, or (2) in any district in which its duly authorized officers or agents are engaged in representing or acting for employee members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c2e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Service of process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The service of summons, subpena, or other legal process of any court of the United States upon an officer or agent of a labor organization, in his capacity as such, shall constitute service upon the labor organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a257c2f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s185/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of question of agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, in determining whether any person is acting as an “agent” of another person so as to make such other person responsible for his acts, the question of whether the specific acts performed were actually authorized or subsequently ratified shall not be controlling.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a257c30-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref href="/us/stat/61/156">61 Stat. 156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a257c31-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a257c32-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a257c33-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this Act” meaning <ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">act June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/136">61 Stat. 136</ref>, known as the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, which is classified principally to this subchapter and subchapters III (§ 171 et seq.) and IV (§ 185 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
