<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b591a2c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853"><num value="1853">§ 1853.</num><heading> Administrative sanctions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b591a2d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil money penalties for violations; criteria for assessment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b591a2e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2), any person who commits a violation of this chapter or any regulation under this chapter, may be assessed a civil money penalty of not more than $1,000 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b591a2f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In determining the amount of any penalty to be assessed under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into account (A) the previous record of the person in terms of compliance with this chapter and with comparable requirements of the Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act of 1963 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2041">7 U.S.C. 2041</ref> et seq.], and with regulations promulgated under this chapter and such Act, and (B) the gravity of the violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b591a30-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b591a31-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The person assessed shall be afforded an opportunity for agency hearing, upon request made within thirty days after the date of issuance of the notice of assessment. In such hearing, all issues shall be determined on the record pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>. If no hearing is requested as herein provided, the assessment shall constitute a final and unappealable order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b591a32-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a hearing is requested, the initial agency decision shall be made by an administrative law judge, and such decision shall become the final order unless the Secretary modifies or vacates the decision. Notice of intent to modify or vacate the decision of the administrative law judge shall be issued to the parties within thirty days after the decision of the administrative law judge. A final order which takes effect under this paragraph shall be subject to review only as provided under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b591a33-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person against whom an order imposing a civil money penalty has been entered after an agency hearing under this section may obtain review by the United States district court for any district in which he is located or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia by filing a notice of appeal in such court within thirty days from the date of such order, and simultaneously sending a copy of such notice by registered mail to the Secretary. The Secretary shall promptly certify and file in such court the record upon which the penalty was imposed. The findings of the Secretary shall be set aside only if found to be unsupported by substantial evidence as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s706/2/E">section 706(2)(E) of title 5</ref>. Any final decision, order, or judgment of such District Court concerning such review shall be subject to appeal as provided in chapter 83 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b591a34-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to pay assessment; maintenance of action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any person fails to pay an assessment after it has become a final and unappealable order, or after the court has entered final judgment in favor of the agency, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General, who shall recover the amount assessed by action in the appropriate United States district court. In such action the validity and appropriateness of the final order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b591a35-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s1853/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of penalties into Treasury of United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All penalties collected under authority of this section shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b591a36-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/470/tV/s503">Pub. L. 97–470, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2596">96 Stat. 2596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b591a37-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5b591a38-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5b591a39-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act of 1963, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/582">Pub. L. 88–582</ref>, <date date="1964-09-07">Sept. 7, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/920">78 Stat. 920</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 52 (§ 2041 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/470/tV/s523">Pub. L. 97–470, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2600">96 Stat. 2600</ref>. See section 1801 et seq. of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b591a3a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id5b591a3b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days from <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/470/s524">section 524 of Pub. L. 97–470</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
