<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a361d7b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s209"><num value="209">§ 209.</num><heading> Attendance of witnesses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of any hearing or investigation provided for in this chapter, the provisions of sections 49 and 50 of title 15 (relating to the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and documents), are made applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Administrator, the Secretary of Labor, and the industry committees.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5a361d7c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch676/s9">June 25, 1938, ch. 676, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1065">52 Stat. 1065</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1(b), eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7873, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1095">60 Stat. 1095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a361d7d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a361d7e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id5a361d7f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definition of “Administrator”</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The term “Administrator” as meaning the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s204">section 204 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id5a361d80-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id5a361d81-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions relating to enforcement and administration of equal pay provisions vested by this section in Secretary of Labor and Administrator of Wage and Hour Division of Department of Labor transferred to Equal Employment Opportunity Commission by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1978, § 1, 43 F.R. 19807, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3781">92 Stat. 3781</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–101 of Ex. Ord. No. 12106, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1053.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all other officers of Department of Labor and functions of all agencies and employees of that Department, with exception of functions vested by Administrative Procedure Act (now covered by sections 551 et seq. and 701 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees) in hearing examiners employed by Department, transferred to Secretary of Labor, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions by any of those officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 6 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Labor” substituted in text for “Chief of the Children’s Bureau” by 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 2. See Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s203">section 203 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
