<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b6045e1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104"><num value="2104">§ 2104.</num><heading> Administration and enforcement of requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b6045e2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil actions against employers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045e3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any employer who orders a plant closing or mass layoff in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref> shall be liable to each aggrieved employee who suffers an employment loss as a result of such closing or layoff for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b6045e4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> back pay for each day of violation at a rate of compensation not less than the higher of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b6045e5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the average regular rate received by such employee during the last 3 years of the employee’s employment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b6045e6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the final regular rate received by such employee; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b6045e7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> benefits under an employee benefit plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/3">section 1002(3) of this title</ref>, including the cost of medical expenses incurred during the employment loss which would have been covered under an employee benefit plan if the employment loss had not occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such liability shall be calculated for the period of the violation, up to a maximum of 60 days, but in no event for more than one-half the number of days the employee was employed by the employer.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045e8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The amount for which an employer is liable under paragraph (1) shall be reduced by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b6045e9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any wages paid by the employer to the employee for the period of the violation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b6045ea-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any voluntary and unconditional payment by the employer to the employee that is not required by any legal obligation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b6045eb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any payment by the employer to a third party or trustee (such as premiums for health benefits or payments to a defined contribution pension plan) on behalf of and attributable to the employee for the period of the violation.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In addition, any liability incurred under paragraph (1) with respect to a defined benefit pension plan may be reduced by crediting the employee with service for all purposes under such a plan for the period of the violation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045ec-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any employer who violates the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref> with respect to a unit of local government shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $500 for each day of such violation, except that such penalty shall not apply if the employer pays to each aggrieved employee the amount for which the employer is liable to that employee within 3 weeks from the date the employer orders the shutdown or layoff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045ed-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If an employer which has violated this chapter proves to the satisfaction of the court that the act or omission that violated this chapter was in good faith and that the employer had reasonable grounds for believing that the act or omission was not a violation of this chapter the court may, in its discretion, reduce the amount of the liability or penalty provided for in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045ee-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A person seeking to enforce such liability, including a representative of employees or a unit of local government aggrieved under paragraph (1) or (3), may sue either for such person or for other persons similarly situated, or both, in any district court of the United States for any district in which the violation is alleged to have occurred, or in which the employer transacts business.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045ef-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> In any such suit, the court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5b6045f0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002192">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002192"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> “aggrieved employee” means an employee who has worked for the employer ordering the plant closing or mass layoff and who, as a result of the failure by the employer to comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref>, did not receive timely notice either directly or through his or her representative as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b6045f1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusivity of remedies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The remedies provided for in this section shall be the exclusive remedies for any violation of this chapter. Under this chapter, a Federal court shall not have authority to enjoin a plant closing or mass layoff.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b6045f2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/379/s5">Pub. L. 100–379, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-08-04">Aug. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/893">102 Stat. 893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b6045f3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b6045f4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id5b6045f5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 6 months after <date date="1988-08-04">Aug. 4, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/379/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 100–379</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
