<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a42055e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254"><num value="254">§ 254.</num><heading> Relief from liability and punishment under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Walsh-Healey Act, and the Bacon-Davis Act for failure to pay minimum wage or overtime compensation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a42055f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities not compensable</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), no employer shall be subject to any liability or punishment under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002026"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> on account of the failure of such employer to pay an employee minimum wages, or to pay an employee overtime compensation, for or on account of any of the following activities of such employee engaged in on or after <date date="1947-05-14">May 14, 1947</date>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a420560-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> walking, riding, or traveling to and from the actual place of performance of the principal activity or activities which such employee is employed to perform, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a420561-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> activities which are preliminary to or postliminary to said principal activity or activities,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">which occur either prior to the time on any particular workday at which such employee commences, or subsequent to the time on any particular workday at which he ceases, such principal activity or activities. For purposes of this subsection, the use of an employer’s vehicle for travel by an employee and activities performed by an employee which are incidental to the use of such vehicle for commuting shall not be considered part of the employee’s principal activities if the use of such vehicle for travel is within the normal commuting area for the employer’s business or establishment and the use of the employer’s vehicle is subject to an agreement on the part of the employer and the employee or representative of such employee.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a420562-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensability by contract or custom</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) which relieve an employer from liability and punishment with respect to any activity, the employer shall not be so relieved if such activity is compensable by either—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a420563-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an express provision of a written or nonwritten contract in effect, at the time of such activity, between such employee, his agent, or collective-bargaining representative and his employer; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a420564-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a custom or practice in effect, at the time of such activity, at the establishment or other place where such employee is employed, covering such activity, not inconsistent with a written or nonwritten contract, in effect at the time of such activity, between such employee, his agent, or collective-bargaining representative and his employer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a420565-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on activities compensable under contract or custom</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of subsection (b), an activity shall be considered as compensable under such contract provision or such custom or practice only when it is engaged in during the portion of the day with respect to which it is so made compensable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a420566-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s254/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of time employed with respect to activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the application of the minimum wage and overtime compensation provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], of the Walsh-Healey Act, or of the Bacon-Davis Act,<sup>1</sup> in determining the time for which an employer employs an employee with respect to walking, riding, traveling, or other preliminary or postliminary activities described in subsection (a) of this section, there shall be counted all that time, but only that time, during which the employee engages in any such activity which is compensable within the meaning of subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a420567-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-05-14/ch52/s4">May 14, 1947, ch. 52, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/86">61 Stat. 86</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, [title II], § 2102, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1928">110 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a420568-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a420569-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a42056a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch676">act June 25, 1938, ch. 676</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1060">52 Stat. 1060</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 201 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Walsh-Healey and Bacon-Davis Acts, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (d), are defined for purposes of this chapter in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s262">section 262 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a42056b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> in closing provisions inserted at end “For purposes of this subsection, the use of an employer’s vehicle for travel by an employee and activities performed by an employee which are incidental to the use of such vehicle for commuting shall not be considered part of the employee’s principal activities if the use of such vehicle for travel is within the normal commuting area for the employer’s business or establishment and the use of the employer’s vehicle is subject to an agreement on the part of the employer and the employee or representative of such employee.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a42056c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a44756d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, [title II], § 2103, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1928">110 Stat. 1928</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/188">“The amendment made by section 2101 [probably means <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s2102">section 2102 of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>] and shall apply in determining the application of section 4 of the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 [this section] to an employee in any civil action brought before such date of enactment but pending on such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
