<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a44758d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259"><num value="259">§ 259.</num><heading> Reliance in future on administrative rulings, etc.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a44758e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In any action or proceeding based on any act or omission on or after <date date="1947-05-14">May 14, 1947</date>, no employer shall be subject to any liability or punishment for or on account of the failure of the employer to pay minimum wages or overtime compensation under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002030"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> if he pleads and proves that the act or omission complained of was in good faith in conformity with and in reliance on any written administrative regulation, order, ruling, approval, or interpretation, of the agency of the United States specified in subsection (b) of this section, or any administrative practice or enforcement policy of such agency with respect to the class of employers to which he belonged. Such a defense, if established, shall be a bar to the action or proceeding, notwithstanding that after such act or omission, such administrative regulation, order, ruling, approval, interpretation, practice, or enforcement policy is modified or rescinded or is determined by judicial authority to be invalid or of no legal effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a44758f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The agency referred to in subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a447590-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.]—the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a447591-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of the Walsh-Healey Act—the Secretary of Labor, or any Federal officer utilized by him in the administration of such Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a447592-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s259/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of the Bacon-Davis Act <sup>1</sup>—the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a447593-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-05-14/ch52/s10">May 14, 1947, ch. 52, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/89">61 Stat. 89</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a447594-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a447595-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a447596-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch676">act June 25, 1938, ch. 676</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1060">52 Stat. 1060</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 201 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Walsh-Healey and Bacon-Davis Acts, referred to in text, are defined for purposes of this chapter in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s262">section 262 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id5a447597-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id5a447598-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions relating to enforcement and administration of equal pay provisions vested by subsec. (b)(1) of this section in Administrator of Wage and Hour Division of Department of Labor transferred to Equal Employment Opportunity Commission by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1978, § 1, 43 F.R. 19807, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3781">92 Stat. 3781</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–101 of Ex. Ord. No. 12106, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1053.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of Labor, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Labor, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 6, of 1950, §§ 1, 2, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
