<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a4475aa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262"><num value="262">§ 262.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475ab-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> When the terms “employer”, “employee”, and “wage” are used in this chapter in relation to the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], they shall have the same meaning as when used in such Act of 1938.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475ac-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> When the term “employer” is used in this chapter in relation to the Walsh-Healey Act or Bacon-Davis Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002031"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> it shall mean the contractor or subcontractor covered by such Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475ad-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> When the term “employee” is used in this chapter in relation to the Walsh-Healey Act or the Bacon-Davis Act <sup>1</sup> it shall mean any individual employed by the contractor or subcontractor covered by such Act in the performance of his contract or subcontract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475ae-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The term “Wash-Healey Act” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002032"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “Walsh-Healey Act”.</note> means the Act entitled “An Act to provide conditions for the purchase of supplies and the making of contracts by the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/2036">49 Stat. 2036</ref>), as amended; <sup>1</sup> and the term “Bacon-Davis Act” means the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Act approved <date date="1931-03-03">March 3, 1931</date>, relating to the rate of wages for laborers and mechanics employed by contractors and subcontractors on public buildings”, approved <date date="1935-08-30">August 30, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/1011">49 Stat. 1011</ref>), as amended.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475af-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s262/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> As used in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s255">section 255 of this title</ref> the term “State” means any State of the United States or the District of Columbia or any Territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a4475b0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-05-14/ch52/s13">May 14, 1947, ch. 52, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/90">61 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a4475b1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a4475b2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a4475b3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch676">act June 25, 1938, ch. 676</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1060">52 Stat. 1060</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 201 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Walsh-Healey Act and the Act entitled “An Act to provide conditions for the purchase of supplies and the making of contracts by the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date>, referred to in subsecs. (b) to (d), are <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-30/ch881">act June 30, 1936, ch. 881</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/2036">49 Stat. 2036</ref>, which was classified principally to sections 35 to 45 of former Title 41, Public Contracts, and was substantially repealed and restated as chapter 65 (§ 6501 et seq.) of Title 41, Public Contracts, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref>, §§ 3, 7(b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3677">124 Stat. 3677</ref>, 3855. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1936 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s101">section 101 of Title 41</ref> and Tables. For disposition of sections of former Title 41, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s101">section 101 of Title 41</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The “Bacon-Davis Act”, as defined for purposes of this chapter in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-30/ch825">act Aug. 30, 1935, ch. 825</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1011">49 Stat. 1011</ref>, which generally amended <ref href="/us/act/1931-03-03/ch411">act Mar. 3, 1931, ch. 411</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1494">46 Stat. 1494</ref>, popularly known as the “Davis-Bacon Act”, and which was classified to sections 276a to 276a–6 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. Sections 276a to 276a–6 of former Title 40 were repealed and reenacted as sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, §§ 1, 6(b), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>, 1304.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
