<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b69bb5f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701"><num value="2701">§ 2701.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb60-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In an increasingly competitive world economy, the companies and nations that lead in the rapid development, commercialization, and application of new and advanced technologies, and in the high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services, will lead in economic growth, employment, and high living standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb61-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> While the United States remains the world leader in science and invention, it has not done well in rapidly making the transition from achievement in its research laboratories to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services. This lag and the unprecedented competitive challenge that the United States has faced from abroad have contributed to a drop in real wages and living standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb62-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Companies that are successfully competitive in the rapid development, commercialization, application, and implementation of advanced technologies, and in the successful delivery of goods and services, recognize that worker participation and labor-management cooperation in the deployment, application, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies make an important contribution to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services and in maintaining and improving real wages for workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb63-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The Federal Government has an important role in encouraging and augmenting private sector efforts relating to the development, application, manufacture, and deployment of new and advanced technologies. The role should be to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb64-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> work with private companies, States, worker organizations, nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education to ensure the development, application, production, and implementation of new and advanced technologies to promote the improvement of workers’ skills, wages, job security, and working conditions, and a healthy environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb65-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> encourage worker and worker organization participation in the development, commercialization, evaluation, selection, application, and implementation of new and advanced technologies in the workplace; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb66-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> promote the use and integration of new and advanced technologies in the workplace that enhance workers’ skills.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb67-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2701/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In working with the private sector to promote the technological leadership and economic growth of the United States, the Federal Government has a responsibility to ensure that Federal technology programs help the United States to remain competitive and to maintain and improve living standards and to create and retain secure jobs in economically stable communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id5b69bb68-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tV/s542">Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4051">108 Stat. 4051</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5b69bb69-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5b69bb6a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id5b69bb6b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/382/s541">Section 541 of Pub. L. 103–382</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/382/s541">“This part [part D (§§ 541–547) of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/103/382">Pub. L. 103–382</ref>, enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Workers Technology Skill Development Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b69bb6c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Report on the “Digital Divide”</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/313/tI/s115">Pub. L. 106–313, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1262">114 Stat. 1262</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/313/tI/s115">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Commerce shall conduct a review of existing public and private high-tech workforce training programs in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>], the Secretary of Commerce shall submit a report to Congress setting forth the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b69bb6d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Older Workers in Information Technology Field</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dC/tIV/s417">Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title IV, § 417</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-656">112 Stat. 2681–656</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dC/tIV/s417">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall enter into a contract with the President of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study, using the best available data, assessing the status of older workers in the information technology field. The study shall consider the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The existence and extent of age discrimination in the information technology workplace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The extent to which there is a difference, based on age, in—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> promotion and advancement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> working hours;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> telecommuting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> salary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> stock options, bonuses, and other benefits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The relationship between rates of advancement, promotion, and compensation to experience, skill level, education, and age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Differences in skill level on the basis of age.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the United States House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the results of the study described in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b69bb6e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on High Technology Labor Market Needs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dC/tIV/s418/a">Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title IV, § 418(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-656">112 Stat. 2681–656</ref>, required the Director of the National Science Foundation to conduct a multifaceted study, in a manner that ensured the participation of individuals representing a variety of points of view, to assess labor market needs for workers with high technology skills during the next 10 years, and to submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study by <date date="2000-10-01">Oct. 1, 2000</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5b69bb6f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Twenty-First Century Workforce Commission</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tIII">Pub. L. 105–220, title III</ref>, subtitle C, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1087">112 Stat. 1087</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s401/15">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 401(15)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–412, known as the “Twenty-First Century Workforce Commission Act”, which established the Commission to study all matters relating to the information technology workforce in the United States, including skills necessary to enter the information technology workforce, ways to expand the number of skilled information technology workers, and the relative efficacy of programs in the United States and foreign countries to train information technology workers, and to submit a report to the President and Congress of its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative and administrative actions, and provided for powers of the Commission, compensation of members, employment of staff, authorization of appropriations, and termination of the Commission 90 days after submission of its final report, which was released <date date="2000-06-27">June 27, 2000</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV/s511/a">Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1705">128 Stat. 1705</ref>, effective <date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
