<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5b69bb7e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704"><num value="2704">§ 2704.</num><heading> Grants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb7f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall, to the extent appropriations are available, award grants to eligible entities to carry out the purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2702">section 2702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb80-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb81-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be a nonprofit organization, or a partnership consortium of such organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb82-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> prepare and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of the activities that the entity will carry out using amounts received under the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb83-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> agree to make available (directly or through donations from public or private entities) non-Federal contributions toward the costs of the activities to be conducted with grant funds, in an amount equal to the amount required under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb84-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An entity shall use amounts received under a grant awarded under this section to carry out the purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2702">section 2702 of this title</ref> through activities such as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb85-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the provision of technical assistance to workers, worker organizations, employers, State economic development agencies, State industrial extension programs, Advanced Technology Centers, and National Manufacturing Technology Centers to identify advanced workplace practices and strategies that enhance the effective evaluation, selection, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb86-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the researching and identification of new and advanced workplace technologies, and advanced workplace practices that promote the improvement of workers’ skills, wages, working conditions, and job security, that research the link between advanced workplace practices and long-term corporate performance, and which are consistent with the needs of local communities and the need for a healthy environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5b69bb87-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the development and dissemination of training programs and materials to be used for and by workers, worker organizations, employers, State economic development agencies, State industrial extension programs, Advanced Technology Centers, and National Manufacturing Technology Centers relating to the activities and services provided pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), and regarding successful practices including practices which address labor-management cooperation and the involvement of workers in the design, development, and implementation of workplace practices and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb88-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms of grants and non-Federal shares</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb89-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Grants awarded under this section shall be for a term not to exceed six years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb8a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts required to be contributed by an entity under subsection (b)(3) shall equal—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb8b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an amount equal to 15 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the first year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb8c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the second year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb8d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an amount equal to 33 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the third year for which the grant is awarded;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb8e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an amount equal to 40 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the fourth year for which the grant is awarded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5b69bb8f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/d/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount provided under the grant in the fifth and sixth years for which the grant is awarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5b69bb90-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s2704/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Department shall develop mechanisms for evaluating the effectiveness of the use of a grant awarded under this section in carrying out the purposes under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2702">section 2702 of this title</ref> and, not later than two years after <date date="1994-10-20">October 20, 1994</date>, and every two years thereafter, prepare and submit a report to Congress concerning such evaluation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5b69bb91-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tV/s545">Pub. L. 103–382, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4053">108 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
