<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a4475d5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402"><num value="402">§ 402.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475d6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> “Commerce” means trade, traffic, commerce, transportation, transmission, or communication among the several States or between any State and any place outside thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475d7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> “State” includes any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, Wake Island, the Canal Zone, and Outer Continental Shelf lands defined in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475d8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> “Industry affecting commerce” means any activity, business, or industry in commerce or in which a labor dispute would hinder or obstruct commerce or the free flow of commerce and includes any activity or industry “affecting commerce” within the meaning of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s141">29 U.S.C. 141</ref> et seq.], or the Railway Labor Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475d9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> “Person” includes one or more individuals, labor organizations, partnerships, associations, corporations, legal representatives, mutual companies, joint-stock companies, trusts, unincorporated organizations, trustees, trustees in cases under title 11, or receivers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475da-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> “Employer” means any employer or any group or association of employers engaged in an industry affecting commerce (1) which is, with respect to employees engaged in an industry affecting commerce, an employer within the meaning of any law of the United States relating to the employment of any employees or (2) which may deal with any labor organization concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours of employment, or conditions of work, and includes any person acting directly or indirectly as an employer or as an agent of an employer in relation to an employee but does not include the United States or any corporation wholly owned by the Government of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475db-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> “Employee” means any individual employed by an employer, and includes any individual whose work has ceased as a consequence of, or in connection with, any current labor dispute or because of any unfair labor practice or because of exclusion or expulsion from a labor organization in any manner or for any reason inconsistent with the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475dc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> “Labor dispute” includes any controversy concerning terms, tenure, or conditions of employment, or concerning the association or representation of persons in negotiating, fixing, maintaining, changing, or seeking to arrange terms or conditions of employment, regardless of whether the disputants stand in the proximate relation of employer and employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475dd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> “Trusteeship” means any receivership, trusteeship, or other method of supervision or control whereby a labor organization suspends the autonomy otherwise available to a subordinate body under its constitution or bylaws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475de-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> “Labor organization” means a labor organization engaged in an industry affecting commerce and includes any organization of any kind, any agency, or employee representation committee, group, association, or plan so engaged in which employees participate and which exists for the purpose, in whole or in part, of dealing with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours, or other terms or conditions of employment, and any conference, general committee, joint or system board, or joint council so engaged which is subordinate to a national or international labor organization, other than a State or local central body.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475df-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><chapeau> A labor organization shall be deemed to be engaged in an industry affecting commerce if it—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a4475e0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is the certified representative of employees under the provisions of the National Labor Relations Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s151">29 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], or the Railway Labor Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a4475e1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> although not certified, is a national or international labor organization or a local labor organization recognized or acting as the representative of employees of an employer or employers engaged in an industry affecting commerce; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a4475e2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has chartered a local labor organization or subsidiary body which is representing or actively seeking to represent employees of employers within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a4475e3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> has been chartered by a labor organization representing or actively seeking to represent employees within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2) as the local or subordinate body through which such employees may enjoy membership or become affiliated with such labor organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a4475e4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> is a conference, general committee, joint or system board, or joint council, subordinate to a national or international labor organization, which includes a labor organization engaged in an industry affecting commerce within the meaning of any of the preceding paragraphs of this subsection, other than a State or local central body.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475e5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> “Secret ballot” means the expression by ballot, voting machine, or otherwise, but in no event by proxy, of a choice with respect to any election or vote taken upon any matter, which is cast in such a manner that the person expressing such choice cannot be identified with the choice expressed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475e6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> “Trust in which a labor organization is interested” means a trust or other fund or organization (1) which was created or established by a labor organization, or one or more of the trustees or one or more members of the governing body of which is selected or appointed by a labor organization, and (2) a primary purpose of which is to provide benefits for the members of such labor organization or their beneficiaries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475e7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content> “Labor relations consultant” means any person who, for compensation, advises or represents an employer, employer organization, or labor organization concerning employee organizing, concerted activities, or collective bargaining activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475e8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> “Officer” means any constitutional officer, any person authorized to perform the functions of president, vice president, secretary, treasurer, or other executive functions of a labor organization, and any member of its executive board or similar governing body.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a4475e9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content> “Member” or “member in good standing”, when used in reference to a labor organization, includes any person who has fulfilled the requirements for membership in such organization, and who neither has voluntarily withdrawn from membership nor has been expelled or suspended from membership after appropriate proceedings consistent with lawful provisions of the constitution and bylaws of such organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a46e5ea-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a46e5eb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content> “Officer, agent, shop steward, or other representative”, when used with respect to a labor organization, includes elected officials and key administrative personnel, whether elected or appointed (such as business agents, heads of departments or major units, and organizers who exercise substantial independent authority), but does not include salaried nonsupervisory professional staff, stenographic, and service personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a46e5ec-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s402/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content> “District court of the United States” means a United States district court and a United States court of any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a46e5ed-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/257/s3">Pub. L. 86–257, § 3</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/520">73 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2678">92 Stat. 2678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a46e5ee-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a46e5ef-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a46e5f0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in the opening phrase, was in the original “titles I, II, III, IV, V (except section 505), and VI of this Act”, which reference includes those sections of the Act which are classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of such titles to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (b), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345">act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1331 et seq.) of chapter 29 of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1947-06-23/ch120">act June 23, 1947, ch. 120</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/136">61 Stat. 136</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 7 (§ 141 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s141">section 141 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (f), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/86/257">Pub. L. 86–257</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/519">73 Stat. 519</ref>, known as the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 153, 158, 159, 160, 164, 186, and 187 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 153, 158, and 481 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s401">section 401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Railway Labor Act, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (j)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-20/ch347">act May 20, 1926, ch. 347</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/577">44 Stat. 577</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 8 (§ 151 et seq.) of Title 45, Railroads. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">section 151 of Title 45</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Labor Relations Act, referred to in subsec. (j)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-07-05/ch372">act July 5, 1935, ch. 372</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/452">49 Stat. 452</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 151 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s167">section 167 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a46e5f1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref> substituted “cases under title 11” for “bankruptcy”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a46e5f2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a46e5f3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s402/a">section 402(a) of Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of Title 11</ref>, Bankruptcy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
