<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a46e61c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432"><num value="432">§ 432.</num><heading> Report of officers and employees of labor organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e61d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing; contents of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every officer of a labor organization and every employee of a labor organization (other than an employee performing exclusively clerical or custodial services) shall file with the Secretary a signed report listing and describing for his preceding fiscal year—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e61e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any stock, bond, security, or other interest, legal or equitable, which he or his spouse or minor child directly or indirectly held in, and any income or any other benefit with monetary value (including reimbursed expenses) which he or his spouse or minor child derived directly or indirectly from, an employer whose employees such labor organization represents or is actively seeking to represent, except payments and other benefits received as a bona fide employee of such employer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e61f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any transaction in which he or his spouse or minor child engaged, directly or indirectly, involving any stock, bond, security, or loan to or from, or other legal or equitable interest in the business of an employer whose employees such labor organization represents or is actively seeking to represent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e620-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any stock, bond, security, or other interest, legal or equitable, which he or his spouse or minor child directly or indirectly held in, and any income or any other benefit with monetary value (including reimbursed expenses) which he or his spouse or minor child directly or indirectly derived from, any business a substantial part of which consists of buying from, selling or leasing to, or otherwise dealing with, the business of an employer whose employees such labor organization represents or is actively seeking to represent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e621-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any stock, bond, security, or other interest, legal or equitable, which he or his spouse or minor child directly or indirectly held in, and any income or any other benefit with monetary value (including reimbursed expenses) which he or his spouse or minor child directly or indirectly derived from, a business any part of which consists of buying from, or selling or leasing directly or indirectly to, or otherwise dealing with such labor organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e622-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any direct or indirect business transaction or arrangement between him or his spouse or minor child and any employer whose employees his organization represents or is actively seeking to represent, except work performed and payments and benefits received as a bona fide employee of such employer and except purchases and sales of goods or services in the regular course of business at prices generally available to any employee of such employer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e623-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> any payment of money or other thing of value (including reimbursed expenses) which he or his spouse or minor child received directly or indirectly from any employer or any person who acts as a labor relations consultant to an employer, except payments of the kinds referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s186/c">section 186(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e624-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report of certain bona fide investments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (a) shall not be construed to require any such officer or employee to report his bona fide investments in securities traded on a securities exchange registered as a national securities exchange under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.], in shares in an investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–1">15 U.S.C. 80a–1</ref> et seq.], or in securities of a public utility holding company registered under the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, or to report any income derived therefrom.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e625-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s432/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from filing requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to require any officer or employee of a labor organization to file a report under subsection (a) unless he or his spouse or minor child holds or has held an interest, has received income or any other benefit with monetary value or a loan, or has engaged in a transaction described therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a46e626-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/257/tII/s202">Pub. L. 86–257, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/525">73 Stat. 525</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a46e627-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a46e628-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a46e629-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Investment Company Act of 1940, referred to in subsec. (b), is title I of <ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">act Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/789">54 Stat. 789</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 80a–1 et seq.) of chapter 2D of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–51">section 80a–51 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, referred to in subsec. (b), is title I of <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-26/ch687">act Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 687</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/803">49 Stat. 803</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 2C (§ 79 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII/s1263">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII, § 1263</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/974">119 Stat. 974</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
