<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a46e62a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433"><num value="433">§ 433.</num><heading> Report of employers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e62b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing and contents of report of payments, loans, promises, agreements, or arrangements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every employer who in any fiscal year made—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e62c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any payment or loan, direct or indirect, of money or other thing of value (including reimbursed expenses), or any promise or agreement therefor, to any labor organization or officer, agent, shop steward, or other representative of a labor organization, or employee of any labor organization, except (A) payments or loans made by any national or State bank, credit union, insurance company, savings and loan association or other credit institution and (B) payments of the kind referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s186/c">section 186(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e62d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any payment (including reimbursed expenses) to any of his employees, or any group or committee of such employees, for the purpose of causing such employee or group or committee of employees to persuade other employees to exercise or not to exercise, or as the manner of exercising, the right to organize and bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing unless such payments were contemporaneously or previously disclosed to such other employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e62e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any expenditure, during the fiscal year, where an object thereof, directly or indirectly, is to interfere with, restrain, or coerce employees in the exercise of the right to organize and bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing, or is to obtain information concerning the activities of employees or a labor organization in connection with a labor dispute involving such employer, except for use solely in conjunction with an administrative or arbitral proceeding or a criminal or civil judicial proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e62f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any agreement or arrangement with a labor relations consultant or other independent contractor or organization pursuant to which such person undertakes activities where an object thereof, directly or indirectly, is to persuade employees to exercise or not to exercise, or persuade employees as to the manner of exercising, the right to organize and bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing, or undertakes to supply such employer with information concerning the activities of employees or a labor organization in connection with a labor dispute involving such employer, except information for use solely in conjunction with an administrative or arbitral proceeding or a criminal or civil judicial proceeding; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e630-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any payment (including reimbursed expenses) pursuant to an agreement or arrangement described in subdivision (4);</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall file with the Secretary a report, in a form prescribed by him, signed by its president and treasurer or corresponding principal officers showing in detail the date and amount of each such payment, loan, promise, agreement, or arrangement and the name, address, and position, if any, in any firm or labor organization of the person to whom it was made and a full explanation of the circumstances of all such payments, including the terms of any agreement or understanding pursuant to which they were made.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e631-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Persuasive activities relating to the right to organize and bargain collectively; supplying information of activities in connection with labor disputes; filing and contents of report of agreement or arrangement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every person who pursuant to any agreement or arrangement with an employer undertakes activities where an object thereof is, directly or indirectly—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e632-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to persuade employees to exercise or not to exercise, or persuade employees as to the manner of exercising, the right to organize and bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a46e633-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to supply an employer with information concerning the activities of employees or a labor organization in connection with a labor dispute involving such employer, except information for use solely in conjunction with an administrative or arbitral proceeding or a criminal or civil judicial proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall file within thirty days after entering into such agreement or arrangement a report with the Secretary, signed by its president and treasurer or corresponding principal officers, containing the name under which such person is engaged in doing business and the address of its principal office, and a detailed statement of the terms and conditions of such agreement or arrangement. Every such person shall file annually, with respect to each fiscal year during which payments were made as a result of such an agreement or arrangement, a report with the Secretary, signed by its president and treasurer or corresponding principal officers, containing a statement (A) of its receipts of any kind from employers on account of labor relations advice or services, designating the sources thereof, and (B) of its disbursements of any kind, in connection with such services and the purposes thereof. In each such case such information shall be set forth in such categories as the Secretary may prescribe.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e634-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory or representative services exempt from filing requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any employer or other person to file a report covering the services of such person by reason of his giving or agreeing to give advice to such employer or representing or agreeing to represent such employer before any court, administrative agency, or tribunal of arbitration or engaging or agreeing to engage in collective bargaining on behalf of such employer with respect to wages, hours, or other terms or conditions of employment or the negotiation of an agreement or any question arising thereunder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e635-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from filing requirements generally</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to require an employer to file a report under subsection (a) unless he has made an expenditure, payment, loan, agreement, or arrangement of the kind described therein. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to require any other person to file a report under subsection (b) unless he was a party to an agreement or arrangement of the kind described therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e636-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Services by and payments to regular officers, supervisors, and employees of employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to require any regular officer, supervisor, or employee of an employer to file a report in connection with services rendered to such employer nor shall any employer be required to file a report covering expenditures made to any regular officer, supervisor, or employee of an employer as compensation for service as a regular officer, supervisor, or employee of such employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e637-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights protected by <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s158/c">section 158(c) of this title</ref></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as an amendment to, or modification of the rights protected by, <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s158/c">section 158(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a46e638-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s433/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> “Interfere with, restrain, or coerce” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “interfere with, restrain, or coerce” as used in this section means interference, restraint, and coercion which, if done with respect to the exercise of rights guaranteed in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s157">section 157 of this title</ref>, would, under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s158/a">section 158(a) of this title</ref>, constitute an unfair labor practice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a46e639-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/257/tII/s203">Pub. L. 86–257, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/526">73 Stat. 526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
