<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a49305e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s464"><num value="464">§ 464.</num><heading> Civil action for enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a49305f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s464/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Complaint; investigation; commencement of action by Secretary, member or subordinate body of labor organization; jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the written complaint of any member or subordinate body of a labor organization alleging that such organization has violated the provisions of this subchapter (except <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>) the Secretary shall investigate the complaint and if the Secretary finds probable cause to believe that such violation has occurred and has not been remedied he shall, without disclosing the identity of the complainant, bring a civil action in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the labor organization for such relief (including injunctions) as may be appropriate. Any member or subordinate body of a labor organization affected by any violation of this subchapter (except <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>) may bring a civil action in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the labor organization for such relief (including injunctions) as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a493060-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s464/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Venue</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of actions under this section, district courts of the United States shall be deemed to have jurisdiction of a labor organization (1) in the district in which the principal office of such labor organization is located, or (2) in any district in which its duly authorized officers or agents are engaged in conducting the affairs of the trusteeship.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a493061-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s464/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Presumptions of validity or invalidity of trusteeship</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any proceeding pursuant to this section a trusteeship established by a labor organization in conformity with the procedural requirements of its constitution and bylaws and authorized or ratified after a fair hearing either before the executive board or before such other body as may be provided in accordance with its constitution or bylaws shall be presumed valid for a period of eighteen months from the date of its establishment and shall not be subject to attack during such period except upon clear and convincing proof that the trusteeship was not established or maintained in good faith for a purpose allowable under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s462">section 462 of this title</ref>. After the expiration of eighteen months the trusteeship shall be presumed invalid in any such proceeding and its discontinuance shall be decreed unless the labor organization shall show by clear and convincing proof that the continuation of the trusteeship is necessary for a purpose allowable under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s462">section 462 of this title</ref>. In the latter event the court may dismiss the complaint or retain jurisdiction of the cause on such conditions and for such period as it deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a493062-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/257/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 86–257, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1959-09-14">Sept. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/531">73 Stat. 531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
