<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a0ff82d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s49c"><num value="49c">§ 49c.</num><heading> Acceptance by States; creation of State agencies</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to obtain the benefits of appropriations apportioned under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s49d">section 49d of this title</ref>, a State shall, pursuant to State statute, accept the provisions of this chapter and, in accordance with such State statute, the Governor shall designate or authorize the creation of a State agency vested with all powers necessary to cooperate with the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5a0ff82e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-06-06/ch49/s4">June 6, 1933, ch. 49, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/114">48 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1081">112 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a0ff82f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a0ff830-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a0ff831-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> substituted “, pursuant to State statute,” for “, through its legislature,”, inserted “, in accordance with such State statute, the Governor shall” after “the provisions of this chapter and”, and substituted “Secretary” for “United States Employment Service”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a0ff832-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a0ff833-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> effective <date date="1999-07-01">July 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/s311">section 311 of Pub. L. 105–220</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s49a">section 49a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a0ff834-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of State Agencies to the States</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1946-07-26/ch672/tI">Act July 26, 1946, ch. 672, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/684">60 Stat. 684</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1946-07-26/ch672/tI">“On <date date="1946-11-15">November 15, 1946</date>, the Secretary of Labor shall transfer, to the State agency in each State designated under section 4 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1933-06-06">June 6, 1933</date>, as amended [this section], as the agency to administer the State-wide system of public employment offices in cooperation with the United States Employment Service under said Act [this chapter], the operation of State and local public employment office facilities and properties which were transferred by such State to the Federal Government in 1942 to promote the national war effort. The Secretary of Labor shall, on request of the State agency, also provide for the transfer and assignment to such State, without reimbursement therefor, of any other public employment office facilities and properties within such State, including records, files, and office equipment: <i>Provided</i>, That as a condition to such transfer and assignment of Federal properties, the Secretary may require the recipient State to waive any claim which may then exist or thereafter arise out of the use made by the Federal Government of, or for the loss of or damage to, property and facilities transferred to the Federal Government as hereinabove described.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
