<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a4ba1c8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s524a"><num value="524a">§ 524a.</num><heading> Elimination of racketeering activities threat; State legislation governing collective bargaining representative</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding this or any other Act regulating labor-management relations, each State shall have the authority to enact and enforce, as part of a comprehensive statutory system to eliminate the threat of pervasive racketeering activity in an industry that is, or over time has been, affected by such activity, a provision of law that applies equally to employers, employees, and collective bargaining representatives, which provision of law governs service in any position in a local labor organization which acts or seeks to act in that State as a collective bargaining representative pursuant to the National Labor Relations Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s151">29 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], in the industry that is subject to that program.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5a4ba1c9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s2201">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 2201</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2192">98 Stat. 2192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a4ba1ca-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a4ba1cb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a4ba1cc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, probably means title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1976">98 Stat. 1976</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Crime Control Act of 1984. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1984 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1">section 1 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Labor Relations Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1935-07-05/ch372">act July 5, 1935, ch. 372</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/449">49 Stat. 449</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 151 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s167">section 167 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5a4ba1cd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
