<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a551746-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626"><num value="626">§ 626.</num><heading> Recordkeeping, investigation, and enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a551747-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Attendance of witnesses; investigations, inspections, records, and homework regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall have the power to make investigations and require the keeping of records necessary or appropriate for the administration of this chapter in accordance with the powers and procedures provided in sections 209 and 211 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a551748-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement; prohibition of age discrimination under fair labor standards; unpaid minimum wages and unpaid overtime compensation; liquidated damages; judicial relief; conciliation, conference, and persuasion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall be enforced in accordance with the powers, remedies, and procedures provided in sections 211(b), 216 (except for subsection (a) thereof), and 217 of this title, and subsection (c) of this section. Any act prohibited under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s623">section 623 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to be a prohibited act under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s215">section 215 of this title</ref>. Amounts owing to a person as a result of a violation of this chapter shall be deemed to be unpaid minimum wages or unpaid overtime compensation for purposes of sections 216 and 217 of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That liquidated damages shall be payable only in cases of willful violations of this chapter. In any action brought to enforce this chapter the court shall have jurisdiction to grant such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, including without limitation judgments compelling employment, reinstatement or promotion, or enforcing the liability for amounts deemed to be unpaid minimum wages or unpaid overtime compensation under this section. Before instituting any action under this section, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall attempt to eliminate the discriminatory practice or practices alleged, and to effect voluntary compliance with the requirements of this chapter through informal methods of conciliation, conference, and persuasion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a578849-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil actions; persons aggrieved; jurisdiction; judicial relief; termination of individual action upon commencement of action by Commission; jury trial</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a57884a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any person aggrieved may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction for such legal or equitable relief as will effectuate the purposes of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the right of any person to bring such action shall terminate upon the commencement of an action by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to enforce the right of such employee under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a57884b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In an action brought under paragraph (1), a person shall be entitled to a trial by jury of any issue of fact in any such action for recovery of amounts owing as a result of a violation of this chapter, regardless of whether equitable relief is sought by any party in such action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a57884c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of charge with Commission; timeliness; conciliation, conference, and persuasion; unlawful practice</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a57884d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> No civil action may be commenced by an individual under this section until 60 days after a charge alleging unlawful discrimination has been filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. Such a charge shall be filed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57884e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> within 180 days after the alleged unlawful practice occurred; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57884f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in a case to which <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s633/b">section 633(b) of this title</ref> applies, within 300 days after the alleged unlawful practice occurred, or within 30 days after receipt by the individual of notice of termination of proceedings under State law, whichever is earlier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578850-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon receiving such a charge, the Commission shall promptly notify all persons named in such charge as prospective defendants in the action and shall promptly seek to eliminate any alleged unlawful practice by informal methods of conciliation, conference, and persuasion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578851-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this section, an unlawful practice occurs, with respect to discrimination in compensation in violation of this chapter, when a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice is adopted, when a person becomes subject to a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice, or when a person is affected by application of a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice, including each time wages, benefits, or other compensation is paid, resulting in whole or in part from such a decision or other practice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a578852-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reliance on administrative rulings; notice of dismissal or termination; civil action after receipt of notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s259">Section 259 of this title</ref> shall apply to actions under this chapter. If a charge filed with the Commission under this chapter is dismissed or the proceedings of the Commission are otherwise terminated by the Commission, the Commission shall notify the person aggrieved. A civil action may be brought under this section by a person defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s630/a">section 630(a) of this title</ref> against the respondent named in the charge within 90 days after the date of the receipt of such notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a578853-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578854-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An individual may not waive any right or claim under this chapter unless the waiver is knowing and voluntary. Except as provided in paragraph (2), a waiver may not be considered knowing and voluntary unless at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578855-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the waiver is part of an agreement between the individual and the employer that is written in a manner calculated to be understood by such individual, or by the average individual eligible to participate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578856-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the waiver specifically refers to rights or claims arising under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578857-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the individual does not waive rights or claims that may arise after the date the waiver is executed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578858-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the individual waives rights or claims only in exchange for consideration in addition to anything of value to which the individual already is entitled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578859-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the individual is advised in writing to consult with an attorney prior to executing the agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57885a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57885b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the individual is given a period of at least 21 days within which to consider the agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57885c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if a waiver is requested in connection with an exit incentive or other employment termination program offered to a group or class of employees, the individual is given a period of at least 45 days within which to consider the agreement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57885d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the agreement provides that for a period of at least 7 days following the execution of such agreement, the individual may revoke the agreement, and the agreement shall not become effective or enforceable until the revocation period has expired;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a57885e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> if a waiver is requested in connection with an exit incentive or other employment termination program offered to a group or class of employees, the employer (at the commencement of the period specified in subparagraph (F)) informs the individual in writing in a manner calculated to be understood by the average individual eligible to participate, as to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a57885f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any class, unit, or group of individuals covered by such program, any eligibility factors for such program, and any time limits applicable to such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a578860-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/1/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the job titles and ages of all individuals eligible or selected for the program, and the ages of all individuals in the same job classification or organizational unit who are not eligible or selected for the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578861-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A waiver in settlement of a charge filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, or an action filed in court by the individual or the individual’s representative, alleging age discrimination of a kind prohibited under section 623 or 633a of this title may not be considered knowing and voluntary unless at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578862-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1) have been met; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a578863-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the individual is given a reasonable period of time within which to consider the settlement agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578864-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In any dispute that may arise over whether any of the requirements, conditions, and circumstances set forth in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), or (H) of paragraph (1), or subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2), have been met, the party asserting the validity of a waiver shall have the burden of proving in a court of competent jurisdiction that a waiver was knowing and voluntary pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a578865-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s626/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> No waiver agreement may affect the Commission’s rights and responsibilities to enforce this chapter. No waiver may be used to justify interfering with the protected right of an employee to file a charge or participate in an investigation or proceeding conducted by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a578866-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/202/s7">Pub. L. 90–202, § 7</ref>, <date date="1967-12-15">Dec. 15, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/604">81 Stat. 604</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/a">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c)(1), <date date="1978-04-06">Apr. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/190">92 Stat. 190</ref>, 191; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 1, § 2, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 19807, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3781">92 Stat. 3781</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/433/tII/s201">Pub. L. 101–433, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1990-10-16">Oct. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/983">104 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/166/tI/s115">Pub. L. 102–166, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1991-11-21">Nov. 21, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1079">105 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/2/s4">Pub. L. 111–2, § 4</ref>, <date date="2009-01-29">Jan. 29, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/6">123 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a578867-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a578868-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a578869-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/2/s4/1/B">Pub. L. 111–2, § 4(1)(B)</ref>–(3), inserted “(1)” before “No civil” and “(2)” before “Upon receiving” and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/2/s4/1/A">Pub. L. 111–2, § 4(1)(A)</ref>, which directed amendment of first sentence by redesignating pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, was executed by making the redesignation in the second sentence to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/166">Pub. L. 102–166</ref> struck out par. (1) designation, substituted “Section” for “Sections 255 and”, inserted at end “If a charge filed with the Commission under this chapter is dismissed or the proceedings of the Commission are otherwise terminated by the Commission, the Commission shall notify the person aggrieved. A civil action may be brought under this section by a person defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s630/a">section 630(a) of this title</ref> against the respondent named in the charge within 90 days after the date of the receipt of such notice.”, and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “For the period during which the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission is attempting to effect voluntary compliance with requirements of this chapter through informal methods of conciliation, conference, and persuasion pursuant to subsection (b), the statute of limitations as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s255">section 255 of this title</ref> shall be tolled, but in no event for a period in excess of one year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/433">Pub. L. 101–433</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/a">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, substituted references to the filing of a charge with the Secretary alleging unlawful discrimination for references to the filing with the Secretary of notice of intent to sue.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/c/1">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a57886a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a57886b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/2">Pub. L. 111–2</ref> effective as if enacted <date date="2007-05-28">May 28, 2007</date>, and applicable to certain claims of discrimination in compensation pending on or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/2/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 111–2</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e–5">section 2000e–5 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a57886c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/166">Pub. L. 102–166</ref> effective <date date="1991-11-21">Nov. 21, 1991</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/166/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 102–166</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1981">section 1981 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a57886d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/433/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 101–433, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-16">Oct. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/984">104 Stat. 984</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/433/tII/s202/a">“The amendment made by section 201 [amending this section] shall not apply with respect to waivers that occur before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-10-16">Oct. 16, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a57886e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-04-06">Apr. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/190">92 Stat. 190</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/256/s4/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) of this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect with respect to civil actions brought after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-04-06">Apr. 6, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/95/256/s4/c/2">Pub. L. 95–256, § 4(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-04-06">Apr. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/191">92 Stat. 191</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/256/s4/c/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) of this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect with respect to conciliations commenced by the Secretary of Labor after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-04-06">Apr. 6, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a57886f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule on Waivers</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/433/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 101–433, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-16">Oct. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/984">104 Stat. 984</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/433/tII/s202/b">“Effective on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-10-16">Oct. 16, 1990</date>], the rule on waivers issued by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and contained in section 1627.16(c) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, shall have no force and effect.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a578870-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Age Discrimination Claims Assistance</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/283">Pub. L. 100–283</ref>, <date date="1988-04-07">Apr. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/78">102 Stat. 78</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/504/s2">Pub. L. 101–504, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1298">104 Stat. 1298</ref>, provided extension period for filing civil actions under this section, such period consisting of 450 days beginning on <date date="1988-04-07">Apr. 7, 1988</date>, in cases where a charge was timely filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, and 450 days beginning on <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, in cases where a charge was timely filed after <date date="1985-04-06">Apr. 6, 1985</date>, but the Commission did not, within the applicable period set forth in subsec. (e) of this section either eliminate the alleged unlawful practice or notify the complainant, in writing, of the disposition of the charge and of right of such person to bring civil action on such claim; required the Commission to provide notice regarding claims for which extension period was applicable; and required the Commission to submit reports to Congress containing, among other things, information as to number of persons eligible for extension period and number of persons who were provided notice regarding claims for which extension period was provided.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id5a578871-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id5a578872-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Equal Employment Opportunity Commission” and “Commission” substituted for “Secretary”, meaning Secretary of Labor, pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1978, § 2, 43 F.R. 19807, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3781">92 Stat. 3781</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred all functions vested by this section in Secretary of Labor to Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–101 of Ex. Ord. No. 12106, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1053.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
