<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a59fa11-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653"><num value="653">§ 653.</num><heading> Geographic applicability; judicial enforcement; applicability to existing standards; report to Congress on duplication and coordination of Federal laws; workmen’s compensation law or common law or statutory rights, duties, or liabilities of employers and employees unaffected</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a59fa12-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> This chapter shall apply with respect to employment performed in a workplace in a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, Wake Island, Outer Continental Shelf lands defined in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.], Johnston Island, and the Canal Zone. The Secretary of the Interior shall, by regulation, provide for judicial enforcement of this chapter by the courts established for areas in which there are no United States district courts having jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a59fa13-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a59fa14-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this chapter shall apply to working conditions of employees with respect to which other Federal agencies, and State agencies acting under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2021">section 2021 of title 42</ref>, exercise statutory authority to prescribe or enforce standards or regulations affecting occupational safety or health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a5c4305-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The safety and health standards promulgated under the Act of <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date>, commonly known as the Walsh-Healey Act,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002040"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Service Contract Act of 1965,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref> <ref href="/us/pl/91/54">Public Law 91–54</ref>, Act of <date date="1969-08-09">August 9, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/742">Public Law 85–742</ref>, Act of <date date="1958-08-23">August 23, 1958</date>, and the National Foundation on Arts and Humanities Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s951">20 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.] are superseded on the effective date of corresponding standards, promulgated under this chapter, which are determined by the Secretary to be more effective. Standards issued under the laws listed in this paragraph and in effect on or after the effective date of this chapter shall be deemed to be occupational safety and health standards issued under this chapter, as well as under such other Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a5c4306-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall, within three years after the effective date of this chapter, report to the Congress his recommendations for legislation to avoid unnecessary duplication and to achieve coordination between this chapter and other Federal laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a5c4307-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s653/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to supersede or in any manner affect any workmen’s compensation law or to enlarge or diminish or affect in any other manner the common law or statutory rights, duties, or liabilities of employers and employees under any law with respect to injuries, diseases, or death of employees arising out of, or in the course of, employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a5c4308-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/596/s4">Pub. L. 91–596, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1592">84 Stat. 1592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a5c4309-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a5c430a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a5c430b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345">act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1331 et seq.) of chapter 29 of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (a), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1936-06-30">June 30, 1936</date>, commonly known as the Walsh-Healey Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-30/ch881">act June 30, 1936, ch. 881</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/2036">49 Stat. 2036</ref>, which was classified principally to sections 35 to 45 of former Title 41, Public Contracts, and was substantially repealed and restated as chapter 65 (§ 6501 et seq.) of Title 41, Public Contracts, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref>, §§ 3, 7(b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3677">124 Stat. 3677</ref>, 3855. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1936 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s101">section 101 of Title 41</ref> and Tables. For disposition of sections of former Title 41, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s101">section 101 of Title 41</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Service Contract Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), was <ref href="/us/pl/89/286">Pub. L. 89–286</ref>, <date date="1965-10-22">Oct. 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1034">79 Stat. 1034</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 6 (§ 351 et seq.) of former Title 41, Public Contracts, and was repealed and restated as chapter 67 (§ 6701 et seq.) of Title 41, Public Contracts, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref>, §§ 3, 7(b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3677">124 Stat. 3677</ref>, 3855. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of sections of former Title 41, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s101">section 101 of Title 41</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/54">Public Law 91–54</ref>, Act of <date date="1969-08-09">August 9, 1969</date>, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/54">Pub. L. 91–54</ref>, <date date="1969-08-09">Aug. 9, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/96">83 Stat. 96</ref>, which amended sections 1 and 2 and added <ref href="/us/pl/87/581/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 87–581</ref>, <date date="1962-08-13">Aug. 13, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/357">76 Stat. 357</ref>. Sections 1 and 2 of <ref href="/us/pl/87/581">Pub. L. 87–581</ref> were set out as notes under section 327, and <ref href="/us/pl/87/581/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 87–581</ref> was classified to section 333, of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. Sections 1 and 2 of <ref href="/us/pl/87/581">Pub. L. 87–581</ref> were repealed, and <ref href="/us/pl/87/581/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 87–581</ref> was repealed and reenacted as sections 3704 and 3705 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, §§ 1, 6(b), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>, 1304.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/85/742">Public Law 85–742</ref>, Act of <date date="1958-08-23">August 23, 1958</date>, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/742">Pub. L. 85–742</ref>, <date date="1958-08-23">Aug. 23, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/835">72 Stat. 835</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s941">section 941 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s941">section 941 of Title 33</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/209">Pub. L. 89–209</ref>, <date date="1965-09-29">Sept. 29, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/845">79 Stat. 845</ref>, known as the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 951 et seq.) of chapter 26 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s951">section 951 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), (3), is the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/91/596">Pub. L. 91–596</ref>, which is 120 days after <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/596/s34">section 34 of Pub. L. 91–596</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">section 651 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a5c430c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a5c430d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">EPA Administrator Not Exercising “Statutory Authority” Under This Section in Exercising Any Authority Under Toxic Substances Control Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In exercising any authority under the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">15 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.) in connection with amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency not, for purposes of subsection (b)(1) of this section, to be considered to be exercising statutory authority to prescribe or enforce standards or regulations affecting occupational safety and health, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s15/b">section 15(b) of Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2646">section 2646 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id5a5c430e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5a5c430f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
