<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a5eb46a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s658"><num value="658">§ 658.</num><heading> Citations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb46b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s658/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to issue; grounds; contents; notice in lieu of citation for de minimis violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, upon inspection or investigation, the Secretary or his authorized representative believes that an employer has violated a requirement of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s654">section 654 of this title</ref>, of any standard, rule or order promulgated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s655">section 655 of this title</ref>, or of any regulations prescribed pursuant to this chapter, he shall with reasonable promptness issue a citation to the employer. Each citation shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of the chapter, standard, rule, regulation, or order alleged to have been violated. In addition, the citation shall fix a reasonable time for the abatement of the violation. The Secretary may prescribe procedures for the issuance of a notice in lieu of a citation with respect to de minimis violations which have no direct or immediate relationship to safety or health.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb46c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s658/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Posting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each citation issued under this section, or a copy or copies thereof, shall be prominently posted, as prescribed in regulations issued by the Secretary, at or near each place a violation referred to in the citation occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb46d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s658/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for issuance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No citation may be issued under this section after the expiration of six months following the occurrence of any violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a5eb46e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/596/s9">Pub. L. 91–596, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1601">84 Stat. 1601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
