<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a5eb474-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660"><num value="660">§ 660.</num><heading> Judicial review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb475-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of petition by persons adversely affected or aggrieved; orders subject to review; jurisdiction; venue; procedure; conclusiveness of record and findings of Commission; appropriate relief; finality of judgment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person adversely affected or aggrieved by an order of the Commission issued under subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s659">section 659 of this title</ref> may obtain a review of such order in any United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the violation is alleged to have occurred or where the employer has its principal office, or in the Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, by filing in such court within sixty days following the issuance of such order a written petition praying that the order be modified or set aside. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Commission and to the other parties, and thereupon the Commission shall file in the court the record in the proceeding as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>. Upon such filing, the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein, and shall have power to grant such temporary relief or restraining order as it deems just and proper, and to make and enter upon the pleadings, testimony, and proceedings set forth in such record a decree affirming, modifying, or setting aside in whole or in part, the order of the Commission and enforcing the same to the extent that such order is affirmed or modified. The commencement of proceedings under this subsection shall not, unless ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the order of the Commission. No objection that has not been urged before the Commission shall be considered by the court, unless the failure or neglect to urge such objection shall be excused because of extraordinary circumstances. The findings of the Commission with respect to questions of fact, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive. If any party shall apply to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence and shall show to the satisfaction of the court that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to adduce such evidence in the hearing before the Commission, the court may order such additional evidence to be taken before the Commission and to be made a part of the record. The Commission may modify its findings as to the facts, or make new findings, by reason of additional evidence so taken and filed, and it shall file such modified or new findings, which findings with respect to questions of fact, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive, and its recommendations, if any, for the modification or setting aside of its original order. Upon the filing of the record with it, the jurisdiction of the court shall be exclusive and its judgment and decree shall be final, except that the same shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb476-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of petition by Secretary; orders subject to review; jurisdiction; venue; procedure; conclusiveness of record and findings of Commission; enforcement of orders; contempt proceedings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may also obtain review or enforcement of any final order of the Commission by filing a petition for such relief in the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the alleged violation occurred or in which the employer has its principal office, and the provisions of subsection (a) shall govern such proceedings to the extent applicable. If no petition for review, as provided in subsection (a), is filed within sixty days after service of the Commission’s order, the Commission’s findings of fact and order shall be conclusive in connection with any petition for enforcement which is filed by the Secretary after the expiration of such sixty-day period. In any such case, as well as in the case of a noncontested citation or notification by the Secretary which has become a final order of the Commission under subsection (a) or (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s659">section 659 of this title</ref>, the clerk of the court, unless otherwise ordered by the court, shall forthwith enter a decree enforcing the order and shall transmit a copy of such decree to the Secretary and the employer named in the petition. In any contempt proceeding brought to enforce a decree of a court of appeals entered pursuant to this subsection or subsection (a), the court of appeals may assess the penalties provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s666">section 666 of this title</ref>, in addition to invoking any other available remedies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a5eb477-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Discharge or discrimination against employee for exercise of rights under this chapter; prohibition; procedure for relief</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a5eb478-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No person shall discharge or in any manner discriminate against any employee because such employee has filed any complaint or instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding under or related to this chapter or has testified or is about to testify in any such proceeding or because of the exercise by such employee on behalf of himself or others of any right afforded by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a5eb479-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any employee who believes that he has been discharged or otherwise discriminated against by any person in violation of this subsection may, within thirty days after such violation occurs, file a complaint with the Secretary alleging such discrimination. Upon receipt of such complaint, the Secretary shall cause such investigation to be made as he deems appropriate. If upon such investigation, the Secretary determines that the provisions of this subsection have been violated, he shall bring an action in any appropriate United States district court against such person. In any such action the United States district courts shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown to restrain violations of paragraph (1) of this subsection and order all appropriate relief including rehiring or reinstatement of the employee to his former position with back pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a61257a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s660/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Within 90 days of the receipt of a complaint filed under this subsection the Secretary shall notify the complainant of his determination under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a61257b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/596/s11">Pub. L. 91–596, § 11</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1602">84 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/32">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(32)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3360">98 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a61257c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a61257d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a61257e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> struck out provision requiring expeditious hearing of petitions filed under this subsection.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a61257f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a612580-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
