<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a6125d9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669"><num value="669">§ 669.</num><heading> Research and related activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a6125da-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct research, experiments, and demonstrations, develop plans, establish criteria, promulgate regulations, authorize programs, and publish results and industrywide studies; consultations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125db-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, after consultation with the Secretary and with other appropriate Federal departments or agencies, shall conduct (directly or by grants or contracts) research, experiments, and demonstrations relating to occupational safety and health, including studies of psychological factors involved, and relating to innovative methods, techniques, and approaches for dealing with occupational safety and health problems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125dc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall from time to time consult with the Secretary in order to develop specific plans for such research, demonstrations, and experiments as are necessary to produce criteria, including criteria identifying toxic substances, enabling the Secretary to meet his responsibility for the formulation of safety and health standards under this chapter; and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, on the basis of such research, demonstrations, and experiments and any other information available to him, shall develop and publish at least annually such criteria as will effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125dd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, on the basis of such research, demonstrations, and experiments, and any other information available to him, shall develop criteria dealing with toxic materials and harmful physical agents and substances which will describe exposure levels that are safe for various periods of employment, including but not limited to the exposure levels at which no employee will suffer impaired health or functional capacities or diminished life expectancy as a result of his work experience.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125de-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall also conduct special research, experiments, and demonstrations relating to occupational safety and health as are necessary to explore new problems, including those created by new technology in occupational safety and health, which may require ameliorative action beyond that which is otherwise provided for in the operating provisions of this chapter. The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall also conduct research into the motivational and behavioral factors relating to the field of occupational safety and health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125df-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in order to comply with his responsibilities under paragraph (2), and in order to develop needed information regarding potentially toxic substances or harmful physical agents, may prescribe regulations requiring employers to measure, record, and make reports on the exposure of employees to substances or physical agents which the Secretary of Health and Human Services reasonably believes may endanger the health or safety of employees. The Secretary of Health and Human Services also is authorized to establish such programs of medical examinations and tests as may be necessary for determining the incidence of occupational illnesses and the susceptibility of employees to such illnesses. Nothing in this or any other provision of this chapter shall be deemed to authorize or require medical examination, immunization, or treatment for those who object thereto on religious grounds, except where such is necessary for the protection of the health or safety of others. Upon the request of any employer who is required to measure and record exposure of employees to substances or physical agents as provided under this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall furnish full financial or other assistance to such employer for the purpose of defraying any additional expense incurred by him in carrying out the measuring and recording as provided in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125e0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish within six months of <date date="1970-12-29">December 29, 1970</date>, and thereafter as needed but at least annually a list of all known toxic substances by generic family or other useful grouping, and the concentrations at which such toxicity is known to occur. He shall determine following a written request by any employer or authorized representative of employees, specifying with reasonable particularity the grounds on which the request is made, whether any substance normally found in the place of employment has potentially toxic effects in such concentrations as used or found; and shall submit such determination both to employers and affected employees as soon as possible. If the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that any substance is potentially toxic at the concentrations in which it is used or found in a place of employment, and such substance is not covered by an occupational safety or health standard promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s655">section 655 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall immediately submit such determination to the Secretary, together with all pertinent criteria.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a6125e1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Within two years of <date date="1970-12-29">December 29, 1970</date>, and annually thereafter the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct and publish industrywide studies of the effect of chronic or low-level exposure to industrial materials, processes, and stresses on the potential for illness, disease, or loss of functional capacity in aging adults.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a6125e2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of Health and Human Services to make inspections and question employers and employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized to make inspections and question employers and employees as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s657">section 657 of this title</ref> in order to carry out his functions and responsibilities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a6125e3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracting authority of Secretary of Labor; cooperation between Secretary of Labor and Secretary of Health and Human Services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts, agreements, or other arrangements with appropriate public agencies or private organizations for the purpose of conducting studies relating to his responsibilities under this chapter. In carrying out his responsibilities under this subsection, the Secretary shall cooperate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services in order to avoid any duplication of efforts under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a636ed4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Dissemination of information to interested parties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Information obtained by the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this section shall be disseminated by the Secretary to employers and employees and organizations thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a636ed5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s669/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation of functions of Secretary of Health and Human Services to Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The functions of the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this chapter shall, to the extent feasible, be delegated to the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health established by <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s671">section 671 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a636ed6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/596/s20">Pub. L. 91–596, § 20</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1610">84 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a636ed7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a636ed8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id5a636ed9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted in text for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref> which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
