<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a7dae82-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732"><num value="732">§ 732.</num><heading> Client assistance program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7dae83-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of grant program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">From funds appropriated under subsection (h), the Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, make grants to States to establish and carry out client assistance programs to provide assistance in informing and advising all clients and client applicants of all available benefits under this chapter, including under sections 733 and 794g of this title, and, upon request of such clients or client applicants, to assist and advocate for such clients or applicants in their relationships with projects, programs, and services provided under this chapter, including assistance and advocacy in pursuing legal, administrative, or other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of the rights of such individuals under this chapter and to facilitate access to the services funded under this chapter through individual and systemic advocacy. The client assistance program shall provide information on the available services and benefits under this chapter and title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12111">42 U.S.C. 12111</ref> et seq.) to individuals with disabilities in the State, especially with regard to individuals with disabilities who have traditionally been unserved or underserved by vocational rehabilitation programs. In providing assistance and advocacy under this subsection with respect to services under this subchapter, a client assistance program may provide the assistance and advocacy with respect to services that are directly related to facilitating the employment of the individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7dae84-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existence of State program as requisite to receiving payments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No State may receive payments from its allotment under this chapter in any fiscal year unless the State has in effect a client assistance program which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae85-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has the authority to pursue legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of rights of individuals with disabilities who are receiving treatments, services, or rehabilitation under this chapter within the State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae86-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> meets the requirements of designation under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7dae87-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of agency to conduct program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae88-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae89-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Governor shall designate a public or private agency to conduct the client assistance program under this section. Except as provided in the last sentence of this subparagraph, the Governor shall designate an agency which is independent of any agency which provides treatment, services, or rehabilitation to individuals under this chapter. If there is an agency in the State which has, or had, prior to <date date="1984-02-22">February 22, 1984</date>, served as a client assistance agency under this section and which received Federal financial assistance under this chapter, the Governor may, in the initial designation, designate an agency which provides treatment, services, or rehabilitation to individuals with disabilities under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae8a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae8b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The Governor may not redesignate the agency designated under subparagraph (A) without good cause and unless—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae8c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the Governor has given the agency 30 days notice of the intention to make such redesignation, including specification of the good cause for such redesignation and an opportunity to respond to the assertion that good cause has been shown;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae8d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> individuals with disabilities or the individuals’ representatives have timely notice of the redesignation and opportunity for public comment; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae8e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the agency has the opportunity to appeal to the Commissioner on the basis that the redesignation was not for good cause.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae8f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> If, after <date date="1998-08-07">August 7, 1998</date>—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae90-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a designated State agency undergoes any change in the organizational structure of the agency that results in the creation of one or more new State agencies or departments or results in the merger of the designated State agency with one or more other State agencies or departments; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7dae91-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an agency (including an office or other unit) within the designated State agency was conducting a client assistance program before the change under the last sentence of subparagraph (A),</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Governor shall redesignate the agency conducting the program. In conducting the redesignation, the Governor shall designate to conduct the program an agency that is independent of any agency that provides treatment, services, or rehabilitation to individuals with disabilities under this chapter.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae92-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Governor shall consult with the director of the State vocational rehabilitation agency, the head of the developmental disability protection and advocacy agency, and with representatives of professional and consumer organizations serving individuals with disabilities in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae93-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The agency designated under this subsection shall be accountable for the proper use of funds made available to the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7dae94-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Class action by designated agency prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The agency designated under subsection (c) of this section may not bring any class action in carrying out its responsibilities under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7dae95-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotment and reallotment of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae96-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae97-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> After reserving funds under subparagraphs (E) and (F), the Secretary shall allot the remainder of the sums appropriated for each fiscal year under this section among the States on the basis of relative population of each State, except that no State shall receive less than $50,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae98-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall allot $30,000 each to American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae99-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For the purpose of this paragraph, the term “State” does not include American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In any fiscal year that the funds appropriated for such fiscal year exceed $7,500,000, the minimum allotment shall be $100,000 for States and $45,000 for territories.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For any fiscal year in which the total amount appropriated under subsection (h) exceeds the total amount appropriated under such subsection for the preceding fiscal year, the Secretary shall increase each of the minimum allotments under clause (i) by a percentage that shall not exceed the percentage increase in the total amount appropriated under such subsection between the preceding fiscal year and the fiscal year involved.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall reserve funds appropriated under subsection (h) to make a grant to the protection and advocacy system serving the American Indian Consortium to provide services in accordance with this section. The amount of such a grant shall be the same amount as is provided to a territory under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7dae9f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> In this subparagraph:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daea0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The term “American Indian Consortium” has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15002">42 U.S.C. 15002</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daea1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The term “protection and advocacy system” means a protection and advocacy system established under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7daea2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> For any fiscal year for which the amount appropriated under subsection (h) equals or exceeds $14,000,000, the Secretary may reserve not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2.2 percent of such amount to provide a grant for training and technical assistance for the programs established under this section. Such training and technical assistance shall be coordinated with activities provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/1/A">section 794e(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7daea3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of an allotment to a State for a fiscal year which the Secretary determines will not be required by the State during the period for which it is available for the purpose for which allotted shall be available for reallotment by the Secretary at appropriate times to other States with respect to which such a determination has not been made, in proportion to the original allotments of such States for such fiscal year, but with such proportionate amount for any of such other States being reduced to the extent it exceeds the sum the Secretary estimates such State needs and will be able to use during such period, and the total of such reduction shall be similarly reallotted among the States whose proportionate amounts were not so reduced. Any such amount so reallotted to a State for a fiscal year shall be deemed to be a part of its allotment for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a7daea4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Except as specifically prohibited by or as otherwise provided in State law, the Secretary shall pay to the agency designated under subsection (c) the amount specified in the application approved under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7daea5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Application by State for grant funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No grant may be made under this section unless the State submits an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary deems necessary to meet the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7daea6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations; minimum requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations applicable to the client assistance program which shall include the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daea7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No employees of such programs shall, while so employed, serve as staff or consultants of any rehabilitation project, program, or facility receiving assistance under this chapter in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daea8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each program shall be afforded reasonable access to policymaking and administrative personnel in the State and local rehabilitation programs, projects, or facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daea9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeaa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each program shall contain provisions designed to assure that to the maximum extent possible alternative means of dispute resolution are available for use at the discretion of an applicant or client of the program prior to resorting to litigation or formal adjudication to resolve a dispute arising under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeab-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In subparagraph (A), the term “alternative means of dispute resolution” means any procedure, including good faith negotiation, conciliation, facilitation, mediation, factfinding, and arbitration, and any combination of procedures, that is used in lieu of litigation in a court or formal adjudication in an administrative forum, to resolve a dispute arising under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeac-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For purposes of any periodic audit, report, or evaluation of the performance of a client assistance program under this section, the Secretary shall not require such a program to disclose the identity of, or any other personally identifiable information related to, any individual requesting assistance under such program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a7daead-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeae-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> $12,000,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeaf-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> $12,927,000 for fiscal year 2016;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeb0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> $13,195,000 for fiscal year 2017;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeb1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> $13,488,000 for fiscal year 2018;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeb2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> $13,805,000 for fiscal year 2019; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a7daeb3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s732/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> $14,098,000 for fiscal year 2020.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a7daeb4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tI/s112">Pub. L. 93–112, title I, § 112</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1163">112 Stat. 1163</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s402/b/9">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 402(b)(9)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–413; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 113–128, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1656">128 Stat. 1656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a7daeb5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a7daeb6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a7daeb7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 12111 et seq.) of chapter 126 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000, referred to in subsec. (e)(1)(E)(ii)(II), is <ref href="/us/pl/106/402">Pub. L. 106–402</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1677">114 Stat. 1677</ref>. Subtitle C of title I of the Act is classified generally to part C (§ 15041 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 144 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15001">section 15001 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id5a7daeb8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior sections 732 and 740 were omitted in the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 732, <ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tI/s112">Pub. L. 93–112, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/371">87 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/516/tI">Pub. L. 93–516, title I</ref>, §§ 102(b), 111(f), <date date="1974-12-07">Dec. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1618">88 Stat. 1618</ref>, 1620; <ref href="/us/pl/93/651/tI">Pub. L. 93–651, title I</ref>, §§ 102(b), 111(f), <date date="1974-11-21">Nov. 21, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/2-3">89 Stat. 2–3</ref>, 2–5; <ref href="/us/pl/94/230">Pub. L. 94–230</ref>, §§ 2(b), 11(b)(4), <date date="1976-03-15">Mar. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/211">90 Stat. 211</ref>, 213; <ref href="/us/pl/95/602/tI">Pub. L. 95–602, title I</ref>, §§ 105, 122(b)(1), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2960">92 Stat. 2960</ref>, 2987; <ref href="/us/pl/97/375/tI/s105">Pub. L. 97–375, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1820">96 Stat. 1820</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/221/tI/s113/a">Pub. L. 98–221, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/20">98 Stat. 20</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/506/tI/s103/d/2/C">Pub. L. 99–506, title I, § 103(d)(2)(C)</ref>, title II, § 209, title X, § 1001(b)(7), <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1810">100 Stat. 1810</ref>, 1818, 1842; <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/tII/s202/f">Pub. L. 100–630, title II, § 202(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3306">102 Stat. 3306</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/52/s2/c">Pub. L. 102–52, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-06">June 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/260">105 Stat. 260</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/tI">Pub. L. 102–569, title I</ref>, §§ 102(p)(10), 133, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4357">106 Stat. 4357</ref>, 4391; <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/tI/s107/g">Pub. L. 103–73, title I, § 107(g)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/723">107 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1041/c">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1041(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/714">109 Stat. 714</ref>, related to client assistance program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 740, <ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tI/s120">Pub. L. 93–112, title I, § 120</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/tI/s134/a">Pub. L. 102–569, title I, § 134(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4392">106 Stat. 4392</ref>, related to State eligibility for grants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 740, <ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tI/s120">Pub. L. 93–112, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/372">87 Stat. 372</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/602/tI">Pub. L. 95–602, title I</ref>, §§ 101(e)(1), 122(b)(1), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2957">92 Stat. 2957</ref>, 2987; <ref href="/us/pl/99/506/tX/s1001/b/8">Pub. L. 99–506, title X, § 1001(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1842">100 Stat. 1842</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/tII/s202/g">Pub. L. 100–630, title II, § 202(g)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3306">102 Stat. 3306</ref>, provided for State allotments to assist in meeting the cost of vocational rehabilitation services, prior to the general amendment of part C of former subchapter I of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/102/569">Pub. L. 102–569</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a7daeb9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s421/1">Pub. L. 113–128, § 421(1)</ref>, inserted “including under sections 733 and 794g of this title,” after “all available benefits under this chapter,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s421/2">Pub. L. 113–128, § 421(2)</ref>, struck out “not later than <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>,” after “has in effect” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s421/3/A">Pub. L. 113–128, § 421(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “After reserving funds under subparagraphs (E) and (F), the Secretary shall allot the remainder of” for “The Secretary shall allot”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s421/3/B">Pub. L. 113–128, § 421(3)(B)</ref>, added subpars. (E) and (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s421/4">Pub. L. 113–128, § 421(4)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which authorized appropriations for fiscal years 1999 through 2003.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> made technical amendment to section designation and catchline in original.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
