<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a84d97b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a"><num value="762a">§ 762a.</num><heading> Research and demonstration projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a84d97c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple and interrelated service needs of individuals with handicaps; report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized to make grants to, and to enter into contract with, public and nonprofit agencies and organizations for the purpose of research and demonstration projects specifically designed to address the multiple and interrelated service needs of individuals with handicaps, the elderly, and children, youths, adults, and families. A report evaluating each project funded under this section shall be submitted to appropriate committees of the Congress within four months after the date each such project is completed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a84d97d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No funds other than those appropriated pursuant to this subsection can be used for the conduct of research specifically authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a84d97e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Study on impact of vocational rehabilitation services; transmittal to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after the date appropriations are made under subsection (b) for purposes of research and demonstration projects under subsection (a), the Secretary shall prepare and transmit to the Congress a study concerning the impact of vocational rehabilitation services provided under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.] on recipients of disability payments under titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq., 1381 et seq.]. The study shall examine the relationship between the vocational rehabilitation services provided under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the programs under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422">42 U.S.C. 422</ref>, 1382d], and shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a84d97f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an analysis of the savings in disability benefit payments under titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act as a result of the provision of vocational rehabilitation services under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a84d980-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a specification of the rate of return to the active labor force by recipients of services under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a84d981-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a specification of the total amount of expenditures, in the five fiscal years preceding the date of submission of the report, for vocational rehabilitation services under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act, and recommendations for the coordinated presentation of such expenditures in the Budget submitted by the President pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a84d982-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s762a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> recommendations to improve the coordination of services under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 with programs under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act, including recommendations for increasing savings in disability benefits payments and the rate of return to the active labor force by recipients of services under sections 222 and 1615 of the Social Security Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a84d983-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/602/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 95–602, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3002">92 Stat. 3002</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/221/tI/s104/c/1">Pub. L. 98–221, title I, § 104(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-02-22">Feb. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/18">98 Stat. 18</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/506/tI/s103/d/2/C">Pub. L. 99–506, title I, § 103(d)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1810">100 Stat. 1810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a84d984-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a84d985-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a84d986-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/112">Pub. L. 93–112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 701 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">section 701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, as amended. Titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act are classified generally to subchapters II (§ 401 et seq.) and XVI (§ 1381 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5a84d987-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c)(3), “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>” was substituted for “section 201 of the Budget and Accounting Act, 1921 [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s11">31 U.S.C. 11</ref>]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Rehabilitation, Comprehensive Services, and Developmental Disabilities Amendments of 1978, and not as part of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a84d988-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/506">Pub. L. 99–506</ref> substituted “individuals with handicaps” for “handicapped individuals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/221">Pub. L. 98–221</ref> substituted “Secretary of Education” for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
