<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a97ed06-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793"><num value="793">§ 793.</num><heading> Employment under Federal contracts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a97ed07-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of contracts or subcontracts; provision for employment and advancement of qualified individuals with disabilities; regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any contract in excess of $10,000 entered into by any Federal department or agency for the procurement of personal property and nonpersonal services (including construction) for the United States shall contain a provision requiring that the party contracting with the United States shall take affirmative action to employ and advance in employment qualified individuals with disabilities. The provisions of this section shall apply to any subcontract in excess of $10,000 entered into by a prime contractor in carrying out any contract for the procurement of personal property and nonpersonal services (including construction) for the United States. The President shall implement the provisions of this section by promulgating regulations within ninety days after <date date="1973-09-26">September 26, 1973</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a97ed08-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative enforcement; complaints; investigations; departmental action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any individual with a disability believes any contractor has failed or refused to comply with the provisions of a contract with the United States, relating to employment of individuals with disabilities, such individual may file a complaint with the Department of Labor. The Department shall promptly investigate such complaint and shall take such action thereon as the facts and circumstances warrant, consistent with the terms of such contract and the laws and regulations applicable thereto.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a97ed09-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver by President; national interest special circumstances for waiver of particular agreements; waiver by Secretary of Labor of affirmative action requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a97ed0a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The requirements of this section may be waived, in whole or in part, by the President with respect to a particular contract or subcontract, in accordance with guidelines set forth in regulations which the President shall prescribe, when the President determines that special circumstances in the national interest so require and states in writing the reasons for such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a97ed0b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a97ed0c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Labor may waive the requirements of the affirmative action clause required by regulations promulgated under subsection (a) with respect to any of a prime contractor’s or subcontractor’s facilities that are found to be in all respects separate and distinct from activities of the prime contractor or subcontractor related to the performance of the contract or subcontract, if the Secretary of Labor also finds that such a waiver will not interfere with or impede the effectuation of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5a97ed0d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such waivers shall be considered only upon the request of the contractor or subcontractor. The Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations that set forth the standards used for granting such a waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a97ed0e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards used in determining violation of section</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The standards used to determine whether this section has been violated in a complaint alleging nonaffirmative action employment discrimination under this section shall be the standards applied under title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12111">42 U.S.C. 12111</ref> et seq.) and the provisions of sections 501 through 504, and 510,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002058"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12201–122">42 U.S.C. 12201–122</ref>04 and 12210), as such sections relate to employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a97ed0f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s793/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Avoidance of duplicative efforts and inconsistencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop procedures to ensure that administrative complaints filed under this section and under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.] are dealt with in a manner that avoids duplication of effort and prevents imposition of inconsistent or conflicting standards for the same requirements under this section and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a97ed10-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tV/s503">Pub. L. 93–112, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/393">87 Stat. 393</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/602/tI/s122/d/1">Pub. L. 95–602, title I, § 122(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2987">92 Stat. 2987</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/506/tI/s103/d/2/B">Pub. L. 99–506, title I, § 103(d)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), title X, §§ 1001(f)(2), (3), 1002(e)(3), <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1810">100 Stat. 1810</ref>, 1843, 1844; <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/tII/s206/c">Pub. L. 100–630, title II, § 206(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3312">102 Stat. 3312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/tI/s102/p/31">Pub. L. 102–569, title I, § 102(p)(31)</ref>, title V, § 505, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4360">106 Stat. 4360</ref>, 4427.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a97ed11-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a97ed12-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a97ed13-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in subsecs. (d) and (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 126 (§ 12101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 12111 et seq.) of chapter 126 of Title 42. Section 510 of the Act was renumbered section 511 by <ref href="/us/pl/110/325/s6/a/2">Pub. L. 110–325, § 6(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-09-25">Sept. 25, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3558">122 Stat. 3558</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a97ed14-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/569">Pub. L. 102–569</ref>, §§ 102(p)(31)(A), 505(a), substituted “$10,000” for “$2,500” in two places, struck out “, in employing persons to carry out such contract,” after “contain a provision requiring that”, and substituted “individuals with disabilities” for “individuals with handicaps as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s706/8">section 706(8) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/s102/p/31/B">Pub. L. 102–569, § 102(p)(31)(B)</ref>, substituted “individual with a disability” for “individual with handicaps” and “individuals with disabilities” for “individuals with handicaps”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/s505/b">Pub. L. 102–569, § 505(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/s505/c">Pub. L. 102–569, § 505(c)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/s206/c/1">Pub. L. 100–630, § 206(c)(1)</ref>, inserted a comma after “to carry out such contract”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/s206/c/2">Pub. L. 100–630, § 206(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “refused” for “refuses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/s206/c/3">Pub. L. 100–630, § 206(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “which the President” for “which The President” and “when the President” for “when The President”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/506">Pub. L. 99–506</ref>, §§ 103(d)(2)(C), 1002(e)(3), substituted “individuals with handicaps” for “handicapped individuals” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s706/8">section 706(8) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s706/7">section 706(7) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/506">Pub. L. 99–506</ref>, §§ 103(d)(2)(B), (C), 1001(f)(2), substituted “individual with handicaps” for “handicapped individual”, “individuals with handicaps” for “handicapped individuals”, and “a contract” for “his contract”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/506/s1001/f/3">Pub. L. 99–506, § 1001(f)(3)</ref>, substituted “The President” for “he” in two places and substituted “the reasons” for “his reasons”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/602">Pub. L. 95–602</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s706/7">section 706(7) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s706/6">section 706(6) of this title</ref>”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
