<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5a9a5d97-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e"><num value="794e">§ 794e.</num><heading> Protection and advocacy of individual rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5d98-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose and construction</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5d99-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The purpose of this section is to support a system in each State to protect the legal and human rights of individuals with disabilities who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5d9a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> need services that are beyond the scope of services authorized to be provided by the client assistance program under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s732">section 732 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5d9b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5d9c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are ineligible for protection and advocacy programs under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.] because the individuals do not have a developmental disability, as defined in section 102 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15002">42 U.S.C. 15002</ref>]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5d9d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are ineligible for services under the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002060"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10801">42 U.S.C. 10801</ref> et seq.) because the individuals are not individuals with mental illness, as defined in section 102 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10802">42 U.S.C. 10802</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5d9e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This section shall not be construed to require the provision of protection and advocacy services that can be provided under the Assistive Technology Act of 1998 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3001">29 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5d9f-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriations less than $5,500,000</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section is less than $5,500,000, the Commissioner may make grants from such amount to eligible systems within States to plan for, develop outreach strategies for, and carry out protection and advocacy programs authorized under this section for individuals with disabilities who meet the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriations of $5,500,000 or more</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section equals or exceeds $5,500,000, the Commissioner shall set aside not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2.2 percent of the amount to provide a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for training and technical assistance to the systems established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant for the eligible system serving the American Indian consortium</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section equals or exceeds $10,500,000, the Commissioner shall reserve a portion, and use the portion to make a grant for the eligible system serving the American Indian consortium. The Commission shall make the grant in an amount of not less than $50,000 for the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For any such fiscal year, after the reservations required by paragraph (1) have been made, the Commissioner shall make allotments from the remainder of such amount in accordance with paragraph (3) to eligible systems within States to enable such systems to carry out protection and advocacy programs authorized under this section for individuals referred to in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Systems within States</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Population basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), from such remainder for each such fiscal year, the Commissioner shall make an allotment to the eligible system within a State of an amount bearing the same ratio to such remainder as the population of the State bears to the population of all States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimums</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this section, and except as provided in paragraph (4), the allotment to any system under subparagraph (A) shall be not less than $100,000 or ⅓ of 1 percent of the remainder for the fiscal year for which the allotment is made, whichever is greater, and the allotment to any system under this section for any fiscal year that is less than $100,000 or ⅓ of 1 percent of such remainder shall be increased to the greater of the two amounts.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Systems within other jurisdictions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5da9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For the purposes of paragraph (3)(B), Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall not be considered to be States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5daa-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The eligible system within a jurisdiction described in subparagraph (A) shall be allotted under paragraph (3)(A) not less than $50,000 for the fiscal year for which the allotment is made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dab-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment for inflation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For any fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 1999, in which the total amount appropriated to carry out this section exceeds the total amount appropriated to carry out this section for the preceding fiscal year, the Commissioner shall increase each of the minimum grants or allotments under paragraphs (1)(B), (3)(B), and (4)(B) by a percentage that shall not exceed the percentage increase in the total amount appropriated to carry out this section between the preceding fiscal year and the fiscal year involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dac-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Proportional reduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To provide minimum allotments to systems within States (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(3)(B), or to provide minimum allotments to systems within States (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(4)(B), the Commissioner shall proportionately reduce the allotments of the remaining systems within States under subsection (c)(3), with such adjustments as may be necessary to prevent the allotment of any such remaining system within a State from being reduced to less than the minimum allotment for a system within a State (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(3)(B), or the minimum allotment for a State (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(4)(B), as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dad-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reallotment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Commissioner determines that any amount of an allotment to a system within a State for any fiscal year described in subsection (c)(1) will not be expended by such system in carrying out the provisions of this section, the Commissioner shall make such amount available for carrying out the provisions of this section to one or more of the systems that the Commissioner determines will be able to use additional amounts during such year for carrying out such provisions. Any amount made available to a system for any fiscal year pursuant to the preceding sentence shall, for the purposes of this section, be regarded as an increase in the allotment of the system (as determined under the preceding provisions of this section) for such year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dae-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to receive assistance under this section, an eligible system shall submit an application to the Commissioner, at such time, in such form and manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Commissioner determines necessary to meet the requirements of this section, including assurances that the eligible system will—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5daf-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> have in effect a system to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> have the same general authorities, including the authority to access records and program income, as are set forth in subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> have the authority to pursue legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies or approaches to ensure the protection of, and advocacy for, the rights of such individuals within the State or the American Indian consortium who are individuals described in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide information on and make referrals to programs and services addressing the needs of individuals with disabilities in the State or the American Indian consortium;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> develop a statement of objectives and priorities on an annual basis, and provide to the public, including individuals with disabilities and, as appropriate, the individuals’ representatives, an opportunity to comment on the objectives and priorities established by, and activities of, the system including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5db4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the objectives and priorities for the activities of the system for each year and the rationale for the establishment of such objectives and priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5a9a5db5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the coordination of programs provided through the system under this section with the advocacy programs of the client assistance program under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s732">section 732 of this title</ref>, the State long-term care ombudsman program established under the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">42 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.), the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15001">42 U.S.C. 15001</ref> et seq.], and the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 <sup>1</sup> (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10801">42 U.S.C. 10801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> establish a grievance procedure for clients or prospective clients of the system to ensure that individuals with disabilities are afforded equal opportunity to access the services of the system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5a9a5db7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/f/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> provide assurances to the Commissioner that funds made available under this section will be used to supplement and not supplant the non-Federal funds that would otherwise be made available for the purpose for which Federal funds are provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5db8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover and direct payment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5db9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commissioner shall pay directly to any system that complies with the provisions of this section, the amount of the allotment of the State or the grant for the eligible system that serves the American Indian consortium involved under this section, unless the State or American Indian consortium provides otherwise.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dba-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any amount paid to an eligible system that serves a State or American Indian consortium for a fiscal year that remains unobligated at the end of such year shall remain available to such system that serves the State or American Indian consortium for obligation during the next fiscal year for the purposes for which such amount was paid.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dbb-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on disclosure requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of any audit, report, or evaluation of the performance of the program established under this section, the Commissioner shall not require such a program to disclose the identity of, or any other personally identifiable information related to, any individual requesting assistance under such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dbc-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative cost</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any State in which an eligible system is located within a State agency, a State may use a portion of any allotment under subsection (c) for the cost of the administration of the system required by this section. Such portion may not exceed 5 percent of the allotment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dbd-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner may delegate the administration of this program to the Commissioner of the Administration on Developmental Disabilities within the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dbe-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner shall annually prepare and submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate a report describing the types of services and activities being undertaken by programs funded under this section, the total number of individuals served under this section, the types of disabilities represented by such individuals, and the types of issues being addressed on behalf of such individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dbf-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $17,650,000 for fiscal year 2015, $19,013,000 for fiscal year 2016, $19,408,000 for fiscal year 2017, $19,838,000 for fiscal year 2018, $20,305,000 for fiscal year 2019, and $20,735,000 for fiscal year 2020.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dc0-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dc1-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/m/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “eligible system” means a protection and advocacy system that is established under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15041">42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.] and that meets the requirements of subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id5a9a5dc2-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s794e/m/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> American Indian consortium</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “American Indian consortium” means a consortium established as described in section 142 <sup>1</sup> of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6042">42 U.S.C. 6042</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5a9a5dc3-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tV/s509">Pub. L. 93–112, title V, § 509</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/569/tV/s510/a">Pub. L. 102–569, title V, § 510(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4430">106 Stat. 4430</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/tI/s112/c">Pub. L. 103–73, title I, § 112(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/727">107 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/12/s9/n">Pub. L. 105–12, § 9(n)</ref>, <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/28">111 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tIV/s408/c">Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 408(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1206">112 Stat. 1206</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/394/tIV/s402/c">Pub. L. 105–394, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3662">112 Stat. 3662</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/tIV/s401/b/3/C">Pub. L. 106–402, title IV, § 401(b)(3)(C)</ref>, (D), <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1738">114 Stat. 1738</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tIV/s457">Pub. L. 113–128, title IV, § 457</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1676">128 Stat. 1676</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5a9a5dc4-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5a9a5dc5-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5a9a5dc6-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(B)(i), (f)(2), (5)(B), and (m)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/106/402">Pub. L. 106–402</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1677">114 Stat. 1677</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 144 (§ 15001 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Subtitle C of title I of the Act is classified generally to part C (§ 15041 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 144 of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15001">section 15001 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(B)(ii) and (f)(5)(B), was <ref href="/us/pl/99/319">Pub. L. 99–319</ref>, <date date="1986-05-23">May 23, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/478">100 Stat. 478</ref>, as amended. <ref href="/us/pl/99/319">Pub. L. 99–319</ref> was renamed the Protection and Advocacy for Individuals with Mental Illness Act by <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXII/s3206/a">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1193">114 Stat. 1193</ref>, and is classified generally to chapter 114 (§ 10801 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10801">section 10801 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Assistive Technology Act of 1998, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/105/394">Pub. L. 105–394</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3627">112 Stat. 3627</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 31 (§ 3001 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Older Americans Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (f)(5)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/73">Pub. L. 89–73</ref>, <date date="1965-07-14">July 14, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/218">79 Stat. 218</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 3001 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 142 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6042">42 U.S.C. 6042</ref>), referred to in subsec. (m)(2), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 106–402, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1737">114 Stat. 1737</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5a9a5dc7-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s457/1">Pub. L. 113–128, § 457(1)</ref>, inserted “a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for” before “training”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s457/2">Pub. L. 113–128, § 457(2)</ref>, substituted “general authorities, including the authority to access records” for “general authorities, including access to records” and inserted “of title I” after “subtitle C”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s457/3">Pub. L. 113–128, § 457(3)</ref>, substituted “$17,650,000 for fiscal year 2015, $19,013,000 for fiscal year 2016, $19,408,000 for fiscal year 2017, $19,838,000 for fiscal year 2018, $20,305,000 for fiscal year 2019, and $20,735,000 for fiscal year 2020.” for “such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1999 through 2003.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (a)(1)(B)(i), (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/s401/b/3/C">Pub. L. 106–402, § 401(b)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000” for “part C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6041">42 U.S.C. 6041</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/s401/b/3/D">Pub. L. 106–402, § 401(b)(3)(D)</ref>, substituted “Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000” for “Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6000">42 U.S.C. 6000</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/s401/b/3/C">Pub. L. 106–402, § 401(b)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000” for “part C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6041">42 U.S.C. 6041</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text consisted of subsecs. (a) to (n) relating to protection and advocacy of individual rights.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/394">Pub. L. 105–394</ref> substituted “the Assistive Technology Act of 1998” for “the Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201">42 U.S.C. 2201</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (f)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/105/12">Pub. L. 105–12</ref> added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “are ineligible for client assistance programs under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s732">section 732 of this title</ref>; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/2">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) <inline class="small-caps">Allotments</inline>.—For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section is less than $5,500,000, the Commissioner may make grants from such amount to eligible systems within States to plan for, develop outreach strategies for, and carry out protection and advocacy programs authorized under this section for individuals with disabilities who meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Other jurisdictions</inline>.—For the purposes of this subsection, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Republic of Palau shall not be considered to be States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/3/A/i">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (3)(B)” for “this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “allotted under paragraph (3)(A)” for “allotted”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/3/B">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(3)(B)</ref>, added par. (5) and struck out heading and text of former par. (5). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) <inline class="small-caps">States</inline>.—For purposes of determining the minimum amount of an allotment under paragraph (3)(B), the amount $100,000 shall, in the case of such allotments for fiscal year 1994 and subsequent fiscal years, be increased to the extent necessary to offset the effects of inflation occurring since October 1992, as measured by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index For All Urban Consumers (U.S. city average) during the period ending on April 1 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the allotment is to be made.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Certain territories</inline>.—For purposes of determining the minimum amount of an allotment under paragraph (4)(B), the amount $50,000 shall, in the case of such allotments for fiscal year 1994 and subsequent fiscal years, be increased to the extent necessary to offset the effects of inflation occurring since October 1992, as measured by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index For All Urban Consumers (U.S. city average) during the period ending on April 1 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the allotment is to be made.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/4">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (d). Text read as follows: “Amounts necessary to provide allotments to systems within States in accordance with subsection (c)(3)(B) as increased under subsection (c)(5), or to provide allotments in accordance with subsection (c)(4)(B) as increased in accordance with subsection (c)(5), shall be derived by proportionately reducing the allotments of the remaining systems within States under subsection (c)(3), but with such adjustments as may be necessary to prevent the allotment of any such remaining systems within States from being thereby reduced to less than the greater of $100,000 or one-third of one percent of the sums made available for purposes of this section for the fiscal year for which the allotment is made, as increased in accordance with subsection (c)(5).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/6">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(6)</ref>, which directed the amendment of this section “in subsection (i), to read as follows:”, was executed by adding subsec. (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/7">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(7)</ref>, added subsec. (j) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (j). Text read as follows: “An eligible system may not use more than 5 percent of any allotment under subsection (c) for the cost of administration of the system required by this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s112/c/5">Pub. L. 103–73, § 112(c)(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (n).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5a9ca7b8-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id5a9ca7b9-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Labor and Human Resources of Senate changed to Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of Senate by Senate Resolution No. 20, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-19">Jan. 19, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5a9ca7ba-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/12">Pub. L. 105–12</ref> effective <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, applicable to Federal payments made pursuant to obligations incurred after <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, for items and services provided on or after such date, and also applicable with respect to contracts entered into, renewed, or extended after <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, as well as contracts entered into before <date date="1997-04-30">Apr. 30, 1997</date>, to the extent permitted under such contracts, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/12/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 105–12</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14401">section 14401 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
