<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5aa1634a-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s796e–0"><num value="796e–0">§ 796e–0.</num><heading> Training and technical assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5aa1634b-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s796e–0/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation of funds for training and technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">From the funds appropriated and made available to carry out this subpart for any fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2015, the Administrator shall first reserve not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2 percent of the funds to provide, either directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements, training and technical assistance to Statewide Independent Living Councils established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s796d">section 796d of this title</ref> for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5aa1634c-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s796e–0/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Survey of Statewide Independent Living Councils</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct a survey of such Statewide Independent Living Councils regarding training and technical assistance needs in order to determine funding priorities for such training and technical assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id5aa1634d-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c" identifier="/us/usc/t29/s796e–0/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of application; peer review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, containing a proposal to provide such training and technical assistance, and containing such additional information, as the Administrator may require. The Administrator shall provide for peer review of applications by panels that include persons who are not government employees and who have experience in the operation of such Statewide Independent Living Councils.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id5aa1634e-3a70-11f1-8704-e0e66b400d7c">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tVII/s711A">Pub. L. 93–112, title VII, § 711A</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tIV/s476/b">Pub. L. 113–128, title IV, § 476(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1690">128 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
