<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcaee1b59-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706"><num value="11706">§ 11706.</num><heading> Liability of rail carriers under receipts and bills of lading</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b5a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> A rail carrier providing transportation or service subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part shall issue a receipt or bill of lading for property it receives for transportation under this part. That rail carrier and any other carrier that delivers the property and is providing transportation or service subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part are liable to the person entitled to recover under the receipt or bill of lading. The liability imposed under this subsection is for the actual loss or injury to the property caused by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b5b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the receiving rail carrier;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b5c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the delivering rail carrier; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b5d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> another rail carrier over whose line or route the property is transported in the United States or from a place in the United States to a place in an adjacent foreign country when transported under a through bill of lading.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Failure to issue a receipt or bill of lading does not affect the liability of a rail carrier. A delivering rail carrier is deemed to be the rail carrier performing the line-haul transportation nearest the destination but does not include a rail carrier providing only a switching service at the destination.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b5e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The rail carrier issuing the receipt or bill of lading under subsection (a) of this section or delivering the property for which the receipt or bill of lading was issued is entitled to recover from the rail carrier over whose line or route the loss or injury occurred the amount required to be paid to the owners of the property, as evidenced by a receipt, judgment, or transcript, and the amount of its expenses reasonably incurred in defending a civil action brought by that person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b5f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b60-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A rail carrier may not limit or be exempt from liability imposed under subsection (a) of this section except as provided in this subsection. A limitation of liability or of the amount of recovery or representation or agreement in a receipt, bill of lading, contract, or rule in violation of this section is void.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b61-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A rail carrier of passengers may limit its liability under its passenger rate for loss or injury of baggage carried on trains carrying passengers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b62-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A rail carrier providing transportation or service subject to the jurisdiction of the Board under this part may establish rates for transportation of property under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b63-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the liability of the rail carrier for such property is limited to a value established by written declaration of the shipper or by a written agreement between the shipper and the carrier; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b64-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> specified amounts are deducted, pursuant to a written agreement between the shipper and the carrier, from any claim against the carrier with respect to the transportation of such property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b65-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b66-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A civil action under this section may be brought in a district court of the United States or in a State court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b67-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b68-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A civil action under this section may only be brought—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b69-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> against the originating rail carrier, in the judicial district in which the point of origin is located;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b6a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> against the delivering rail carrier, in the judicial district in which the principal place of business of the person bringing the action is located if the delivering carrier operates a railroad or a route through such judicial district, or in the judicial district in which the point of destination is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b6b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> against the carrier alleged to have caused the loss or damage, in the judicial district in which such loss or damage is alleged to have occurred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b6c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In this section, “judicial district” means (i) in the case of a United States district court, a judicial district of the United States, and (ii) in the case of a State court, the applicable geographic area over which such court exercises jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcaee1b6d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> A rail carrier may not provide by rule, contract, or otherwise, a period of less than 9 months for filing a claim against it under this section and a period of less than 2 years for bringing a civil action against it under this section. The period for bringing a civil action is computed from the date the carrier gives a person written notice that the carrier has disallowed any part of the claim specified in the notice. For the purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b6e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an offer of compromise shall not constitute a disallowance of any part of the claim unless the carrier, in writing, informs the claimant that such part of the claim is disallowed and provides reasons for such disallowance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcaee1b6f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s11706/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> communications received from a carrier’s insurer shall not constitute a disallowance of any part of the claim unless the insurer, in writing, informs the claimant that such part of the claim is disallowed, provides reasons for such disallowance, and informs the claimant that the insurer is acting on behalf of the carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcaee1b70-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/847">109 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcaee1b71-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcaee1b72-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idcaee1b73-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s11707">section 11707 of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of this subtitle by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 11706, <ref href="/us/pl/95/473">Pub. L. 95–473</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1452">92 Stat. 1452</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s3/n">Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(n)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1066">96 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/521/s12/c">Pub. L. 99–521, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2998">100 Stat. 2998</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/180/s3">Pub. L. 103–180, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-12-03">Dec. 3, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2049">107 Stat. 2049</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/429/s6/18">Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(18)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4379">108 Stat. 4379</ref>, related to limitation on actions by and against common carriers, prior to the general amendment of this subtitle by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, § 102(a)</ref>. See sections 11705, 14705, and 15905 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcaf08b74-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcaf08b75-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
