<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcafee3c3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303"><num value="14303">§ 14303.</num><heading> Consolidation, merger, and acquisition of control of motor carriers of passengers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3c4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approval Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The following transactions involving motor carriers of passengers subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 may be carried out only with the approval of the Board:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3c5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Consolidation or merger of the properties or franchises of at least 2 carriers into one operation for the ownership, management, and operation of the previously separately owned properties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3c6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A purchase, lease, or contract to operate property of another carrier by any number of carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3c7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Acquisition of control of a carrier by any number of carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3c8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Acquisition of control of at least 2 carriers by a person that is not a carrier.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3c9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Acquisition of control of a carrier by a person that is not a carrier but that controls any number of carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3ca-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standard for Approval</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Board shall approve and authorize a transaction under this section when it finds the transaction is consistent with the public interest. The Board shall consider at least the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3cb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The effect of the proposed transaction on the adequacy of transportation to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3cc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The total fixed charges that result from the proposed transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcafee3cd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The interest of carrier employees affected by the proposed transaction.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Board may impose conditions governing the transaction.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3ce-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of Completeness of Application</inline>.—</heading><content>Within 30 days after the date on which an application is filed under this section, the Board shall either publish a notice of the application in the Federal Register or reject the application if it is incomplete.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3cf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comments</inline>.—</heading><content>Written comments about an application may be filed with the Board within 45 days after the date on which notice of the application is published under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadlines</inline>.—</heading><content>The Board shall conclude evidentiary proceedings by the 240th day after the date on which notice of the application is published under subsection (c). The Board shall issue a final decision by the 180th day after the conclusion of the evidentiary proceedings. The Board may extend a time period under this subsection; except that the total of all such extensions with respect to any application shall not exceed 90 days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Approval</inline>.—</heading><content>A carrier or corporation participating in or resulting from a transaction approved by the Board under this section, or exempted by the Board from the application of this section pursuant to section 13541, may carry out the transaction, own and operate property, and exercise control or franchises acquired through the transaction without the approval of a State authority. A carrier, corporation, or person participating in the approved or exempted transaction is exempt from the antitrust laws and from all other law, including State and municipal law, as necessary to let that person carry out the transaction, hold, maintain, and operate property, and exercise control or franchises acquired through the transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall not apply to transactions involving carriers whose aggregate gross operating revenues were not more than $2,000,000 during a period of 12 consecutive months ending not more than 6 months before the date of the agreement of the parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Certain Provisions</inline>.—</heading><content>When the Board approves and authorizes a transaction under this section in which a person not a carrier providing transportation subject to jurisdiction under subchapter I of chapter 135 acquires control of at least 1 carrier subject to such jurisdiction, the person is subject, as a carrier, to the following provisions of this title that apply to the carrier being acquired by that person, to the extent specified by the Board: sections 504(f), 14121–14123, 14901(a), and 14907.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim Approval</inline>.—</heading><content>Pending determination of an application filed under this section, the Board may approve, for a period of not more than 180 days, the operation of the properties sought to be acquired by the person proposing in the application to acquire those properties, when it appears that failure to do so may result in destruction of or injury to those properties or substantially interfere with their future usefulness in providing adequate and continuous service to the public. Transportation provided by a motor carrier under a grant of approval under this subsection is subject to this part.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcafee3d5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14303/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Orders</inline>.—</heading><content>When cause exists, the Board may issue appropriate orders supplemental to an order made in a proceeding under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcafee3d6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tI/s103">Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/897">109 Stat. 897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcafee3d7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcafee3d8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idcafee3d9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 11341, 11343, 11344, 11345a, 11348, 11349, and 11351 of this title prior to the general amendment of this subtitle by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcafee3da-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcafee3db-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
