<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcb039e02-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704"><num value="14704">§ 14704.</num><heading> Rights and remedies of persons injured by carriers or brokers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb039e03-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e04-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of order</inline>.—</heading><content>A person injured because a carrier or broker providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 does not obey an order of the Secretary or the Board, as applicable, under this part, except an order for the payment of money, may bring a civil action to enforce that order under this subsection. A person may bring a civil action for injunctive relief for violations of sections 14102, 14103, and 14915(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e05-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Damages for violations</inline>.—</heading><content>A carrier or broker providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 is liable for damages sustained by a person as a result of an act or omission of that carrier or broker in violation of this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb039e06-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Liability and Damages for Exceeding Tariff Rate</inline>.—</heading><content>A carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 is liable to a person for amounts charged that exceed the applicable rate for transportation or service contained in a tariff in effect under section 13702.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb039e07-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Election.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e08-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Complaint to dot or board; civil action</inline>.—</heading><content>A person may file a complaint with the Board or the Secretary, as applicable, under section 14701(b) or bring a civil action under subsection (b) to enforce liability against a carrier or broker providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e09-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Order of dot or board.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcb039e0a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>When the Board or Secretary, as applicable, makes an award under subsection (b) of this section, the Board or Secretary, as applicable, shall order the carrier to pay the amount awarded by a specific date. The Board or Secretary, as applicable, may order a carrier or broker providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 to pay damages only when the proceeding is on complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcb039e0b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement by civil action</inline>.—</heading><content>The person for whose benefit an order of the Board or Secretary requiring the payment of money is made may bring a civil action to enforce that order under this paragraph if the carrier or broker does not pay the amount awarded by the date payment was ordered to be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb039e0c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedure.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e0d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>When a person begins a civil action under subsection (b) of this section to enforce an order of the Board or Secretary requiring the payment of damages by a carrier or broker providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 of this title, the text of the order of the Board or Secretary must be included in the complaint. In addition to the district courts of the United States, a State court of general jurisdiction having jurisdiction of the parties has jurisdiction to enforce an order under this paragraph. The findings and order of the Board or Secretary are competent evidence of the facts stated in them. Trial in a civil action brought in a district court of the United States under this paragraph is in the judicial district in which the plaintiff resides or in which the principal operating office of the carrier or broker is located. In a civil action under this paragraph, the plaintiff is liable for only those costs that accrue on an appeal taken by the plaintiff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb039e0e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Parties</inline>.—</heading><content>All parties in whose favor the award was made may be joined as plaintiffs in a civil action brought in a district court of the United States under this subsection and all the carriers that are parties to the order awarding damages may be joined as defendants. Trial in the action is in the judicial district in which any one of the plaintiffs could bring the action against any one of the defendants. Process may be served on a defendant at its principal operating office when that defendant is not in the district in which the action is brought. A judgment ordering recovery may be made in favor of any of those plaintiffs against the defendant found to be liable to that plaintiff.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb039e0f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s14704/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Attorney’s Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The district court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee under this section. The district court shall tax and collect that fee as part of the costs of the action.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcb039e10-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tI/s103">Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/905">109 Stat. 905</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tII/s32922/a">Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title II, § 32922(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/828">126 Stat. 828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcb039e11-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcb039e12-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idcb039e13-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s11705">section 11705 of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of this subtitle by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcb039e14-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> substituted “, 14103, and 14915(c)” for “and 14103”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcb039e15-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of Title 23</ref>, Highways.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcb039e16-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcb039e17-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
