<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcb11f684-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151"><num value="20151">§ 20151.</num><heading> Railroad trespassing, vandalism, and highway-rail grade crossing warning sign violation prevention strategy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb11f685-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation of Existing Laws</inline>.—</heading><content>In consultation with affected parties, the Secretary of Transportation shall evaluate and review current local, State, and Federal laws regarding trespassing on railroad property, vandalism affecting railroad safety, and violations of highway-rail grade crossing signs, signals, markings, or other warning devices and develop model prevention strategies and enforcement laws to be used for the consideration of State and local legislatures and governmental entities. The first such evaluation and review shall be completed within 1 year after the date of enactment of the Rail Safety Improvement Act of 2008. The Secretary shall revise the model prevention strategies and enforcement codes periodically.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb11f686-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach Program for Trespassing and Vandalism Prevention</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop and maintain a comprehensive outreach program to improve communications among Federal railroad safety inspectors, State inspectors certified by the Federal Railroad Administration, railroad police, and State and local law enforcement officers, for the purpose of addressing trespassing and vandalism problems on railroad property, and strengthening relevant enforcement strategies. This program shall be designed to increase public and police awareness of the illegality of, dangers inherent in, and the extent of, trespassing on railroad rights-of-way, to develop strategies to improve the prevention of trespassing and vandalism, and to improve the enforcement of laws relating to railroad trespass, vandalism, and safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb144077-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Model Legislation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb144078-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Within 18 months after <date date="1994-11-02">November 2, 1994</date>, the Secretary, after consultation with State and local governments and railroad carriers, shall develop and make available to State and local governments model State legislation providing for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb144079-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> civil or criminal penalties, or both, for vandalism of railroad equipment or property which could affect the safety of the public or of railroad employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb14407a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> civil or criminal penalties, or both, for trespassing on a railroad owned or leased right-of-way.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb14407b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the Rail Safety Improvement Act of 2008, the Secretary, after consultation with State and local governments and railroad carriers, shall develop and make available to State and local governments model State legislation providing for civil or criminal penalties, or both, for violations of highway-rail grade crossing signs, signals, markings, or other warning devices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb14407c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term “violation of highway-rail grade crossing signs, signals, markings, or other warning devices” includes any action by a motorist, unless directed by an authorized safety officer—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb14407d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to drive around a grade crossing gate in a position intended to block passage over railroad tracks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb14407e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to drive through a flashing grade crossing signal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb14407f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to drive through a grade crossing with passive warning signs without ensuring that the grade crossing could be safely crossed before any train arrived; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb144080-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20151/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the vicinity of a grade crossing, who creates a hazard of an accident involving injury or property damage at the grade crossing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcb144081-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/440/tII/s219/a">Pub. L. 103–440, title II, § 219(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4625">108 Stat. 4625</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s5/49">Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(49)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3393">110 Stat. 3393</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/dA/tII/s208/a">Pub. L. 110–432, div. A, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4875">122 Stat. 4875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcb144082-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcb144083-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcb144084-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Rail Safety Improvement Act of 2008, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c)(2), is the date of enactment of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/110/432">Pub. L. 110–432</ref>, which was approved <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcb144085-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/432/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 110–432, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Railroad trespassing, vandalism, and highway-rail grade crossing warning sign violation prevention strategy” for “Railroad trespassing and vandalism prevention strategy” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/s208/a/2">Pub. L. 110–432, § 208(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In consultation with affected parties, the Secretary of Transportation shall evaluate and review current local, State, and Federal laws regarding trespassing on railroad property and vandalism affecting railroad safety, and develop model prevention strategies and enforcement laws to be used for the consideration of State and local legislatures and governmental entities. The first such evaluation and review shall be completed within 1 year after <date date="1994-11-02">November 2, 1994</date>. The Secretary shall revise such model prevention strategies and enforcement codes periodically.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/s208/a/3">Pub. L. 110–432, § 208(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “for Trespassing and Vandalism Prevention” after “Outreach Program” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/s208/a/4">Pub. L. 110–432, § 208(a)(4)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, of par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/s208/a/5">Pub. L. 110–432, § 208(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/287">Pub. L. 104–287</ref> substituted “<date date="1994-11-02">November 2, 1994</date>” for “the date of enactment of the Federal Railroad Safety Authorization Act of 1994”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
