<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcb16b1b0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161"><num value="20161">§ 20161.</num><heading> Fostering introduction of new technology to improve safety at highway-rail grade crossings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb16b1b1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Collisions between highway users and trains at highway-rail grade crossings continue to cause an unacceptable loss of life, serious personal injury, and property damage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> While elimination of at-grade crossings through consolidation of crossings and grade separations offers the greatest long-term promise for optimizing the safety and efficiency of the two modes of transportation, over 140,000 public grade crossings remain on the general rail system—approximately one for each route mile on the general rail system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Conventional highway traffic control devices such as flashing lights and gates are often effective in warning motorists of a train’s approach to an equipped crossing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Since enactment of the Highway Safety Act of 1973, over $4,200,000,000 of Federal funding has been invested in safety improvements at highway-rail grade crossings, yet a majority of public highway-rail grade crossings are not yet equipped with active warning systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The emergence of new technologies presents opportunities for more effective and affordable warnings and safer passage of highway users and trains at remaining highway-rail grade crossings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Implementation of new crossing safety technology will require extensive cooperation between highway authorities and railroad carriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb16b1b8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Federal Railroad Administration regulations establishing performance standards for processor-based signal and train control systems provide a suitable framework for qualification of new or novel technology at highway-rail grade crossings, and the Federal Highway Administration’s Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices provides an appropriate means of determining highway user interface with such new technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb16b1b9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the policy of the United States to encourage the development of new technology that can prevent loss of life and injuries at highway-rail grade crossings. The Secretary of Transportation is designated to carry out this policy in consultation with States and necessary public and private entities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb16b1ba-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of New Technology Proposals</inline>.—</heading><content>Railroad carriers and railroad suppliers may submit for review and approval to the Secretary such new technology designed to improve safety at highway-rail grade crossings. The Secretary shall approve by order the new technology designed to improve safety at highway-rail grade crossings in accordance with Federal Railroad Administration standards for the development and use of processor-based signal and train control systems and shall consider the effects on safety of highway-user interface with the new technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb16b1bb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s20161/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Secretarial Approval</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary approves by order new technology to provide warning to highway users at a highway-rail grade crossing and such technology is installed at a highway-rail grade crossing in accordance with the conditions of the approval, this determination preempts any State statute or regulation concerning the adequacy of the technology in providing warning at the crossing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcb16b1bc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/dA/tII/s210/a">Pub. L. 110–432, div. A, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4876">122 Stat. 4876</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcb16b1bd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcb16b1be-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcb16b1bf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Highway Safety Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/93/87">Pub. L. 93–87</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/282">87 Stat. 282</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1973 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s401">section 401 of Title 23</ref>, Highways, and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
