<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcb2c0e9f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201"><num value="24201">§ 24201.</num><heading> Efficient environmental reviews</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb2c0ea0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Efficient Environmental Reviews.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Transportation shall apply the project development procedures, to the greatest extent feasible, described in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s139">section 139 of title 23</ref> to any railroad project that requires the approval of the Secretary under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations and procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall incorporate into agency regulations and procedures pertaining to railroad projects described in paragraph (1) aspects of such project development procedures, or portions thereof, determined appropriate by the Secretary in a manner consistent with this section, that increase the efficiency of the review of railroad projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discretion</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may choose not to incorporate into agency regulations and procedures pertaining to railroad projects described in paragraph (1) such project development procedures that could only feasibly apply to highway projects, public transportation capital projects, and multimodal projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s139">section 139 of title 23</ref> shall apply to railroad projects described in paragraph (1), except that the limitation on claims of 150 days shall be 2 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb2c0ea5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Categorical Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> survey the use by the Federal Railroad Administration of categorical exclusions in transportation projects since 2005; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb2c0ea7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> publish in the Federal Register for notice and public comment a review of the survey that includes a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcb2c0ea8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the types of actions categorically excluded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcb2c0ea9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any actions the Secretary is considering for new categorical exclusions, including those that would conform to those of other modal administrations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb2c0eaa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">New Categorical Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, the Secretary shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking to propose new and existing categorical exclusions for railroad projects that require the approval of the Secretary under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), including those identified under subsection (b), and develop a process for considering new categorical exclusions to the extent that the categorical exclusions meet the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb2c0eab-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transparency</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall maintain and make publicly available, including on the Internet, a database that identifies project-specific information on the use of a categorical exclusion on any railroad project carried out under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb2c0eac-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s24201/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protections for Existing Agreements and NEPA</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in subtitle E of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, or any amendment made by such subtitle, shall affect any existing environmental review process, program, agreement, or funding arrangement approved by the Secretary under title 49, as that title was in effect on the day preceding the date of enactment of such subtitle.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcb2c0ead-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tXI/s11503/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11503(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1691">129 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcb2c0eae-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcb2c0eaf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcb2c0eb0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (c), is the date of enactment of title XI of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, which was approved <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subtitle E of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, referred to in subsec. (e), is subtitle E (§§ 11501–11504) of title XI of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, known as the Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act and also as the TRAIN Act, which enacted this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s24202">section 24202 of this title</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s303">section 303 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s138">section 138 of Title 23</ref>, Highways, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4370m">section 4370m of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this subtitle to the Code, see Short Title of 2015 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s20101">section 20101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of such subtitle, referred to in subsec. (e), is the date of enactment of subtitle E of title XI of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, which was approved <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcb2c0eb1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcb2c0eb2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2015 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
