<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcb57151c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305"><num value="30305">§ 30305.</num><heading> Access to Register information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57151d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Referrals of Information Requests</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57151e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To carry out duties related to driver licensing, driver improvement, or transportation safety, the chief driver licensing official of a participating State may request the Secretary of Transportation to refer, electronically or by United States mail, a request for information about the motor vehicle driving record of an individual to the chief driver licensing official of a State of record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57151f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation shall relay, electronically or by United States mail, information received from the chief driver licensing official of a State of record in response to a request under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the chief driver licensing official of the participating State requesting the information. However, the Secretary may refuse to relay information to the chief driver licensing official of a participating State that does not comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s30304">section 30304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571520-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requests To Obtain Information</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571521-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board and the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to obtain information under subsection (a) of this section about an individual who is the subject of an accident investigation conducted by the Board or the Administrator. The Chairman and the Administrator may receive the information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571522-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An individual who is employed, or is seeking employment, as a driver of a motor vehicle may request the chief driver licensing official of the State in which the individual is employed or seeks employment to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the individual’s employer or prospective employer. An employer or prospective employer may receive the information and shall make the information available to the individual. Information may not be obtained from the National Driver Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 3 years before the request, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571523-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An individual who has received, or is applying for, an airman’s certificate may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration. The Administrator may receive the information and shall make the information available to the individual for review and written comment. The Administrator may use the information to verify information required to be reported to the Administrator by an airman applying for an airman medical certificate and to evaluate whether the airman meets the minimum standards prescribed by the Administrator to be issued an airman medical certificate. The Administrator may not otherwise divulge or use the information. Information may not be obtained from the Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 3 years before the request, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571524-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An individual who is employed, or is seeking employment, by a rail carrier as an operator of a locomotive may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the individual’s employer or prospective employer or to the Secretary of Transportation. Information may not be obtained from the Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 3 years before the request, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571525-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> An individual who holds, or is applying for, a license or certificate of registry under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s7101">section 7101 of title 46</ref>, or a merchant mariner’s document under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s7302">section 7302 of title 46</ref>, may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. The Secretary may receive the information and shall make the information available to the individual for review and written comment before denying, suspending, or revoking the license, certificate, or document of the individual based on the information and before using the information in an action taken under chapter 77 of title 46. The Secretary may not otherwise divulge or use the information, except for purposes of section 7101, 7302, or 7703 of title 46. Information may not be obtained from the Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 3 years before the request, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571526-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The head of a Federal department or agency that issues motor vehicle operator’s licenses may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to obtain information under subsection (a) of this section about an individual applicant for a motor vehicle operator’s license from such department or agency. The department or agency may receive the information, provided it transmits to the Secretary a report regarding any individual who is denied a motor vehicle operator’s license by that department or agency for cause; whose motor vehicle operator’s license is revoked, suspended, or canceled by that department or agency for cause; or about whom the department or agency has been notified of a conviction of any of the motor vehicle-related offenses or comparable offenses listed in section 30304(a)(3) and over whom the department or agency has licensing authority. The report shall contain the information specified in section 30304(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571527-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> An individual who is an officer, chief warrant officer, or enlisted member of the Coast Guard or Coast Guard Reserve (including a cadet or an applicant for appointment or enlistment of any of the foregoing and any member of a uniformed service who is assigned to the Coast Guard) may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the Commandant of the Coast Guard. The Commandant may receive the information and shall make the information available to the individual. Information may not be obtained from the Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 3 years before the request, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571528-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571529-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An individual who is seeking employment by an air carrier as a pilot may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the prospective employer of the individual, the authorized agent of the prospective employer, or the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57152a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An air carrier that is the prospective employer of an individual described in subparagraph (A), or an authorized agent of such an air carrier, may request and receive information about that individual from the National Driver Register through an organization approved by the Secretary for purposes of requesting, receiving, and transmitting such information directly to the prospective employer of such an individual or the authorized agent of the prospective employer. This paragraph shall be carried out in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (11) of section 44703(h) and the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681">15 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57152b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Information may not be obtained from the National Driver Register under this paragraph if the information was entered in the Register more than 5 years before the request unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57152c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> An individual who has or is seeking access to national security information for purposes of Executive Order No. 12968, or any successor Executive order, or an individual who is being investigated for Federal employment under authority of Executive Order No. 10450, or any successor Executive order, may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to a Federal department or agency that is authorized to investigate the individual for the purpose of assisting in the determination of the eligibility of the individual for access to national security information or for Federal employment in a position requiring access to national security information. A Federal department or agency that receives information about an individual under the preceding sentence may use such information only for purposes of the authorized investigation and only in accordance with applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57152d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> A request under this subsection shall be made in the form and way the Secretary of Transportation prescribes by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb57152e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> An individual may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to obtain information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb57152f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to learn whether information about the individual is being provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb571530-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to verify the accuracy of the information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb571531-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to obtain a certified copy of the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571532-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The head of a Federal department or agency authorized to receive information regarding an individual from the Register under this section may request and receive such information from the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571533-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information under subsection (a) of this section about an individual in connection with a safety investigation under the Administrator’s jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571534-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A request for, or receipt of, information from the Register is subject to sections 552 and 552a of title 5, and other applicable laws of the United States or a State, except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb571535-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Transportation may not relay or otherwise provide information specified in section 30304(b)(1)(A) or (C) of this title to a person not authorized by this section to receive the information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb571536-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a request for, or receipt of, information by a chief driver licensing official, or by a person authorized by subsection (b) of this section to request and receive the information, is deemed to be a routine use under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a/b">section 552a(b) of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcb571537-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> receipt of information by a person authorized by this section to receive the information is deemed to be a disclosure under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a/c">section 552a(c) of title 5</ref>, except that the Secretary of Transportation is not required to retain the accounting made under section 552a(c)(1) for more than 7 years after the disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcb571538-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s30305/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Information Provided Under Prior Law</inline>.—</heading><content>Information provided by a State under the Act of <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date> (<ref href="/us/pl/86/660">Public Law 86–660</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/526">74 Stat. 526</ref>), as restated by section 401 of the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966 (<ref href="/us/pl/89/563">Public Law 89–563</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/730">80 Stat. 730</ref>), and under this chapter, shall be available under this section during the transition from the register maintained under that Act to the Register maintained under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcb571539-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s1/e">Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/976">108 Stat. 976</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 104–264, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3262">110 Stat. 3262</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tII/s207/b">Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3908">110 Stat. 3908</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2205">111 Stat. 2205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tII/s2006/b">Pub. L. 105–178, title II, § 2006(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/335">112 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tX/s1061">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1061</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2056">118 Stat. 2056</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tV/s5512">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title V, § 5512</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1556">129 Stat. 1556</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s563">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 563</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3384">132 Stat. 3384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcb57153a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcb57153b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idcb57153c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Pub. L</html:span>. 103–272</html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>30305</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">23:401 (note).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 25, 1982</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/97/364/s206">Pub. L. 97–364, § 206</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/96/1743">96 Stat. 1743</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Dec. 30, 1987</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/223/s305">Pub. L. 100–223, § 305</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/101/1525">101 Stat. 1525</html:a>; <html:span class="date">June 22, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/342/s4/b">Pub. L. 100–342, § 4(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/102/626">102 Stat. 626</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Aug. 18, 1990</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/101/380/s4105/a">Pub. L. 101–380, § 4105(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/104/512">104 Stat. 512</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(1), the words “on and after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="1982-10-25">Oct. 25, 1982</date>]” are omitted as obsolete.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(1), the word “Administrator” is substituted for “Bureau of Motor Carrier Safety” for consistency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (d) is substituted for the last 2 sentences (added twice by mistake) in paragraphs (1) and (2) and for the last sentence in paragraphs (3), (4), and (7)(C) of section 206(b) of the National Driver Register Act of 1982 (<ref href="/us/pl/97/364">Public Law 97–364</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1744">96 Stat. 1744</ref>) for clarity and to avoid repeating the provision unnecessarily.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcb57153d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps"><ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/A">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(A)</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This amends 49:30305(b)(8), as redesignated by section 207(b) of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/324">Public Law 104–324</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3908">110 Stat. 3908</ref>), to correct an erroneous cross-reference.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcb57153e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps"><ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/B">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(B)</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This amends 49:30305(b) to redesignate paragraph (8), as redesignated by section 502(b)(1) of the Federal Aviation Reauthorization Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Public Law 104–264</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3262">110 Stat. 3262</ref>), as paragraph (9), because section 207(b) of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/324">Public Law 104–324</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3908">110 Stat. 3908</ref>), redesignated paragraph (7) as paragraph (8) but did not redesignate paragraph (8) as paragraph (9).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcb57153f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcb571540-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Credit Reporting Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(8)(B), is title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/90/321">Pub. L. 90–321</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/91/508/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 91–508, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1127">84 Stat. 1127</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1681 et seq.) of chapter 41 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 12968, referred to in subsec. (b)(9), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 10450, referred to in subsec. (b)(9), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7311">section 7311 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, referred to in subsec. (d), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s30302">section 30302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcb571541-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> amended par. (8) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (8) read as follows: “An individual who is seeking employment by an air carrier as a pilot may request the chief driver licensing official of a State to provide information about the individual under subsection (a) of this section to the prospective employer of the individual or to the Secretary of Transportation. Information may not be obtained from the National Driver Register under this subsection if the information was entered in the Register more than 5 years before the request unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(9) to (12). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> added par. (9) and redesignated former pars. (9) to (11) as (10) to (12), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/1/A">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, unless the information is about a revocation or suspension still in effect on the date of the request”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/2/B">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (6). Former par. (6) redesignated (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/1/C">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(1)(C)</ref>, directed amendment identical to that made by <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/B">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(B)</ref>. See 1997 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, directed amendment identical to that made by <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/A">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(A)</ref>. See 1997 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/1/C">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(1)(C)</ref>, directed amendment identical to that made by <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/B">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(B)</ref>. See 1997 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/2/A">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(2)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (10) and transferred it to appear after par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s2006/b/2/C">Pub. L. 105–178, § 2006(b)(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/B">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (8), relating to request, as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/A">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(A)</ref>, in par. (8), relating to individual seeking employment as pilot, substituted “subsection (a) of this section” for “paragraph (2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/18/B">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(18)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (8), relating to request, as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s207/b">Pub. L. 104–324, § 207(b)</ref>, added par. (7). Former par. (7), relating to individual seeking employment as pilot, redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/264/s502/b">Pub. L. 104–264, § 502(b)</ref>, added par. (7). Former par. (7), relating to request, redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s207/b">Pub. L. 104–324, § 207(b)</ref>, redesignated par. (7), relating to individual seeking employment as pilot, as (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/264/s502/b">Pub. L. 104–264, § 502(b)</ref>, redesignated par. (7), relating to request, as (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcb571542-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcb571543-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcb571544-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, and not to be construed as affecting funds made available for a fiscal year ending before <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 104–264</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/264/tV/s502/d">Pub. L. 104–264, title V, § 502(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3263">110 Stat. 3263</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/264/tV/s502/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 44936 and 46301 of this title] shall apply to any air carrier hiring an individual as a pilot whose application was first received by the carrier on or after the 120th day following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idcb571545-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
