<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcbe60f1c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506"><num value="44506">§ 44506.</num><heading> Air traffic controllers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f1d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research on Effect of Automation on Performance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To develop the means necessary to establish appropriate selection criteria and training methodologies for the next generation of air traffic controllers, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall conduct research to study the effect of automation on the performance of the next generation of air traffic controllers and the air traffic control system. The research shall include investigating—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f1e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> methods for improving and accelerating future air traffic controller training through the application of advanced training techniques, including the use of simulation technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f1f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the role of automation in the air traffic control system and its physical and psychological effects on air traffic controllers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f20-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the attributes and aptitudes needed to function well in a highly automated air traffic control system and the development of appropriate testing methods for identifying individuals with those attributes and aptitudes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f21-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> innovative methods for training potential air traffic controllers to enhance the benefits of automation and maximize the effectiveness of the air traffic control system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f22-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> new technologies and procedures for exploiting automated communication systems, including Mode S Transponders, to improve information transfers between air traffic controllers and aircraft pilots.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f23-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research on Human Factor Aspects of Automation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrators of the Federal Aviation Administration and National Aeronautics and Space Administration may make an agreement for the use of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s unique human factor facilities and expertise in conducting research activities to study the human factor aspects of the highly automated environment for the next generation of air traffic controllers. The research activities shall include investigating—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f24-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> human perceptual capabilities and the effect of computer-aided decision making on the workload and performance of air traffic controllers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f25-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> information management techniques for advanced air traffic control display systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f26-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> air traffic controller workload and performance measures, including the development of predictive models.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f27-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collegiate Training Initiative</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f28-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may maintain the Collegiate Training Initiative program by making new agreements and continuing existing agreements with institutions of higher education (as defined by the Administrator) under which the institutions prepare students for the position of air traffic controller with the Department of Transportation (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2109">section 2109 of title 5</ref>). The Administrator may establish standards for the entry of institutions into the program and for their continued participation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f29-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f2a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may appoint an individual who has successfully completed a course of training in a program described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to the position of air traffic controller noncompetitively in the excepted service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2103">section 2103 of title 5</ref>). An individual appointed under this paragraph serves at the pleasure of the Administrator, subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7511">section 7511 of title 5</ref>. However, an appointment under this paragraph may be converted from one in the excepted service to a career conditional or career appointment in the competitive civil service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2102">section 2102 of title 5</ref>) when the individual achieves full performance level air traffic controller status, as decided by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f2b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The authority under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph to make appointments in the excepted service expires on <date date="1997-10-06">October 6, 1997</date>, except that the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may extend the authority for one or more successive one-year periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f2c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air Traffic Control Specialist Qualification Training.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f2d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment of air traffic control specialists</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator is authorized to appoint a qualified air traffic control specialist candidate for placement in an airport traffic control facility if the candidate has—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f2e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> received a control tower operator certification (referred to in this subsection as a “CTO” certificate); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f2f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> satisfied all other applicable qualification requirements for an air traffic control specialist position, including successful completion of orientation training at the Federal Aviation Administration Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f30-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compensation and benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>An individual appointed under paragraph (1) shall receive the same compensation and benefits, and be treated in the same manner as, any other individual appointed as a developmental air traffic controller.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f31-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that evaluates the effectiveness of the air traffic control specialist qualification training provided pursuant to this section, including the graduation rates of candidates who received a CTO certificate and are working in airport traffic control facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f32-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional appointments</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator determines that air traffic control specialists appointed pursuant to this subsection are more successful in carrying out the duties of an air traffic controller than air traffic control specialists hired from the general public without any such certification, the Administrator shall increase, to the maximum extent practicable, the number of appointments of candidates who possess such certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f33-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for travel expenses associated with certifications.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f34-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Administrator may accept reimbursement from an educational entity that provides training to an air traffic control specialist candidate to cover reasonable travel expenses of the Administrator associated with issuing certifications to such candidates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f35-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of reimbursements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref>, any reimbursement authorized to be collected under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f36-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be credited as offsetting collections to the account that finances the activities and services for which the reimbursement is accepted;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f37-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be available for expenditure only to pay the costs of activities and services for which the reimbursement is accepted, including all costs associated with collecting such reimbursement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f38-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/d/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> remain available until expended.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f39-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Staffing Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit annually to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f3a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the staffing standards used to determine the number of fully certified air traffic controllers needed to operate the air traffic control system of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f3b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> for each air traffic control facility operated by the Federal Aviation Administration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f3c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the current certified professional controller staffing levels;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f3d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the operational staffing targets for certified professional controllers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f3e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the anticipated certified professional controller attrition for each of the next 3 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f3f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the number of certified professional controller trainees;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f40-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a 3-year projection of the number of controllers needed to be employed to operate the system to meet the standards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f41-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a detailed plan for employing the controllers, including projected budget requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbe60f42-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hiring of Certain Air Traffic Control Specialists.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f43-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of applicants.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f44-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ensuring selection of most qualified applicants</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In appointing individuals to the position of air traffic controller, the Administrator shall give preferential consideration to qualified individuals maintaining 52 consecutive weeks of air traffic control experience involving the full-time active separation of air traffic after receipt of an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating within 5 years of application while serving at—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f45-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a Federal Aviation Administration air traffic control facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f46-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a civilian or military air traffic control facility of the Department of Defense (including a facility of the National Guard); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f47-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a tower operating under contract with the Federal Aviation Administration under section 47124.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f48-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of additional applicants.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f49-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>After giving preferential consideration to applicants under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consider additional applicants for the position of air traffic controller by giving further preferential consideration, within each qualification category based upon pre-employment testing results (including application of veterans’ preference as required under section 40122(g)(2)(B)), to pool 1 applicants described in clause (ii) before pool 2 applicants described in clause (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f4a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pool 1</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Pool 1 applicants are individuals who—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f4b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> have successfully completed air traffic controller training and graduated from an institution participating in the Collegiate Training Initiative program maintained under subsection (c)(1) and who have received from the institution—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idcbe60f4c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> an appropriate recommendation; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idcbe60f4d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> an endorsement certifying that the individual would have met the requirements in effect as of <date date="2013-12-31">December 31, 2013</date>, for an appropriate recommendation;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f4e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> are eligible for a veterans recruitment appointment pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4214">section 4214 of title 38</ref> and provide a Certificate of Release or Discharge from Active Duty within 120 days of the announcement closing;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f4f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> are eligible veterans (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4211">section 4211 of title 38</ref>) maintaining aviation experience obtained in the course of the individual’s military experience; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f50-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> are preference eligible veterans (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2108">section 2108 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f51-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pool 2</inline>.—</heading><content>Pool 2 applicants are individuals who apply under a vacancy announcement recruiting from all United States citizens.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f52-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f53-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), after giving preferential consideration to applicants under subparagraph (A) and if, after consulting with the labor organization recognized as the exclusive representative of air traffic controllers under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7111">section 7111 of title 5</ref>, the Administrator determines there are unique circumstances affecting a covered facility that warrant a vacancy announcement with a limited area of consideration, the Administrator may consider applicants for the position of air traffic controller who apply under a vacancy announcement recruiting from the local commuting area for that covered facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f54-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biographical assessments</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall not use any biographical assessment with respect to an applicant under this subparagraph who would otherwise qualify as a Pool 1 applicant under subparagraph (B)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f55-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered facility defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subparagraph the term “covered facility” means a radar facility with at least 1,000,000 operations annually that is located in a metropolitan statistical area (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget) with a population estimate by the Bureau of the Census of more than 15,000,000 (as of <date date="2016-07-01">July 1, 2016</date>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f56-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of biographical assessments.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f57-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biographical assessments</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall not use any biographical assessment when hiring under paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f58-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reconsideration of applicants disqualified on basis of biographical assessments.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f59-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If an individual described in paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B)(ii), who applied for the position of air traffic controller with the Administration in response to Vacancy Announcement FAA–AMC–14–ALLSRCE–33537 (issued on <date date="2014-02-10">February 10, 2014</date>), was disqualified from the position as the result of a biographical assessment, the Administrator shall provide the applicant an opportunity to reapply for the position as soon as practicable under the revised hiring practices.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbe60f5a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver of age restriction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall waive any maximum age restriction for the position of air traffic controller with the Administration that would otherwise disqualify an individual from the position if the individual—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f5b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is reapplying for the position pursuant to clause (i) on or before <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbe60f5c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> met the maximum age requirement on the date of the individual’s previous application for the position during the interim hiring process.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f5d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum entry age for experienced controllers</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3307">section 3307 of title 5</ref>, except for individuals covered by the program described in paragraph (4), the maximum limit of age for an original appointment to a position as an air traffic controller shall be 35 years of age for those maintaining 52 weeks of air traffic control experience involving the full-time active separation of air traffic after receipt of an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating in a civilian or military air traffic control facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbe60f5e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retired military controllers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator may establish a program to provide an original appointment to a position as an air traffic controller for individuals who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f5f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> are on terminal leave pending retirement from active duty military service or have retired from active duty military service within 5 years of applying for the appointment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbe60f60-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> have held either an air traffic certification or air traffic control facility rating according to Administration standards within 5 years of applying for the appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcbe60f61-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s1/e">Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1178">108 Stat. 1178</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s5/9">Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3389">110 Stat. 3389</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tVI/s607">Pub. L. 112–95, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/114">126 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/190/tII/s2106/a">Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2106(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/620">130 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dM/tI/s108">Pub. L. 115–141, div. M, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1047">132 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXI">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI</ref>, §§ 1132, 1133, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1615">133 Stat. 1615</ref>, 1616; <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV</ref>, §§ 433, 437(e)(2), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1174">138 Stat. 1174</ref>, 1178.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcbe60f62-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcbe60f63-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idcbe60f64-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44506(a), (b)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1353 (note).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Nov. 3, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/591/s8/a">Pub. L. 100–591, § 8(a)</html:a>–(c), <html:a href="/us/stat/102/3015">102 Stat. 3015</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Nov. 17, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/685">Pub. L. 100–685</html:a>, §§ 601–603, <html:a href="/us/stat/102/4102">102 Stat. 4102</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44506(c)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1348a.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 6, 1992</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/102/388/s362">Pub. L. 102–388, § 362</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/106/1560">106 Stat. 1560</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44506(d)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1348 (note).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 31, 1992</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/102/581/s120">Pub. L. 102–581, § 120</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/106/4884">106 Stat. 4884</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsections (a) and (b), the text of section 8(a) and (b)(3) of the Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/581">Public Law 100–581</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3015">102 Stat. 3015</ref>, 3016) and sections 601 and 602(3) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/685">Public Law 100–685</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4102">102 Stat. 4102</ref>, 4103) is omitted as executed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c), the words “institutions of higher education” are substituted for “post-secondary educational institutions” for consistency in the revised title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcbe60f65-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcbe60f66-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, referred to in subsec. (d)(3), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/112/95">Pub. L. 112–95</ref>, which was approved <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcbe60f67-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s437/e/2/A">Pub. L. 118–63, § 437(e)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “the number of fully certified air traffic controllers needed” for “the number of air traffic controllers needed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s437/e/2/B">Pub. L. 118–63, § 437(e)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), added par. (2) and redesignated former pars. (2) and (3) as (3) and (4), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s433">Pub. L. 118–63, § 433</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(B)” for “paragraph (1)(B)(ii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (f)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1133">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1133</ref>, inserted “(including a facility of the National Guard)” after “Department of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1132">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1132</ref>, substituted “giving further preferential consideration, within each qualification category based upon pre-employment testing results (including application of veterans’ preference as required under section 40122(g)(2)(B)), to pool 1 applicants described in clause (ii) before pool 2 applicants described in clause (iii).” for “referring an approximately equal number of individuals for appointment among the 2 applicant pools described in this subparagraph. The number of individuals referred for consideration from each group shall not differ by more than 10 percent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (f)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s108/1">Pub. L. 115–141, § 108(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s108/2/A">Pub. L. 115–141, § 108(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “except for individuals covered by the program described in paragraph (4),” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3307">section 3307 of title 5</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s108/2/B">Pub. L. 115–141, § 108(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/190">Pub. L. 114–190</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95">Pub. L. 112–95</ref> added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/287">Pub. L. 104–287</ref> substituted “Transportation and Infrastructure” for “Public Works and Transportation”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcbe60f68-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f69-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improved Access to Air Traffic Control Simulation Training</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s415">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1160">138 Stat. 1160</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s415">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall continue making tower simulator systems (in this section referred to as ‘TSS’) more accessible to all air traffic controller specialists assigned to an air traffic control tower of the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] (in this section referred to as an ‘ATCT’), regardless of facility assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cloud-based Visual Database and Software System</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator shall develop and implement a cloud-based visual database and software system that is compatible with existing and future TSS that, at a minimum, includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the unique runway layout, approach paths, and lines of sight of every ATCT; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> specifications that meet all applicable data security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">TSS Upgrades</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall upgrade existing, permanent TSS so that the TSS is, at a minimum, capable of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> securely and quickly downloading data from the cloud-based visual database and software system described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> running scenarios for each ATCT involving differing levels of air traffic volume and varying complexities, including, aircraft emergencies, rapidly changing weather, issuance of safety alerts, special air traffic procedures for events of national or international significance, and recovering from unforeseen events or losses of separation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Mobile TSS</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall acquire and implement mobile TSS at each ATCT that is without an existing, permanent TSS so that the mobile TSS is capable of, at a minimum, the capabilities described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collaboration</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out this section, the Administrator may collaborate with the exclusive bargaining representative of air traffic controllers certified under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7111">section 7111 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Ensuring Hiring of Air Traffic Control Specialists Is Based on Assessment of Job-Relevant Aptitudes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s417">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 417</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1162">138 Stat. 1162</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s417">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review of the Air Traffic Skills Assessment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall review and revise, if necessary, the Air Traffic Skills Assessment (in this section referred to as the ‘AT–SA’) administered to air traffic controller applicants described in clauses (ii) and (iii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B">section 44506(f)(1)(B) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, in accordance with the following requirements, the Administrator shall:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Evaluate all questions on the AT–SA and determine whether a peer-reviewed job analysis that ensures all questions test job-relevant aptitudes would result in improvements in the air traffic control specialist workforce training and hiring process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Assess the assumptions and methodologies used to develop the AT–SA, the job-relevant aptitudes measured, and the scoring process for the assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Assess whether any other revisions to the AT–SA are necessary to enhance the air traffic control specialist workforce training and hiring process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DOT Inspector General Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the completion of the review and any necessary revision of the AT–SA required under subsection (a), the inspector general of the Department of Transportation shall submit to the Administrator, the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives], and, upon request, to any member of Congress, a report that assesses the AT–SA and any applicable revisions, a description of any associated actions taken by the Administrator, and any other recommendations to address the results of the report.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Air Traffic Control Workforce Staffing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s437">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 437</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1176">138 Stat. 1176</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s437">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum Hiring</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028, the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall set as the minimum hiring target for new air traffic controllers (excluding individuals described in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/A">section 44506(f)(1)(A) of title 49</ref>, United States Code) the maximum number of individuals able to be trained at the Federal Aviation Administration Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transportation Research Board Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator shall submit an attestation to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] demonstrating an agreement entered into with the with the National Academies Transportation Research Board to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> compare the Certified Professional Controller (in this section referred to as ‘CPC’) operational staffing models and methodologies in determining the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] Controller Staffing Standard included in the 2023 Air Traffic Controller Workforce Plan of the FAA, with such models and methodologies developed by the Collaborative Resource Workgroup of the FAA (in this subsection referred to as ‘CRWG’) to determine CPC operational staffing targets necessary to meet facility operational, statutory, contractual and safety requirements, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the availability factor multiplier and other formula components;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the independent facility staffing targets of CPCs able to control traffic;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> air traffic controller position utilization;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> attrition rates at each air traffic control facility operated by the Administration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> the time needed to meet facility operational, statutory, and contractual requirements, including relevant resources to develop, evaluate, and implement processes and initiatives affecting the national airspace system;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> examine the current and estimated budgets of the FAA to implement the FAA Controller Staffing Standard included in the 2023 Controller Workforce Plan in comparison to the funding needed to implement the CRWG CPC operational staffing targets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> assess future needs of the air traffic control system and potential impacts on staffing standards, including projected air traffic in the airspace of each air traffic control facility operated by the Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> determine which staffing models and methodologies evaluated pursuant to this subsection best accounts for the operational staffing needs of the air traffic control system and provide a justification for such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the agreement entered into pursuant to paragraph (b)(1), the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies shall submit a report to the Administrator and appropriate committees of Congress on the findings and recommendations under this subsection, including the determination pursuant to subparagraph (D).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the assessment under this subsection, the Transportation Research Board shall consult with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic control specialists of the Administration certified under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7111">section 7111 of title 5</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> front line managers of the air traffic control system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> managers and employees responsible for training air traffic controllers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the MITRE Corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Chief Operating Officer of the Air Traffic Organization of the FAA, and other Federal Government representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> users and operators in the air traffic control system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> relevant industry representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> other parties determined appropriate by the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Implementation of Identified Staffing Model.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of staffing model</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall, as appropriate, take such action that may be necessary to implement and use the staffing model identified by the Transportation Research Board pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(D), including any recommendations for improving such model, not later than one year after enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after taking such actions to implement and use the staffing model identified by the Transportation Research Board pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(D), the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress regarding the reasons for why any recommendation by the Transportation Research Board study was not incorporated into the implemented staffing model.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revised Staffing Standards</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administration shall revise the FAA CPC operational staffing standards of the Administration implemented under subsection (c) to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> provide that the controller and management workforce is sufficiently staffed to safely and efficiently manage and oversee the air traffic control system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> account for the target number of CPCs able to control traffic at each independent facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> avoid any required or requested reduction of national airspace system capacity or aircraft operations as a result of inadequate air traffic control system staffing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim Adoption of Collaborative Resource Workgroup Models.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In submitting a Controller Workforce Plan of the FAA to Congress published after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall adopt and use the staffing models and methodologies developed by the Collaborative Resource Workgroup that were recommended in the 2023 Controller Workforce Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revisions to the controller workforce plan</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<p>[Amended this section.]</p></note>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements of paragraph (1) shall cease to be effective upon the adoption and implementation of a revised staffing model by the Administrator as required under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Controller Training</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In any Controller Workforce Plan of the FAA published after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> identify all limiting factors on the ability of the Administrator to hire and train controllers in line with the staffing standards target set out in such Plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> describe what actions the Administrator intends to take to rectify any impediments to meeting staffing standards targets and identify contributing factors that are outside the control of the Administrator.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification of Vacancies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/190/tII/s2106/b">Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2106(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/622">130 Stat. 622</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/190/tII/s2106/b">“The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall consider directly notifying secondary schools and institutions of higher learning, including Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, Minority Institutions, and Tribal Colleges and Universities, of a vacancy announcement under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44506/f/1/B/iii">section 44506(f)(1)(B)(iii) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Air Traffic Controller Staffing Initiatives and Analysis</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tII/s224">Pub. L. 112–95, title II, § 224</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/55">126 Stat. 55</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/95/tII/s224">
<inline>“As soon as practicable, and not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>], the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> ensure, to the extent practicable, a sufficient number of contract instructors, classroom space (including off-site locations as needed), and simulators to allow for an increase in the number of air traffic controllers at air traffic control facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> distribute, to the extent practicable, the placement of certified professional air traffic controllers-in-training and developmental air traffic controllers at facilities evenly across the calendar year in order to avoid training bottlenecks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> initiate an analysis, to be conducted in consultation with the exclusive bargaining representative of air traffic controllers certified under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7111">section 7111 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, of scheduling processes and practices, including overtime scheduling practices at those facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> provide, to the extent practicable and where appropriate, priority to certified professional air traffic controllers-in-training when filling staffing vacancies at facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> assess training programs at air traffic control facilities with below-average success rates to determine if training is being carried out in accordance with Administration standards, and conduct exit interview analyses with all candidates to determine potential weaknesses in training protocols, or in the execution of such training protocols; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> prioritize, to the extent practicable, such efforts to address the recommendations for the facilities identified in the Department of Transportation’s Office of the Inspector General Report Number: AV-2009-047.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f6f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Facility Training Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tVI/s609/b">Pub. L. 112–95, title VI, § 609(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/116">126 Stat. 116</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/95/tVI/s609/b">
<inline>“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall conduct a comprehensive review and evaluation of its Academy and facility training efforts. The Administrator shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> clarify responsibility for oversight and direction of the Academy’s facility training program at the national level;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> communicate information concerning that responsibility to facility managers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> establish standards to identify the number of developmental air traffic controllers that can be accommodated at each facility, based on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number of available on-the-job training instructors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> available classroom space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the number of available simulators;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> training requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the number of recently placed new personnel already in training.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f70-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Controller Staffing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dG/tI">Pub. L. 116–6, div. G, title I</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/401">133 Stat. 401</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/6/dG/tI">“That not later than March 31 of each fiscal year hereafter, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall transmit to Congress an annual update to the report submitted to Congress in December 2004 pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s221">section 221 of Public Law 108–176</ref> [set out below]”.</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dD/tI">Pub. L. 119–75, div. D, title I</ref>, <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/333">140 Stat. 333</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dF/tI">Pub. L. 118–42, div. F, title I</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/307">138 Stat. 307</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dL/tI">Pub. L. 117–328, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5102">136 Stat. 5102</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dL/tI">Pub. L. 117–103, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/691">136 Stat. 691</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dL/tI">Pub. L. 116–260, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1830">134 Stat. 1830</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dH/tI">Pub. L. 116–94, div. H, title I</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2940">133 Stat. 2940</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dL/tI">Pub. L. 115–141, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/977">132 Stat. 977</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dK/tI">Pub. L. 115–31, div. K, title I</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/730">131 Stat. 730</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dL/tI">Pub. L. 114–113, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2839">129 Stat. 2839</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dK/tI">Pub. L. 113–235, div. K, title I</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2700">128 Stat. 2700</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dL/tI">Pub. L. 113–76, div. L, title I</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/578">128 Stat. 578</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/55/dC/tI">Pub. L. 112–55, div. C, title I</ref>, <date date="2011-11-18">Nov. 18, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/645">125 Stat. 645</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/117/dA/tI">Pub. L. 111–117, div. A, title I</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3039">123 Stat. 3039</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dI/tI">Pub. L. 111–8, div. I, title I</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/918">123 Stat. 918</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dK/tI">Pub. L. 110–161, div. K, title I</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2378">121 Stat. 2378</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/176/tII/s221">Pub. L. 108–176, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2526">117 Stat. 2526</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/176/tII/s221">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning with the submission of the Budget of the United States to the Congress for fiscal year 2005, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall transmit a report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure that describes the overall air traffic controller staffing plan, including strategies to address anticipated retirement and replacement of air traffic controllers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Human Capital Workforce Strategy.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall develop a comprehensive human capital workforce strategy to determine the most effective method for addressing the need for more air traffic controllers that is identified in the June 2002 report of the General Accounting Office [now Government Accountability Office].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Completion date</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>], the Administrator shall complete development of the strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the strategy is completed, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a report describing the strategy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idcbe60f71-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbe60f72-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Keeping Americans Safe in Aviation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2025-01-21">Jan. 21, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8651, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of Transportation [and] the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Every day, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), within the U.S. Department of Transportation, oversees safety for more than 45,000 flights and 2.9 million airline passengers. These Americans trust the FAA’s public servants with their lives, and it is therefore imperative that they maintain a commitment to excellence and efficiency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">During the prior administration, however, the FAA betrayed its mission by elevating dangerous discrimination over excellence. For example, prior to my Inauguration, the FAA Diversity and Inclusion website revealed that the prior administration sought to specifically recruit and hire individuals with serious infirmities that could impact the execution of their essential life-saving duties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Illegal and discriminatory diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) hiring, including on the basis of race, sex, disability, or any other criteria other than the safety of airline passengers and overall job excellence, competency, and qualification, harms all Americans, who deserve to fly with confidence. It also penalizes hard-working Americans who want to serve in the FAA but are unable to do so, as they lack a requisite disability or skin color. FAA Federal servants must hold the qualifications and ability to perform their jobs to the highest possible standard of excellence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I hereby order the Secretary of Transportation and the Federal Aviation Administrator to immediately return to non-discriminatory, merit-based hiring, as required by law. All so-called DEI initiatives, including all dangerous preferencing policies or practices, shall immediately be rescinded in favor of hiring, promoting, and otherwise treating employees on the basis of individual capability, competence, achievement, and dedication.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation and the Federal Aviation Administrator shall review the past performance and performance standards of all individuals in critical safety positions and take all appropriate action to ensure that any individual who fails or has failed to demonstrate requisite capability is replaced by a high-capability individual that will ensure top-notch air safety and efficiency.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
