<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcbf1f5d3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703"><num value="44703">§ 44703.</num><heading> Airman certificates</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5d4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue an airman certificate to an individual when the Administrator finds, after investigation, that the individual is qualified for, and physically able to perform the duties related to, the position to be authorized by the certificate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5d5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5d6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An airman certificate shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5d7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be numbered and recorded by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5d8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> contain the name, address, and description of the individual to whom the certificate is issued;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5d9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> contain terms the Administrator decides are necessary to ensure safety in air commerce, including terms on the duration of the certificate, periodic or special examinations, and tests of physical fitness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5da-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> specify the capacity in which the holder of the certificate may serve as an airman with respect to an aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5db-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> designate the class the certificate covers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5dc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A certificate issued to a pilot serving in scheduled air transportation shall have the designation “airline transport pilot” of the appropriate class.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5dd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5de-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the information contained in the records of contents of any airman certificate issued under this section that is limited to an airman’s name, address, and ratings held shall be made available to the public after the 120th day following the date of the enactment of the Wendell H. Ford Aviation Investment and Reform Act for the 21st Century.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5df-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Opportunity to withhold information</inline>.—</heading><content>Before making any information concerning an airman available to the public under paragraph (1), the airman shall be given an opportunity to elect that the information not be made available to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5e0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development and implementation of program</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the Wendell H. Ford Aviation Investment and Reform Act for the 21st Century, the Administrator shall develop and implement, in cooperation with representatives of the aviation industry, a one-time written notification to airmen to set forth the implications of making information concerning an airman available to the public under paragraph (1) and to carry out paragraph (2). The Administrator shall also provide such written notification to each individual who becomes an airman after such date of enactment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5e1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appeals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5e2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An individual whose application for the issuance or renewal of an airman certificate has been denied may appeal the denial to the National Transportation Safety Board, except if the individual holds a certificate that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5e3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is suspended at the time of denial; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5e4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> was revoked within one year from the date of the denial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5e5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Board shall conduct a hearing on the appeal at a place convenient to the place of residence or employment of the applicant. The Board is not bound by findings of fact of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration. At the end of the hearing, the Board shall decide whether the individual meets the applicable regulations and standards. The Administrator is bound by that decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5e6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A person who is substantially affected by an order of the Board under this subsection, or the Administrator if the Administrator decides that an order of the Board will have a significant adverse impact on carrying out this subtitle, may seek judicial review of the order under section 46110. The Administrator shall be made a party to the judicial review proceedings. The findings of fact of the Board in any such case are conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5e7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restrictions and Prohibitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5e8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> restrict or prohibit issuing an airman certificate to an alien; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5e9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make issuing the certificate to an alien dependent on a reciprocal agreement with the government of a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5ea-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Controlled Substance Violations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may not issue an airman certificate to an individual whose certificate is revoked under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44710">section 44710 of this title</ref> except—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5eb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> when the Administrator decides that issuing the certificate will facilitate law enforcement efforts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5ec-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44710/e/2">section 44710(e)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5ed-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modifications in System</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5ee-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall make modifications in the system for issuing airman certificates necessary to make the system more effective in serving the needs of airmen and officials responsible for enforcing laws related to the regulation of controlled substances (as defined in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802">21 U.S.C. 802</ref>)) and related to combating acts of terrorism. The modifications shall ensure positive and verifiable identification of each individual applying for or holding a certificate and shall address at least each of the following deficiencies in, and abuses of, the existing system:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5ef-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the use of fictitious names and addresses by applicants for those certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5f0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the use of stolen or fraudulent identification in applying for those certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5f1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the use by an applicant of a post office box or “mail drop” as a return address to evade identification of the applicant’s address.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5f2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the use of counterfeit and stolen airman certificates by pilots.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5f3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the absence of information about physical characteristics of holders of those certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5f4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prescribe regulations to carry out paragraph (1) of this subsection and provide a written explanation of how the regulations address each of the deficiencies and abuses described in paragraph (1). In prescribing the regulations, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall consult with the Administrator of Drug Enforcement, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, other law enforcement officials of the United States Government, representatives of State and local law enforcement officials, representatives of the general aviation aircraft industry, representatives of users of general aviation aircraft, and other interested persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5f5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the term “acts of terrorism” means an activity that involves a violent act or an act dangerous to human life that is a violation of the criminal laws of the United States or of any State, or that would be a criminal violation if committed within the jurisdiction of the United States or of any State, and appears to be intended to intimidate or coerce a civilian population to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion or to affect the conduct of a government by assassination or kidnaping.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5f6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Administrator is authorized and directed to work with State and local authorities, and other Federal agencies, to assist in the identification of individuals applying for or holding airmen certificates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf1f5f7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002155">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002155"><num>1</num><inline class="small-caps" /> See Termination Date note below.</note> <inline class="small-caps">Records of Employment of Pilot Applicants.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf1f5f8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to paragraph (14), before allowing an individual to begin service as a pilot, an air carrier shall request and receive the following information:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf1f5f9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FAA records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>From the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, records pertaining to the individual that are maintained by the Administrator concerning—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf466fa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> current airman certificates (including airman medical certificates) and associated type ratings, including any limitations to those certificates and ratings; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf466fb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> summaries of legal enforcement actions resulting in a finding by the Administrator of a violation of this title or a regulation prescribed or order issued under this title that was not subsequently overturned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf466fc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air carrier and other records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>From any air carrier or other person (except a branch of the United States Armed Forces, the National Guard, or a reserve component of the United States Armed Forces) that has employed the individual as a pilot of a civil or public aircraft at any time during the 5-year period preceding the date of the employment application of the individual, or from the trustee in bankruptcy for such air carrier or person—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf466fd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> records pertaining to the individual that are maintained by an air carrier (other than records relating to flight time, duty time, or rest time) under regulations set forth in—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf466fe-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> section 121.683 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf466ff-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> paragraph (A) of section VI, appendix I, part 121 of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46700-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> paragraph (A) of section IV, appendix J, part 121 of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46701-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> section 125.401 of such title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46702-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> section 135.63(a)(4) of such title; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46703-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> other records pertaining to the individual’s performance as a pilot that are maintained by the air carrier or person concerning—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46704-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the training, qualifications, proficiency, or professional competence of the individual, including comments and evaluations made by a check airman designated in accordance with section 121.411, 125.295, or 135.337 of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46705-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any disciplinary action taken with respect to the individual that was not subsequently overturned; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46706-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> any release from employment or resignation, termination, or disqualification with respect to employment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46707-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National driver register records</inline>.—</heading><content>In accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8">section 30305(b)(8) of this title</ref>, from the chief driver licensing official of a State, information concerning the motor vehicle driving record of the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46708-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Written consent; release from liability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An air carrier making a request for records under paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46709-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be required to obtain written consent to the release of those records from the individual that is the subject of the records requested; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4670a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may, notwithstanding any other provision of law or agreement to the contrary, require the individual who is the subject of the records to request to execute a release from liability for any claim arising from the furnishing of such records to or the use of such records by such air carrier (other than a claim arising from furnishing information known to be false and maintained in violation of a criminal statute).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4670b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> 5-<inline class="small-caps">year reporting period</inline>.—</heading><content>A person shall not furnish a record in response to a request made under paragraph (1) if the record was entered more than 5 years before the date of the request, unless the information concerns a revocation or suspension of an airman certificate or motor vehicle license that is in effect on the date of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4670c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement to maintain records</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator and air carriers shall maintain pilot records described in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) for a period of at least 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4670d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Receipt of consent; provision of information</inline>.—</heading><content>A person shall not furnish a record in response to a request made under paragraph (1) without first obtaining a copy of the written consent of the individual who is the subject of the records requested; except that, for purposes of paragraph (15), the Administrator may allow an individual designated by the Administrator to accept and maintain written consent on behalf of the Administrator for records requested under paragraph (1)(A). A person who receives a request for records under this subsection shall furnish a copy of all of such requested records maintained by the person not later than 30 days after receiving the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4670e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Right to receive notice and copy of any record furnished</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A person who receives a request for records under paragraph (1) shall provide to the individual who is the subject of the records—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4670f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> on or before the 20th day following the date of receipt of the request, written notice of the request and of the individual’s right to receive a copy of such records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46710-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in accordance with paragraph (10), a copy of such records, if requested by the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46711-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reasonable charges for processing requests and furnishing copies</inline>.—</heading><content>A person who receives a request under paragraph (1) or (6) may establish a reasonable charge for the cost of processing the request and furnishing copies of the requested records.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46712-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standard forms</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall promulgate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46713-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> standard forms that may be used by an air carrier to request records under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46714-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> standard forms that may be used by an air carrier to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46715-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> obtain the written consent of the individual who is the subject of a request under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46716-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> inform the individual of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46717-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the request; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46718-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/8/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the individual right of that individual to receive a copy of any records furnished in response to the request.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46719-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Right to correct inaccuracies</inline>.—</heading><content>An air carrier that maintains or requests and receives the records of an individual under paragraph (1) shall provide the individual with a reasonable opportunity to submit written comments to correct any inaccuracies contained in the records before making a final hiring decision with respect to the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4671a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Right of pilot to review certain records</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or agreement, an air carrier shall, upon written request from a pilot who is or has been employed by such carrier, make available, within a reasonable time, but not later than 30 days after the date of the request, to the pilot for review, any and all employment records referred to in paragraph (1)(B)(i) or (ii) pertaining to the employment of the pilot.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4671b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Privacy protections</inline>.—</heading><content>An air carrier that receives the records of an individual under paragraph (1) may use such records only to assess the qualifications of the individual in deciding whether or not to hire the individual as a pilot. The air carrier shall take such actions as may be necessary to protect the privacy of the pilot and the confidentiality of the records, including ensuring that information contained in the records is not divulged to any individual that is not directly involved in the hiring decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4671c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Periodic review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of the Pilot Records Improvement Act of 1996, and at least once every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a statement that contains, taking into account recent developments in the aviation industry—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4671d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> recommendations by the Administrator concerning proposed changes to Federal Aviation Administration records, air carrier records, and other records required to be furnished under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4671e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reasons why the Administrator does not recommend any proposed changes to the records referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4671f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46720-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to protect—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46721-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the personal privacy of any individual whose records are requested under paragraph (1) and disseminated under paragraph (15); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46722-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the confidentiality of those records;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46723-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to preclude the further dissemination of records received under paragraph (1) by the person who requested those records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46724-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/13/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to ensure prompt compliance with any request made under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46725-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules with respect to certain pilots.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46726-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/14/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilots of certain small aircraft</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an air carrier, before receiving information requested about an individual under paragraph (1), may allow the individual to begin service for a period not to exceed 90 days as a pilot of an aircraft with a maximum payload capacity (as defined in section 119.3 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) of 7,500 pounds or less, or a helicopter, on a flight that is not a scheduled operation (as defined in such section). Before the end of the 90-day period, the air carrier shall obtain and evaluate such information. The contract between the carrier and the individual shall contain a term that provides that the continuation of the individual’s employment, after the last day of the 90-day period, depends on a satisfactory evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46727-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/14/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good faith exception</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an air carrier, without obtaining information about an individual under paragraph (1)(B) from an air carrier or other person that no longer exists or from a foreign government or entity that employed the individual, may allow the individual to begin service as a pilot if the air carrier required to request the information has made a documented good faith attempt to obtain such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46728-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Electronic access to faa records</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of increasing timely and efficient access to Federal Aviation Administration records described in paragraph (1), the Administrator may allow, under terms established by the Administrator, an individual designated by the air carrier to have electronic access to a specified database containing information about such records. The terms shall limit such access to instances in which information in the database is required by the designated individual in making a hiring decision concerning a pilot applicant and shall require that the designated individual provide assurances satisfactory to the Administrator that information obtained using such access will not be used for any purpose other than making the hiring decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46729-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/h/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>This subsection shall cease to be effective on the date specified in regulations issued under subsection (i).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf4672a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> FAA <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Records Database.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4672b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Before allowing an individual to begin service as a pilot, an air carrier shall access and evaluate, in accordance with the requirements of this subsection, information pertaining to the individual from the pilot records database established under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4672c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot records database</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2017-04-30">April 30, 2017</date>, the Administrator shall establish and make available for use an electronic database (in this subsection referred to as the “database”) containing the following records:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4672d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> FAA <inline class="small-caps">records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>From the Administrator—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf4672e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> records that are maintained by the Administrator concerning current airman certificates, including airman medical certificates and associated type ratings and information on any limitations to those certificates and ratings;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf4672f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> records that are maintained by the Administrator concerning any failed attempt of an individual to pass a practical test required to obtain a certificate or type rating under part 61 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46730-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> summaries of legal enforcement actions resulting in a finding by the Administrator of a violation of this title or a regulation prescribed or order issued under this title that was not subsequently overturned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46731-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air carrier and other records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>From any air carrier or other person (except a branch of the Armed Forces, the National Guard, or a reserve component of the Armed Forces) that has employed an individual as a pilot of a civil or public aircraft, or from the trustee in bankruptcy for the air carrier or person—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46732-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> records pertaining to the individual that are maintained by the air carrier (other than records relating to flight time, duty time, or rest time) or person, including records under regulations set forth in—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46733-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> section 121.683 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46734-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> section 121.111(a) of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46735-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> section 121.219(a) of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46736-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> section 125.401 of such title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46737-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> section 135.63(a)(4) of such title; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46738-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> other records pertaining to the individual’s performance as a pilot that are maintained by the air carrier or person concerning—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46739-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the training, qualifications, proficiency, or professional competence of the individual, including comments and evaluations made by a check airman designated in accordance with section 121.411, 125.295, or 135.337 of such title;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4673a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any disciplinary action taken with respect to the individual that was not subsequently overturned; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4673b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> any release from employment or resignation, termination, or disqualification with respect to employment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4673c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National driver register records</inline>.—</heading><content>In accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s30305/b/8">section 30305(b)(8) of this title</ref>, from the chief driver licensing official of a State, information concerning the motor vehicle driving record of the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4673d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Written consent; release from liability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An air carrier—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4673e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall obtain the written consent of an individual before accessing records pertaining to the individual under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4673f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may, notwithstanding any other provision of law or agreement to the contrary, require an individual with respect to whom the carrier is accessing records under paragraph (1) to execute a release from liability for any claim arising from accessing the records or the use of such records by the air carrier in accordance with this section (other than a claim arising from furnishing information known to be false and maintained in violation of a criminal statute).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46740-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46741-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting by administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall enter data described in paragraph (2)(A) into the database promptly to ensure that an individual’s records are current.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46742-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting by air carriers and other persons.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46743-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Air carriers and other persons shall report data described in paragraphs (2)(B) and (2)(C) to the Administrator promptly for entry into the database.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46744-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data to be reported</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Air carriers and other persons shall report, at a minimum, under clause (i) the following data described in paragraph (2)(B):</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46745-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Records that are generated by the air carrier or other person after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46746-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/4/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Records that the air carrier or other person is maintaining, on such date of enactment, pursuant to subsection (h)(4).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46747-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement to maintain records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46748-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall maintain all records entered into the database under paragraph (2) pertaining to an individual until the date of receipt of notification that the individual is deceased; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46749-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may remove the individual’s records from the database after that date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4674a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Receipt of consent</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall not permit an air carrier to access records pertaining to an individual from the database under paragraph (1) without the air carrier first demonstrating to the satisfaction of the Administrator that the air carrier has obtained the written consent of the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4674b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Right of pilot to review certain records and correct inaccuracies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or agreement, the Administrator, upon receipt of written request from an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4674c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall make available, not later than 30 days after the date of the request, to the individual for review all records referred to in paragraph (2) pertaining to the individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4674d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall provide the individual with a reasonable opportunity to submit written comments to correct any inaccuracies contained in the records.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4674e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reasonable charges for processing requests and furnishing copies.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4674f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may establish a reasonable charge for the cost of processing a request under paragraph (1) or (7) and for the cost of furnishing copies of requested records under paragraph (7).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46750-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crediting appropriations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Funds received by the Administrator pursuant to this paragraph shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46751-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be credited to the appropriation current when the amount is received;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46752-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be merged with and available for the purposes of such appropriation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46753-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/8/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> remain available until expended.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46754-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Privacy protections.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46755-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of records</inline>.—</heading><content>An air carrier that accesses records pertaining to an individual under paragraph (1) may use the records only to assess the qualifications of the individual in deciding whether or not to hire the individual as a pilot. The air carrier shall take such actions as may be necessary to protect the privacy of the individual and the confidentiality of the records accessed, including ensuring that information contained in the records is not divulged to any individual that is not directly involved in the hiring decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46756-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of information.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46757-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided by clause (ii), information collected by the Administrator under paragraph (2) shall be exempt from the disclosure requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/3/B">section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46758-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Clause (i) shall not apply to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf46759-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> deidentified, summarized information to explain the need for changes in policies and regulations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4675a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> information to correct a condition that compromises safety;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4675b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> information to carry out a criminal investigation or prosecution;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4675c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> information to comply with section 44905, regarding information about threats to civil aviation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf4675d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/9/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> such information as the Administrator determines necessary, if withholding the information would not be consistent with the safety responsibilities of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4675e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Periodic review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, and at least once every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a statement that contains, taking into account recent developments in the aviation industry—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4675f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> recommendations by the Administrator concerning proposed changes to Federal Aviation Administration records, air carrier records, and other records required to be included in the database under paragraph (2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46760-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reasons why the Administrator does not recommend any proposed changes to the records referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46761-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations for protection and security of records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46762-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to protect and secure—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46763-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the personal privacy of any individual whose records are accessed under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46764-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the confidentiality of those records; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46765-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to preclude the further dissemination of records received under paragraph (1) by the person who accessed the records.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46766-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good faith exception</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an air carrier may allow an individual to begin service as a pilot, without first obtaining information described in paragraph (2)(B) from the database pertaining to the individual, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46767-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the air carrier has made a documented good faith attempt to access the information from the database; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46768-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the air carrier has received written notice from the Administrator that the information is not contained in the database because the individual was employed by an air carrier or other person that no longer exists or by a foreign government or other entity that has not provided the information to the database.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46769-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on electronic access to records.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4676a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access by individuals designated by air carriers</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of increasing timely and efficient access to records described in paragraph (2), the Administrator may allow, under terms established by the Administrator, an individual designated by an air carrier to have electronic access to the database.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4676b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The terms established by the Administrator under subparagraph (A) for allowing a designated individual to have electronic access to the database shall limit such access to instances in which information in the database is required by the designated individual in making a hiring decision concerning a pilot applicant and shall require that the designated individual provide assurances satisfactory to the Administrator that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf4676c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/13/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the designated individual has received the written consent of the pilot applicant to access the information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf4676d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/13/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> information obtained using such access will not be used for any purpose other than making the hiring decision.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4676e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorized expenditures</inline>.—</heading><content>Of amounts appropriated under section 106(k)(1), a total of $6,000,000 for fiscal years 2010 through 2013 may be used to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4676f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46770-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall issue regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46771-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The regulations shall specify the date on which the requirements of this subsection take effect and the date on which the requirements of subsection (h) cease to be effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46772-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46773-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Administrator shall begin to establish the database under paragraph (2) not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46774-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Administrator shall maintain records in accordance with paragraph (5) beginning on the date of enactment of this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46775-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/15/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> air carriers and other persons shall maintain records to be reported to the database under paragraph (4)(B) in the period beginning on such date of enactment and ending on the date that is 5 years after the requirements of subsection (h) cease to be effective pursuant to subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46776-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/i/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule</inline>.—</heading><content>During the one-year period beginning on the date on which the requirements of this section become effective pursuant to paragraph (15)(B), paragraph (7)(A) shall be applied by substituting “45 days” for “30 days”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf46777-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Liability; Preemption of State Law.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46778-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on liability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No action or proceeding may be brought by or on behalf of an individual who has applied for or is seeking a position with an air carrier as a pilot and who has signed a release from liability, as provided for under subsection (h)(2) or (i)(3), against—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46779-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the air carrier requesting the records of that individual under subsection (h)(1) or accessing the records of that individual under subsection (i)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4677a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a person who has complied with such request;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4677b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a person who has entered information contained in the individual’s records; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4677c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an agent or employee of a person described in subparagraph (A) or (B);</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">in the nature of an action for defamation, invasion of privacy, negligence, interference with contract, or otherwise, or under any Federal or State law with respect to the furnishing or use of such records in accordance with subsection (h) or (i).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4677d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preemption</inline>.—</heading><content>No State or political subdivision thereof may enact, prescribe, issue, continue in effect, or enforce any law (including any regulation, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law) that prohibits, penalizes, or imposes liability for furnishing or using records in accordance with subsection (h) or (i).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4677e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of knowingly false information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply with respect to a person who furnishes information in response to a request made under subsection (h)(1) or who furnished information to the database established under subsection (i)(2), that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf4677f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the person knows is false; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46780-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> was maintained in violation of a criminal statute of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46781-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on actions and proceedings against air carriers.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46782-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hiring decisions</inline>.—</heading><content>An air carrier may refuse to hire an individual as a pilot if the individual did not provide written consent for the air carrier to receive records under subsection (h)(2)(A) or (i)(3)(A) or did not execute the release from liability requested under subsection (h)(2)(B) or (i)(3)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46783-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/j/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Actions and proceedings</inline>.—</heading><content>No action or proceeding may be brought against an air carrier by or on behalf of an individual who has applied for or is seeking a position as a pilot with the air carrier if the air carrier refused to hire the individual after the individual did not provide written consent for the air carrier to receive records under subsection (h)(2)(A) or (i)(3)(A) or did not execute a release from liability requested under subsection (h)(2)(B) or (i)(3)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf46784-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in subsection (h) or (i) shall be construed as precluding the availability of the records of a pilot in an investigation or other proceeding concerning an accident or incident conducted by the Administrator, the National Transportation Safety Board, or a court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf46785-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary Airman Certificate</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual may obtain a temporary airman certificate from the Administrator after requesting a permanent replacement airman certificate issued under this section. A temporary airman certificate shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf46786-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> made available—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46787-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> electronically to the individual immediately upon submitting an online application for a replacement certificate to the Administrator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf46788-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> physically to the individual at a flight standards district office—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf46789-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if the individual submits an online application for a replacement certificate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf4678a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the individual applies for a permanent replacement certificate other than by online application and such application has been received by the Federal Aviation Administration; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf4678b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44703/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> destroyed upon receipt of the permanent replacement airman certificate from the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcbf4678c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s1/e">Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1186">108 Stat. 1186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/181/tVII/s715">Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 715</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/162">114 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/71/tI">Pub. L. 107–71, title I</ref>, §§ 129, 138(b), 140(a), <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/633">115 Stat. 633</ref>, 640, 641; <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/tII/s203">Pub. L. 111–216, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2010-08-01">Aug. 1, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2352">124 Stat. 2352</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2010-09-30">Sept. 30, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2629">124 Stat. 2629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tIII">Pub. L. 112–95, title III</ref>, §§ 301(a), 310(c), <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/56">126 Stat. 56</ref>, 65; <ref href="/us/pl/112/153/s2/c/1">Pub. L. 112–153, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-03">Aug. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1160">126 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tVIII/s802/d/2">Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/210">130 Stat. 210</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/190/tII/s2101">Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2101</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/619">130 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s813">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1327">138 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcbf4678d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcbf4678e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls65,xs89,tp7,s10,xls65,xs89; " id="idcbf4678f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:69pt ; max-width:69pt;" />
<html:col style="width:93pt ; max-width:93pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:69.0pt ; max-width:69.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:93.0pt ; max-width:93.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(a)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(1) (1st sentence, 2d sentence words before 6th comma).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 23, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/726/s602/b/1">Pub. L. 85–726, § 602(b)(1)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/72/776">72 Stat. 776</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Oct. 19, 1984</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/98/499/s3">Pub. L. 98–499, § 3</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/98/2313">98 Stat. 2313</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Aug. 26, 1992</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/102/345/s4">Pub. L. 102–345, § 4</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/106/926">106 Stat. 926</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 15, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/670/s6/c/1">Pub. L. 89–670, § 6(c)(1)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/938">80 Stat. 938</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Jan. 12, 1983</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/97/449/s7/b">Pub. L. 97–449, § 7(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/96/2444">96 Stat. 2444</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(b)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(a) (11th–last words).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 23, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/726/s602/a">Pub. L. 85–726, § 602(a)</html:a> (9th–last words), (c), <html:a href="/us/stat/72/776">72 Stat. 776</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(1) (2d sentence words after 6th comma), (c).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(c)(1)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(1) (3d sentence).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(c)(2)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(1) (4th, 5th sentences, last sentence words before proviso).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(d)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(1) (last sentence proviso).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(e)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(b)(2)(A), (B).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 23, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/726">Pub. L. 85–726</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/72/731">72 Stat. 731</html:a>, § 602(b)(2)(A), (B); added <html:span class="date">Oct. 19, 1984</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/98/499/s3">Pub. L. 98–499, § 3</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/98/2313">98 Stat. 2313</html:a>; restated <html:span class="date">Nov. 18, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/690/s7204/a">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7204(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/102/4425">102 Stat. 4425</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(f)(1)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1422(d).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 23, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/726">Pub. L. 85–726</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/72/731">72 Stat. 731</html:a>, § 602(d); added <html:span class="date">Nov. 18, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/690/s7205/a">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7205(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/102/4426">102 Stat. 4426</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44703(f)(2)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1401 (note).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Nov. 18, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/100/690/s7207/a">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7207(a)</html:a> (1st sentence), (b), <html:a href="/us/stat/102/4427">102 Stat. 4427</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p>In subsections (a)–(d), the word “Administrator” in section 602(a), (b)(1), and (c) of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 (<ref href="/us/pl/85/726">Public Law 85–726</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/776">72 Stat. 776</ref>) is retained on authority of 49:106(g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the text of 49 App.:1422(b) (1st sentence) is omitted as surplus. The words “is qualified” are substituted for “possesses proper qualifications” to eliminate unnecessary words. The words “to be authorized by the certificate” are substituted for “for which the airman certificate is sought” for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(1)(C), the words “conditions, and limitations” are omitted as being included in “terms”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(1)(E), the word “designate” is substituted for “be entitled with the designation of” to eliminate unnecessary words.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(1), before clause (A), the words “may appeal . . . to” are substituted for “may file with . . . a petition for review of the Secretary of Transportation’s action” for consistency with section 1109 of the revised title. The words “the individual holds a certificate that” are substituted for “persons whose certificates” for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(2), the words “conduct a hearing on the appeal” are substituted for “thereupon assign such petition for hearing” for consistency. The words “In the conduct of such hearing and in determining whether the airman meets the pertinent rules, regulations, or standards” are omitted as surplus. The word “Administrator” is substituted for “Federal Aviation Administration” because of 49:106(b) and (g). The words “meets the applicable regulations” are substituted for “meets the pertinent rules, regulations” because “rules” and “regulations” are synonymous and for consistency in the revised title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (d), before clause (1), the words “in his discretion” are omitted as surplus. In clause (2), the words “the terms of” and “entered into” are omitted as surplus. The words “government of a foreign country” are substituted for “foreign governments” for consistency in the revised title and with other titles of the United States Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f)(1), before clause (A), the words “established under this chapter” and “to pilots” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f)(2), the words “Not later than <date date="1989-09-18">September 18, 1989</date>” and “final” are omitted as obsolete. The words “Administrator of Drug Enforcement” are substituted for “Drug Enforcement Administration of the Department of Justice” because of section 5(a) of Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1973 (eff. <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1092">87 Stat. 1092</ref>). The words “Commissioner of Customs” are substituted for “United States Customs Service” because of 19:2071.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcbf46790-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcbf46791-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Wendell H. Ford Aviation Investment and Reform Act for the 21st Century, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), (3), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/106/181">Pub. L. 106–181</ref>, which was approved <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Pilot Records Improvement Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (h)(12), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref>, which was approved <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this paragraph, referred to in subsec. (i)(4)(B)(ii), (10), (15)(C), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/111/216">Pub. L. 111–216</ref>, which was approved <date date="2010-08-01">Aug. 1, 2010</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcbf46792-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The text of section 44936(f) to (h) of this title, which was transferred to the end of this section, redesignated as subsecs. (h) to (j), respectively, and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/71">Pub. L. 107–71</ref>, §§ 138(b), 140(a), was based on <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/tV/s502/a">Pub. L. 104–264, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3259">110 Stat. 3259</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/102/s2/25">Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(25)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2205">111 Stat. 2205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/142/s1">Pub. L. 105–142, § 1</ref>, <date date="1997-12-05">Dec. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2650">111 Stat. 2650</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/181/tV/s508/b">Pub. L. 106–181, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/140">114 Stat. 140</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcbf46793-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63">Pub. L. 118–63</ref> added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/190">Pub. L. 114–190</ref> substituted “Not later than <date date="2017-04-30">April 30, 2017</date>, the Administrator shall establish and make available for use” for “The Administrator shall establish”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/153">Pub. L. 112–153</ref> struck out “but is bound by all validly adopted interpretations of laws and regulations the Administrator carries out unless the Board finds an interpretation is arbitrary, capricious, or otherwise not according to law” after “Federal Aviation Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/s301/a">Pub. L. 112–95, § 301(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(9)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/s310/c">Pub. L. 112–95, § 310(c)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/3/B">section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (h)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/a">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(a)</ref>, added par. (16).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/b/2">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/A">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, substituted “Limitations” for “Limitation” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (j). Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/B/i">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, (iii), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, substituted “subsection (h)(2) or (i)(3)” for “paragraph (2)” in introductory provisions and “subsection (h) or (i)” for “subsection (h)” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, inserted “or accessing the records of that individual under subsection (i)(1)” before semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/C">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(C)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, substituted “subsection (h) or (i)” for “subsection (h)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/D">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(D)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, inserted “or who furnished information to the database established under subsection (i)(2)” after “subsection (h)(1)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/1/E">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(1)(E)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/3">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/c/2">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(c)(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6/4">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6(4)</ref>, substituted “subsection (h) or (i)” for “subsection (h)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/216/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 111–216, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/71/s129/1">Pub. L. 107–71, § 129(1)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “needs of airmen” for “needs of pilots” and inserted “and related to combating acts of terrorism” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/71/s129/2">Pub. L. 107–71, § 129(2)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/107/71">Pub. L. 107–71</ref>, §§ 138(b), 140(a), amended section identically, redesignating subsecs. (f) to (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44936">section 44936 of this title</ref> as subsecs. (h) to (j), respectively, of this section, and substituting “subsection (h)” for “subsection (f)” wherever appearing in subsecs. (i) and (j). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (c) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/106/181">Pub. L. 106–181</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) to (f) as (d) to (g), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcbf46794-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idcbf46795-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection” substituted for “Commissioner of Customs” in subsec. (g)(2) on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/d/2">section 802(d)(2) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcbf46796-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6">Pub. L. 111–249, § 6</ref>, <date date="2010-09-30">Sept. 30, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2628">124 Stat. 2628</ref>, provided that the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/111/249/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 111–249</ref> are effective as of <date date="2010-08-01">Aug. 1, 2010</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/111/216">Pub. L. 111–216</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcbf46797-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/181">Pub. L. 106–181</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1999-09-30">Sept. 30, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/181/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 106–181</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="idcbf46798-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h) of this section ceased to be effective beginning on <date date="2024-09-09">Sept. 9, 2024</date>, pursuant to par. (16) of that subsec. See 14 C.F.R. § 111.5(b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idcbf46799-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf4679a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deemed References to Chapters 509 and 511 of Title 51</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">General references to “this title” deemed to refer also to chapters 509 and 511 of Title 51, National and Commercial Space Programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/314/s4/d/8">section 4(d)(8) of Pub. L. 111–314</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf4679b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhanced Qualification Program for Restricted Airline Transport Pilot Certificate</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s372">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 372</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1139">138 Stat. 1139</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s372">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall establish the requirements for a program to be known as the Enhanced Qualification Program (in this section referred to as the ‘Program’) under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> qualified air carriers are certified by the Administrator to provide enhanced training for eligible pilots seeking to obtain restricted airline transport certificates, either directly by the air carrier or by a certified training institution under part 141 or part 142 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that is under contract with the qualified air carrier; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> qualified instructors and evaluators provide enhanced training to eligible pilots pursuant to the curriculum requirements under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified instructors and evaluators</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the Program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> all testing and training shall be performed by qualified instructors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> all evaluations shall be performed by qualified evaluators.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot assessment</inline>.—</heading><content>Under the Program, the Administrator shall establish guidelines for an assessment that prospective pilots are required to pass in order to participate in the training under the Program. Such assessment shall include an evaluation of the pilot’s aptitude, ability, and readiness for operation of transport category aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program curriculum</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the Program, the Administrator shall establish requirements for the curriculum to be provided under the Program. Such curriculum shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> a nationally standardized, non-air carrier or aircraft-specific training curriculum which shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> ensure prospective pilots have appropriate knowledge at the commercial pilot certificate, multi-engine rating, and instrument rating level;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> introduce the pilots to concepts associated with air carrier operations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> meet all requirements for an ATP Certification Training Program under part 61.156 or part 142 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> include a course of instruction designed to prepare the prospective pilot to take the ATP Multiengine Airplane Knowledge Test;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> an aircraft-specific training curriculum, developed by the air carrier using objectives and learning standards developed by the Administrator, which shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> only be administered to prospective pilots who have completed the requirements under subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> resemble a type rating training curriculum that includes aircraft ground and flight training that culminates in—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the completion of a maneuvers evaluation that incorporates elements of a type rating practical test; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> at the discretion of the air carrier, an actual type rating practical test resulting in the issuance of a type rating for the specific aircraft; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> ensure the prospective pilot has an adequate understanding and working knowledge of transport category aircraft automation and autoflight systems; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> air carrier-specific procedures using objectives and learning standards developed by the Administrator to further expand on the concepts described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), which shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> only be administered to prospective pilots who have completed requirements under subparagraphs (A) and (B) and an ATP Multiengine Airplane Knowledge Test;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> include instructions on air carrier checklist usage and standard operating procedures; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> integrate aircraft-specific training in appropriate flight simulation training devices representing the specific aircraft type, including complete crew resource management and scenario-based training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application and certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the Program, the Administrator shall establish a process for air carriers to apply for training program certification. Such process shall include a review to ensure that the training provided by the air carrier will meet the requirements of this section, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the assessment requirements under paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the curriculum requirements under paragraph (4);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the requirements for qualified instructors under subsection (d)(5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the requirements for eligible pilots under subsection (d)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data</inline>.—</heading><content>Under the Program, the Administrator shall require that each qualified air carrier participating in the Program collect and submit to the Administrator such data from the Program that the Administrator determines is appropriate for the Administrator to provide for oversight of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regular inspection</inline>.—</heading><content>Under the Program, the Administrator shall provide for the regular inspection of qualified air carriers certified under paragraph (5) to ensure that the air carrier continues to meet the requirements under the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may issue regulations or guidance as determined necessary to carry out the Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Clarification Regarding Required Flight Hours</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this section shall have no effect on the total flight hours required under part 61.159 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to receive an airline transport pilot certificate, or the Administrator’s authority under section 217(d) of the Airline Safety and Federal Aviation Administration Extension Act of 2010 [<ref href="/us/pl/111/216">Pub. L. 111–216</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</ref> note) (as in effect on the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>]).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air carrier</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘air carrier’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40102">section 40102 of title 49</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible pilot</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘eligible pilot’ means a pilot that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> has—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> graduated from a United States Armed Forces undergraduate pilot training school;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> obtained a degree with an aviation major from an institution of higher education (as defined in part 61.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) that has been issued a letter of authorization by the Administrator under part 61.169 of such title 14; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> completed flight and ground training for a commercial pilot certificate in the airplane category and an airplane instrument rating at a certified training institution under part 141 of such title 14;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> has a current commercial pilot certificate under part 61.123 of such title 14, with airplane category multi-engine and instrument ratings under part 61.129 of such title 14; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> meets the pilot assessment requirements under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified air carrier</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘qualified air carrier’ means an air carrier that has been issued a part 119 operating certificate for conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified evaluator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘qualified evaluator’ means an individual that meets the requirements for a training center evaluator under part 142.55 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or for check airmen under part 121.411 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified instructor</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified instructor’ means an individual that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is qualified in accordance with the minimum training requirements for an ATP Certification Training Program under paragraphs (1) through (3) of part 121.410(b) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> if the instructor is a flight instructor, is qualified in accordance with part 121.410(b)(4) of such title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> if the instructor is administering type rating practical tests, is qualified as an appropriate examiner for such rating;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> received training in threat and error management, facilitation, and risk mitigation determined appropriate by the Administrator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> meets any other requirement determined appropriate by the Administrator.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf4679c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Civil Airmen Statistics</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1148">138 Stat. 1148</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s402">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication Frequency</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall publish the study commonly referred to as the ‘U.S. Civil Airmen Statistics’ on a monthly basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presentation of Data</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall make the data from the study under subsection (a) publicly available on the website of the Administration in a user-friendly, downloadable format.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expanded Data Criteria</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator shall ensure that data sets and tables published as part of the study described in subsection (a) display information relating to the sex of certificate holders in more instances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Historical Data</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall make all previously published annual data from the study described in subsection (a) available on the website of the Administration.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf4679d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Airman’s Medical Bill of Rights</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1153">138 Stat. 1153</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s407">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall develop a document (in this section referred to as the ‘Airman’s Medical Bill of Rights’) detailing the rights of an individual before, during, and after a medical examination conducted by an Aviation Medical Examiner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Airman’s Medical Bill of Rights required under paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, contain information about the right of an individual to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> bring a trusted companion or request to have a chaperone present for a medical examination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> terminate an exam in accordance with guidelines from the Administrator for appropriately terminating such exam;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> receive medical examination with respect and recognition of the dignity of the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> be assured of privacy and confidentiality;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> select an Aviation Medical Examiner of the choice of the individual, as long as the Aviation Medical Examiner has the required designations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> privacy when changing, undressing, and using the restroom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> ask questions about FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] medical standards and the applicability to the current health status of the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> report an incident of misconduct by an Aviation Medical Examiner to the appropriate authorities, including to the State licensing board of the Aviation Medical Examiner or the FAA;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> report to the Administrator an allegation regarding alleged Aviation Medical Examiner misconduct without fear of retaliation or negative action relating to an airman certificate of the individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> be advised of any known conflicts of interest an Aviation Medical Examiner may have with respect to the medical examination of the individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public availability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Airman’s Medical Bill of Rights required under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> made available to, and acknowledged by, an individual in the MedXpress system (or any successor system);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> made available in a hard-copy format by an Aviation Medical Examiner at the time of exam upon request by an individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> displayed in a common space in the office of the Aviation Medical Examiner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expectations for Medical Examinations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop a simplified document explaining the standard procedures performed during a medical examination conducted by an Aviation Medical Examiner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public availability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The document required under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> made available to, and acknowledged by, an individual in the MedXpress system (or any successor system);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> made available in a hard-copy format by an Aviation Medical Examiner at the time of exam upon request by an individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> displayed in a common space in the office of the Aviation Medical Examiner.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf4679e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improved Designee Misconduct Reporting Process</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s408">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1154">138 Stat. 1154</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s408">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Improved Designee Misconduct Reporting Process.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall establish a streamlined process for individuals involved in incidents of alleged misconduct by a designee to report such incidents in a manner that protects the privacy and confidentiality of such individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public access to reporting process</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The process for reporting alleged misconduct by a designee shall be made available to the public on the website of the Administration, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the designee locator search webpage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the webpage of the Office of Audit and Evaluation of the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obligation to report criminal charges</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall revise the orders and policies governing the Designee Management System to clarify that designees are obligated to report any arrest, indictment, or conviction for violation of a local, State, or Federal law within a period of time specified by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Audit of reporting process by inspector general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the Administrator finalizes the update of the reporting process under paragraph (1), the inspector general of the Department of Transportation shall conduct an audit of such reporting process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the audit of the reporting process described in subparagraph (A), the inspector general shall, at a minimum—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> review the efforts of the Administration to improve the reporting process and solutions developed to respond to and investigate allegations of misconduct;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> analyze reports of misconduct brought to the Administrator prior to any changes made to the reporting process as a result of the enactment of this Act [<ref href="/us/pl/118/63">Pub. L. 118–63</ref>], including the ultimate outcomes of those reports and whether any reports resulted in the Administrator taking action against the accused designee;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> determine whether the reporting process results in appropriate action, including reviewing, investigating, and closing out reports; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> if applicable, make recommendations to improve the reporting process.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of initiation of the audit described in subparagraph (A), the inspector general shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a report on the results of such audit, including findings and recommendations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designee Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘designee’ means an individual who has been designated to act as a representative of the Administrator as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an Aviation Medical Examiner (as described in section 183.21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a pilot examiner (as described in section 183.23 of such title); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a technical personnel examiner (as described in section 183.25 of such title).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d79f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Aeromedical Innovation and Modernization Working Group</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1156">138 Stat. 1156</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s411">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall establish a working group (in this section referred to as the ‘working group’) to review the medical processes, policies, and procedures of the Administration and to make recommendations to the Administrator on modernizing such processes, policies, and procedures to ensure timely and efficient certification of airmen.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The working group shall consist of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> 2 co-chairs described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> not less than 15 individuals appointed by the Administrator, each of whom shall have knowledge or a background in aerospace medicine, psychiatry, neurology, cardiology, or internal medicine.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Co-chairs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The working group shall be co-chaired by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Federal Air Surgeon of the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a member described under paragraph (1)(A) to be selected by members of the working group.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator, in appointing members pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), shall give preference to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Aviation Medical Examiners (as described in section 183.21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> licensed medical physicians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> practitioners holding a pilot certificate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> individuals having demonstrated research and expertise in aeromedical research or sciences.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In reviewing the aeromedical decision-making processes, policies, and procedures of the Administration in accordance with subsection (a), the working group, at a minimum, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> assess the medical conditions an Aviation Medical Examiner may issue a medical certificate directly to an individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> determine the appropriateness of the list of such medical conditions as of the date of enactment of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> assess the special issuance process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> determine the appropriateness of whether a renewal of a special issuance can be based on a medical evaluation and treatment plan by the treating medical specialist of the individual pursuant to approval from an Aviation Medical Examiner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> evaluate advancements in technologies to address forms of red-green color blindness and determine whether such technologies may be approved for use by airmen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> review policies and guidance relating to Attention-Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder and Attention Deficit Disorder;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> evaluate whether medications used to treat such disorders may be safely prescribed to airmen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> review protocols pertaining to the Human Intervention Motivation Study of the FAA;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><chapeau> review protocols and policies relating to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> neurological disorders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> cardiovascular conditions to ensure alignment with medical best practices, latest research;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> review mental health protocols and medications approved for treating such mental health conditions, including such actions taken resulting from recommendations by the Mental Health and Aviation Medical Clearances Rulemaking Committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> assess processes and protocols pertaining to recertification of airmen receiving disability insurance post-recovery from the medical condition, injury, or disability that precludes airmen from exercising the privileges of an airman certificate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> assess processes and protocols pertaining to the certification of veterans reporting a disability rating from the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="13">“(13)</num><content> assess and evaluate the user interface and information-sharing capabilities of any online medical portal administered by the FAA.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Aviation Workforce Mental Health Task Group.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the working group pursuant to subsection (a) is established, the co-chairs of such working group shall establish an aviation workforce mental health task group (referred to in this subsection as the ‘task group’) to oversee, monitor, and evaluate efforts of the Administrator related to supporting the mental health of the aviation workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The co-chairs of such working group shall appoint—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a Chair of the task group; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> members of the task group from among the members of the working group appointed by the Administrator under subsection (b)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The duties of the task group shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> carrying out the activities described in subsection (c)(10);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> soliciting feedback from aviation industry professionals or other licensed professionals representing air carrier operations under part 121 and part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and general aviation operations under part 91 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> reviewing and evaluating guidance issued by the International Civil Aviation Organization on aviation workforce mental health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> providing advice, as appropriate, on the implementation of the final recommendations issued by the inspector general of the Department of Transportation in the report titled, ‘FAA Conduct Comprehensive Evaluations of Pilots With Mental Health Challenges, but Opportunities Exist to Further Mitigate Safety Risks’, published on <date date="2023-07-12">July 12, 2023</date> (AV2023038);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> monitoring and evaluating the implementation of recommendations by the Mental Health and Aviation Medical Clearances Rulemaking Committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> expanding and improving mental health outreach, education, and assistance programs for the aviation workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> reducing the stigma associated with mental healthcare in the aviation workforce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of the establishment of the task group, the task group shall submit to the Secretary [of Transportation] and the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a report detailing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the results of the review under paragraph (3)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> progress on the implementation of recommendations pursuant to subparagraphs (D) and (E) of paragraph (3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the activities carried out pursuant to fulfilling the duties described in subparagraphs (F) and (G) of paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Support</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall seek to enter into 1 or more agreements with the National Academies to support the activities of the working group described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings and Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the working group shall submit to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the findings and recommendations resulting from the activities carried out under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after receiving recommendations outlined in the report under subsection (f), the Administrator may take such action, as appropriate, to implement such recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The working group shall terminate on <date date="2028-10-01">October 1, 2028</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Medical Portal Modernization Task Group</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1159">138 Stat. 1159</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s413">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the working group pursuant to section 411 [of <ref href="/us/pl/118/63">Pub. L. 118–63</ref>, set out as a note above] is established, the co-chairs of such working group shall establish a medical portal modernization task group (in this section referred to as the ‘task group’) to evaluate the user interface and information sharing capabilities of an online medical portal administered by the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The co-chairs of the working group provided for in section 411 shall appoint—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a Chair of the task group; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> members of the task group from among the members of the working group appointed by the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] under section 411(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment; Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The task group shall, at a minimum, assess and evaluate the capabilities of any such medical portal and provide recommendations to improve the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The cybersecurity protections and protocols of any such medical portal, including the secure exchange of health information and records between Aviation Medical Examiners and pilots, or their designee, including the ability for airmen to submit additional information requested by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The status of an airman’s medical application and the disclosure of how long an airman can expect to wait for a final determination to be issued by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The disclosure of the name and contact information of the Administrator’s representative managing an airman’s case so that an Aviation Medical Examiner has a point of contact within the Administration who is familiar with an airman’s application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the duties described in subsection (c), the task group may consult with cybersecurity experts and individuals with a knowledge of securing electronic health care transactions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the establishment of the task group, the task group shall submit to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a report detailing activities and recommendations of the task group.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after receiving the report described in subsection (e), the Administrator may take such action as may be necessary to implement recommendations of the task group to improve any such medical portal.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Military Aviation Maintenance Technicians Rule</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s426">Pub. L. 118–63, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1168">138 Stat. 1168</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIV/s426">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Streamlined Certification for Eligible Military Maintenance Technicians.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to revise part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> create a military mechanic written competency test that addresses gaps between military and civilian experience; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> develop, as necessary, a relevant Airman Certification Standard to qualify eligible military maintenance technicians for a civilian mechanic certificate with airframe or powerplant ratings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall evaluate and consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> whether to allow a certificate of eligibility from the Joint Services Aviation Maintenance Technician Certification Council (in this section referred to as the ‘JSAMTCC’) evidencing completion of a training curriculum for any rating sought to serve as a substitute to fulfill the requirement under such part 65 for oral and practical tests administered by a designated mechanic examiner for eligible military maintenance technicians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> aeronautical knowledge subject areas contained in the Aviation Mechanic General, Airframe, and Powerplant Airman Certification Standards as described in section 65.75 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as appropriate, to the rating sought; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any applicable recommendations by the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Airman Certification System Working Group.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expansion of Testing Locations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall determine—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> whether an expansion of the number of active testing locations operated within military installation testing centers would increase access to testing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> how to implement such expansion, if appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach and Awareness</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall develop a plan to increase outreach and awareness regarding services made available by the JSAMTCC and how such services can assist in facilitating the transition between military and civilian aviation maintenance careers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Administrator develops the outreach and awareness plan pursuant to subsection (c), the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a briefing on the activities planned to implement the outreach and awareness plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Periodic briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a briefing on any rulemaking activities carried out pursuant to subsection (a), including a timeline for the issuance of a final rule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Military Maintenance Technician Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section, the term ‘eligible military maintenance technician’ means an individual who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> has been a maintenance technician during service in the armed forces who was honorably discharged or has retired from the armed forces (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> presents an official record of service in the armed forces confirming that the individual has been a military aviation maintenance technician, holding an appropriate Military Occupational Specialty Code, as determined by the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> presents documentary evidence of experience in accordance with the requirements under section 65.77 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Timely Resolution of Investigations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s805">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1323">138 Stat. 1323</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s805">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of issuance of a letter of investigation to any person, as required by section 2(b) of the Pilot’s Bill of Rights [<ref href="/us/pl/112/153">Pub. L. 112–153</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</ref> note), the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> make a determination regarding such investigation and pursue subsequent action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> close such investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If, upon review of the facts and status of an investigation described in subsection (a), the Administrator determines that the time provided to make a final determination or close such investigation is insufficient, the Administrator shall approve an extension of such investigation for 2 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional extensions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may approve consecutive extensions under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may not delegate the authority to approve an extension described in subsection (b) to anyone other than the leadership of the Administration as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106/b">section 106(b) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">All Makes and Models Authorization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1323">138 Stat. 1323</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s806">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Unlimited letter of authorization</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall take such action as may be necessary to allow for the issuance of letters of authorizations to airmen with the authorization for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> all types and makes of experimental high–performance single engine piston powered aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> all types and makes of experimental high–performance multiengine piston powered aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual who holds a letter of authorization and applies for an authorization described in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> shall be given an all-makes and models authorization of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> experimental single–engine piston powered authorized aircraft; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> experimental multiengine piston powered authorized aircraft;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> shall hold the appropriate category and class rating for the authorized aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> shall hold 3 experimental aircraft authorizations in aircraft of the same category and class rating for the authorization sought; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> may become qualified in additional experimental aircraft by completing aircraft-specific ground and flight training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed to disallow an individual from being given both an authorization described in paragraph (1)(A) and an authorization described in paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to Comply.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator fails to implement subsection (a) within the time period prescribed in such subsection, the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] on the status of the implementation of such subsection on a monthly basis until the implementation is complete.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No delegation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may not delegate the briefing described in paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">BasicMed for Examiners Administering Tests or Proficiency Checks</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s815">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 815</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1328">138 Stat. 1328</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s815">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equivalent Pilot-in-command Medical Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 61.23(a)(3)(iv) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, an examiner may administer a practical test or proficiency check if such examiner meets the medical qualification requirements under part 68 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, if the operation being conducted is in a covered aircraft, as such term is defined in section 2307(j) of the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016 [<ref href="/us/pl/114/190">Pub. L. 114–190</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall issue a final rule to update part 61 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to implement the requirements under subsection (a), in addition to any related requirements the Administrator finds are in the interest of aviation safety.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Designee Locator Tool Improvements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s816">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1328">138 Stat. 1328</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s816">
<inline>“Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall ensure that the designee locator search function of the public website of the Designee Management System of the Administration has the functionality to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> filter a search for an Aviation Medical Examiner (as described in section 183.21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) by sex, if such information is available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> display credentials and aircraft qualifications of a designated pilot examiner (as described in section 183.23 of such title); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> display the scheduling availability of a designated pilot examiner (as described in section 183.23 of such title) to administer a test or proficiency check to an airman.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Coordination and Oversight of Designated Pilot Examiners</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s833">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 833</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1339">138 Stat. 1339</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s833">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall establish an office to provide oversight and facilitate national coordination of designated pilot examiners appointed under section 183.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The office described in subsection (a) shall be responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Oversight of designated pilot examiners appointed under section 183.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Coordinating with other offices, as appropriate, to support the standardization of policy, guidance, and regulations across the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] pertaining to the selection, training, duties, and deployment of designated pilot examiners appointed under section 183.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, including evaluating the consistency by which such examiners apply Administration policies, orders, and guidance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Evaluating the consistency by which such examiners apply FAA policies, orders, and guidance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Coordinating placement and deployment of such examiners across regions based on demand for examinations from the pilot community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Developing a code of conduct for such examiners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Deploying a survey system to track the performance and merit of such examiners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Facilitating an industry partnership to create a formal mentorship program for such examiners.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the responsibilities listed in subsection (b), the Administrator shall ensure the office—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> coordinates on an ongoing basis with flight standards district offices, designated pilot examiner managing specialists, and aviation industry stakeholders, including representatives of the general aviation community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> considers whether to implement the final recommendations report issued by the Designated Pilot Examiner Reforms Working Group and accepted by the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee on <date date="2021-06-17">June 17, 2021</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], and biennially thereafter through fiscal year 2028, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a report that evaluates the use of designated pilot examiners appointed under section 183.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), for testing, including both written and practical tests.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report under paragraph (1) shall include an analysis of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the methodology and rationale by which designated pilot examiners are deployed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to the previous fiscal year, the average time an individual in each region must wait to schedule an appointment with a designated pilot examiner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> with respect to the previous fiscal year, the estimated total time individuals in each region were forced to wait to schedule an appointment with a designated pilot examiner;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the primary reasons and best ways to reduce wait times described in subparagraph (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the number of tests conducted by designated pilot examiners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the number and percentage of available designated pilot examiners that perform such tests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> the average rate of retests, including of both written and practical tests.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Medical Certification Standards to Operators of Air Balloons</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tIII/s318">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3269">132 Stat. 3269</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tIII/s318">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short Title</inline>.—</heading><content>This section may be cited as the ‘Commercial Balloon Pilot Safety Act of 2018’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall revise section 61.3(c) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to second-class medical certificates), to apply to an operator of an air balloon to the same extent such regulations apply to a pilot flight crewmember of other aircraft.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air Balloon Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘air balloon’ has the meaning given the term ‘balloon’ in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Designated Pilot Examiner Reforms</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tIII/s319">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 319</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3269">132 Stat. 3269</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tIII/s319">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall assign to the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the ‘Committee’) the task of reviewing all regulations and policies related to designated pilot examiners appointed under section 183.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations. The Committee shall focus on the processes and requirements by which the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] selects, trains, and deploys individuals as designated pilot examiners, and provide recommendations with respect to the regulatory and policy changes necessary to ensure an adequate number of designated pilot examiners are deployed and available to perform their duties. The Committee also shall make recommendations with respect to the regulatory and policy changes if necessary to allow a designated pilot examiner perform a daily limit of 3 new check rides with no limit for partial check rides and to serve as a designed pilot examiner without regard to any individual managing office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action Based on Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after receiving recommendations under subsection (a), the Administrator shall take such action as the Administrator considers appropriate with respect to those recommendations.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7a9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Public Aircraft Eligible for Logging Flight Times</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s826">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 826</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1332">138 Stat. 1332</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s826">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forestry and Fire Protection Flight Time Logging.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, aircraft under the direct operational control of forestry and fire protection agencies are eligible to log pilot flight times, if the flight time was acquired by the pilot while engaged on an official forestry or fire protection flight, in the same manner as aircraft under the direct operational control of a Federal, State, county, or municipal law enforcement agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retroactive application</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall be applied as if enacted on <date date="2018-10-05">October 5, 2018</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall make such regulatory changes as are necessary to conform to the requirements of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s517">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3359">132 Stat. 3359</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s517">“The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall issue regulations modifying section 61.51(j)(4) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, so as to include aircraft under the direct operational control of forestry and fire protection agencies as public aircraft eligible for logging flight times.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7aa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Portability of Repairman Certificates</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s582">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 582</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3399">132 Stat. 3399</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s582">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall assign to the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee the task of making recommendations with respect to the regulatory and policy changes, as appropriate, to allow a repairman certificate issued under section 65.101 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to be portable from one employing certificate holder to another.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action Based on Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after receiving recommendations under subsection (a), the Administrator may take such action as the Administrator considers appropriate with respect to those recommendations.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7ab-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Medical Certification of Certain Small Aircraft Pilots</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/190/tII/s2307">Pub. L. 114–190, title II, § 2307</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/641">130 Stat. 641</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s828/a">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 828(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1336">138 Stat. 1336</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s828/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>], the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue or revise regulations to ensure that an individual may operate as pilot in command of a covered aircraft if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the individual possesses a valid driver’s license issued by a State, territory, or possession of the United States and complies with all medical requirements or restrictions associated with that license;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the individual holds a medical certificate issued by the Federal Aviation Administration or has held such a certificate at any time after <date date="2006-07-14">July 14, 2006</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> the most recent medical certificate issued by the Federal Aviation Administration to the individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> indicates whether the certificate is first, second, or third class;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may include authorization for special issuance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> may be expired;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> cannot have been revoked or suspended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> cannot have been withdrawn;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the most recent application for airman medical certification submitted to the Federal Aviation Administration by the individual cannot have been completed and denied;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the individual has completed a medical education course described in subsection (c) during the 24 calendar months before acting as pilot in command of a covered aircraft and demonstrates proof of completion of the course;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the individual, when serving as a pilot in command, is under the care and treatment of a physician if the individual has been diagnosed with any medical condition that may impact the ability of the individual to fly;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><chapeau> the individual has received a comprehensive medical examination from a State-licensed physician during the previous 48 calendar months and—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> prior to the examination, the individual—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> completed the individual’s section of the checklist described in subsection (b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> provided the completed checklist to the physician performing the examination; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the physician conducted the comprehensive medical examination in accordance with the checklist described in subsection (b), checking each item specified during the examination and addressing, as medically appropriate, every medical condition listed, and any medications the individual is taking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><chapeau> the individual is operating in accordance with the following conditions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The covered aircraft is carrying not more than 6 passengers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The individual is operating the covered aircraft under visual flight rules or instrument flight rules.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> The flight, including each portion of that flight, is not carried out—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for compensation or hire, including that no passenger or property on the flight is being carried for compensation or hire;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> at an altitude that is more than 18,000 feet above mean sea level;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> outside the United States, unless authorized by the country in which the flight is conducted; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> at an indicated air speed exceeding 250 knots.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive Medical Examination.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>], the Administrator shall develop a checklist for an individual to complete and provide to the physician performing the comprehensive medical examination required in subsection (a)(7).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The checklist shall contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> a section, for the individual to complete that contains—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> boxes 3 through 13 and boxes 16 through 19 of the Federal Aviation Administration Form 8500–8 (3–99) (or any successor form); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> a signature line for the individual to affirm that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the answers provided by the individual on that checklist, including the individual’s answers regarding medical history, are true and complete;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the individual understands that he or she is prohibited under Federal Aviation Administration regulations from acting as pilot in command, or any other capacity as a required flight crew member, if he or she knows or has reason to know of any medical deficiency or medically disqualifying condition that would make the individual unable to operate the aircraft in a safe manner; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> the individual is aware of the regulations pertaining to the prohibition on operations during medical deficiency and has no medically disqualifying conditions in accordance with applicable law;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a section with instructions for the individual to provide the completed checklist to the physician performing the comprehensive medical examination required in subsection (a)(7); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> a section, for the physician to complete, that instructs the physician—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> to perform a clinical examination of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> head, face, neck, and scalp;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> nose, sinuses, mouth, and throat;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> ears, general (internal and external canals), and eardrums (perforation);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="IV">     “(IV)</num><content> eyes (general), ophthalmoscopic, pupils (equality and reaction), and ocular motility (associated parallel movement, nystagmus);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="V">     “(V)</num><content> lungs and chest (not including breast examination);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="VI">     “(VI)</num><content> heart (precordial activity, rhythm, sounds, and murmurs);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="VII">     “(VII)</num><content> vascular system (pulse, amplitude, and character, and arms, legs, and others);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="VIII">     “(VIII)</num><content> abdomen and viscera (including hernia);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="IX">     “(IX)</num><content> anus (not including digital examination);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="X">     “(X)</num><content> skin;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XI">     “(XI)</num><content> G–U system (not including pelvic examination);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XII">     “(XII)</num><content> upper and lower extremities (strength and range of motion);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XIII">     “(XIII)</num><content> spine and other musculoskeletal;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XIV">     “(XIV)</num><content> identifying body marks, scars, and tattoos (size and location);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XV">     “(XV)</num><content> lymphatics;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XVI">     “(XVI)</num><content> neurologic (tendon reflexes, equilibrium, senses, cranial nerves, and coordination, etc.);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XVII">     “(XVII)</num><content> psychiatric (appearance, behavior, mood, communication, and memory);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XVIII">     “(XVIII)</num><content> general systemic;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XIX">     “(XIX)</num><content> hearing;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XX">     “(XX)</num><content> vision (distant, near, and intermediate vision, field of vision, color vision, and ocular alignment);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XXI">     “(XXI)</num><content> blood pressure and pulse; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="XXII">     “(XXII)</num><content> anything else the physician, in his or her medical judgment, considers necessary;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to exercise medical discretion to address, as medically appropriate, any medical conditions identified, and to exercise medical discretion in determining whether any medical tests are warranted as part of the comprehensive medical examination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> to discuss all drugs the individual reports taking (prescription and nonprescription) and their potential to interfere with the safe operation of an aircraft or motor vehicle;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> to sign the checklist, stating: ‘I certify that I discussed all items on this checklist with the individual during my examination, discussed any medications the individual is taking that could interfere with their ability to safely operate an aircraft or motor vehicle, and performed an examination that included all of the items on this checklist. I certify that I am not aware of any medical condition that, as presently treated, could interfere with the individual’s ability to safely operate an aircraft.’; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> to provide the date the comprehensive medical examination was completed, and the physician’s full name, address, telephone number, and State medical license number.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Logbook</inline>.—</heading><content>The completed checklist shall be retained in the individual’s logbook and made available on request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medical Education Course Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The medical education course described in this subsection shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> be available on the Internet free of charge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> be developed and periodically updated in coordination with representatives of relevant nonprofit and not-for-profit general aviation stakeholder groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> educate pilots on conducting medical self-assessments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> advise pilots on identifying warning signs of potential serious medical conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> identify risk mitigation strategies for medical conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> increase awareness of the impacts of potentially impairing over-the-counter and prescription drug medications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> encourage regular medical examinations and consultations with primary care physicians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> inform pilots of the regulations pertaining to the prohibition on operations during medical deficiency and medically disqualifying conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> provide the checklist developed by the Federal Aviation Administration in accordance with subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><chapeau> upon successful completion of the course, electronically provide to the individual and transmit to the Federal Aviation Administration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a certification of completion of the medical education course, which shall be printed and retained in the individual’s logbook and made available upon request, and shall contain the individual’s name, address, and airman certificate number;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> subject to subsection (d), a release authorizing the National Driver Register through a designated State Department of Motor Vehicles to furnish to the Federal Aviation Administration information pertaining to the individual’s driving record;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a certification by the individual that the individual is under the care and treatment of a physician if the individual has been diagnosed with any medical condition that may impact the ability of the individual to fly, as required under subsection (a)(6);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> a form that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the name, address, telephone number, and airman certificate number of the individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the name, address, telephone number, and State medical license number of the physician performing the comprehensive medical examination required in subsection (a)(7);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the date of the comprehensive medical examination required in subsection (a)(7); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> a certification by the individual that the checklist described in subsection (b) was followed and signed by the physician in the comprehensive medical examination required in subsection (a)(7); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a statement, which shall be printed, and signed by the individual certifying that the individual understands the existing prohibition on operations during medical deficiency by stating: ‘I understand that I cannot act as pilot in command, or any other capacity as a required flight crew member, if I know or have reason to know of any medical condition that would make me unable to operate the aircraft in a safe manner.’.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Driver Register</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorization under subsection (c)(10)(B) shall be an authorization for a single access to the information contained in the National Driver Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Issuance Process.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual who has qualified for the third-class medical certificate exemption under subsection (a) and is seeking to serve as a pilot in command of a covered aircraft shall be required to have completed the process for obtaining an Authorization for Special Issuance of a Medical Certificate for each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> A mental health disorder, limited to an established medical history or clinical diagnosis of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> personality disorder that is severe enough to have repeatedly manifested itself by overt acts;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> psychosis, defined as a case in which an individual—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> has manifested delusions, hallucinations, grossly bizarre or disorganized behavior, or other commonly accepted symptoms of psychosis; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> may reasonably be expected to manifest delusions, hallucinations, grossly bizarre or disorganized behavior, or other commonly accepted symptoms of psychosis;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> bipolar disorder; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> substance dependence within the previous 2 years, as defined in section 67.307(a)(4) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> A neurological disorder, limited to an established medical history or clinical diagnosis of any of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Epilepsy.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Disturbance of consciousness without satisfactory medical explanation of the cause.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> A transient loss of control of nervous system functions without satisfactory medical explanation of the cause.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> A cardiovascular condition, limited to a one-time special issuance for each diagnosis of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Myocardial infraction [sic].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Coronary heart disease that has required treatment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Cardiac valve replacement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> Heart replacement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for cardiovascular conditions</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of an individual with a cardiovascular condition, the process for obtaining an Authorization for Special Issuance of a Medical Certificate shall be satisfied with the successful completion of an appropriate clinical evaluation without a mandatory wait period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for mental health conditions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of an individual with a clinically diagnosed mental health condition, the third-class medical certificate exemption under subsection (a) shall not apply if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> in the judgment of the individual’s State-licensed medical specialist, the condition—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> renders the individual unable to safely perform the duties or exercise the airman privileges described in subsection (a)(8); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> may reasonably be expected to make the individual unable to perform the duties or exercise the privileges described in subsection (a)(8); or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the individual’s driver’s license is revoked by the issuing agency as a result of a clinically diagnosed mental health condition.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subparagraph (A), an individual clinically diagnosed with a mental health condition shall certify every 2 years, in conjunction with the certification under subsection (c)(10)(C), that the individual is under the care of a State-licensed medical specialist for that mental health condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for neurological conditions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of an individual with a clinically diagnosed neurological condition, the third-class medical certificate exemption under subsection (a) shall not apply if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> in the judgment of the individual’s State-licensed medical specialist, the condition—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> renders the individual unable to safely perform the duties or exercise the airman privileges described in subsection (a)(8); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> may reasonably be expected to make the individual unable to perform the duties or exercise the privileges described in subsection (a)(8); or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the individual’s driver’s license is revoked by the issuing agency as a result of a clinically diagnosed neurological condition.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subparagraph (A), an individual clinically diagnosed with a neurological condition shall certify every 2 years, in conjunction with the certification under subsection (c)(10)(C), that the individual is under the care of a State-licensed medical specialist for that neurological condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Identification of Additional Medical Conditions for CACI Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>], the Administrator shall review and identify additional medical conditions that could be added to the program known as the Conditions AMEs Can Issue (CACI) program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultations</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with aviation, medical, and union stakeholders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a report listing the medical conditions that have been added to the CACI program under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited Authorization for Special Issuance of a Medical Certificate.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall implement procedures to expedite the process for obtaining an Authorization for Special Issuance of a Medical Certificate under section 67.401 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultations</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with aviation, medical, and union stakeholders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing how the procedures implemented under paragraph (1) will streamline the process for obtaining an Authorization for Special Issuance of a Medical Certificate and reduce the amount of time needed to review and decide special issuance cases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator, in coordination with the National Transportation Safety Board, shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that describes the effect of the regulations issued or revised under subsection (a) and includes statistics with respect to changes in small aircraft activity and safety incidents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Enforcement Actions</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator may not take an enforcement action for not holding a valid third-class medical certificate against a pilot of a covered aircraft for a flight if the pilot and the flight meet, through a good faith effort, the applicable requirements under subsection (a), except paragraph (5) of that subsection, unless the Administrator has published final regulations in the Federal Register under that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Aircraft Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘covered aircraft’ means an aircraft that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is authorized under Federal law to carry not more than 7 occupants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> has a maximum certificated takeoff weight of not more than 12,500 pounds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> is not a transport category rotorcraft certified to airworthiness standards under part 29 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operations Covered</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions and requirements covered in this section do not apply to pilots who elect to operate under the medical requirements under subsection (b) or subsection (c) of section 61.23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="l">“(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Require Additional Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator receives credible or urgent information, including from the National Driver Register or the Administrator’s Safety Hotline, that reflects on an individual’s ability to safely operate a covered aircraft under the third-class medical certificate exemption in subsection (a), the Administrator may require the individual to provide additional information or history so that the Administrator may determine whether the individual is safe to continue operating a covered aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may use credible or urgent information received under paragraph (1) to request an individual to provide additional information or to take actions under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44709/b">section 44709(b) of title 49</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s828/b">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 828(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1336">138 Stat. 1336</ref>, provided that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(b) <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking</inline>.—The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall update regulations in parts 61 and 68 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as necessary, to implement the amendments made by this section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/114/190/s2307">section 2307 of Pub. L. 114–190</ref>, set out above].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator shall apply parts 61 and 68, Code of Federal Regulations, in a manner reflecting the amendments made by this section.”]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf6d7ac-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Aviation Administration Enforcement Proceedings and Elimination of Deference</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/153/s2">Pub. L. 112–153, § 2</ref>, <date date="2012-08-03">Aug. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1159">126 Stat. 1159</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tIII/s392">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 392</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3323">132 Stat. 3323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s807">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1324">138 Stat. 1324</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s807">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Any proceeding conducted under subpart C, D, or F of part 821 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to denial, amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of an airman certificate, shall be conducted, to the extent practicable, in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure [28 U.S.C. App.] and the Federal Rules of Evidence [28 U.S.C. App.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access to Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided under paragraph (3), the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (referred to in this section as the ‘Administrator’) shall provide timely, written notification to an individual who is the subject of an investigation relating to the approval, denial, suspension, modification, or revocation of an airman certificate under chapter 447 of title 49, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The notification required under paragraph (1) shall inform the individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> of the nature of the investigation and the specific activity on which the investigation is based;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that an oral or written response to a Letter of Investigation from the Administrator is not required;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> that no action or adverse inference can be taken against the individual for declining to respond to a Letter of Investigation from the Administrator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> that any response to a Letter of Investigation from the Administrator or to an inquiry made by a representative of the Administrator by the individual may be used as evidence against the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> that the releasable portions of the Administrator’s investigative report will be available to the individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> that the individual is entitled to access or otherwise obtain air traffic data described in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may delay notification under paragraph (1) if the Administrator determines that such notification may threaten the integrity of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access to air traffic data.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FAA air traffic data</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall provide an individual described in paragraph (1) with timely access to any air traffic data in the possession of the Federal Aviation Administration that would facilitate the individual’s ability to productively participate in a proceeding relating to an investigation described in such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air traffic data defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in subparagraph (A), the term ‘air traffic data’ includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> relevant air traffic communication tapes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> radar information;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> air traffic controller statements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> flight data;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> investigative reports; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> any other air traffic or flight data in the Federal Aviation Administration’s possession that would facilitate the individual’s ability to productively participate in the proceeding.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Government contractor air traffic data.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any individual described in paragraph (1) is entitled to obtain any air traffic data that would facilitate the individual’s ability to productively participate in a proceeding relating to an investigation described in such paragraph from a government contractor that provides operational services to the Federal Aviation Administration, including control towers and flight service stations.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required information from individual</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The individual may obtain the information described in clause (i) by submitting a request to the Administrator that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> describes the facility at which such information is located; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> identifies the date on which such information was generated.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of information to individual</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Administrator receives a request under this subparagraph, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> request the contractor to provide the requested information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> upon receiving such information, transmitting the information to the requesting individual in a timely manner.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading><content>Except when the Administrator determines that an emergency exists under section 44709(e)(2) or 46105(c) [of title 49, United States Code], the Administrator may not proceed against an individual that is the subject of an investigation described in paragraph (1) during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the air traffic data required under paragraph (4) is made available to the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Response to letter of investigation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If an individual decides to respond to a Letter of Investigation described in paragraph (2)(B), such individual may respond not later than 30 days after receipt of such Letter, including providing written comments on the incident to the investigating office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to diminish the authority of the Administrator (as of the day before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>]) to take emergency action relating to an airman certificate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments to Title </inline>49.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airman certificates</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf9219d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<p>[Amended this section.]</p></note>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments, modifications, suspensions, and revocations of certificates</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf9219e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<p>[Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44709">section 44709 of this title</ref>.]</p></note>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revocation of airman certificates for controlled substance violations</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf9219f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<p>[Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44710">section 44710 of this title</ref>.]</p></note>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appeal From Certificate Actions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon a decision by the National Transportation Safety Board upholding an order or a final decision by the Administrator denying an airman certificate under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44703/d">section 44703(d) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, or imposing a punitive civil action or an emergency order of revocation under subsections (d) and (e) of section 44709 of such title, an individual substantially affected by an order of the Board may, at the individual’s election, file an appeal in the United States district court in which the individual resides or in which the action in question occurred, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. If the individual substantially affected by an order of the Board elects not to file an appeal in a United States district court, the individual may file an appeal in an appropriate United States court of appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency order pending judicial review</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsequent to a decision by the Board to uphold an Administrator’s emergency order under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44709/e/2">section 44709(e)(2) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, and absent a stay of the enforcement of that order by the Board, the emergency order of amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of a certificate shall remain in effect, pending the exhaustion of an appeal to a Federal district court as provided in this Act [amending this section and sections 44709 and 44710 of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 40101 and 44701 of this title].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standard of Review.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In an appeal filed under subsection (d) in a United States district court, the district court shall give full independent review of a denial, suspension, or revocation ordered by the Administrator, including substantive independent and expedited review of any decision by the Administrator to make such order effective immediately.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evidence</inline>.—</heading><content>A United States district court’s review under paragraph (1) shall include in evidence any record of the proceeding before the Administrator and any record of the proceeding before the National Transportation Safety Board, including hearing testimony, transcripts, exhibits, decisions, and briefs submitted by the parties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Release of Investigative Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency orders</inline>.—</heading><content>In any proceeding conducted under part 821 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to the amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of an airman certificate, in which the Administrator issues an emergency order under subsections (d) and (e) of section 44709, section 44710, or <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s46105/c">section 46105(c) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, or another order that takes effect immediately, the Administrator shall provide, upon request, to the individual holding the airman certificate the releasable portion of the investigative report at the time the Administrator issues the order. If the complete Report of Investigation is not available at the time of the request, the Administrator shall issue all portions of the report that are available at the time and shall provide the full report not later than 5 days after its completion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other orders</inline>.—</heading><content>In any nonemergency proceeding conducted under part 821 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to the amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of an airman certificate, in which the Administrator notifies the certificate holder of a proposed certificate action under subsections (b) and (c) of section 44709 or <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44710">section 44710 of title 49</ref>, United States Code, the Administrator shall, upon the written request of the covered certificate holder and at any time after that notification, provide to the covered certificate holder the releasable portion of the investigative report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Motion for dismissal</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator does not provide the releasable portions of the investigative report to the individual holding the airman certificate subject to the proceeding referred to in paragraph (1) by the time required by that paragraph, the individual may move to dismiss the complaint of the Administrator or for other relief and, unless the Administrator establishes good cause for the failure to provide the investigative report or for a lack of timeliness, the administrative law judge shall order such relief as the judge considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Releasable portion of investigative report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), the releasable portion of an investigative report is all information in the report, except for the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Information that is privileged.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Information that constitutes work product or reflects internal deliberative process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Information that would disclose the identity of a confidential source.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Information the disclosure of which is prohibited by any other provision of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Information that is not relevant to the subject matter of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Information the Administrator can demonstrate is withheld for good cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Sensitive security information, as defined in section 15.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar ruling or regulation).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the Administrator from releasing to an individual subject to an investigation described in subsection (b)(1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> information in addition to the information included in the releasable portion of the investigative report; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a copy of the investigative report before the Administrator issues a complaint.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf921a0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Medical Certification</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/153/s4">Pub. L. 112–153, § 4</ref>, <date date="2012-08-03">Aug. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1162">126 Stat. 1162</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/153/s4">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-08-03">Aug. 3, 2012</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate an assessment of the Federal Aviation Administration’s medical certification process and the associated medical standards and forms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Comptroller General shall submit a report to Congress based on the assessment required under paragraph (1) that examines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> revisions to the medical application form that would provide greater clarity and guidance to applicants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the alignment of medical qualification policies with present-day qualified medical judgment and practices, as applied to an individual’s medically relevant circumstances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> steps that could be taken to promote the public’s understanding of the medical requirements that determine an airman’s medical certificate eligibility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Goals of the Federal Aviation Administration’s Medical Certification Process</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The goals of the Federal Aviation Administration’s medical certification process are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> to provide questions in the medical application form that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> are appropriate without being overly broad;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> are subject to a minimum amount of misinterpretation and mistaken responses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> allow for consistent treatment and responses during the medical application process; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> avoid unnecessary allegations that an individual has intentionally falsified answers on the form;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide questions that elicit information that is relevant to making a determination of an individual’s medical qualifications within the standards identified in the Administrator’s regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to give medical standards greater meaning by ensuring the information requested aligns with present-day medical judgment and practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> to ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the application of such medical standards provides an appropriate and fair evaluation of an individual’s qualifications; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the individual understands the basis for determining medical qualifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advice From Private Sector Groups</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall establish a panel, which shall be comprised of representatives of relevant nonprofit and not-for-profit general aviation pilot groups, aviation medical examiners, and other qualified medical experts, to advise the Administrator in carrying out the goals of the assessment required under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Aviation Administration Response</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the issuance of the report by the Comptroller General pursuant to subsection (a)(2), the Administrator shall take appropriate actions to respond to such report.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf921a1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reexamination of an Airman Certificate</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/153/s5">Pub. L. 112–153, § 5</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 118–63, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1320">138 Stat. 1320</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tVIII/s801">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall provide timely, written notification to an individual subject to a reexamination of an airman certificate issued under chapter 447 of title 49, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In providing notification under subsection (a), the Administrator shall inform the individual—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> of the nature of the reexamination and the specific activity on which the reexamination is necessitated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that the reexamination shall occur within 1 year from the date of the notice provided by the Administrator, however, if the reexamination is not conducted within 30 days, the Administrator may restrict passenger carrying operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> that if such reexamination is not conducted after 1 year from date of notice, the airman certificate of the individual may be suspended or revoked; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> when, as determined by the Administrator, an oral or written response to the notification from the Administrator is not required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section prohibits the Administrator from reexamining a certificate holder if the Administrator has reasonable grounds—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to establish that an airman may not be qualified to exercise the privileges of a certificate or rating based upon an act or omission committed by the airman while exercising such privileges or performing ancillary duties associated with the exercise of such privileges; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to demonstrate that the airman obtained such a certificate or rating through fraudulent means or through an examination that was inadequate to establish the qualifications of an airman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standard of Review</inline>.—</heading><content>An order issued by the Administrator to amend, modify, suspend, or revoke an airman certificate after reexamination of the airman is subject to the standard of review provided for under section 2 of this Act [<ref href="/us/pl/112/153">Pub. L. 112–153</ref>, set out as a note above].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf921a2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improved Pilot Licenses</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 112–95, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/71">126 Stat. 71</ref>, which related to the issuance by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration of improved pilot licenses and required reports to Congress, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tII/s218/j/2">Pub. L. 118–63, title II, § 218(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1056">138 Stat. 1056</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tIV/s4022">Pub. L. 108–458, title IV, § 4022</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3723">118 Stat. 3723</ref>, which related to the issuance of improved pilot licenses, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tII/s218/j/1">Pub. L. 118–63, title II, § 218(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1056">138 Stat. 1056</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf921a3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Crediting of Law Enforcement Flight Time</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/424/s14">Pub. L. 106–424, § 14</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1888">114 Stat. 1888</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/424/s14">
<inline>“In determining whether an individual meets the aeronautical experience requirements imposed under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44703">section 44703 of title 49</ref>, United States Code, for an airman certificate or rating, the Secretary of Transportation shall take into account any time spent by that individual operating a public aircraft as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40102">section 40102 of title 49</ref>, United States Code, if that aircraft is—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> identifiable by category and class; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> used in law enforcement activities.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
