<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcbf921a4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704"><num value="44704">§ 44704.</num><heading> Type certificates, production certificates, airworthiness certificates, and design and production organization certificates</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921a5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Type Certificates</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921a6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance, investigations, and tests</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue a type certificate for an aircraft, aircraft engine, or propeller, or for an appliance specified under paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection when the Administrator finds that the aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance is properly designed and manufactured, performs properly, and meets the regulations and minimum standards prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44701/a">section 44701(a) of this title</ref>. On receiving an application for a type certificate, the Administrator shall investigate the application and may conduct a hearing. The Administrator shall make, or require the applicant to make, tests the Administrator considers necessary in the interest of safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921a7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specifications</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921a8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> specify in regulations those appliances that reasonably require a type certificate in the interest of safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921a9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include in a type certificate terms required in the interest of safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921aa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> record on the certificate a numerical specification of the essential factors related to the performance of the aircraft, aircraft engine, or propeller for which the certificate is issued.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921ab-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules for new aircraft and appliances</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (4), if the holder of a type certificate agrees to permit another person to use the certificate to manufacture a new aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance, the holder shall provide the other person with written evidence, in a form acceptable to the Administrator, of that agreement. Such other person may manufacture a new aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance based on a type certificate only if such other person is the holder of the type certificate or has permission from the holder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921ac-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation for aircraft manufactured before <date date="2004-08-05">august 5, 2004</date></inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (3) shall not apply to a person who began the manufacture of an aircraft before <date date="2004-08-05">August 5, 2004</date>, and who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that such manufacture began before <date date="2004-08-05">August 5, 2004</date>, if the name of the holder of the type certificate for the aircraft does not appear on the airworthiness certificate or identification plate of the aircraft. The holder of the type certificate for the aircraft shall not be responsible for the continued airworthiness of the aircraft. A person may invoke the exception provided by this paragraph with regard to the manufacture of only one aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921ad-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Release of data.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921ae-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may make available upon request, to a person seeking to maintain the airworthiness or develop product improvements of an aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance, engineering data in the possession of the Administration relating to a type certificate or a supplemental type certificate for such aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance, without the consent of the owner of record, if the Administrator determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921af-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the certificate containing the requested data has been inactive for 3 or more years, except that the Administrator may reduce this time if required to address an unsafe condition associated with the product;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921b0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> after using due diligence, the Administrator is unable to find the owner of record, or the owner of record’s heir, of the type certificate or supplemental type certificate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921b1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> making such data available will enhance aviation safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921b2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Engineering data defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “engineering data” as used with respect to an aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance means type design drawing and specifications for the entire aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance or change to the aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance, including the original design data, and any associated supplier data for individual parts or components approved as part of the particular certificate for the aircraft, engine, propeller, or appliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921b3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement to maintain data</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall maintain engineering data in the possession of the Administration relating to a type certificate or a supplemental type certificate that has been inactive for 3 or more years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921b4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of data</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>When an applicant submits design data to the Administrator for a finding of compliance as part of an application for a type certificate, the applicant shall certify to the Administrator that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921b5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the submitted design data demonstrates compliance with the applicable airworthiness standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921b6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any airworthiness standards not complied with are compensated for by factors that provide an equivalent level of safety, as agreed upon by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921b7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Type Certificates.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921b8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may issue a type certificate designated as a supplemental type certificate for a change to an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921b9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><content>A supplemental type certificate issued under paragraph (1) shall consist of the change to the aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance with respect to the previously issued type certificate for the aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921ba-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>If the holder of a supplemental type certificate agrees to permit another person to use the certificate to modify an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance, the holder shall provide the other person with written evidence, in a form acceptable to the Administrator, of that agreement. A person may change an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance based on a supplemental type certificate only if the person requesting the change is the holder of the supplemental type certificate or has permission from the holder to make the change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921bb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Production Certificates</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall issue a production certificate authorizing the production of a duplicate of an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance for which a type certificate has been issued when the Administrator finds the duplicate will conform to the certificate. On receiving an application, the Administrator shall inspect, and may require testing of, a duplicate to ensure that it conforms to the requirements of the certificate. The Administrator may include in a production certificate terms required in the interest of safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921bc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airworthiness Certificates</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921bd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The registered owner of an aircraft may apply to the Administrator for an airworthiness certificate for the aircraft. The Administrator shall issue an airworthiness certificate when the Administrator finds that the aircraft conforms to its type certificate and, after inspection, is in condition for safe operation. The Administrator shall register each airworthiness certificate and may include appropriate information in the certificate. The certificate number or other individual designation the Administrator requires shall be displayed on the aircraft. The Administrator may include in an airworthiness certificate terms required in the interest of safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921be-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person applying for the issuance or renewal of an airworthiness certificate for an aircraft for which ownership has not been recorded under section 44107 or 44110 of this title must submit with the application information related to the ownership of the aircraft the Administrator decides is necessary to identify each person having a property interest in the aircraft and the kind and extent of the interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921bf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonconformity with approved type design.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921c0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Consistent with the requirements of paragraph (1), a holder of a production certificate for an aircraft may not present a nonconforming aircraft, either directly or through the registered owner of such aircraft or a person described in paragraph (2), to the Administrator for issuance of an initial airworthiness certificate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921c1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Civil penalty</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 46301, a production certificate holder who knowingly violates subparagraph (A) shall be liable to the Administrator for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each nonconforming aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921c2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalty considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining the amount of a civil penalty under subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921c3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation, including the length of time the nonconformity was known by the holder of a production certificate but not disclosed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921c4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior violations, and the size of the business concern.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921c5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonconforming aircraft defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this paragraph, the term “nonconforming aircraft” means an aircraft that does not conform to the approved type design for such aircraft type.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921c6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of Safety Critical Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921c7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding a delegation described in section 44702(d), the Administrator shall require an applicant for, or holder of, a type certificate for a transport category airplane covered under part 25 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to submit safety critical information with respect to such airplane to the Administrator in such form, manner, or time as the Administrator may require. Such safety critical information shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921c8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any design and operational details, intended functions, and failure modes of any system that, without being commanded by the flight crew, commands the operation of any safety critical function or feature required for control of an airplane during flight or that otherwise changes the flight path or airspeed of an airplane;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921c9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the design and operational details, intended functions, failure modes, and mode annunciations of autopilot and autothrottle systems, if applicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921ca-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any failure or operating condition that the applicant or holder anticipates or has concluded would result in an outcome with a severity level of hazardous or catastrophic, as defined in the appropriate Administration airworthiness requirements and guidance applicable to transport category airplanes defining risk severity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921cb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any adverse handling quality that fails to meet the requirements of applicable regulations without the addition of a software system to augment the flight controls of the airplane to produce compliant handling qualities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921cc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a system safety assessment with respect to a system described in subparagraph (A) or (B) or with respect to any component or other system for which failure or erroneous operation of such component or system could result in an outcome with a severity level of hazardous or catastrophic, as defined in the appropriate Administration airworthiness requirements and guidance applicable to transport category airplanes defining risk severity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921cd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ongoing communications.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921ce-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Newly discovered information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall require that an applicant for, or holder of, a type certificate disclose to the Administrator, in such form, manner, or time as the Administrator may require, any newly discovered information or design or analysis change that would materially alter any submission to the Administrator under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921cf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">System development changes</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall establish multiple milestones throughout the certification process at which a proposed airplane system will be assessed to determine whether any change to such system during the certification process is such that such system should be considered novel or unusual by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921d0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Flight manuals</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall ensure that an airplane flight manual and a flight crew operating manual (as appropriate or applicable) for an airplane contains a description of the operation of a system described in paragraph (1)(A) and flight crew procedures for responding to a failure or aberrant operation of such system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921d1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Civil penalty.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921d2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 46301, an applicant for, or holder of, a type certificate that knowingly violates paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of this subsection shall be liable to the Administrator for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921d3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalty considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining the amount of a civil penalty under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921d4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation, including the length of time that such safety critical information was known but not disclosed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921d5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior violations, and the size of the business concern.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921d6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revocation and civil penalty for individuals.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921d7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall revoke any airline transport pilot certificate issued under section 44703 held by any individual who, while acting on behalf of an applicant for, or holder of, a type certificate, knowingly makes a false statement with respect to any of the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921d8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to impose civil penalty</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may impose a civil penalty under section 46301 for each violation described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921d9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect or otherwise inhibit the authority of the Administrator to deny an application by an applicant for a type certificate or to revoke or amend a type certificate of a holder of such certificate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921da-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of type certificate</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term “type certificate”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921db-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> means a type certificate issued under subsection (a) or an amendment to such certificate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921dc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include a supplemental type certificate issued under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921dd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hearing Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator may find that a person has violated subsection (d)(3) or paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (e) and impose a civil penalty under the applicable subsection only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing. The Administrator shall provide a person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921de-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> written notice of the violation and the amount of penalty; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921df-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the opportunity for a hearing under subpart G of part 13 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcbf921e0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification Dispute Resolution.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921e1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dispute resolution process and appeals.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921e2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall issue an order establishing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an effective, timely, and milestone-based issue resolution process for type certification activities under subsection (a); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a process by which a decision, finding of compliance or noncompliance, or other act of the Administration, with respect to compliance with design requirements, may be appealed by a covered person directly involved with the certification activities in dispute on the basis that such decision, finding, or act is erroneous or inconsistent with this chapter, regulations, or guidance materials promulgated by the Administrator, or other requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921e5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Escalation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The order issued under subparagraph (A) shall provide processes for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> resolution of technical issues at pre-established stages of the certification process, as agreed to by the Administrator and the type certificate applicant;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> automatic elevation to appropriate management personnel of the Administration and the type certificate applicant of any major certification process milestone that is not completed or resolved within a specific period of time agreed to by the Administrator and the type certificate applicant;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> resolution of a major certification process milestone elevated pursuant to clause (ii) within a specific period of time agreed to by the Administrator and the type certificate applicant;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921e9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> initial review by appropriate Administration employees of any appeal described in subparagraph (A)(ii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921ea-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> subsequent review of any further appeal by appropriate management personnel of the Administration and the Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921eb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disposition.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921ec-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Written decision</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety shall issue a written decision that states the grounds for the decision of the Associate Administrator on—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf921ed-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> each appeal submitted under subparagraph (A)(ii); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idcbf921ee-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> An appeal to the Associate Administrator submitted under subparagraph (B)(v).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921ef-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than December 31 of each calendar year through calendar year 2028, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report summarizing each appeal resolved under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921f0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final review.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921f1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>A written decision of the Associate Administrator under subparagraph (C) may be appealed to the Administrator for a final review and determination.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921f2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Decline to review</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may decline to review an appeal initiated pursuant to clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921f3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/1/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Judicial review</inline>.—</heading><content>No decision under this paragraph (including a decision to decline to review an appeal) shall be subject to judicial review.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921f4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibited contacts.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921f5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition generally</inline>.—</heading><content>During the course of an appeal under this subsection, no covered official may engage in an ex parte communication (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551">section 551 of title 5</ref>) with an individual representing or acting on behalf of an applicant for, or holder of, a certificate under this section in relation to such appeal unless such communication is disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921f6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading><content>If, during the course of an appeal under this subsection, a covered official engages in, receives, or is otherwise made aware of an ex parte communication, the covered official shall disclose such communication in the public record at the time of the issuance of the written decision under paragraph (1)(C), including the time and date of the communication, subject of communication, and all persons engaged in such communication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf921f7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921f8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered person</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “covered person” means either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921f9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an employee of the Administration whose responsibilities relate to the certification of aircraft, engines, propellers, or appliances; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921fa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an applicant for, or holder of, a type certificate or amended type certificate issued under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf921fb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered official</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “covered official” means the following officials:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921fc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Executive Director or any Deputy Director of the Aircraft Certification Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921fd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Deputy Executive Director for Regulatory Operations of the Aircraft Certification Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921fe-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Director or Deputy Director of the Compliance and Airworthiness Division of the Aircraft Certification Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf921ff-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The Director or Deputy Director of the System Oversight Division of the Aircraft Certification Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92200-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The Director or Deputy Director of the Policy and Innovation Division of the Aircraft Certification Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92201-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The Executive Director or any Deputy Executive Director of the Flight Standards Service.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92202-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> The Associate Administrator or Deputy Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92203-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> The Deputy Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92204-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcbf92205-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/B/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> Any similarly situated or successor FAA management position to those described in clauses (i) through (ix), as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf92206-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Major certification process milestone</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “major certification process milestone” means a milestone related to the type certification basis, type certification plan, type inspection authorization, issue paper, or other major type certification activity agreed to by the Administrator and the type certificate applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcbf92207-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this subsection shall apply to the communication of a good-faith complaint by any individual alleging—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf92208-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> gross misconduct;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf92209-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a violation of title 18; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcbf9220a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44704/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a violation of any of the provisions of part 2635 or 6001 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcbf9220b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s1/e">Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1188">108 Stat. 1188</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 104–264, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3256">110 Stat. 3256</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/tII/s227/b/2">Pub. L. 108–176, title II, § 227(b)(2)</ref>, (e)(1), title VIII, § 811, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2531">117 Stat. 2531</ref>, 2532, 2590; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tIV/s4405">Pub. L. 109–59, title IV, § 4405</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1776">119 Stat. 1776</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tIII">Pub. L. 112–95, title III</ref>, §§ 302, 303(a), (c)(1), <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/56">126 Stat. 56</ref>, 57; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tII/s214">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3250">132 Stat. 3250</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I</ref>, §§ 105(a), (b), 110, 120, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2317">134 Stat. 2317</ref>, 2328, 2343; <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII">Pub. L. 118–63, title III</ref>, §§ 306(c), 343(a), title XI, § 1101(k), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1072">138 Stat. 1072</ref>, 1101, 1414.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcbf9220c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idcbf9220d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idcbf9220e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44704(a)(1)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1423(a)(2) (1st–4th sentences).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 23, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/726">Pub. L. 85–726</html:a>, §§ 503(h), 603(a)(1) (related to regulations for appliances), (2), (b) (related to basis for issuing, and contents of, certificates), (c) (related to basis for issuing, and contents of, certificates), <html:a href="/us/stat/72/774">72 Stat. 774</html:a>, 776.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 15, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/670/s6/c/1">Pub. L. 89–670, § 6(c)(1)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/938">80 Stat. 938</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Jan. 12, 1983</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/97/449/s7/b">Pub. L. 97–449, § 7(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/96/2444">96 Stat. 2444</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44704(a)(2)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1423(a)(1) (related to regulations for appliances), (2) (5th, last sentences).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44704(b)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1423(b) (related to basis for issuing, and contents of, certificates).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44704(c)(1)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1423(c) (related to basis for issuing, and contents of, certificates).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>44704(c)(2)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1403(h).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1655(c)(1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p>In subsections (a)–(c)(1), the word “Administrator” in section 603 of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 (<ref href="/us/pl/85/726">Public Law 85–726</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/776">72 Stat. 776</ref>) is retained on authority of 49:106(g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(1), the text of 49 App.:1423(a)(2) (1st sentence 1st–16th words) and the words “in regulations” are omitted as surplus. The words “properly designed and manufactured, performs properly” are substituted for “of proper design, material, specification, construction, and performance for safe operation” to eliminate unnecessary words. The word “rules” is omitted as being synonymous with “regulations”. The words “under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44701/a">section 44701(a) of this title</ref>” and “for a type certificate” are added for clarity. The words “including flight tests and tests of raw materials or any part or appurtenance of such aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(2)(A), the words “issuance of” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(2)(B), the words “the duration thereof and such other” are omitted as surplus. The words “conditions, and limitations” are omitted as being included in “terms”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(2)(C), the words “issued for aircraft, aircraft engines, or propellers” and “all of” are omitted as surplus. The word “specification” is substituted for “determination” for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), the word “satisfactorily” is omitted as surplus. The words “shall inspect, and may require testing of, a duplicate to ensure that it conforms to the requirements of the certificate” are substituted for “shall make such inspection and may require such tests of any aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance manufactured under a production certificate as may be necessary to assure manufacture of each unit in conformity with the type certificate or any amendment or modification thereof” to eliminate unnecessary words. The words “the duration thereof and such other . . . conditions, and limitations” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(1), the words “may apply to” are substituted for “may file with . . . an application” to eliminate unnecessary words. The words “in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Transportation” are omitted because of 49:322(a). The words “the duration of such certificate, the type of service for which the aircraft may be used, and such other . . . conditions, and limitations” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(2), the words “having a property interest” are substituted for “who are holders of property interests” to eliminate unnecessary words.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcbf9220f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcbf92210-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, which was approved <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcbf92211-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s343/a">Pub. L. 118–63, § 343(a)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s1101/k">Pub. L. 118–63, § 1101(k)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d)(3)” for “subsection (a)(6)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/s306/c">Pub. L. 118–63, § 306(c)</ref>, substituted “calendar year 2028” for “calendar year 2025”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s110/b">Pub. L. 116–260, § 110(b)</ref>, struck out par. (6) which related to type certification resolution process.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s105/a">Pub. L. 116–260, § 105(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and struck out former subsec. (e) which related to design and production organization certificates.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s105/b">Pub. L. 116–260, § 105(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s110/a">Pub. L. 116–260, § 110(a)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s214/b">Pub. L. 115–254, § 214(b)</ref>, substituted “airworthiness certificates,” for “airworthiness certificates,,” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s214/a">Pub. L. 115–254, § 214(a)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/95/s303/c/1">Pub. L. 112–95, § 303(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “, and design and production organization certificates” for “and design organization certificates” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/s302">Pub. L. 112–95, § 302</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/s303/a">Pub. L. 112–95, § 303(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) related to design organization certificates.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(1) to (3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s4405/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 4405(1)</ref>–(3), (5), (6), inserted par. headings, realigned margins, and substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (4), if” for “If” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s4405/4">Pub. L. 109–59, § 4405(4)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s227/e/1">Pub. L. 108–176, § 227(e)(1)</ref>, added section catchline and struck out former section catchline which read as follows: “Type certificates, production certificates, and airworthiness certificates”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s811">Pub. L. 108–176, § 811</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s227/b/2">Pub. L. 108–176, § 227(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref> added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsecs. (b) and (c) as (c) and (d), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcbf92212-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcbf92213-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/176">Pub. L. 108–176</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–176</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcbf92214-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, and not to be construed as affecting funds made available for a fiscal year ending before <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 104–264</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf92215-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Advanced Tools and High-Risk Flight Testing in Certifying Aerospace Products</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1074">138 Stat. 1074</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s311">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall complete an assessment of the use of advanced tools during the testing, analysis, and verification stages of aerospace certification projects to reduce the risks associated with high-risk flight profiles and performing limit testing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the assessment under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> instances in which high-risk flight profiles and limit testing have occurred in the certification process and the applicability of the data produced by such testing for use in other aspects of flight testing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the safety of pilots during such testing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the value and accuracy of data collected using the advanced tools described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the ability to produce more extensive data sets using such advanced tools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> any aspects of such testing for which the use of such advanced tools would not be valuable or applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the cost of using such advanced tools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the best practices of other international civil aviation authorities that permit the use of advanced tools during aerospace certification projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the assessment under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> aircraft manufacturers, including manufacturers that have designed and certified aircraft under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> part 23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> part 25 of such title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> part 27 of such title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> aircraft manufacturers that have designed and certified, or are in the process of certifying, aircraft with a novel design under part 21.17(b) of such title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> associations representing aircraft manufacturers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> researchers and academics in related fields; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> pilots who are experts in flight testing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the completion of the assessment under subsection (a), the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] on the results of the assessment conducted under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Updates.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall take necessary actions based on the results of the assessment under subsection (a), including, as appropriate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> amending part 21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> modifying any associated advisory circulars, guidance, or policy of the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In taking actions under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> developing validation criteria and procedures whereby data produced in high-fidelity engineering laboratories and facilities may be allowed (in conjunction with, or in lieu of) data produced on a flying test article to support an applicant’s showing of compliance required under section 21.35(a)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> developing criteria and procedures whereby an Organization Designation Authorization (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44736/c/5">section 44736(c)(5) of title 49</ref>, United States Code) may recommend that certain data produced during an applicant’s flight test program may be accepted by the FAA as final compliance data in accordance with section 21.35(b) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, at the sole discretion of the FAA; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> working with other international civil aviation authorities representing States of Design to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> identify their best practices relative to high risk-flight testing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> adopt such practices into the flight-testing requirements of the FAA to the maximum extent practicable.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf92216-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transport Airplane and Propulsion Certification Modernization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1076">138 Stat. 1076</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s312">“Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking for the item titled ‘Transport Airplane and Propulsion Certification Modernization’, published in Fall 2022 in the Unified Agenda of Federal Regulatory and Deregulatory Actions (RIN 2120–AL42).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf92217-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Instructions for Continued Airworthiness Aviation Rulemaking Committee</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s349">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 349</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1109">138 Stat. 1109</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s349">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall convene an aviation rulemaking committee to review, and develop findings and recommendations regarding, instructions for continued airworthiness (as described in section 21.50 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations), and provide to the Administrator a report on such findings and recommendations and for other related purposes as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The aviation rulemaking committee established pursuant to subsection (a) shall consist of members appointed by the Administrator, including representatives of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> holders of type certificates (as described in subpart B of part 21, title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> holders of production certificates (as described in subpart G of part 21, title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> holders of parts manufacturer approvals (as described in subpart K of part 21, title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> holders of technical standard order authorizations (as described in subpart O of part 21, title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> operators under parts 121, 125, or 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> holders of repair station certificates (as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s145">section 145 of title 14</ref>, Code of Federal Regulations) that are not also type certificate holders as included under paragraph (1), production certificate holders as included under paragraph (2), or aircraft operators as included under paragraph (5) (or associated with any such entities);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the certified bargaining representative of aviation safety inspectors and engineers for the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> general aviation operators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> mechanics certificated under part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> holders of supplemental type certificates (as described in subpart E of part 21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> designated engineering representatives employed by repair stations described in paragraph (6); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> aviation safety experts with specific knowledge of instructions for continued airworthiness policies and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The aviation rulemaking committee established pursuant to subsection (a) shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> existing standards, regulations, certifications, assessments, and guidance related to instructions for continued airworthiness and the clarity of such standards, regulations, certifications, assessments, and guidance to all parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the sufficiency of safety data used in preparing instructions for continued airworthiness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the sufficiency of maintenance data used in preparing instructions for continued airworthiness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the protection of proprietary information and intellectual property in instructions for continued airworthiness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the availability of instructions for continued airworthiness, as needed, for maintenance activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the need to harmonize or deconflict proposed and existing regulations with other Federal regulations, guidance, and policies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> international collaboration, where appropriate and consistent with the interests of safety in air commerce and national security, with other civil aviation authorities, international aviation and standards organizations, and any other appropriate entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> any other matter the Administrator determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], submit to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a copy of the aviation rulemaking committee report under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the report under paragraph (1), initiate a rulemaking activity or make such policy and guidance updates necessary to address any consensus recommendations reached by the aviation rulemaking committee established pursuant to subsection (a), as determined appropriate by the Administrator.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbf92218-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Wildfire Suppression</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s360">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 360</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1120">138 Stat. 1120</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s360">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], to ensure that sufficient firefighting resources are available to suppress wildfires and protect public safety and property, and notwithstanding any other provision of law or agency regulation, the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall issue a rule under which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an operation described in section 21.25(b)(7) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall allow for the transport of firefighters to and from the site of a wildfire to perform ground wildfire suppression and designate the firefighters conducting such an operation as essential crewmembers on board a covered aircraft operated on a mission to suppress wildfire;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the aircraft maintenance, inspections, and pilot training requirements under part 135 of such title 14 may apply to such an operation, if determined by the Administrator to be necessary to maintain the safety of firefighters carrying out wildfire suppression missions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the noise standards described in part 36 of such title 14 shall not apply to such an operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Surplus Military Aircraft</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In issuing a rule under subsection (a), the Administrator may not enable any aircraft of a type that has been—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> manufactured in accordance with the requirements of, and accepted for use by, the armed forces (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> later modified to be used for wildfire suppression operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conforming Amendments to FAA Documents</inline>.—</heading><content>In issuing a rule under subsection (a), the Administrator shall revise the order of the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] titled ‘Restricted Category Type Certification’, issued on <date date="2006-02-27">February 27, 2006</date> (FAA Order 8110.56), as well as any corresponding policy or guidance material, to reflect the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Provision</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator to take action otherwise authorized by law to protect aviation safety or passenger safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered aircraft</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘covered aircraft’ means an aircraft type-certificated in the restricted category under section 21.25 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, used for transporting firefighters to and from the site of a wildfire in order to perform ground wildfire suppression for the purpose of extinguishing a wildfire on behalf of, or pursuant to a contract with, a Federal, State, or local government agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Firefighters</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘firefighters’ means a trained fire suppression professional the transport of whom is necessary to accomplish a wildfire suppression operation.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9319-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Required Submission of Outline of System Changes at the Beginning of the Certification Process</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s105/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2319">134 Stat. 2319</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s105/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator shall initiate a process to revise procedures to require an applicant for an amendment to a type certificate for a transport category aircraft to disclose to the Administrator, in a single document submitted at the beginning of the process for amending such certificate, all new systems and intended changes to existing systems then known to such applicant. The Administrator shall finalize the revision of such procedures not later than 18 months after initiating such process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><content>Compliance with the procedures revised pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not preclude an applicant from making additional changes to aircraft systems as the design and application process proceeds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings provision</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the obligations of an applicant for an amended type certificate for a transport category airplane under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e">section 44704(e) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, as amended in this title.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “Administrator” and “type certificate” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s105/c">section 105(c) of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Integrated Project Teams</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s108">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2326">134 Stat. 2326</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s306/b">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 306(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1072">138 Stat. 1072</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s306/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon receipt of an application for a type certificate for a transport category airplane, the Administrator shall convene an interdisciplinary integrated project team responsible for coordinating review and providing advice and recommendations, as appropriate, to the Administrator on such application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In convening an interdisciplinary integrated project team under subsection (a), the Administrator shall appoint employees of the Administration or other Federal agencies, such as the Air Force, Volpe National Transportation Systems Center, or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (with the concurrence of the head of such other Federal agency), with specialized expertise and experience in the fields of engineering, systems design, human factors, and pilot training, including, at a minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not less than 1 designee of the Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety whose duty station is in the Administration’s headquarters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> representatives of the Aircraft Certification Service of the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> representatives of the Flight Standards Service of the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> experts in the fields of human factors, aerodynamics, flight controls, software, and systems design; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> any other subject matter expert whom the Administrator determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to carry out its duties with respect to the areas specified in subsection (d), a project team shall be available to the Administrator, upon request, at any time during the certification process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A project team shall advise the Administrator and make written recommendations to the Administrator, to be retained in the certification project file, including recommendations for any plans, analyses, assessments, and reports required to support and document the certification project, in the following areas associated with a new technology or novel design:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Initial review of design proposals proposed by the applicant and the establishment of the certification basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Identification of new technology, novel design, or safety critical design features or systems that are potentially catastrophic, either alone or in combination with another failure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Determination of compliance findings, system safety assessments, and safety critical functions the Administration should retain in terms of new technology, novel design, or safety critical design features or systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Evaluation of the Administration’s expertise or experience necessary to support the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Review and evaluation of an applicant’s request for exceptions or exemptions from compliance with airworthiness standards codified in title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of application for the change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Conduct of design reviews, procedure evaluations, and training evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Review of the applicant’s final design documentation and other data to evaluate compliance with all relevant Administration regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Documentation of FAA Response</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall provide a written response to each recommendation of each project team and shall retain such response in the certification project file.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], and annually thereafter through fiscal year 2028, the Administrator shall submit to the congressional committees of jurisdiction a report on the establishment of each integrated project team in accordance with this section during such fiscal year, including the role and composition of each such project team.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s108">section 108 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Employment Restrictions: Disqualification Based on Prior Employment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s111/a">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2330">134 Stat. 2330</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s111/a">“An employee of the [Federal Aviation] Administration with supervisory responsibility may not direct, conduct, or otherwise participate in oversight of a holder of a certificate issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44704">section 44704 of title 49</ref>, United States Code, that previously employed such employee in the preceding 1-year period.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">System Safety Assessments and Other Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s115">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2333">134 Stat. 2333</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s115">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator shall issue such regulations as are necessary to amend part 25 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and any associated advisory circular, guidance, or policy of the Administration, in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">System Safety Assessments and Other Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing regulations under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> require an applicant for an amended type certificate for a transport airplane to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> perform a system safety assessment with respect to each proposed design change that the Administrator determines is significant, with such assessment considering the airplane-level effects of individual errors, malfunctions, or failures and realistic pilot response times to such errors, malfunctions, or failures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> update such assessment to account for each subsequent proposed design change that the Administrator determines is significant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> provide appropriate employees of the Administration with the data and assumptions underlying each assessment and amended assessment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> provide for document traceability and clarity of explanations for changes to aircraft type designs and system safety assessment certification documents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> work with other civil aviation authorities representing states of design to ensure such regulations remain harmonized internationally.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Guidance or an advisory circular issued under subsection (a) shall, at minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> emphasize the importance of clear documentation of the technical details and failure modes and effects of a design change described in subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> ensure appropriate review of any change that results in a functional hazard assessment classification of major or greater, as such term is defined in FAA Advisory Circular 25.1309-1A (or any successor or replacement document).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FAA Review</inline>.—</heading><content>Appropriate employees of the Aircraft Certification Service and the Flight Standards Service of the Administration shall review each system safety assessment required under subsection (b)(1)(A), updated assessment required under subsection (b)(1)(B), and supporting data and assumptions required under subsection (b)(1)(C), to ensure that each such assessment sufficiently addresses the considerations listed in subsection (b)(1)(A).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s115">section 115 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931d-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Flight Crew Alerting</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s116">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2334">134 Stat. 2334</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dO/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 117–328, div. O, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5231">136 Stat. 5231</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dO/tV/s501/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator shall implement National Transportation Safety Board recommendations A–19–11 and A–19–12 (as contained in the safety recommendation report adopted on <date date="2019-09-09">September 9, 2019</date>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, the Administrator may not issue a type certificate for a transport category aircraft unless, in the case of a transport category aircraft other than a transport airplane, the type certificate applicant provides a means acceptable to the Administrator to assist the flight crew in prioritizing corrective actions and responding to systems failures (including by cockpit or flight manual procedures).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Existing Airplane Designs</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that the FAA shall ensure that any system safety assessment with respect to the Boeing 737-7, 737-8, 737-9, and 737-10 airplanes, as described in National Transportation Safety Board recommendation A-19-10, is conducted in accordance with such recommendation.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s116">section 116 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931e-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Changed Product Rule</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s344">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1101">138 Stat. 1101</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s344">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>], the Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to revise section 21.101 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to achieve the following objectives:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> For any significant design change, as determined by the Administrator, to require that the exception related to impracticality under subsection (b)(3) of such section from the requirement to comply with the latest amendments of the applicable airworthiness standards in effect on the date of application for the change be approved only after providing public notice and opportunity to comment on such exception.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To ensure appropriate documentation of any exception or exemption from airworthiness requirements in title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of application for the change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives] a briefing on the implementation by the FAA [Federal Aviation Administration] of the recommendations of the Changed Product Rule International Authorities Working Group, established for purposes of carrying out the requirements of section 117 of the Aircraft Certification, Safety, and Accountability Act [<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44704">49 U.S.C. 44704</ref> note), including recommendations on harmonized changes and reforms regarding the impractical exception.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue a final rule based on the notice of proposed rulemaking issued under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning in 2025 and annually thereafter through 2028, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an annual report detailing the number of all significant design change exceptions approved and denied under paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 21.101(b) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s117">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2335">134 Stat. 2335</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s306/f">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 306(f)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1072">138 Stat. 1072</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s306/f">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review and Reevaluation of Amended Type Certificates.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International leadership</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall exercise leadership in the creation of international policies and standards relating to the issuance of amended type certificates within the Certification Management Team.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reevaluation of amended type certificates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> encourage Certification Management Team members to examine and address any relevant covered recommendations (as defined in section 121(c) [<ref href="/us/stat/134/2344">134 Stat. 2344</ref>]) relating to the issuance of amended type certificates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> reevaluate existing assumptions and practices inherent in the amended type certificate process and assess whether such assumptions and practices are valid; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that Federal regulations relating to the issuance of amended type certificates are harmonized with the regulations of other international states of design.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amended Type Certificate Report and Rulemaking.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], and annually thereafter through fiscal year 2028, the Administrator shall brief the congressional committees of jurisdiction on the work and status of the development of such recommendations by the Certification Management Team.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initiation of action</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Administrator shall take action to revise and improve the process of issuing amended type certificates in accordance with this section. Such action shall include, at minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> initiation of a rulemaking proceeding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> development or revision of guidance and training materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In taking actions required under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall do the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Ensure that proposed changes to an aircraft are evaluated from an integrated whole aircraft system perspective that examines the integration of proposed changes with existing systems and associated impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Define key terms used for the changed product process under sections 21.19 and 21.101 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> Consider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the findings and work of the Certification Management Team and other similar international harmonization efforts;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> any relevant covered recommendations (as defined in section 121(c) [<ref href="/us/stat/134/2344">134 Stat. 2344</ref>]); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> whether a fixed time beyond which a type certificate may not be amended would improve aviation safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> Establish the extent to which the following design characteristics should preclude the issuance of an amended type certificate:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> A new or revised flight control system.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Any substantial changes to aerodynamic stability resulting from a physical change that may require a new or modified software system or control law in order to produce positive and acceptable stability and handling qualities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> A flight control system or augmented software to maintain aerodynamic stability in any portion of the flight envelope that was not required for a previously certified derivative.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> A change in structural components (other than a stretch or shrink of the fuselage) that results in a change in structural load paths or the magnitude of structural loads attributed to flight maneuvers or cabin pressurization.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> A novel or unusual system, component, or other feature whose failure would present a hazardous or catastrophic risk.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Develop objective criteria for helping to determine what constitutes a substantial change and a significant change.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Implement mandatory aircraft-level reviews throughout the certification process to validate the certification basis and assumptions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Require maintenance of relevant records of agreements between the FAA and an applicant that affect certification documentation and deliverables.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Ensure appropriate documentation of any exception or exemption from airworthiness requirements codified in title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of application for the change.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance materials</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall consider the following when developing orders and regulatory guidance, including advisory circulars, where appropriate:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Early FAA involvement and feedback paths in the aircraft certification process to ensure the FAA is aware of changes to design assumptions and product design impacting a changed product assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Presentation to the FAA of new technology, novel design, or safety critical features or systems, initially and throughout the certification process, when development and certification prompt design or compliance method revision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Examples of key terms used for the changed product process under sections 21.19 and 21.101 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Type certificate data sheet improvements to accurately state which regulations and amendment level the aircraft complies to and when compliance is limited to a subset of the aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Policies to guide applicants on proper visibility, clarity, and consistency of key design and compliance information that is submitted for certification, particularly with new design features.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> The creation, validation, and implementation of analytical tools appropriate for the analysis of complex system for the FAA and applicants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Early coordination processes with the FAA for the functional hazard assessments validation and preliminary system safety assessments review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training materials</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> develop training materials for establishing the certification basis for changed aeronautical products pursuant to section 21.101 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, applications for a new type certificate pursuant to section 21.19 of such title, and the regulatory guidance developed as a result of the rulemaking conducted pursuant to paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> procedures for disseminating such materials to implementing personnel of the FAA, designees, and applicants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification management team defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Certification Management Team’ means the team framework under which the FAA, the European Aviation Safety Agency, the Transport Canada Civil Aviation, and the National Civil Aviation Agency of Brazil, manage the technical, policy, certification, manufacturing, export, and continued airworthiness issues common among the 4 authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall finalize the actions initiated under paragraph (2) not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Leadership</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall exercise leadership within the ICAO and among other civil aviation regulators representing states of aircraft design to advocate for the adoption of an amended changed product rule on a global basis, consistent with ICAO standards.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s117">section 117 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb931f-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expert Safety Review</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s119/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 119(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2339">134 Stat. 2339</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s119/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator shall initiate an expert safety review of assumptions relied upon by the Administration and manufacturers of transport category aircraft in the design and certification of such aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The expert safety review required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a review of Administration regulations, guidance, and directives related to pilot response assumptions relied upon by the FAA and manufacturers of transport category aircraft in the design and certification of such aircraft, and human factors and human system integration, particularly those related to pilot and aircraft interfaces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a focused review of the assumptions relied on regarding the time for pilot responses to non-normal conditions in designing such aircraft’s systems and instrumentation, including responses to safety-significant failure conditions and failure scenarios that trigger multiple, and possibly conflicting, warnings and alerts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a review of human factors assumptions with applicable operational data, human factors research and the input of human factors experts and FAA operational data, and as appropriate, recommendations for modifications to existing assumptions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a review of revisions made to the airman certification standards for certificates over the last 4 years, including any possible effects on pilot competency in basic manual flying skills;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> consideration of the global nature of the aviation marketplace, varying levels of pilot competency, and differences in pilot training programs worldwide;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> a process for aviation stakeholders, including pilots, airlines, inspectors, engineers, test pilots, human factors experts, and other aviation safety experts, to provide and discuss any observations, feedback, and best practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> a review of processes currently in place to ensure that when carrying out the certification of a new aircraft type, or an amended type, the cumulative effects that new technologies, and the interaction between new technologies and unchanged systems for an amended type certificate, may have on pilot interactions with aircraft systems are properly assessed through system safety assessments or otherwise; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> a review of processes currently in place to account for any necessary adjustments to system safety assessments, pilot procedures and training requirements, or design requirements when there are changes to the assumptions relied upon by the Administration and manufacturers of transport category aircraft in the design and certification of such aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the conclusion of the expert safety review pursuant to paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit to the congressional committees of jurisdiction a report on the results of the review, including any recommendations for actions or best practices to ensure the FAA and the manufacturers of transport category aircraft have accounted for pilot response assumptions to be relied upon in the design and certification of transport category aircraft and tools or methods identified to better integrate human factors throughout the process for such certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International engagement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall notify other international regulators that certify transport category aircraft type designs of the expert panel report and encourage them to review the report and evaluate their regulations and processes in light of the recommendations included in the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The expert safety review shall end upon submission of the report required pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall issue or update such regulations as are necessary to implement the recommendations of the expert safety review that the Administrator determines are necessary to improve aviation safety.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s119/c">section 119(c) of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9320-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Human Factors Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s126">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2347">134 Stat. 2347</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s126">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Human Factors</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator, in consultation with aircraft manufacturers, operators, and pilots, and in coordination with the head of such other Federal agency that the Administrator determines appropriate, shall develop research requirements to address the integration of human factors in the design and certification of aircraft that are intended for use in air transportation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing such research requirements, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> establish goals for research in areas of study relevant to advancing technology, improving design engineering and certification practices, and facilitating better understanding of human factors concepts in the context of the growing development and reliance on automated or complex flight deck systems in aircraft operations, including the development of tools to validate pilot recognition and response assumptions and diagnostic tools to improve the clarity of failure indications presented to pilots;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> take into consideration and leverage any existing or planned research that is conducted by, or conducted in partnership with, the FAA; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> focus on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> preventing a recurrence of the types of accidents that have involved transport category airplanes designed and manufactured in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> increasingly complex aircraft systems and designs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>In implementing the research requirements developed under this section, the Administrator shall work with appropriate organizations and authorities with expertise including, to the maximum extent practicable, the Center of Excellence for Technical Training and Human Performance and the Center of Excellence developed or expanded pursuant to section 127 [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44513">section 44513 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $7,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2023, out of funds made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s48102/a">section 48102(a) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s126">section 126 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9321-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Operational Evaluations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s128">Pub. L. 116–260, div. V, title I, § 128</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2349">134 Stat. 2349</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dV/tI/s128">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Operational Evaluations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Administrator shall revise existing policies for manufacturers of transport airplanes to ensure that pilot operational evaluations for airplane types that are submitted for certification utilize pilots from air carriers that are expected to operate such airplanes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Such manufacturer shall ensure, to the satisfaction of the Administrator, that the air carrier and foreign air carrier pilots used for such evaluations include pilots of varying levels of experience.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s128">section 128 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dV/s137">section 137 of div. V of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9322-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Securing Aircraft Avionics Systems</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dB/tV/s506">Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3354">132 Stat. 3354</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s394">Pub. L. 118–63, title III, § 394</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1145">138 Stat. 1145</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/63/tIII/s394">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator [of the Federal Aviation Administration] shall revise, as appropriate, existing Federal Aviation Administration regulations regarding airworthiness certification—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to address cybersecurity for avionics systems, including software components;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to require that aircraft avionics systems used for flight guidance or aircraft control be secured against unauthorized access via passenger in-flight entertainment systems through such means as the Administrator determines appropriate to protect the avionics systems from unauthorized external and internal access; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to establish a process and timeline by which software-based systems and equipment, including aircraft flight critical systems of aircraft operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, can be regularly screened to attempt to determine whether the software-based systems and equipment have been compromised by unauthorized external or internal access.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall consider the recommendations of the Aircraft Systems Information Security Protection Working Group under section 2111 of the FAA Extension Safety and Security Act of 2016 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/190">Public Law 114–190</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/130/615">130 Stat. 615</ref> [625]) [<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44903">49 U.S.C. 44903</ref> note].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9323-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Small Airplane Revitalization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/53">Pub. L. 113–53</ref>, <date date="2013-11-27">Nov. 27, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/584">127 Stat. 584</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/53">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Small Airplane Revitalization Act of 2013’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A healthy small aircraft industry is integral to economic growth and to maintaining an effective transportation infrastructure for communities and countries around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Small airplanes comprise nearly 90 percent of general aviation aircraft certified by the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> General aviation provides for the cultivation of a workforce of engineers, manufacturing and maintenance professionals, and pilots who secure the economic success and defense of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> General aviation contributes to well-paying jobs in the manufacturing and technology sectors in the United States and products produced by those sectors are exported in great numbers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Technology developed and proven in general aviation aids in the success and safety of all sectors of aviation and scientific competence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The average small airplane in the United States is now 40 years old and the regulatory barriers to bringing new designs to the market are resulting in a lack of innovation and investment in small airplane design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Since 2003, the United States lost 10,000 active private pilots per year on average, partially due to a lack of cost-effective, new small airplanes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> General aviation safety can be improved by modernizing and revamping the regulations relating to small airplanes to clear the path for technology adoption and cost-effective means to retrofit the existing fleet with new safety technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> SAFETY AND REGULATORY IMPROVEMENTS FOR GENERAL AVIATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2015-12-15">December 15, 2015</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue a final rule—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to advance the safety and continued development of small airplanes by reorganizing the certification requirements for such airplanes under part 23 to streamline the approval of safety advancements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that meets the objectives described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objectives Described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The objectives described in this subsection are based on the recommendations of the Part 23 Reorganization Aviation Rulemaking Committee:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The establishment of a regulatory regime for small airplanes that will improve safety and reduce the regulatory cost burden for the Federal Aviation Administration and the aviation industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The establishment of broad, outcome-driven safety objectives that will spur innovation and technology adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The replacement of current, prescriptive requirements under part 23 with performance-based regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The use of consensus standards accepted by the Federal Aviation Administration to clarify how the safety objectives of part 23 may be met using specific designs and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consensus-Based Standards</inline>.—</heading><content>In prescribing regulations under this section, the Administrator shall use consensus standards, as described in section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1996 [1995] (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s272">15 U.S.C. 272</ref> note), to the extent practicable while continuing traditional methods for meeting part 23.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Safety Cooperation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall lead the effort to improve general aviation safety by working with leading aviation regulators to assist them in adopting a complementary regulatory approach for small airplanes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consensus standards.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘consensus standards’ means standards developed by an organization described in subparagraph (B) that may include provisions requiring that owners of relevant intellectual property have agreed to make that intellectual property available on a nondiscriminatory, royalty-free, or reasonable royalty basis to all interested persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Organizations described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An organization described in this subparagraph is a domestic or international organization that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> plans, develops, establishes, or coordinates, through a process based on consensus and using agreed-upon procedures, voluntary standards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> operates in a transparent manner, considers a balanced set of interests with respect to such standards, and provides for due process and an appeals process with respect to such standards.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part 23</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘part 23’ means part 23 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part 23 reorganization aviation rulemaking committee</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Part 23 Reorganization Aviation Rulemaking Committee’ means the aviation rulemaking committee established by the Federal Aviation Administration in August 2011 to consider the reorganization of the regulations under part 23.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Small airplane</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘small airplane’ means an airplane which is certified to part 23 standards.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9324-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tIII/s303/b">Pub. L. 112–95, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/57">126 Stat. 57</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/95/tIII/s303/b">“Before <date date="2013-01-01">January 1, 2013</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may continue to issue certificates under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44704/e">section 44704(e) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9325-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Aircraft Certification Process Review and Reform</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 112–95, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/66">126 Stat. 66</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/95/tIII/s312">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, in consultation with representatives of the aviation industry, shall conduct an assessment of the certification and approval process under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44704">section 44704 of title 49</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the assessment, the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the expected number of applications for product certifications and approvals the Administrator will receive under section 44704 of such title in the 1-year, 5-year, and 10-year periods following the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> process reforms and improvements necessary to allow the Administrator to review and approve the applications in a fair and timely fashion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the status of recommendations made in previous reports on the Administration’s certification process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> methods for enhancing the effective use of delegation systems, including organizational designation authorization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> methods for training the Administration’s field office employees in the safety management system and auditing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the status of updating airworthiness requirements, including implementing recommendations in the Administration’s report entitled ‘Part 23—Small Airplane Certification Process Study’ (OK–09–3468, dated July 2009).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting the assessment, the Administrator shall make recommendations to improve efficiency and reduce costs through streamlining and reengineering the certification process under section 44704 of such title to ensure that the Administrator can conduct certifications and approvals under such section in a manner that supports and enables the development of new products and technologies and the global competitiveness of the United States aviation industry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>], the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of the assessment, together with an explanation of how the Administrator will implement recommendations made under subsection (c) and measure the effectiveness of the recommendations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>], the Administrator shall begin to implement the recommendations made under subsection (c).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9326-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical Aircraft Documents</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tVIII/s816">Pub. L. 112–95, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/126">126 Stat. 126</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/95/tVIII/s816">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preservation of Documents.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall take such actions as the Administrator determines necessary to preserve original aircraft type certificate engineering and technical data in the possession of the Federal Aviation Administration related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> approved aircraft type certificate numbers ATC 1 through ATC 713; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Group-2 approved aircraft type certificate numbers 2–1 through 2–544.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of order</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>], the Administrator shall revise FAA Order 1350.15C, Item Number 8110. Such revision shall prohibit the destruction of the historical aircraft documents identified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator may carry out paragraph (1) in consultation with the Archivist of the United States and the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Documents.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Freedom of information act requests</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall make the documents to be preserved under subsection (a)(1) available to a person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> upon receipt of a request made by the person pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> subject to a prohibition on use of the documents for commercial purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trade secrets, commercial, and financial information</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 552(b)(4) of such title shall not apply to requests for documents to be made available pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Holder of Type Certificate.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rights of holder</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall affect the rights of a holder or owner of a type certificate identified in subsection (a)(1), nor require the holder or owner to provide, surrender, or preserve any original or duplicate engineering or technical data to or for the Federal Aviation Administration, a person, or the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Liability</inline>.—</heading><content>There shall be no liability on the part of, and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against, a holder of a type certificate, its authorized representative, its agents, or its employees, or any firm, person, corporation, or insurer related to the type certificate data and documents identified in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airworthiness</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the holder of a type certificate identified in subsection (a)(1) shall only be responsible for Federal Aviation Administration regulation requirements related to type certificate data and documents identified in subsection (a)(1) for aircraft having a standard airworthiness certificate issued prior to the date the documents are released to a person by the Federal Aviation Administration under subsection (b)(1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcbfb9327-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Development and Oversight of System for Certification of Design Organizations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/176/tII/s227/b/1">Pub. L. 108–176, title II, § 227(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2531">117 Stat. 2531</ref>, provided that, not later than 4 years after <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration was to transmit to Congress a plan for the development and oversight of a certification system of design organizations to ensure compliance with the requirements and minimum standards of <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44701/a">section 44701(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
