<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcc2d9fd2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924"><num value="44924">§ 44924.</num><heading> Repair station security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fd3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security Review and Audit</inline>.—</heading><content>To ensure the security of maintenance and repair work conducted on air carrier aircraft and components at foreign repair stations, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall complete a security review and audit of foreign repair stations that are certified by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and that work on air carrier aircraft and components. The review shall be completed not later than 6 months after the date on which the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration issues regulations under subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fd4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Addressing Security Concerns</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall require a foreign repair station to address the security issues and vulnerabilities identified in a security audit conducted under subsection (a) within 90 days of providing notice to the repair station of the security issues and vulnerabilities so identified and shall notify the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration that a deficiency was identified in the security audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fd5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Suspensions and Revocations of Certificates.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc2d9fd6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to carry out effective security measures</inline>.—</heading><content>If, after the 90th day on which a notice is provided to a foreign repair station under subsection (b), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration determines that the foreign repair station does not maintain and carry out effective security measures, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall notify the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration of the determination. Upon receipt of the determination, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall suspend the certification of the repair station until such time as the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration determines that the repair station maintains and carries out effective security measures and transmits the determination to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc2d9fd7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Immediate security risk</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration determines that a foreign repair station poses an immediate security risk, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall notify the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration of the determination. Upon receipt of the determination, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall revoke the certification of the repair station.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc2d9fd8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures for appeals</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish procedures for appealing a revocation of a certificate under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fd9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure To Meet Audit Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>If the security audits required by subsection (a) are not completed on or before the date that is 6 months after the date on which the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration issues regulations under subsection (f), the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall be barred from certifying any foreign repair station (other than a station that was previously certified, or is in the process of certification, by the Administration under this part) until such audits are completed for existing stations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fda-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority for Audits</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting the audits described in subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall give priority to foreign repair stations located in countries identified by the Government as posing the most significant security risks.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fdb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall issue final regulations to ensure the security of foreign and domestic aircraft repair stations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc2d9fdc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s44924/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration does not issue final regulations before the deadline specified in subsection (f), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall transmit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing an explanation as to why the deadline was not met and a schedule for issuing the final regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcc2d9fdd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/tVI/s611/b/1">Pub. L. 108–176, title VI, § 611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2571">117 Stat. 2571</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXVI/s1616/b">Pub. L. 110–53, title XVI, § 1616(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/488">121 Stat. 488</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dK/tI/s1991/d/20">Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, § 1991(d)(20)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3637">132 Stat. 3637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcc2d9fde-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcc2d9fdf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcc2d9fe0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/D">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(D)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration” for “Under Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/A">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(A)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration,” for “Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security of the Department of Homeland Security,” and “Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under” for “Administrator under”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/B">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(B)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/B">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(B)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration” for “Administrator”, was executed by making the substitution wherever appearing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/B">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(B)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/C">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(C)</ref>, substituted “The” for “Not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this section, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1991/d/20/B">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1991(d)(20)(B)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s1616/b/1">Pub. L. 110–53, § 1616(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “6 months” for “18 months”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s1616/b/2">Pub. L. 110–53, § 1616(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “(other than a station that was previously certified, or is in the process of certification, by the Administration under this part)” after “foreign repair station”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s1616/b/1">Pub. L. 110–53, § 1616(b)(1)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (b) by substituting “6 months” for “18 months”, was executed by making the substitution in subsec. (d), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcc2d9fe1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcc2d9fe2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/176/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–176</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2003 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcc2d9fe3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Suspension of Certification of Foreign Repair Stations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXVI/s1616/a">Pub. L. 110–53, title XVI, § 1616(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/488">121 Stat. 488</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/53/tXVI/s1616/a">“If the regulations required by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44924/f">section 44924(f) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, are not issued within 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>], the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may not certify any foreign repair station under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, after such date unless the station was previously certified, or is in the process of certification by the Administration under that part.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
