<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcc5face3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145"><num value="47145">§ 47145.</num><heading> Pilot program for airport accessibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5face4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish and carry out a pilot program to award grants to sponsors to carry out capital projects to upgrade the accessibility of commercial service airports for individuals with disabilities by increasing the number of commercial service airports, airport terminals, or airport facilities that meet or exceed the standards and regulations under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12131">42 U.S.C. 12131</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002186">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002186"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">29 U.S.C. 701</ref> note) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002186">1</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5face5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5face6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), a sponsor shall use a grant awarded under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5face7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for a project to repair, improve, or relocate the infrastructure of an airport, airport terminal, or airport facility to increase accessibility for individuals with disabilities, or as part of a plan to increase accessibility for individuals with disabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5face8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> to develop or modify a plan (as described in subsection (e)) for a project that increases accessibility for individuals with disabilities, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcc5face9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assessments of accessibility or assessments of planned modifications to an airport, airport terminal, or airport facility for passenger use, performed by the disability advisory committee of the recipient airport (if applicable), the protection and advocacy system for individuals with disabilities in the applicable State, a center for independent living, or a disability organization, including an advocacy or nonprofit organization that represents or provides services to individuals with disabilities; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcc5facea-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> coordination by the disability advisory committee of the recipient airport with a protection and advocacy system, center for independent living, or such disability organization; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5faceb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to carry out any other project that meets or exceeds the standards and regulations described in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facec-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Eligible costs for a project funded with a grant awarded under this section shall be limited to the costs associated with carrying out the purpose authorized under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5faced-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A sponsor may use a grant under this section to upgrade a commercial service airport that is accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facee-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consistent with the current (as of the date of the upgrade) standards and regulations described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facef-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> even if the related service, program, or activity, when viewed in the entirely of the service, program, or activity, is readily accessible and usable as so described.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5facf0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection Criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In making grants to sponsors under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to sponsors that are proposing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facf1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a capital project to upgrade the accessibility of a commercial service airport that is not accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities consistent with standards and regulations described in subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facf2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to meet or exceed the Airports Council International accreditation under the Accessibility Enhancement Accreditation, through the incorporation of universal design principles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5facf3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Accessibility Commitment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A sponsor that receives a grant under this section shall adopt a plan under which the sponsor commits to pursuing airport accessibility projects that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facf4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> enhance the passenger experience and maximize accessibility of commercial service airports, airport terminals, or airport facilities for individuals with disabilities, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5facf5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> upgrading bathrooms, counters, or pumping rooms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5facf6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> increasing audio and visual accessibility on information boards, security gates, or paging systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5facf7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> updating airport terminals to increase the availability of accessible seating and power outlets for durable medical equipment (such as powered wheelchairs);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5facf8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> updating airport websites and other information communication technology to be accessible for individuals with disabilities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcc5facf9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> increasing the number of elevators, including elevators that move power wheelchairs to an aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facfa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> improve the operations of, provide efficiencies of service to, and enhance the use of commercial service airports for individuals with disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facfb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish a disability advisory committee if the airport is a small, medium, or large hub airport; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facfc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> make improvements in personnel, infrastructure, and technology that can assist passenger self-identification regarding disability and needing assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5facfd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Disability Advocacy Entities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In administering grants under this section, the Secretary shall encourage—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facfe-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> engagement with disability advocacy entities (such as the disability advisory committee of the sponsor) and a protection and advocacy system for individuals with disabilities in the applicable State, a center for independent living, or a disability organization, including an advocacy or nonprofit organization that represents or provides services to individuals with disabilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5facff-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assessments of accessibility or assessments of planned modifications to commercial service airports to the extent merited by the scope of the capital project of the sponsor proposed to be assisted under this section, taking into account any such assessment already conducted by the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5fad00-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Share of Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Government’s share of allowable project costs for a project carried out with a grant under this section shall be the Government’s share of allowable project costs specified under section 47109.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5fad01-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5fad02-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Center for independent living</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “center for independent living” has the meaning given such term in section 702 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s796a">29 U.S.C. 796a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5fad03-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disability advisory committee</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “disability advisory committee” means a body of stakeholders (including airport staff, airline representatives, and individuals with disabilities) that provide to airports and appropriate transportation authorities input from individuals with disabilities, including identifying opportunities for removing barriers, expanding accessibility features, and improving accessibility for individuals with disabilities at airports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcc5fad04-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection and advocacy system</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “protection and advocacy system” means a system established in accordance with section 143 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15043">42 U.S.C. 15043</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc5fad05-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s47145/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028, the Secretary may use up to $20,000,000 of the amounts that would otherwise be used to make grants from the discretionary fund under section 47115 for each such fiscal year to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcc5fad06-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/118/63/tVII/s725/a">Pub. L. 118–63, title VII, § 725(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1267">138 Stat. 1267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcc5fad07-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcc5fad08-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcc5fad09-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 126 (§ 12101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 12131 et seq.) of chapter 126 of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/112">Pub. L. 93–112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 701 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">section 701 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
