<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca9377b8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121"><num value="5121">§ 5121.</num><heading> Administrative</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377b9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>To carry out this chapter, the Secretary may investigate, conduct tests, make reports, issue subpenas, conduct hearings, require the production of records and property, take depositions, and conduct research, development, demonstration, and training activities. Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary may issue an order requiring compliance with this chapter or a regulation prescribed, or an order, special permit, or approval issued, under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377ba-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records, Reports, and Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A person subject to this chapter shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377bb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> maintain records and property, make reports, and provide information the Secretary by regulation or order requires; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377bc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make the records, property, reports, and information available for inspection when the Secretary undertakes an investigation or makes a request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377bd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inspections and Investigations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377be-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A designated officer, employee, or agent of the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377bf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may inspect and investigate, at a reasonable time and in a reasonable manner, records and property relating to a function described in section 5103(b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> except in the case of packaging immediately adjacent to its hazardous material contents, may gain access to, open, and examine a package offered for, or in, transportation when the officer, employee, or agent has an objectively reasonable and articulable belief that the package may contain a hazardous material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> may remove from transportation a package or related packages in a shipment offered for or in transportation for which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377c2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such officer, employee, or agent has an objectively reasonable and articulable belief that the package may pose an imminent hazard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377c3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such officer, employee, or agent contemporaneously documents such belief in accordance with procedures set forth in guidance or regulations prescribed under subsection (e);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> may gather information from the offeror, carrier, packaging manufacturer or tester, or other person responsible for the package, to ascertain the nature and hazards of the contents of the package;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> as necessary, under terms and conditions specified by the Secretary, may order the offeror, carrier, packaging manufacturer or tester, or other person responsible for the package to have the package transported to, opened, and the contents examined and analyzed, at a facility appropriate for the conduct of such examination and analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> when safety might otherwise be compromised, may authorize properly qualified personnel to assist in the activities conducted under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377c7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> shall provide to the affected offeror, carrier, packaging manufacturer or tester, or other person responsible for the package reasonable notice of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377c8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> his or her decision to exercise his or her authority under paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377c9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any findings made; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377ca-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/1/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any actions being taken as a result of a finding of noncompliance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377cb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Display of credentials</inline>.—</heading><content>An officer, employee, or agent acting under this subsection shall display proper credentials, in person or in writing, when requested.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377cc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Safe resumption of transportation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In instances when, as a result of an inspection or investigation under this subsection, an imminent hazard is not found to exist, the Secretary, in accordance with procedures set forth in regulations prescribed under subsection (e), shall assist—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377cd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the safe and prompt resumption of transportation of the package concerned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377ce-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in any case in which the hazardous material being transported is perishable, in the safe and expeditious resumption of transportation of the perishable hazardous material.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377cf-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency Orders.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If, upon inspection, investigation, testing, or research, the Secretary determines that a violation of a provision of this chapter, or a regulation prescribed under this chapter, or an unsafe condition or practice, constitutes or is causing an imminent hazard, the Secretary may issue or impose emergency restrictions, prohibitions, recalls, or out-of-service orders, without notice or an opportunity for a hearing, but only to the extent necessary to abate the imminent hazard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Written orders</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The action of the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be in a written emergency order that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377d2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describes the violation, condition, or practice that constitutes or is causing the imminent hazard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377d3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> states the restrictions, prohibitions, recalls, or out-of-service orders issued or imposed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377d4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> describes the standards and procedures for obtaining relief from the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Opportunity for review</inline>.—</heading><content>After taking action under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide for review of the action under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref> if a petition for review is filed within 20 calendar days of the date of issuance of the order for the action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expiration of effectiveness of order</inline>.—</heading><content>If a petition for review of an action is filed under paragraph (3) and the review under that paragraph is not completed by the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date the petition is filed, the action shall cease to be effective at the end of such period unless the Secretary determines, in writing, that the imminent hazard providing a basis for the action continues to exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Out-of-service order defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term “out-of-service order” means a requirement that an aircraft, vessel, motor vehicle, train, railcar, locomotive, other vehicle, transport unit, transport vehicle, freight container, potable tank, or other package not be moved until specified conditions have been met.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377d8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377d9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety and Security Reauthorization Act of 2005, the Secretary shall issue temporary regulations to carry out subsections (c) and (d). The temporary regulations shall expire on the date of issuance of the regulations under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377da-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after such date of enactment, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out subsections (c) and (d) in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377db-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters to be addressed</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations issued under this subsection shall address—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377dc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the safe and expeditious resumption of transportation of perishable hazardous material, including radiopharmaceuticals and other medical products, that may require timely delivery due to life-threatening situations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377dd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the means by which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377de-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> noncompliant packages that present an imminent hazard are placed out-of-service until the condition is corrected; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca9377df-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> noncompliant packages that do not present a hazard are moved to their final destination;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377e0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> appropriate training and equipment for inspectors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca9377e1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/e/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the proper closure of packaging in accordance with the hazardous material regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377e2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Facility, Staff, and Reporting System on Risks, Emergencies, and Actions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377e3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377e4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> maintain a facility and technical staff sufficient to provide, within the United States Government, the capability of evaluating a risk related to the transportation of hazardous material and material alleged to be hazardous;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377e5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> maintain a central reporting system and information center capable of providing information and advice to law enforcement and firefighting personnel, other interested individuals, and officers and employees of the Government and State and local governments on meeting an emergency related to the transportation of hazardous material; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377e6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> conduct a continuous review on all aspects of transporting hazardous material to decide on and take appropriate actions to ensure safe transportation of hazardous material.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377e7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not prevent the Secretary from making a contract with a private entity for use of a supplemental reporting system and information center operated and maintained by the contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377e8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grants and Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may enter into grants and cooperative agreements with a person, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, a unit of State or local government, an Indian tribe, a foreign government (in coordination with the Department of State), an educational institution, or other appropriate entity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377e9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to expand risk assessment and emergency response capabilities with respect to the safety and security of transportation of hazardous material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377ea-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to enhance emergency communications capacity as determined necessary by the Secretary, including the use of integrated, interoperable emergency communications technologies where appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377eb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to conduct research, development, demonstration, risk assessment, and emergency response planning and training activities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377ec-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to otherwise carry out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca9377ed-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall, once every 2 years, prepare and make available to the public on the Department of Transportation’s Internet Web site a comprehensive report on the transportation of hazardous materials during the preceding 2 calendar years. The report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377ee-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a statistical compilation of accidents and casualties related to the transportation of hazardous material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377ef-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a list and summary of applicable Government regulations, criteria, orders, and special permits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377f0-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a summary of the basis for each special permit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377f1-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an evaluation of the effectiveness of enforcement activities relating to a function regulated by the Secretary under section 5103(b)(1) and the degree of voluntary compliance with regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377f2-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a summary of outstanding problems in carrying out this chapter in order of priority; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca9377f3-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s5121/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> recommendations for appropriate legislation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca9377f4-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s1/d">Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/779">108 Stat. 779</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/311/tI">Pub. L. 103–311, title I</ref>, §§ 108, 117(a)(2), <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1674">108 Stat. 1674</ref>, 1678; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tVII">Pub. L. 109–59, title VII</ref>, §§ 7118, 7126, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1902">119 Stat. 1902</ref>, 1909; <ref href="/us/pl/110/244/tIII/s302/e">Pub. L. 110–244, title III, § 302(e)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-06">June 6, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1618">122 Stat. 1618</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tII/s32501/c">Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title II, § 32501(c)</ref>, title III, § 33009(a), (b)(1), (c), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/803">126 Stat. 803</ref>, 836, 837; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tVII/s7205">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title VII, § 7205</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1592">129 Stat. 1592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca9377f5-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idca9377f6-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idca9377f7-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5121(a)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1808(a) (1st sentence, last sentence words before semicolon).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Jan. 3, 1975</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/93/633/s109/a">Pub. L. 93–633, § 109(a)</html:a> (1st sentence, last sentence words before semicolon), (b), (c), <html:a href="/us/stat/88/2159">88 Stat. 2159</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5121(b)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1808(b).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5121(c)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1808(c).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5121(d)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1808(d).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Jan. 3, 1975</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/93/633/s109/d">Pub. L. 93–633, § 109(d)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/88/2159">88 Stat. 2159</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Oct. 30, 1984</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/98/559/s1/a">Pub. L. 98–559, § 1(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/98/2907">98 Stat. 2907</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Nov. 16, 1990</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/101/615/s11">Pub. L. 101–615, § 11</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/104/3259">104 Stat. 3259</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5121(e)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">49 App.:1808(e).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Jan. 3, 1975</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/93/633/s109/e">Pub. L. 93–633, § 109(e)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/88/2159">88 Stat. 2159</html:a>; <html:span class="date">Oct. 30, 1984</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/98/559/s1/b">Pub. L. 98–559, § 1(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/98/2907">98 Stat. 2907</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the words “to the extent necessary . . . his responsibilities under” and “relevant” are omitted as surplus. The word “documents” is omitted as being included in “records”. The words “directly or indirectly” are omitted as surplus. The word “prescribed” is substituted for “issued” for consistency in the revised title and with other titles of the United States Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), before clause (1), the words “requirements under” are omitted as surplus. In clause (1), the words “establish and” are omitted as surplus. The word “requires” is substituted for “prescribe” for clarity and consistency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(1), before clause (A), the words “enter upon . . . and examine” and “of persons to the extent such records and properties” are omitted as surplus. In clause (B), the words “or shipment by any person” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (d)(1), before clause (A), the words “establish and” are omitted as executed. In clause (B), the words “capable of” are substituted for “so as to be able to” to eliminate unnecessary words. The words “technical and other” and “of communities” are omitted as surplus. The words “and employees” are added for consistency in the revised title and with other titles of the Code. In clause (C), the words “in order” and “to be able to” are omitted as surplus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (e), before clause (1), the words “prepare and” and “comprehensive” are omitted as surplus. In clause (1), the word “thorough” is omitted as surplus. In clause (2), the words “in effect” are omitted as surplus. In clause (3), the words “granted or maintained” are omitted as surplus. In clause (6), the words “additional . . . as are deemed necessary or” are omitted as surplus.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca9377f8-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca9377f9-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety and Security Reauthorization Act of 2005, referred to in subsec. (e), is the date of enactment of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/109/59">Pub. L. 109–59</ref>, which was approved <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca9377fa-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> substituted “make available to the public on the Department of Transportation’s Internet Web site” for “transmit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (c)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s33009/a">Pub. L. 112–141, § 33009(a)</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s32501/c">Pub. L. 112–141, § 32501(c)</ref>, inserted “, in person or in writing,” after “proper credentials”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s33009/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 33009(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s33009/c">Pub. L. 112–141, § 33009(c)</ref>, inserted “safety and” before “security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/244/s302/e/1">Pub. L. 110–244, § 302(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “special permits” for “exemptions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/244/s302/e/2">Pub. L. 110–244, § 302(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “special permit” for “exemption”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7126">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7126</ref>, substituted “Secretary may investigate” for “Secretary of Transportation may investigate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/a">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(a)</ref>, inserted “conduct tests,” after “investigate,” and substituted “Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), after” for “After” and “regulation prescribed, or an order, special permit, or approval issued,” for “regulation prescribed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/b/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and property” after “records”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/b/2">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “property,” after “records,” and “for inspection” after “available” and substituted “undertakes an investigation or makes a request” for “requests”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/c">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(c)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) The Secretary may authorize an officer, employee, or agent to inspect, at a reasonable time and in a reasonable way, records and property related to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) manufacturing, fabricating, marking, maintaining, reconditioning, repairing, testing, or distributing a packaging or a container for use by a person in transporting hazardous material in commerce; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the transportation of hazardous material in commerce.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) An officer, employee, or agent under this subsection shall display proper credentials when requested.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/d">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(d)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e). Former subsecs. (d) and (e) redesignated (f) and (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/d/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/e">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(e)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/f/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(f)(1)</ref>, substituted “transmit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate” for “submit to the President for transmittal to the Congress” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/d/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s7118/f/2">Pub. L. 109–59, § 7118(f)(2)</ref>, inserted “relating to a function regulated by the Secretary under section 5103(b)(1)” after “activities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/311/s117/a/2">Pub. L. 103–311, § 117(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “a packaging or a” for “a package or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/311/s108">Pub. L. 103–311, § 108</ref>, substituted “Report” for “Annual Report” in heading and substituted first sentence for former first sentence which read as follows: “The Secretary shall submit to the President, for submission to Congress, not later than June 15th of each year, a report about the transportation of hazardous material during the prior calendar year.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca9377fb-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca9377fc-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca9377fd-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of Title 23</ref>, Highways.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca9377fe-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Paperless Hazard Communications Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33005">Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title III, § 33005</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/833">126 Stat. 833</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33005">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] may conduct pilot projects to evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of using paperless hazard communications systems. At least 1 of the pilot projects under this section shall take place in a rural area.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting pilot projects under this section, the Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> may not waive the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s5110">section 5110 of title 49</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> shall consult with organizations representing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> fire services personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> law enforcement and other appropriate enforcement personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> other emergency response providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> persons who offer hazardous material for transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> persons who transport hazardous material by air, highway, rail, and water; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> employees of persons who transport or offer for transportation hazardous material by air, highway, rail, and water.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of Title 23</ref>, Highways], the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> prepare a report on the results of the pilot projects carried out under this section, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a detailed description of the pilot projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an evaluation of each pilot project, including an evaluation of the performance of each paperless hazard communications system in such project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an assessment of the safety and security impact of using paperless hazard communications systems, including any impact on the public, emergency response, law enforcement, and the conduct of inspections and investigations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> an analysis of the associated benefits and costs of using the paperless hazard communications systems for each mode of transportation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a recommendation that incorporates the information gathered in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) on whether paperless hazard communications systems should be permanently incorporated into the Federal hazardous material transportation safety program under chapter 51 of title 49, United States Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> submit a final report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that contains the results of the pilot projects carried out under this section, including the matters described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Paperless Hazard Communications System Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘paperless hazard communications system’ means the use of advanced communications methods, such as wireless communications devices, to convey hazard information between all parties in the transportation chain, including emergency responders and law enforcement personnel. The format of communication may be equivalent to that used by the carrier.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca9377ff-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Hazardous Material Enforcement Training</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33008">Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title III, § 33008</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/836">126 Stat. 836</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33008">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of Title 23</ref>, Highways], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall develop uniform performance standards for training hazardous material inspectors and investigators on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> how to collect, analyze, and publish findings from inspections and investigations of accidents or incidents involving the transportation of hazardous material; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> how to identify noncompliance with regulations issued under chapter 51 of title 49, United States Code, and take appropriate enforcement action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standards and Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may develop—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> guidelines for hazardous material inspector and investigator qualifications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> best practices and standards for hazardous material inspector and investigator training programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> standard protocols to coordinate investigation efforts among Federal, State, and local jurisdictions on accidents or incidents involving the transportation of hazardous material.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The standards, protocols, and guidelines established under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> shall be mandatory for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Department of Transportation’s multimodal personnel conducting hazardous material enforcement inspections or investigations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> State employees who conduct federally funded compliance reviews, inspections, or investigations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall be made available to Federal, State, and local hazardous material safety enforcement personnel.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca937800-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Finalizing Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33009/b/2">Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title III, § 33009(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/837">126 Stat. 837</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dC/tIII/s33009/b/2">“In accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s5103/b/2">section 5103(b)(2) of title 49</ref>, United States Code, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of Title 23</ref>, Highways], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall take all actions necessary to finalize a regulation under paragraph (1) of this subsection [amending this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca937801-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Toll Free Number for Reporting</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/311/tI/s116">Pub. L. 103–311, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1678">108 Stat. 1678</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/311/tI/s116">“The Secretary of Transportation shall designate a toll free telephone number for transporters of hazardous materials and other individuals to report to the Secretary possible violations of chapter 51 of title 49, United States Code, or any order or regulation issued under that chapter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
