<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcc85d1ff-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136"><num value="60136">§ 60136.</num><heading> Petroleum product transportation capacity study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d200-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretaries of Transportation and Energy shall conduct periodic analyses of the domestic transport of petroleum products by pipeline. Such analyses should identify areas of the United States where unplanned loss of individual pipeline facilities may cause shortages of petroleum products or price disruptions and where shortages of pipeline capacity and reliability concerns may have or are anticipated to contribute to shortages of petroleum products or price disruptions. Upon identifying such areas, the Secretaries may determine if the current level of regulation is sufficient to minimize the potential for unplanned losses of pipeline capacity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d201-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In preparing any analysis under this section, the Secretaries may consult with the heads of other government agencies and public- and private-sector experts in pipeline and other forms of petroleum product transportation, energy consumption, pipeline capacity, population, and economic development.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d202-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2008-06-01">June 1, 2008</date>, the Secretaries shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report setting forth their recommendations to reduce the likelihood of the shortages and price disruptions referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d203-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretaries shall submit additional reports to the congressional committees referred to in subsection (c) containing the results of any subsequent analyses performed under subsection (a) and any additional recommendations, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d204-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60136/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Petroleum Product Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “petroleum product” means oil of any kind or in any form, gasoline, diesel fuel, aviation fuel, fuel oil, kerosene, any product obtained from refining or processing of crude oil, liquefied petroleum gases, natural gas liquids, petrochemical feedstocks, condensate, waste or refuse mixtures containing any of such oil products, and any other liquid hydrocarbon compounds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcc85d205-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/468/s8/a">Pub. L. 109–468, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3492">120 Stat. 3492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
