<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcc85d206-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137"><num value="60137">§ 60137.</num><heading> Pipeline control room management</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d207-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2008-06-01">June 1, 2008</date>, the Secretary shall issue regulations requiring each operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline to develop, implement, and submit to the Secretary or, in the case of an operator of an intrastate pipeline located within the boundaries of a State that has in effect an annual certification under section 60105, to the head of the appropriate State authority, a human factors management plan designed to reduce risks associated with human factors, including fatigue, in each control center for the pipeline. Each plan must include, among the measures to reduce such risks, a maximum limit on the hours of service established by the operator for individuals employed as controllers in a control center for the pipeline.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d208-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review and Approval of the Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary or, in the case of an operator of an intrastate pipeline located within the boundaries of a State that has in effect an annual certification under section 60105, the head of the appropriate State authority, shall review and approve each plan submitted to the Secretary or the head of such authority under subsection (a). The Secretary and the head of such authority may not approve a plan that does not include a maximum limit on the hours of service established by the operator of the pipeline for individuals employed as controllers in a control center for the pipeline.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d209-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of the Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary or the head of the appropriate State authority determines that an operator’s plan submitted to the Secretary or the head of such authority under subsection (a), or implementation of such a plan, does not comply with the regulations issued under this section or is inadequate for the safe operation of a pipeline, the Secretary or the head of such authority may take action consistent with this chapter and enforce the requirements of such regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d20a-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance With the Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Each operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline shall document compliance with the plan submitted by the operator under subsection (a) and the reasons for any deviation from compliance with such plan. The Secretary or the head of the appropriate State authority, as the case may be, shall review the reasonableness of any such deviation in considering whether to take enforcement action or discontinue approval of the operator’s plan under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcc85d20b-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70" identifier="/us/usc/t49/s60137/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deviation Reporting Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>In issuing regulations under subsection (a), the Secretary shall develop and include in such regulations requirements for an operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline to report deviations from compliance with the plan submitted by the operator under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcc85d20c-47c4-11f1-9671-b5c725212f70">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/468/s12/a">Pub. L. 109–468, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3494">120 Stat. 3494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
