<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca1c5b1c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1062"><num value="1062">§ 1062.</num><heading> Suits for violations of law</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the United States attorney for the proper district, on affidavit filed with him by any citizen of the United States that <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1061">section 1061 of this title</ref> is being violated showing a description of the land inclosed with reasonable certainty, not necessarily by metes and bounds nor by governmental subdivisions of surveyed lands, but only so that the inclosure may be identified, and the persons guilty of the violation as nearly as may be, and by description, if the name cannot on reasonable inquiry be ascertained, to institute a civil suit in the proper United States district court, or territorial district court, in the name of the United States, and against the parties named or described who shall be in charge of or controlling the inclosure complained of as defendants; and jurisdiction is also conferred on any United States district court or territorial district court having jurisdiction over the locality where the land inclosed, or any part thereof, shall be situated, to hear and determine proceedings in equity, by writ of injunction, to restrain violations of the provisions of this chapter; and it shall be sufficient to give the court jurisdiction if service of original process be had in any civil proceeding on any agent or employee having charge or control of the inclosure. In any case if the inclosure shall be found to be unlawful, the court shall make the proper order, judgment, or decree for the destruction of the inclosure, in a summary way, unless the inclosure shall be removed by the defendant within five days after the order of the court.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca1c5b1d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1885-02-25/ch149/s2">Feb. 25, 1885, ch. 149, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/23/321">23 Stat. 321</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s291">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1167">36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s1">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/909">62 Stat. 909</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/43">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(43)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3360">98 Stat. 3360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca1c5b1e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca1c5b1f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca1c5b20-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> struck out provision that any suit brought under this section had precedence for hearing and trial over other cases on the civil docket of the court, and had to be tried and determined at the earliest practicable day.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca1c5b21-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idca1c5b22-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>, substituted “United States attorney” for “district attorney of the United States.” See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s541">section 541 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, and Historical and Revision Notes thereunder.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “district court” substituted for “district or circuit court” in two places to conform to act <date date="1911-03-03">Mar. 3, 1911</date>, which abolished the circuit courts and transferred their powers and duties to the district courts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca1c5b23-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
