<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca1eccc7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331"><num value="1331">§ 1331.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccc8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outer Continental Shelf</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “outer Continental Shelf” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccc9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> all submerged lands lying seaward and outside of the area of lands beneath navigable waters as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>, and of which the subsoil and seabed appertain to the United States and are subject to its jurisdiction and control or within the exclusive economic zone of the United States and adjacent to any territory of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccca-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> does not include any area conveyed by Congress to a territorial government for administration;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecccb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, except that with respect to functions under this subchapter transferred to, or vested in, the Secretary of Energy or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission by or pursuant to the Department of Energy Organization Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">42 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.), the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy, or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecccc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lease</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “lease” means any form of authorization which is issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337">section 1337 of this title</ref> or maintained under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1335">section 1335 of this title</ref> and which authorizes exploration for, and development and production of, minerals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecccd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Person</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “person” includes, in addition to a natural person, an association, a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a private, public, or municipal corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccce-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coastal zone</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “coastal zone” means the coastal waters (including the lands therein and thereunder) and the adjacent shorelands (including the waters therein and thereunder), strongly influenced by each other and in proximity to the shorelines of the several coastal States, and includes islands, transition and intertidal areas, salt marshes, wetlands, and beaches, which zone extends seaward to the outer limit of the United States territorial sea and extends inland from the shorelines to the extent necessary to control shorelands, the uses of which have a direct and significant impact on the coastal waters, and the inward boundaries of which may be identified by the several coastal States, pursuant to the authority of section 1454(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002068">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002068"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 16.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecccf-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affected State</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “affected State” means, with respect to any program, plan, lease sale, or other activity, proposed, conducted, or approved pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, any State—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccd0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the laws of which are declared, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1333/a/2">section 1333(a)(2) of this title</ref>, to be the law of the United States for the portion of the outer Continental Shelf on which such activity is, or is proposed to be, conducted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccd1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> which is, or is proposed to be, directly connected by transportation facilities to any artificial island or structure referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1333/a/1">section 1333(a)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccd2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> which is receiving, or in accordnace <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002069">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002069"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “accordance”.</note> with the proposed activity will receive, oil for processing, refining, or transshipment which was extracted from the outer Continental Shelf and transported directly to such State by means of vessels or by a combination of means including vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccd3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> which is designated by the Secretary as a State in which there is a substantial probability of significant impact on or damage to the coastal, marine, or human environment, or a State in which there will be significant changes in the social, governmental, or economic infrastructure, resulting from the exploration, development, and production of oil and gas anywhere on the outer Continental Shelf; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccd4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> in which the Secretary finds that because of such activity there is, or will be, a significant risk of serious damage, due to factors such as prevailing winds and currents, to the marine or coastal environment in the event of any oilspill, blowout, or release of oil or gas from vessels, pipelines, or other transshipment facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccd5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Marine environment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “marine environment” means the physical, atmospheric, and biological components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the productivity, state, condition, and quality of the marine ecosystem, including the waters of the high seas, the contiguous zone, transitional and intertidal areas, salt marshes, and wetlands within the coastal zone and on the outer Continental Shelf.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccd6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coastal environment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “coastal environment” means the physical atmospheric, and biological components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the productivity, state, condition, and quality of the terrestrial ecosystem from the shoreline inward to the boundaries of the coastal zone.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccd7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Human environment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “human environment” means the physical, social, and economic components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the state, condition, and quality of living conditions, employment, and health of those affected, directly or indirectly, by activities occurring on the outer Continental Shelf.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccd8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Governor</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Governor” means the Governor of a State, or the person or entity designated by, or pursuant to, State law to exercise the powers granted to such Governor pursuant to this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccd9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exploration</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “exploration” means the process of searching for minerals, including (1) geophysical surveys where magnetic, gravity, seismic, or other systems are used to detect or imply the presence of such minerals, and (2) any drilling, whether on or off known geological structures, including the drilling of a well in which a discovery of oil or natural gas in paying quantities is made and the drilling of any additional delineation well after such discovery which is needed to delineate any reservoir and to enable the lessee to determine whether to proceed with development and production.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccda-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “development” means those activities which take place following discovery of minerals in paying quantities, including geophysical activity, drilling, platform construction, and operation of all onshore support facilities, and which are for the purpose of ultimately producing the minerals discovered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccdb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Production</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “production” means those activities which take place after the successful completion of any means for the removal of minerals, including such removal, field operations, transfer of minerals to shore, operation monitoring, maintenance, and work-over drilling.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccdc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Antitrust law</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “antitrust law” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccdd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Sherman Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">15 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccde-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Clayton Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">15 U.S.C. 12</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccdf-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1ecce0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Wilson Tariff Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">15 U.S.C. 8</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1ecce1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/n/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, chapter 592 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">15 U.S.C. 13</ref>, 13a, 13b, and 21a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecce2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fair market value</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “fair market value” means the value of any mineral (1) computed at a unit price equivalent to the average unit price at which such mineral was sold pursuant to a lease during the period for which any royalty or net profit share is accrued or reserved to the United States pursuant to such lease, or (2) if there were no such sales, or if the Secretary finds that there were an insufficient number of such sales to equitably determine such value, computed at the average unit price at which such mineral was sold pursuant to other leases in the same region of the outer Continental Shelf during such period, or (3) if there were no sales of such mineral from such region during such period, or if the Secretary finds that there are an insufficient number of such sales to equitably determine such value, at an appropriate price determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecce3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Major Federal action</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “major Federal action” means any action or proposal by the Secretary which is subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332/2/C">section 4332(2)(C) of title 42</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecce4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minerals</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “minerals” includes oil, gas, sulphur, geopressured-geothermal and associated resources, and all other minerals which are authorized by an Act of Congress to be produced from “public lands” as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1702">section 1702 of this title</ref>; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002070">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002070"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “title.”</note></content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecce5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002071">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002071"><num>4</num><inline class="small-caps" /> So in original. Another subsec. (r) is set out following subsec. (s).</note> <inline class="small-caps">Carbon dioxide stream.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1ecce6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “carbon dioxide stream” means carbon dioxide that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca1ecce7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has been captured; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca1ecce8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> consists overwhelmingly of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca1ecce9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> carbon dioxide plus incidental associated substances derived from the source material or capture process; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idca1eccea-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any substances added to the stream for the purpose of enabling or improving the injection process.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1ecceb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “carbon dioxide stream” does not include additional waste or other matter added to the carbon dioxide stream for the purpose of disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1eccec-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/s"><num value="s">(s)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Carbon sequestration</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “carbon sequestration” means the act of storing carbon dioxide that has been removed from the atmosphere or captured through physical, chemical, or biological processes that can prevent the carbon dioxide from reaching the atmosphere.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca1ecced-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002072">5</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002072"><num>5</num> So in original. Another subsec. (r) is set out following subsec. (q).</note> The term “State” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccee-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> each of the several States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccef-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccf0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Guam;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccf1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> American Samoa;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccf2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the United States Virgin Islands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca1eccf3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1331/r/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca1eccf4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s2">Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–372, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/632">92 Stat. 632</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dD/tIII/s40307/a">Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title III, § 40307(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1002">135 Stat. 1002</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/tV/s50251/b/1/A">Pub. L. 117–169, title V, § 50251(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2054">136 Stat. 2054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca1eccf5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca1eccf6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca1eccf7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Department of Energy Organization Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/565">91 Stat. 565</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 84 (§ 7101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1454/b">Section 1454(b) of title 16</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVI/s6205">Pub. L. 101–508, title VI, § 6205</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-302">104 Stat. 1388–302</ref>, and, as so amended, does not contain a par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Sherman Act, referred to in subsec. (n)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-07-02/ch647">act July 2, 1890, ch. 647</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/209">26 Stat. 209</ref>, which enacted sections 1 to 7 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">section 1 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clayton Act, referred to in subsec. (n)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323">act Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>, which is classified generally to sections 12, 13, 14 to 19, 21, and 22 to 27 of Title 15, and sections 52 and 53 of Title 29, Labor. For further details and complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (n)(3), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilson Tariff Act, referred to in subsec. (n)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1894-08-27/ch349">act Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349</ref>, §§ 73 to 77, <ref href="/us/stat/28/570">28 Stat. 570</ref>. Sections 73 to 76 enacted sections 8 to 11 of Title 15. Section 77 is not classified to the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">section 8 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, referred to in subsec. (n)(5), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-19/ch592">act June 19, 1936, ch. 592</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1526">49 Stat. 1526</ref>, popularly known as the Robinson-Patman Act, the Robinson-Patman Antidiscrimination Act, and the Robinson-Patman Price Discrimination Act, which enacted sections 13a, 13b, and 21a of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of Title 15</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca2115e8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s50251/b/1/A/i/I">Pub. L. 117–169, § 50251(b)(1)(A)(i)(I)</ref>, (III), substituted “means—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) all”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for “means all” and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s50251/b/1/A/i/II">Pub. L. 117–169, § 50251(b)(1)(A)(i)(II)</ref>, which directed substitution of “control or within the exclusive economic zone of the United States and adjacent to any territory of the United States; and” for “control;”, was executed by making the substitution for “control.” to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s40307/a/3">Pub. L. 117–58, § 40307(a)(3)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s50251/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–169, § 50251(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, which directed striking “and” after the semicolon at the end, could not be executed due to the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s40307/a/3">Pub. L. 117–58, § 40307(a)(3)</ref>. See 2021 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s50251/b/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 117–169, § 50251(b)(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, substituted “title; and” for “title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s50251/b/1/A/iv">Pub. L. 117–169, § 50251(b)(1)(A)(iv)</ref>, added at end subsec. (r) defining “State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s40307/a/1">Pub. L. 117–58, § 40307(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “In this subchapter:” for “When used in this subchapter—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a) to (q). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s40307/a/2">Pub. L. 117–58, § 40307(a)(2)</ref>, (3), inserted headings in subsecs. (a) to (q) comprised of the term defined in the subsec., substituted a period for semicolon at end of subsecs. (a) to (<i>o</i>) and a period for “; and” at end of subsec. (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (r), (s). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s40307/a/4">Pub. L. 117–58, § 40307(a)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (r) defining “carbon dioxide stream” and subsec. (s).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/s201/a">Pub. L. 95–372, § 201(a)</ref>, inserted provision that, with respect to functions under this subchapter transferred to, or vested in, the Secretary of Energy or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission by or pursuant to the Department of Energy Organization Act, “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, as the case may be.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/s201/a">Pub. L. 95–372, § 201(a)</ref>, substituted “lease” for “mineral lease” as term defined and in definition of that term substituted “any form of authorization which is issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337">section 1337 of this title</ref> or maintained under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1335">section 1335 of this title</ref> and which authorizes exploration for, and development and production of, minerals;” for “any form of authorization for the exploration for, or development or removal of deposits of, oil, gas, or other minerals; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 95–372, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, substituted semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (q). <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/s201/b/2">Pub. L. 95–372, § 201(b)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (q).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca2115e9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idca2115ea-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of <ref href="/us/pl/95/372">Pub. L. 95–372</ref> as the “Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act Amendments of 1978”, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 95–372</ref>, set out as a Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idca2115eb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of act <date date="1953-08-07">Aug. 7, 1953</date>, which enacted this subchapter, as the “Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act”, see section 1 of act <date date="1953-08-07">Aug. 7, 1953</date>, set out as a note under section 1301 of this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idca2115ec-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s17">Act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 17</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/471">67 Stat. 471</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s17">“If any provision of this Act [enacting this subchapter], or any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase or individual word, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of the Act and of the application of any such provision, section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase or individual word to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca2115ed-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations under this subchapter which relate to fostering of competition for Federal leases, implementation of alternative bidding systems authorized for award of Federal leases, establishment of diligence requirements for operations conducted on Federal leases, setting of rates for production of Federal leases, and specifying of procedures, terms, and conditions for acquisition and disposition of Federal royalty interests taken in kind, transferred to Secretary of Energy by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7152/b">section 7152(b) of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7152/b">Section 7152(b) of Title 42</ref> was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/100/tII/s201">Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1407">95 Stat. 1407</ref>, and functions of Secretary of Energy returned to Secretary of the Interior. See House Report No. 97–315, pp. 25, 26, <date date="1981-11-05">Nov. 5, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115ee-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dD/tIII/s40307/d">Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title III, § 40307(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1003">135 Stat. 1003</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dD/tIII/s40307/d">“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>], the Secretary of the Interior shall promulgate regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337">section 1337 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115ef-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Wage Rate Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to rates of wages to be paid to laborers and mechanics on projects for construction, alteration, or repair work funded under div. D or an amendment by div. D of <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, including authority of Secretary of Labor, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18851">section 18851 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Offshore Oil and Gas Leasing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tV/s50102/a">Pub. L. 119–21, title V, § 50102(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/139-141">139 Stat. 139–141</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/21/tV/s50102/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lease Sales.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Gulf of america region.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the 2024–2029 National Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program (and any successor leasing program that does not satisfy the requirements of this section), in addition to lease sales which may be held under that program, and except within areas subject to existing oil and gas leasing moratoria, the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a minimum of 30 region-wide oil and gas lease sales, in a manner consistent with the schedule described in subparagraph (B), in the region identified in the map depicting lease terms and economic conditions accompanying the final notice of sale of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management entitled ‘Gulf of Mexico Outer Continental Shelf Region-Wide Oil and Gas Lease Sale 254’ (85 Fed. Reg. 8010 (<date date="2020-02-12">February 12, 2020</date>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Of the not fewer than 30 region-wide lease sales required under this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> hold not fewer than 1 lease sale in the region described in subparagraph (A) by <date date="2025-12-15">December 15, 2025</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> hold not fewer than 2 lease sales in that region in each of calendar years 2026 through 2039, 1 of which shall be held by March 15 of the applicable calendar year and 1 of which shall be held after March 15 but not later than August 15 of the applicable calendar year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> hold not fewer than 1 lease sale in that region in calendar year 2040, which shall be held by <date date="2040-03-15">March 15, 2040</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alaska region.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a minimum of 6 offshore lease sales, in a manner consistent with the schedule described in subparagraph (B), in the Cook Inlet Planning Area as identified in the 2017–2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Proposed Final Program published on <date date="2016-11-18">November 18, 2016</date>, by the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management (as announced in the notice of availability of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management entitled ‘Notice of Availability of the 2017–2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Proposed Final Program’ (81 Fed. Reg. 84612 (<date date="2016-11-23">November 23, 2016</date>))).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the not fewer than 6 lease sales required under this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior shall hold not fewer than 1 lease sale in the area described in subparagraph (A) in each of calendar years 2026 through 2028, and in each of calendar years 2030 through 2032, by March 15 of the applicable calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and stipulations for gulf of america sales</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting lease sales under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of the Interior—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall, subject to subparagraph (C), offer the same lease form, lease terms, economic conditions, and lease stipulations 4 through 9 as contained in the final notice of sale of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management entitled ‘Gulf of Mexico Outer Continental Shelf Region-Wide Oil and Gas Lease Sale 254’ (85 Fed. Reg. 8010 (<date date="2020-02-12">February 12, 2020</date>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may update lease stipulations 1 through 3 and 10 described in that final notice of sale to reflect current conditions for lease sales conducted under subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> shall set the royalty rate at not less than 12½ percent but not greater than 16⅔ percent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> shall, for a lease in water depths of 800 meters or deeper issued as a result of a sale, set the primary term for 10 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and stipulations for alaska region sales.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting lease sales under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of the Interior shall offer the same lease form, lease terms, economic conditions, and stipulations as contained in the final notice of sale of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management entitled ‘Cook Inlet Planning Area Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Lease Sale 244’ (82 Fed. Reg. 23291 (<date date="2017-05-22">May 22, 2017</date>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revenue sharing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding section 8(g) and section 9 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337/g">43 U.S.C. 1337(g)</ref>, 1338), and beginning in fiscal year 2034, of the bonuses, rents, royalties, and other revenues derived from lease sales conducted under subsection (a)(2)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> 70 percent shall be paid to the State of Alaska; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> 30 percent shall be deposited in the Treasury and credited to miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Area offered for lease.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Gulf of america region</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For each offshore lease sale conducted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of the Interior shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> offer not fewer than 80,000,000 acres; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> if there are fewer than 80,000,000 acres that are unleased and available, offer all unleased and available acres.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alaska region</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For each offshore lease sale conducted under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of the Interior shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> offer not fewer than 1,000,000 acres; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> if there are fewer than 1,000,000 acres that are unleased and available, offer all unleased and available acres.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Offshore Commingling</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Interior shall approve a request of an operator to commingle oil or gas production from multiple reservoirs within a single wellbore completed on the outer Continental Shelf in the Gulf of America Region unless the Secretary of the Interior determines that conclusive evidence establishes that the commingling—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> could not be conducted by the operator in a safe manner; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> would result in an ultimate recovery from the applicable reservoirs to be reduced in comparison to the expected recovery of those reservoirs if they had not been commingled.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Gulf of Mexico Energy Security</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tI">Pub. L. 109–432, div. C, title I</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3000">120 Stat. 3000</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3270">128 Stat. 3270</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tII/s20002">Pub. L. 115–97, title II, § 20002</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2237">131 Stat. 2237</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tV/s50102/e">Pub. L. 119–21, title V, § 50102(e)</ref>, <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/142">139 Stat. 142</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/21/tV/s50102/e">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="101">“SEC. 101.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title may be cited as the ‘Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="102">“SEC. 102.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this title:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> 181 <inline class="small-caps">area</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘181 Area’ means the area identified in map 15, page 58, of the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program for 1997–2002, dated August 1996, of the Minerals Management Service, available in the Office of the Director of the Minerals Management Service, excluding the area offered in OCS Lease Sale 181, held on <date date="2001-12-05">December 5, 2001</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> 181 <inline class="small-caps">south area</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘181 South Area’ means any area—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> located—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> south of the 181 Area;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> west of the Military Mission Line; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> in the Central Planning Area;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> excluded from the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program for 1997–2002, dated August 1996, of the Minerals Management Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> included in the areas considered for oil and gas leasing, as identified in map 8, page 37 of the document entitled ‘Draft Proposed Program Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2007–2012’, dated February 2006.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bonus or royalty credit</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘bonus or royalty credit’ means a legal instrument or other written documentation, or an entry in an account managed by the Secretary, that may be used in lieu of any other monetary payment for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a bonus bid for a lease on the outer Continental Shelf; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a royalty due on oil or gas production from any lease located on the outer Continental Shelf.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Central planning area</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Central Planning Area’ means the Central Gulf of Mexico Planning Area of the outer Continental Shelf, as designated in the document entitled ‘Draft Proposed Program Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2007–2012’, dated February 2006.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eastern planning area</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Eastern Planning Area’ means the Eastern Gulf of Mexico Planning Area of the outer Continental Shelf, as designated in the document entitled ‘Draft Proposed Program Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2007–2012’, dated February 2006.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> 2002–2007 <inline class="small-caps">planning area</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘2002–2007 planning area’ means any area—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> located in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Eastern Planning Area, as designated in the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2002–2007, dated April 2002, of the Minerals Management Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Central Planning Area, as designated in the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2002–2007, dated April 2002, of the Minerals Management Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the Western Planning Area, as designated in the Proposed Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program 2002–2007, dated April 2002, of the Minerals Management Service; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> not located in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> an area in which no funds may be expended to conduct offshore preleasing, leasing, and related activities under sections 104 through 106 of the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/54">Public Law 109–54</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/119/521">119 Stat. 521</ref>) (as in effect on <date date="2005-08-02">August 2, 2005</date>);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> an area withdrawn from leasing under the ‘Memorandum on Withdrawal of Certain Areas of the United States Outer Continental Shelf from Leasing Disposition’, from 34 Weekly Comp. Pres. Doc. 1111, dated <date date="1998-06-12">June 12, 1998</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the 181 Area or 181 South Area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Gulf producing state</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Gulf producing State’ means each of the States of Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military mission line</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Military Mission Line’ means the north-south line at 86°41′ W. longitude.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified outer continental shelf revenues.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues’ means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of each of fiscal years 2007 through 2016, all rentals, royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and payable to the United States from leases entered into on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>] for—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> areas in the 181 Area located in the Eastern Planning Area; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the 181 South Area; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> in the case of fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter, all rentals, royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and payable to the United States received on or after <date date="2016-10-01">October 1, 2016</date>, from leases entered into on or after the date of enactment of this Act for—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the 181 Area;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the 181 South Area; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> the 2002–2007 planning area.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues’ does not include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> revenues from the forfeiture of a bond or other surety securing obligations other than royalties, civil penalties, or royalties taken by the Secretary in-kind and not sold; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> revenues generated from leases subject to section 8(g) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337/g">43 U.S.C. 1337(g)</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coastal political subdivision</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘coastal political subdivision’ means a political subdivision of a Gulf producing State any part of which political subdivision is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> within the coastal zone (as defined in section 304 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</ref>)) of the Gulf producing State as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> not more than 200 nautical miles from the geographic center of any leased tract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="103">“SEC. 103.</num><heading> OFFSHORE OIL AND GAS LEASING IN 181 AREA AND 181 SOUTH AREA OF GULF OF MEXICO.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> 181 <inline class="small-caps">Area Lease Sale</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in section 104, the Secretary shall offer the 181 Area for oil and gas leasing pursuant to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.) as soon as practicable, but not later than 1 year, after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> 181 <inline class="small-caps">South Area Lease Sale</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall offer the 181 South Area for oil and gas leasing pursuant to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.) as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Leasing Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The 181 Area and 181 South Area shall be offered for lease under this section notwithstanding the omission of the 181 Area or the 181 South Area from any outer Continental Shelf leasing program under section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conforming Amendment</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<p>[Amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/54/s105">section 105 of Pub. L. 109–54</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/522">119 Stat. 522</ref>.]</p></note>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="104">“SEC. 104.</num><heading> MORATORIUM ON OIL AND GAS LEASING IN CERTAIN AREAS OF GULF OF MEXICO.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Effective during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>] and ending on <date date="2022-06-30">June 30, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall not offer for leasing, preleasing, or any related activity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any area east of the Military Mission Line in the Gulf of Mexico;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any area in the Eastern Planning Area that is within 125 miles of the coastline of the State of Florida; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> any area in the Central Planning Area that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> within—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the 181 Area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> 100 miles of the coastline of the State of Florida; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> outside the 181 Area;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> east of the western edge of the Pensacola Official Protraction Diagram (UTM X coordinate 1,393,920 (NAD 27 feet)); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> within 100 miles of the coastline of the State of Florida.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Mission Line</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the United States reserves the right to designate by and through the Secretary of Defense, with the approval of the President, national defense areas on the outer Continental Shelf pursuant to section 12(d) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1341/d">43 U.S.C. 1341(d)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exchange of Certain Leases.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall permit any person that, as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>], has entered into an oil or gas lease with the Secretary in any area described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a) to exchange the lease for a bonus or royalty credit that may only be used in the Gulf of Mexico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Valuation of existing lease</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amount of the bonus or royalty credit for a lease to be exchanged shall be equal to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the amount of the bonus bid; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any rental paid for the lease as of the date the lessee notifies the Secretary of the decision to exchange the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revenue distribution</inline>.—</heading><content>No bonus or royalty credit may be used under this subsection in lieu of any payment due under, or to acquire any interest in, a lease subject to the revenue distribution provisions of section 8(g) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337/g">43 U.S.C. 1337(g)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that shall provide a process for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> notification to the Secretary of a decision to exchange an eligible lease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> issuance of bonus or royalty credits in exchange for relinquishment of the existing lease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> transfer of the bonus or royalty credit to any other person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> determining the proper allocation of bonus or royalty credits to each lease interest owner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="105">“SEC. 105.</num><heading> DISPOSITION OF QUALIFIED OUTER CONTINENTAL SHELF REVENUES FROM 181 AREA, 181 SOUTH AREA, AND 2002–2007 PLANNING AREAS OF GULF OF MEXICO.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding section 9 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1338">43 U.S.C. 1338</ref>) and subject to the other provisions of this section, for each applicable fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> 50 percent of qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues in the general fund of the Treasury; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> 50 percent of qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues in a special account in the Treasury from which the Secretary shall disburse—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> 75 percent to Gulf producing States in accordance with subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> 25 percent to provide financial assistance to States in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200305">section 200305 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, which shall be considered income to the Land and Water Conservation Fund for purposes of section 200302 of that title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation Among Gulf Producing States and Coastal Political Subdivisions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation among gulf producing states for fiscal years 2007 through 2016.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subparagraph (B), effective for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2016, the amount made available under subsection (a)(2)(A) shall be allocated to each Gulf producing State in amounts (based on a formula established by the Secretary by regulation) that are inversely proportional to the respective distances between the point on the coastline of each Gulf producing State that is closest to the geographic center of the applicable leased tract and the geographic center of the leased tract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum allocation</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount allocated to a Gulf producing State each fiscal year under subparagraph (A) shall be at least 10 percent of the amounts available under subsection (a)(2)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation among gulf producing states for fiscal year 2017 and thereafter.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), effective for fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the amount made available under subsection (a)(2)(A) from any lease entered into within the 181 Area or the 181 South Area shall be allocated to each Gulf producing State in amounts (based on a formula established by the Secretary by regulation) that are inversely proportional to the respective distances between the point on the coastline of each Gulf producing State that is closest to the geographic center of the applicable leased tract and the geographic center of the leased tract; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the amount made available under subsection (a)(2)(A) from any lease entered into within the 2002–2007 planning area shall be allocated to each Gulf producing State in amounts that are inversely proportional to the respective distances between the point on the coastline of each Gulf producing State that is closest to the geographic center of each historical lease site and the geographic center of the historical lease site, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum allocation</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount allocated to a Gulf producing State each fiscal year under subparagraph (A) shall be at least 10 percent of the amounts available under subsection (a)(2)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Historical lease sites.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to clause (ii), for purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the historical lease sites in the 2002–2007 planning area shall include all leases entered into by the Secretary for an area in the Gulf of Mexico during the period beginning on <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date> (or an earlier date if practicable, as determined by the Secretary), and ending on <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment</inline>.—</heading><content>Effective <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, the ending date described in clause (i) shall be extended for an additional 5 calendar years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payments to coastal political subdivisions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall pay 20 percent of the allocable share of each Gulf producing State, as determined under paragraphs (1) and (2), to the coastal political subdivisions of the Gulf producing State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount paid by the Secretary to coastal political subdivisions shall be allocated to each coastal political subdivision in accordance with subparagraphs (B), (C), and (E) of section 31(b)(4) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1356a/b/4">43 U.S.C. 1356a(b)(4)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading><content>The amounts required to be deposited under paragraph (2) of subsection (a) for the applicable fiscal year shall be made available in accordance with that paragraph during the fiscal year immediately following the applicable fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorized Uses.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), each Gulf producing State and coastal political subdivision shall use all amounts received under subsection (b) in accordance with all applicable Federal and State laws, only for 1 or more of the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Projects and activities for the purposes of coastal protection, including conservation, coastal restoration, hurricane protection, and infrastructure directly affected by coastal wetland losses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Mitigation of damage to fish, wildlife, or natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Implementation of a federally-approved marine, coastal, or comprehensive conservation management plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Mitigation of the impact of outer Continental Shelf activities through the funding of onshore infrastructure projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Planning assistance and the administrative costs of complying with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not more than 3 percent of amounts received by a Gulf producing State or coastal political subdivision under subsection (b) may be used for the purposes described in paragraph (1)(E).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Amounts made available under subsection (a)(2) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> be made available, without further appropriation, in accordance with this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> remain available until expended; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> be in addition to any amounts appropriated under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> chapter 2003 of title 54, United States Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any other provision of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Amount of Distributed Qualified Outer Continental Shelf Revenues.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to paragraph (2), the total amount of qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues made available under subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> $650,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2024;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> $650,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2035 through 2055.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expenditures</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of paragraph (1), for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2055, expenditures under subsection (a)(2) shall be net of receipts from that fiscal year from any area in the 181 Area in the Eastern Planning Area and the 181 South Area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pro rata reductions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If paragraph (1) limits the amount of qualified outer Continental Shelf revenue that would be paid under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Secretary shall reduce the amount of qualified outer Continental Shelf revenue provided to each recipient on a pro rata basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any remainder of the qualified outer Continental Shelf revenues shall revert to the general fund of the Treasury.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2)(A)(i), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3270">128 Stat. 3270</ref>, which directed substitution of “<ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200305">section 200305 of title 54</ref>, United States Code” for “section 6 of the Land And Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</ref><i>l</i>–8)” in subsec. (a)(2)(B) of section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tI">Public Law 109–432, div. C, title I</ref>), set out above, was executed by making the substitution for “section 6 of the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</ref><i>l</i>–8)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[The Minerals Management Service was abolished and functions divided among the Office of Natural Resources Revenue, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, and the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement. See Secretary of the Interior Orders No. 3299 of <date date="2010-05-19">May 19, 2010</date>, and No. 3302 of <date date="2010-06-18">June 18, 2010</date>, and chapters II, V, and XII of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations, as revised by final rules of the Department of the Interior at 75 F.R. 61051 and 76 F.R. 64432.]</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dE/tI">Pub. L. 112–74, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/995">125 Stat. 995</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/74/dE/tI">“That for fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter, the term ‘qualified Outer Continental Shelf revenues’, as defined in section 102(9)(A) of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act [of 2006], [title I of] division C of <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</ref> [set out above], shall include only the portion of rental revenues that would have been collected by the Secretary at the rental rates in effect before <date date="1993-08-05">August 5, 1993</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in the following appropriation act:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dE/tI">Pub. L. 112–74, div. E, title I</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/994">125 Stat. 994</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Naval Petroleum Reserve</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s13">Act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/470">67 Stat. 470</ref>, revoked Ex. Ord. No. 10426, <date date="1953-01-16">Jan. 16, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 405, which had set aside certain submerged lands as a naval petroleum reserve and had transferred functions with respect thereto from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of the Navy.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization of Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s16">Act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/471">67 Stat. 471</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s16">“There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act [enacting this subchapter].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca2115f5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proc. No. 5928. Territorial Sea of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 5928, <date date="1988-12-27">Dec. 27, 1988</date>, 54 F.R. 777, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">International law recognizes that coastal nations may exercise sovereignty and jurisdiction over their territorial seas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The territorial sea of the United States is a maritime zone extending beyond the land territory and internal waters of the United States over which the United States exercises sovereignty and jurisdiction, a sovereignty and jurisdiction that extend to the airspace over the territorial sea, as well as to its bed and subsoil.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Extension of the territorial sea by the United States to the limits permitted by international law will advance the national security and other significant interests of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, I, RONALD REAGAN, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution of the United States of America, and in accordance with international law, do hereby proclaim the extension of the territorial sea of the United States of America, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession over which the United States exercises sovereignty.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The territorial sea of the United States henceforth extends to 12 nautical miles from the baselines of the United States determined in accordance with international law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In accordance with international law, as reflected in the applicable provisions of the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea, within the territorial sea of the United States, the ships of all countries enjoy the right of innocent passage and the ships and aircraft of all countries enjoy the right of transit passage through international straits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in this Proclamation:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) extends or otherwise alters existing Federal or State law or any jurisdiction, rights, legal interests, or obligations derived therefrom; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) impairs the determination, in accordance with international law, of any maritime boundary of the United States with a foreign jurisdiction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this 27th day of December, in the year of our Lord nineteen hundred and eighty-eight, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and thirteenth.</p>
<signature>
<name>Ronald Reagan.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proc. No. 7219. Contiguous Zone of the United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 7219, <date date="1999-09-02">Sept. 2, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 48701, 49844, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">International law recognizes that coastal nations may establish zones contiguous to their territorial seas, known as contiguous zones.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The contiguous zone of the United States is a zone contiguous to the territorial sea of the United States, in which the United States may exercise the control necessary to prevent infringement of its customs, fiscal, immigration, or sanitary laws and regulations within its territory or territorial sea, and to punish infringement of the above laws and regulations committed within its territory or territorial sea.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Extension of the contiguous zone of the United States to the limits permitted by international law will advance the law enforcement and public health interests of the United States. Moreover, this extension is an important step in preventing the removal of cultural heritage found within 24 nautical miles of the baseline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, I, WILLIAM J. CLINTON, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution of the United States, and in accordance with international law, do hereby proclaim the extension of the contiguous zone of the United States of America, including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession over which the United States exercises sovereignty, as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The contiguous zone of the United States extends to 24 nautical miles from the baselines of the United States determined in accordance with international law, but in no case within the territorial sea of another nation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In accordance with international law, reflected in the applicable provisions of the 1982 Convention on the Law of the Sea, within the contiguous zone of the United States the ships and aircraft of all countries enjoy the high seas freedoms of navigation and overflight and the laying of submarine cables and pipelines, and other internationally lawful uses of the sea related to those freedoms, such as those associated with the operation of ships, aircraft, and submarine cables and pipelines, and compatible with the other provisions of international law reflected in the 1982 Convention on the Law of the Sea.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in this proclamation:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(a) amends existing Federal or State law;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(b) amends or otherwise alters the rights and duties of the United States or other nations in the Exclusive Economic Zone of the United States established by Proclamation 5030 of <date date="1983-03-10">March 10, 1983</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</ref> note]; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(c) impairs the determination, in accordance with international law, of any maritime boundary of the United States with a foreign jurisdiction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this second day of September, in the year of our Lord nineteen hundred and ninety-nine, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and twenty-fourth.</p>
<signature>
<name>William J. Clinton.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idca2115f8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13795</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13795, <date date="2017-04-28">Apr. 28, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 20815, which related to an America-first offshore energy strategy and encouraged energy exploration and production, including on the Outer Continental Shelf, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13990, § 7(a), <date date="2021-01-20">Jan. 20, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 7041, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2115f9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Withdrawal of All Areas on the Outer Continental Shelf From Offshore Wind Leasing and Review of the Federal Government’s Leasing and Permitting Practices for Wind Projects</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8363, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of the Treasury[,] the Attorney General[,] the Secretary of the Interior[,] the Secretary of Agriculture[,] the Secretary of Energy[, and] the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Temporary Withdrawal of Areas</i>. Consistent with the principles of responsible public stewardship that are entrusted to this office, with due consideration for a variety of relevant factors, including the need to foster an energy economy capable of meeting the country’s growing demand for reliable energy, the importance of marine life, impacts on ocean currents and wind patterns, effects on energy costs for Americans–especially those who can least afford it–and to ensure that the United States is able to maintain a robust fishing industry for future generations and provide low cost energy to its citizens, I hereby direct as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Under the authority granted to me in section 12(a) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1341/a">43 U.S.C. 1341(a)</ref>, I hereby withdraw from disposition for wind energy leasing all areas within the Offshore Continental Shelf (OCS) as defined in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref>. This withdrawal shall go into effect beginning on <date date="2025-01-21">January 21, 2025</date>, and shall remain in effect until this Presidential Memorandum is revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">To the extent that an area is already withdrawn from disposition for wind energy leasing, the area’s withdrawal is extended for a time period beginning on <date date="2025-01-21">January 21, 2025</date>, until this Presidential Memorandum is revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This withdrawal temporarily prevents consideration of any area in the OCS for any new or renewed wind energy leasing for the purposes of generation of electricity or any other such use derived from the use of wind. This withdrawal does not apply to leasing related to any other purposes such as, but not limited to, oil, gas, minerals, and environmental conservation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in this withdrawal affects rights under existing leases in the withdrawn areas. With respect to such existing leases, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Attorney General as needed, shall conduct a comprehensive review of the ecological, economic, and environmental necessity of terminating or amending any existing wind energy leases, identifying any legal bases for such removal, and submit a report with recommendations to the President, through the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Temporary Cessation and Immediate Review of Federal Wind Leasing and Permitting Practices</i>. (a) In light of various alleged legal deficiencies underlying the Federal Government’s leasing and permitting of onshore and offshore wind projects, the consequences of which may lead to grave harm–including negative impacts on navigational safety interests, transportation interests, national security interests, commercial interests, and marine mammals–and in light of potential inadequacies in various environmental reviews required by the National Environmental Policy Act [of 1969, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] to lease or permit wind projects, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the heads of all other relevant agencies, shall not issue new or renewed approvals, rights of way, permits, leases, or loans for onshore or offshore wind projects pending the completion of a comprehensive assessment and review of Federal wind leasing and permitting practices. The Secretary of the Interior shall lead that assessment and review in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. The assessment shall consider the environmental impact of onshore and offshore wind projects upon wildlife, including, but not limited to, birds and marine mammals. The assessment shall also consider the economic costs associated with the intermittent generation of electricity and the effect of subsidies on the viability of the wind industry.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In light of criticism that the Record of Decision (ROD) issued by the Bureau of Land Management on <date date="2024-12-05">December 5, 2024</date>, with respect to the Lava Ridge Wind Project Final Environmental Impact Statement (EIS), as approved by the Department of the Interior, is allegedly contrary to the public interest and suffers from legal deficiencies, the Secretary of the Interior shall, as appropriate, place a temporary moratorium on all activities and rights of Magic Valley Energy, LLC, or any other party under the ROD, including, but not limited to, any rights-of-way or rights of development or operation of any projects contemplated in the ROD. The Secretary of the Interior shall review the ROD and, as appropriate, conduct a new, comprehensive analysis of the various interests implicated by the Lava Ridge Wind Project and the potential environmental impacts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assess the environmental impact and cost to surrounding communities of defunct and idle windmills and deliver a report to the President, through the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy, with their findings and recommended authorities to require the removal of such windmills.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Attorney General may, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, provide notice of this order to any court with jurisdiction over pending litigation related to any aspect of the Federal leasing or permitting of onshore or offshore wind projects or the Lava Ridge Wind Project, and may, in the Attorney General’s discretion, request that the court stay the litigation or otherwise delay further litigation, or seek other appropriate relief consistent with this order, pending the completion of the actions described in subsection (a) or subsection (b) of this section, as applicable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person. You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
