<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca2386fa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332"><num value="1332">§ 1332.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is hereby declared to be the policy of the United States that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2386fb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the subsoil and seabed of the outer Continental Shelf appertain to the United States and are subject to its jurisdiction, control, and power of disposition as provided in this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2386fc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> this subchapter shall be construed in such a manner that the character of the waters above the outer Continental Shelf as high seas and the right to navigation and fishing therein shall not be affected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2386fd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the outer Continental Shelf is a vital national resource reserve held by the Federal Government for the public, which should be made available for expeditious and orderly development, subject to environmental safeguards, in a manner which is consistent with the maintenance of competition and other national needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2386fe-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> since exploration, development, and production of the minerals of the outer Continental Shelf will have significant impacts on coastal and non-coastal areas of the coastal States, and on other affected States, and, in recognition of the national interest in the effective management of the marine, coastal, and human environments—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2386ff-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such States and their affected local governments may require assistance in protecting their coastal zones and other affected areas from any temporary or permanent adverse effects of such impacts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca238700-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the distribution of a portion of the receipts from the leasing of mineral resources of the outer Continental Shelf adjacent to State lands, as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1337/g">section 1337(g) of this title</ref>, will provide affected coastal States and localities with funds which may be used for the mitigation of adverse economic and environmental effects related to the development of such resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca238701-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such States, and through such States, affected local governments, are entitled to an opportunity to participate, to the extent consistent with the national interest, in the policy and planning decisions made by the Federal Government relating to exploration for, and development and production of, minerals of the outer Continental Shelf.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002073"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca238702-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the rights and responsibilities of all States and, where appropriate, local governments, to preserve and protect their marine, human, and coastal environments through such means as regulation of land, air, and water uses, of safety, and of related development and activity should be considered and recognized; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca238703-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1332/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> operations in the outer Continental Shelf should be conducted in a safe manner by well-trained personnel using technology, precautions, and techniques sufficient to prevent or minimize the likelihood of blowouts, loss of well control, fires, spillages, physical obstruction to other users of the waters or subsoil and seabed, or other occurrences which may cause damage to the environment or to property, or endanger life or health.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idca238704-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s3">Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tII/s202">Pub. L. 95–372, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/634">92 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tVIII/s8002">Pub. L. 99–272, title VIII, § 8002</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/148">100 Stat. 148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca238705-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca238706-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca238707-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Par. (4)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/372">Pub. L. 95–372</ref> redesignated subsecs. (a) and (b) as pars. (1) and (2) and added pars. (3) to (6).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
