<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca2d239c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348"><num value="1348">§ 1348.</num><heading> Enforcement of safety and environmental regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d239d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of Federal departments and agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, and the Secretary of the Army shall enforce safety and environmental regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter. Each such Federal department may by agreement utilize, with or without reimbursement, the services, personnel, or facilities of other Federal departments and agencies for the enforcement of their respective regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d239e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of holders of lease or permit</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of any holder of a lease or permit under this subchapter to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2d239f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> maintain all places of employment within the lease area or within the area covered by such permit in compliance with occupational safety and health standards and, in addition, free from recognized hazards to employees of the lease holder or permit holder or of any contractor or subcontractor operating within such lease area or within the area covered by such permit on the outer Continental Shelf;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2d23a0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> maintain all operations within such lease area or within the area covered by such permit in compliance with regulations intended to protect persons, property, and the environment on the outer Continental Shelf; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2d23a1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> allow prompt access, at the site of any operation subject to safety regulations, to any inspector, and to provide such documents and records which are pertinent to occupational or public health, safety, or environmental protection, as may be requested.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d23a2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Onsite inspection of facilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall individually, or jointly if they so agree, promulgate regulations to provide for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2d23a3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> scheduled onsite inspection, at least once a year, of each facility on the outer Continental Shelf which is subject to any environmental or safety regulation promulgated pursuant to this subchapter, which inspection shall include all safety equipment designed to prevent or ameliorate blowouts, fires, spill­ages, or other major accidents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2d23a4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> periodic onsite inspection without advance notice to the operator of such facility to assure compliance with such environmental or safety regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d23a5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation and report on major fires, oil spills, death, or serious injury</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca2d23a6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary or the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall make an investigation and public report on each major fire and each major oil spillage occurring as a result of operations conducted pursuant to this subchapter, and may, in his discretion, make an investigation and report of lesser oil spillages. For purposes of this subsection, a major oil spillage is any spillage in one instance of more than two hundred barrels of oil during a period of thirty days. All holders of leases or permits issued or maintained under this subchapter shall cooperate with the appropriate Secretary in the course of any such investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca2d23a7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary or the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall make an investigation and public report on any death or serious injury occurring as a result of operations conducted pursuant to this subchapter, and may, in his discretion, make an investigation and report of any injury. For purposes of this subsection, a serious injury is one resulting in substantial impairment of any bodily unit or function. All holders of leases or permits issued or maintained under this subchapter shall cooperate with the appropriate Secretary in the course of any such investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d23a8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of allegations of violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, or, in the case of occupational safety and health, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may review any allegation from any person of the existence of a violation of a safety regulation issued under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca2d23a9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1348/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Summoning of witnesses and production of evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any investigation conducted pursuant to this section, the Secretary or the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall have power to summon witnesses and to require the production of books, papers, documents, and any other evidence. Attendance of witnesses or the production of books, papers, documents, or any other evidence shall be compelled by a similar process, as in the district courts of the United States. Such Secretary, or his designee, shall administer all necessary oaths to any witnesses summoned before such investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca2d23aa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s22">Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 22</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tII/s208">Pub. L. 95–372, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/655">92 Stat. 655</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3290">112 Stat. 3290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca2d23ab-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca2d23ac-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca2d23ad-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out subsec. (g) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall, after consultation with the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, include in his annual report to the Congress required by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1343">section 1343 of this title</ref> the number of violations of safety regulations reported or alleged, any investigations undertaken, the results of such investigations, and any administrative or judicial action taken as a result of such investigations, and the results of the diving studies conducted under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1347/e">section 1347(e) of this title</ref>.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca2d23ae-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca2d23af-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2d23b0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report and Recommendations by Secretary to Congress for Training Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tVI/s607">Pub. L. 95–372, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/697">92 Stat. 697</ref>, required the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, not later than ninety days after <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, to prepare and submit to the Congress a training program report concerning individuals employed on any artificial island, installation, or other device located on the Outer Continental Shelf and who, as part of their employment, operate or supervise the operation of pollution-prevention equipment.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
