<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca2f6e3a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355"><num value="1355">§ 1355.</num><heading> Restrictions on employment of former officers or employees of Department of the Interior</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No full-time officer or employee of the Department of the Interior who directly or indirectly discharged duties or responsibilities under this subchapter, and who was at any time during the twelve months preceding the termination of his employment with the Department compensated under the Executive Schedule or compensated at or above the annual rate of basic pay for grade GS–16 of the General Schedule shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2f6e3b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> within two years after his employment with the Department has ceased—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2f6e3c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> knowingly act as agent or attorney for, or otherwise represent, any other person (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2f6e3d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with the intent to influence, make any oral or written communication on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2f6e3e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> knowingly aid or assist in representing any other person (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">any department, agency, or court of the United States, or any officer or employee thereof, in connection with any judicial or other proceeding, application, request for a ruling or other determination, regulation, order, lease, permit, rulemaking, or other particular matter involving a specific party or parties in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest which was actually pending under his official responsibility as an officer or employee within a period of one year prior to the termination of such responsibility or in which he participated personally and substantially as an officer or employee; or</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca2f6e3f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> within one year after his employment with the Department has ceased—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2f6e40-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> knowingly act as agent or attorney for, or otherwise represent, any other person (except the United States) in any formal or informal appearance before; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca2f6e41-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1355/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with the intent to influence, make any oral or written communication on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Department of the Interior, or any officer or employee thereof, in connection with any judicial, rulemaking, regulation, order, lease, permit, regulation, or other particular matter which is pending before the Department of the Interior or in which the Department has a direct and substantial interest.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idca2f6e42-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345/s29">Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345, § 29</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tII/s208">Pub. L. 95–372, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/668">92 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca2f6e43-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca2f6e44-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca2f6e45-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Executive Schedule, referred to in text, is set out in section 5311 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca2f6e46-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca2f6e47-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
