<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca36998c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a"><num value="1457a">§ 1457a.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations for particular programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca36998d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum amounts for specified years</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there shall not be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior for Department of the Interior programs as defined in subsection (e) in excess of $4,095,404,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>; in excess of $3,970,267,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>; $4,680,223,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>; and $4,797,281,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca36998e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Ceilings on certain appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the appropriation targets for such fiscal years should be: not less than $275,000,000 to be appropriated annually pursuant to the provisions of chapter 2003 of title 54; not less than $30,000,000 to be appropriated annually pursuant to the provisions of division A of subtitle III of title 54; not less than $10,000,000 to be appropriated annually pursuant to the provisions of chapter 2005 of title 54; not less than $105,000,000 to be appropriated annually to be used for the restoration and rehabilitation of units of the National Park System, as authorized by law; not less than $239,000,000 to be appropriated annually for the Office of Territorial and International Affairs (including amounts for the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands); not less than $6,200,000 to be appropriated annually to carry out the provisions of title III of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<ref href="/us/stat/91/445">91 Stat. 445</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002087"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and not less than $100,000,000 to be appropriated annually pursuant to chapter 69 of title 31 including not less than $5,000,000 annually to carry out the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6904">section 6904 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca36998f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the limitation otherwise imposed by subsection (a) of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369990-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the authorization for obligation and appropriations for the Department of the Interior may exceed the amount specified in subsection (a) by such amount as permanent and annual indefinite appropriations exceed the estimates for such appropriations as contained in “The Budget of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 1982,” as revised by the March 1981, publication of the Office of Management and Budget entitled “Fiscal Year 1982 Budget Revisions”, when receipts available to be appropriated equal or exceed such appropriations, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369991-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the authorization for obligation and appropriations for the Department of the Interior may exceed the amount specified in subsection (a) by such amounts as may be required for emergency firefighting and for increased pay costs authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca369992-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca369993-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “Department of the Interior programs” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369994-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Alaska Native Fund amounts included in Bureau of Indian Affairs programs funded from Miscellaneous Trust Funds and Miscellaneous Permanent Appropriations accounts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369995-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Bureau of Land Management programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369996-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> United States Bureau of Mines programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369997-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> National Park Service programs other than the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (including those programs formerly administered by the Heritage Conservation and Recreation Service as of <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369998-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Offices of the Solicitor and the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca369999-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca36999a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Office of Territorial Affairs programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca36999b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> United States Geological Survey programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca36999c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1457a/e/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Bureau of Reclamation (including those programs formerly administered by the Water and Power Resources Service).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca36999d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXIV/s1401">Pub. L. 97–35, title XIV, § 1401</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/748">95 Stat. 748</ref>, 749; <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/172">106 Stat. 172</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3271">128 Stat. 3271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca36999e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca36999f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca3699a0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<ref href="/us/stat/91/445">91 Stat. 445</ref>), referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/87">Pub. L. 95–87</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/445">91 Stat. 445</ref>. Title III of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 was formerly classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1221 et seq.) of chapter 25 of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining, prior to the replacement of subchapter III by <ref href="/us/pl/98/409">Pub. L. 98–409</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1201">section 1201 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca3699a1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b), “chapter 69 of title 31” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6904">section 6904 of title 31</ref>” substituted for “the Act of <date date="1976-10-20">October 20, 1976</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/2662">90 Stat. 2662</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1601">31 U.S.C. 1601</ref>, et. seq.)” and “section 3 of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1603">31 U.S.C. 1603</ref>]”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d) of this section is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1734">section 1734 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca3699a2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3)(B), (C), substituted “division A of subtitle III of title 54” for “the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (<ref href="/us/stat/80/915">80 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s470">16 U.S.C. 470</ref>)” and “chapter 2005 of title 54” for “the Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/stat/92/3538">92 Stat. 3538</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2501">16 U.S.C. 2501</ref>, et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3)(A), which directed substitution of “chapter 2003 of title 54” for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (78 Stat; 897; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460z">16 U.S.C. 460z</ref>)” was executed by making the substitution for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/stat/78/897">78 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460z">16 U.S.C. 460z</ref>)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca3699a3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idca3699a4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Bureau of Mines” substituted for “Bureau of Mines” in subsec. (e)(3) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">section 10(b) of Pub. L. 102–285</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining. For provisions relating to closure and transfer of functions of the United States Bureau of Mines, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca3699a5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Circular of Office of Management and Budget and Similar Orders or Directives Inapplicable to Certain Public Land Activities Without Affecting Other Authorizations; Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/540/s3">Pub. L. 98–540, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2718">98 Stat. 2718</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/540/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the public lands administered by the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service contain valuable wildlife, scenery, natural and historic features, and other resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Congress has specified the duties and responsibilities of the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to balance the conservation and protection of these public lands and resources with permitted uses in ways Congress has found to be appropriate for each of the various land areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service are currently under congressional mandates to maintain sufficient visitor and recreational services in our national parks, campgrounds, and wildlife refuges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Congress has authorized the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to contract for the provision of certain facilities, accommodations, and services by non-Federal entities, but with certain limitations that reflect the values and appropriate management policies of the various conservation areas, parks, wildlife refuges, and other public lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> expansion of the contracting authority of the managers of these conservation areas, parks, wildlife refuges, and lands should be considered only after careful study of the existing management mandates and contracting authorities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> management and regulation of natural resources on Federal lands are inherently Government functions and should be performed by Federal employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The provisions of Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 and any similar provisions in any other order or directive shall not apply to activities conducted by the National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Land Management which involve ten full time equivalents (FTE) or less.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> For fiscal years 1985 through and including 1988, no contracts, for activities conducted by the National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Bureau of Land Management which have been subject to the provisions of Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 or any similar provision in any other order or directive, shall be entered into by the United States until funds have been specifically provided therefore by an Act of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall prevent the National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Land Management from entering into contracts for services and materials under provisions of law and rules, regulations, orders, and policies other than the circular referred to in paragraph (1) or any similar order or directive.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca3699a6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca3699a7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
