<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca3699c6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1460"><num value="1460">§ 1460.</num><heading> Copies of records, documents, etc.; charges; disposition of receipts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, or any of the officers of that Department may, when not prejudicial to the interests of the Government, furnish authenticated or unauthenticated copies of any official books, records, papers, documents, maps, plats, or diagrams within his custody and may charge therefore a sum equal to the cost of production thereof, plus the cost of administrative services involved in handling the records for such purpose, as these costs may be determined by the Secretary of the Interior or such subordinate officials or employees as he may designate, and in addition the sum of 25 cents for each certificate of verification and the seal attached to authenticated copies. There shall be no charge for the making or verification of copies required for official use by the officers of any branch of the Government. Only a charge of 25 cents shall be made for furnishing authenticated copies of any rules, regulations, or instructions printed by the government for gratuitous distribution. The money received for copies under this section shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriations then current and chargeable for the cost of furnishing copies as herein authorized.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca3699c7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1912-08-24/ch370/s1">Aug. 24, 1912, ch. 370, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/497">37 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-30/ch354/s1">July 30, 1947, ch. 354, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/521">61 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-03/ch526">Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 526</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/402">64 Stat. 402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca3699c8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca3699c9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca3699ca-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s488">section 488 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca3699cb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-08-03">Aug. 3, 1950</date>, included within the price of copies of records furnished by the Department the cost of the administrative expenses involved as well as the cost of production.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1947—Act <date date="1947-07-30">July 30, 1947</date>, omitted specific charges for copies of books, records, etc., inserted provision that charge for copies would amount to cost of production as determined by the Secretary of the Interior or his designee, and inserted provision relating to deposit of receipts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca3699cc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca3699cd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
