<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca3699eb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1466"><num value="1466">§ 1466.</num><heading> Administration of oaths, affirmations, etc., by employees of Division of Investigations; force and effect</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Special agents and such other employees of the Division of Investigations, Department of the Interior of the United States, as are designated by the Secretary of the Interior for that purpose, are authorized and empowered to administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, affidavit, or deposition whenever necessary in the performance of their official duties. Any such oath, affirmation, affidavit, or deposition administered or taken by or before a special agent or such other employee of the Division of Investigations, Department of the Interior, designated by the Secretary of the Interior, when certified under his hand, shall have like force and effect as if administered or taken before an officer having a seal.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca3699ec-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-10-14/ch878">Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 878</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1175">54 Stat. 1175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca3699ed-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca3699ee-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca3699ef-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s498">section 498 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca3699f0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca3699f1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
