<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca390b40-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472"><num value="1472">§ 1472.</num><heading> Bureau of Reclamation working capital fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b41-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; management of support activities of Bureau</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 30 days after <date date="1985-11-01">November 1, 1985</date>, there shall be established in the Treasury of the United States a working capital fund to assist in the management of certain support activities of the Bureau of Reclamation (hereafter referred to as the “Bureau”), Department of the Interior. The fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for expenses necessary for furnishing materials, supplies, equipment, work, and services in support of Bureau programs, and, as authorized by law, to agencies of the Federal Government and others. Such expenses may include the acquisition, replacement, and operation of a central computer and related automatic data processing equipment; engineering services; payroll and other management services; acquisition and replacement of equipment and facilities, including the purchase, lease, or rent of motor vehicles and aircraft within any limitations set forth in appropriations made to carry out the functions of the Bureau and such other activities as may be approved by the Director, Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b42-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fund credits; transfers to fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fund shall be credited with appropriations made for the purpose of providing or increasing capital. There are authorized to be transferred to the fund (at fair and reasonable values at the time of transfer) the inventories, equipment, receivables, and other assets, less the liabilities, related to the functions to be financed by the fund as determined by the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b43-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds to provide materials, supplies, equipment, work, and services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fund shall be credited with appropriations and other funds of the Bureau, and other agencies of the Department of the Interior, other Federal agencies, and other sources, for providing materials, supplies, equipment, work, and services as authorized by law. Such payments may be made in advance or upon performance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b44-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges to users</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Charges to users will be at rates approximately equal to the costs of furnishing the materials, supplies, equipment, facilities, and services (including such items as depreciation of equipment and accrued annual leave).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b45-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca390b46-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1472/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Unnecessary funds covered into miscellaneous receipts of Treasury</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds that are not necessary to carry out the activities to be financed by the fund, as determined by the Secretary, shall be covered into miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca390b47-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/141/tII/s205">Pub. L. 99–141, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1985-11-01">Nov. 1, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/571">99 Stat. 571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
