<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca4036f4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551"><num value="1551">§ 1551.</num><heading> Construction of Colorado River Basin Act</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4036f5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to alter, amend, repeal, modify, or be in conflict with the provisions of the Colorado River Compact (<ref href="/us/stat/45/1057">45 Stat. 1057</ref>), the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact (<ref href="/us/stat/63/31">63 Stat. 31</ref>), the Water Treaty of 1944 with the United Mexican States (Treaty Series 994; <ref href="/us/stat/59/1219">59 Stat. 1219</ref>), the decree entered by the Supreme Court of the United States in Arizona against California and others (376 U.S. 340), or, except as otherwise provided herein, the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<ref href="/us/stat/45/1057">45 Stat. 1057</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s617">43 U.S.C. 617</ref> et seq.], the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/stat/54/774">54 Stat. 774</ref>), [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s618">43 U.S.C. 618</ref> et seq.], or the Colorado River Storage Project Act (<ref href="/us/stat/70/105">70 Stat. 105</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620">43 U.S.C. 620</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4036f6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is directed to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4036f7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> make reports as to the annual consumptive uses and losses of water from the Colorado River system after each successive five-year period, beginning with the five-year period starting on <date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>. Such reports shall include a detailed breakdown of the beneficial consumptive use of water on a State-by-State basis. Specific figures on quantities consumptively used from the major tributary streams flowing into the Colorado River shall also be included on a State-by-State basis. Such reports shall be prepared in consultation with the States of the lower basin individually and with the Upper Colorado River Commission, and shall be transmitted to the President, the Congress, and to the Governors of each State signatory to the Colorado River Compact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4036f8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> condition all contracts for the delivery of water originating in the drainage basin of the Colorado River system upon the availability of water under the Colorado River Compact.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4036f9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1551/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance of Federal officers and agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All Federal officers and agencies are directed to comply with the applicable provisions of this chapter, and of the laws, treaty, compacts, and decree referred to in subsection (a) of this section, in the storage and release of water from all reservoirs and in the operation and maintenance of all facilities in the Colorado River system under the jurisdiction and supervision of the Secretary, and in the operation and maintenance of all works which may be authorized hereafter for the augmentation of the water supply of the Colorado River system. In the event of failure of any such officer or agency to so comply, any affected State may maintain an action to enforce the provisions of this section in the Supreme Court of the United States and consent is given to the joinder of the United States as a party in such suit or suits, as a defendant or otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca4036fa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/537/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 90–537, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1968-09-30">Sept. 30, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/899">82 Stat. 899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca4036fb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca4036fc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca4036fd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/537">Pub. L. 90–537</ref>, <date date="1968-09-30">Sept. 30, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/885">82 Stat. 885</ref>, known as the Colorado River Basin Project Act, which enacted this chapter and sections 616aa–1, 620a–1, 620a–2, 620c–1, and 620d–1 of this title, amended sections 616hh, 620, and 620a of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 620, 620k, and 1501 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Boulder Canyon Project Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1928-12-21/ch42">act Dec. 21, 1928, ch. 42</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1057">45 Stat. 1057</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 617 et seq.) of chapter 12A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s617t">section 617t of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1940-07-19/ch643">act July 19, 1940, ch. 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/774">54 Stat. 774</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 618 et seq.) of chapter 12A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 618<i>o</i> of this title and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Colorado River Storage Project Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1956-04-11/ch203">act Apr. 11, 1956, ch. 203</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/105">70 Stat. 105</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12B (§ 620 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620">section 620 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca4036fe-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (b)(1) of this section relating to the requirement that the Secretary transmit a report to Congress every five years, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and the 9th item on page 114 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
