<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9b5d149-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s156"><num value="156">§ 156.</num><heading> Approval by Congress necessary for withdrawal, reservation, or restriction of over 5,000 acres for any Department of Defense project or facility</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No public land, water, or land and water area shall, except by Act of Congress, on and after <date date="1958-02-28">February 28, 1958</date> be (1) withdrawn from settlement, location, sale, or entry for the use of the Department of Defense for defense purposes; (2) reserved for such use; or (3) restricted from operation of the mineral leasing provisions of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.], if such withdrawal, reservation, or restriction would result in the withdrawal, reservation, or restriction of more than five thousand acres in the aggregate for any one defense project or facility of the Department of Defense since <date date="1958-02-28">February 28, 1958</date>, or since the last previous Act of Congress which withdrew, reserved, or restricted public land, water, or land and water area for that project or facility, whichever is later.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9b5d14a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/337/s2">Pub. L. 85–337, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-02-28">Feb. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/28">72 Stat. 28</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9b5d14b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9b5d14c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9b5d14d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345">act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1331 et seq.) of chapter 29 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
