<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9b5d14e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157"><num value="157">§ 157.</num><heading> Application for withdrawal, reservation, or restriction; specifications</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any application filed on and after <date date="1958-02-28">February 28, 1958</date> for a withdrawal, reservation, or restriction, the approval of which will, under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s156">section 156 of this title</ref>, require an Act of Congress, shall specify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d14f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the name of the requesting agency and intended using agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d150-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> location of the area involved, to include a detailed description of the exterior boundaries and excepted areas, if any, within such proposed withdrawal, reservation, or restriction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d151-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> gross land and water acreage within the exterior boundaries of the requested withdrawal, reservation, or restriction, and net public land, water, or public land and water acreage covered by the application;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d152-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the purpose or purposes for which the area is proposed to be withdrawn, reserved, or restricted, or if the purpose or purposes are classified for national security reasons, a statement to that effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d153-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> whether the proposed use will result in contamination of any or all of the requested withdrawal, reservation, or restriction area, and if so, whether such contamination will be permanent or temporary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d154-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the period during which the proposed withdrawal, reservation, or restriction will continue in effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d155-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> whether, and if so to what extent, the proposed use will affect continuing full operation of the public land laws and Federal regulations relating to conservation, utilization, and development of mineral resources, timber and other material resources, grazing resources, fish and wildlife resources, water resources, and scenic, wilderness, and recreation and other values; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9b5d156-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s157/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> if effecting the purpose for which the area is proposed to be withdrawn, reserved, or restricted, will involve the use of water in any State, whether, subject to existing rights under law, the intended using agency has acquired, or proposes to acquire, rights to the use thereof in conformity with State laws and procedures relating to the control, appropriation, use, and distribution of water.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idc9b5d157-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/337/s3">Pub. L. 85–337, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-02-28">Feb. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/28">72 Stat. 28</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
