<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca42815a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1578"><num value="1578">§ 1578.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated the sum of $356,400,000 for the construction of the works and accomplishment of the purposes authorized in sections 1571, 1572, 1573, and 1579 of this title, of which $3,579,000 is authorized for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses associated with replacement of the Coachella Canal in California, and $6,960,000 is authorized for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses associated with the Desalting Complex Unit and the Protective and Regulatory Pumping Unit in Arizona, based on January 1979, prices plus or minus such amounts as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuation in construction costs involved therein, and such sums as may be required to operate and maintain such works and to provide for such modifications as may be made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1574">section 1574 of this title</ref>. In order to provide for the utilization of significant improvements in desal­inization technologies which may have been developed since the Bureau’s evaluation, the Secretary is directed to evaluate such cost effective improvements and implement such improved designs into the plant operations when the evaluation indicates that cost savings will result: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no more than five percent of the amount authorized to be appropriated is used for these purposes. There is further authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to pay condemnation awards in excess of appraised values and to cover costs required in connection with the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601">42 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca42815b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/320/tI/s109">Pub. L. 93–320, title I, § 109</ref>, formerly § 108, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/270">88 Stat. 270</ref>; renumbered § 109 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/336">Pub. L. 96–336</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1064">94 Stat. 1064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca42815c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca42815d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca42815e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/91/646">Pub. L. 91–646</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1894">84 Stat. 1894</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 61 (§ 4601 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601">section 4601 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca42815f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/336/s5">Pub. L. 96–336, § 5</ref>, substituted appropriations authorization of $356,400,000 to carry out sections 1571, 1572, 1573, and 1579 of this title for prior authorizations of $121,500,000 and $34,000,000 for purposes of sections 1571 and 1572, and 1573 of this title, and use of January 1979 for April 1973 price basis, authorized sums of $3,579,000 and $6,960,000 for mitigation of fish and wildlife losses in California and Arizona, and provided for cost savings desalinization plant operations limited to five percent of appropriations authorization.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca428160-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca428161-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/336/s5">Pub. L. 96–336, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1064">94 Stat. 1064</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 5 is effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
