<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca428171-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1591"><num value="1591">§ 1591.</num><heading> Salinity control policy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca428172-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1591/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation by Secretary of the Interior</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall implement the salinity control policy adopted for the Colorado River in the “Conclusions and Recommendations” published in the Proceedings of the Reconvened Seventh Session of the Conference in the Matter of Pollution of the Interstate Waters of the Colorado River and Its Tributaries in the States of California, Colorado, Utah, Arizona, Nevada, New Mexico, and Wyoming, held in Denver, Colorado, on April 26–27, 1972, under the authority of section 10 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1160">33 U.S.C. 1160</ref>), and approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency on <date date="1972-06-09">June 9, 1972</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca428173-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1591/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Expeditious investigation, planning, and implementation of salinity control program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby directed to expedite the investigation, planning, and implementation of the salinity control program generally as described in chapter VI of the Secretary’s report entitled, “Colorado River Water Quality Improvement Program, February 1972”. In determining the relative priority of implementing additional units or new self-contained portions of units authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref>, the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, shall give preference to those additional units or new self-contained portions of units which reduce salinity of the Colorado River at the least cost per unit of salinity reduction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca428174-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1591/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conformity with subsection (a) and the authority of the Environmental Protection Agency under Federal laws, the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Secretary of Agriculture are directed to cooperate and coordinate their activities effectively to carry out the objective of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca428175-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/320/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/270">88 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/569/s1">Pub. L. 98–569, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2933">98 Stat. 2933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca428176-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca428177-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca428178-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Water Pollution Control Act, referred to in subsec. (a), which was formerly classified to chapter 23 (§ 1151 et seq.) of Title 33, Navigation and Navigable Waters, was revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/92/500">Pub. L. 92–500</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/816">86 Stat. 816</ref>, and is classified generally to chapter 25 (§ 1251 et seq.) of Title 33.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca428179-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/569">Pub. L. 98–569</ref> inserted “In determining the relative priority of implementing additional units or new self-contained portions of units authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref>, the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, shall give preference to those additional units or new self-contained portions of units which reduce salinity of the Colorado River at the least cost per unit of salinity reduction.”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca42817a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca42817b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/569/s6">Pub. L. 98–569, § 6</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2939">98 Stat. 2939</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/569/s6">“The amendments made by this Act [amending this section and sections 620d, 1543, 1592, 1593, 1595, and 1598 of this title] shall take effect upon enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
