<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca44f1f2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1596"><num value="1596">§ 1596.</num><heading> Biennial report to President, Congress, and Advisory Council</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Commencing on <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, and every two years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit, simultaneously, to the President, the Congress, and the Advisory Council created in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1594/a">section 1594(a) of this title</ref>, a report on the Colorado River salinity control program authorized by this subchapter covering the progress of investigations, planning, and construction of salinity control units for the previous fiscal year, the effectiveness of such units, anticipated work needed to be accomplished in the future to meet the objectives of this subchapter, with emphasis on the needs during the five years immediately following the date of each report, and any special problems that may be impeding progress in attaining an effective salinity control program. Said report may be included in the biennial report on the quality of water of the Colorado River Basin prepared by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620n">section 620n of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s615ww">section 615ww of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s616e">section 616e of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca44f1f3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/320/tII/s206">Pub. L. 93–320, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1974-06-24">June 24, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/274">88 Stat. 274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca44f1f4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca44f1f5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca44f1f6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 615ww and 616e of this title, referred to in text, were omitted from the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca44f1f7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca44f1f8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in this section relating to the requirement that the Secretary submit a biennial report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and the 4th item on page 113 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca44f1f9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
