<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca473c3e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c"><num value="1600c">§ 1600c.</num><heading> Colorado River Floodway</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca473c3f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established the Colorado River Floodway as identified and generally depicted on maps that are to be submitted by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca473c40-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Study of tributary floodflows; determination of Floodway boundary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within eighteen months after <date date="1986-10-08">October 8, 1986</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the seven Colorado River Basin States, represented by persons designated by the Governors of those States, the Colorado River Floodway Task Force, and any other interested parties shall:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca473c41-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> complete a study of the tributary floodflows downstream of Davis Dam;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca473c42-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> define the specific boundaries of the Colorado River Floodway so that the Floodway can accommodate either a one-in-one hundred year river flow consisting of controlled releases and tributary inflow, or a flow of forty thousand cubic feet per second (cfs), whichever is greater, from below Davis Dam to the Southerly International Boundary between the United States of America and the Republic of Mexico.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca473c43-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and modification of boundaries; notice and comment; written justification for decision of Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca473c44-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall conduct, at least once every five years, a review of the Colorado River Floodway and make, after notice to and in consultation with appropriate chief executive officers of States, counties, municipalities, water districts, Indian tribes, or equivalent jurisdictions in which the Floodway is located, and others, such minor and technical modifications to the boundaries of the Floodway as are necessary solely to reflect changes that have occurred in the size or location of any portion of the floodplain as a result of natural forces, and as necessary pursuant to subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1600e">section 1600e of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca473c45-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, in the case of any minor and technical modification to the boundaries of the Floodway made under the authority of this subsection, an appropriate chief executive officer of a State, county, municipality, water district, Indian tribe, or equivalent jurisdiction, to which notice was given in accordance with this subsection files comments disagreeing with all or part of the modification and the Secretary makes a modification which is in conflict with such comments, the Secretary shall submit to the chief executive officer a written justification for his failure to make modifications consistent with such comments or proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca473c46-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/450/s5">Pub. L. 99–450, § 5</ref>, <date date="1986-10-08">Oct. 8, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1131">100 Stat. 1131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tIX/s901/d">Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3289">112 Stat. 3289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca473c47-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca473c48-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca473c49-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/s901/d/1">Pub. L. 105–362, § 901(d)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (1) designation, redesignated cls. (i) and (ii) of former par. (1) as pars. (1) and (2), respectively, and struck out former pars. (2) and (3) which related to preparation and filing of maps with congressional committees, Federal, State, and local government agencies, and federally insured financial institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/s901/d/2">Pub. L. 105–362, § 901(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “appropriate chief executive officers of States, counties, municipalities, water districts, Indian tribes, or equivalent jurisdictions in which the Floodway is located,” for “the appropriate officers referred to in paragraph (3) of subsection (b) of this section,”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
