<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca473c88-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1600l"><num value="1600l">§ 1600l.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Interior $600,000, through the end of fiscal year 1990, in addition to any other funds now available to the Department to discharge its duties to implement sections 1600b to 1600k of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4029">section 4029 of title 42</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That by mutual agreement, such funds shall be made available to the Federal Emergency Management Agency to discharge its duties under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4029">section 4029 of title 42</ref>: <i>Provided further</i>, That the provisions of sections 1600d and 1600e of this title shall not be affected by this section: <i>And Provided further</i>, in addition, Indian tribes may be eligible under <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Public Law 93–638</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.] to contract for studies of Indian lands required under the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca473c89-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/450/s15">Pub. L. 99–450, § 15</ref>, <date date="1986-10-08">Oct. 8, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1136">100 Stat. 1136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca473c8a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca473c8b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca473c8c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Public Law 93–638</ref>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, known as the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, which is classified principally to chapter 46 (§ 5301 et seq.) of Title 25, Indians. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca473c8d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca473c8e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
