<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca4c1ea7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1607"><num value="1607">§ 1607.</num><heading> Village Corporations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4c1ea8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1607/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Organization of Corporation prerequisite to receipt of patent to lands or benefits under chapter</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Native residents of each Native village entitled to receive lands and benefits under this chapter shall organize as a business for profit or nonprofit corporation under the laws of the State before the Native village may receive patent to lands or benefits under this chapter, except as otherwise provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4c1ea9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1607/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional Corporation: approval of initial articles; review and approval of amendments to articles and annual budgets; assistance in preparation of articles and other documents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The initial articles of incorporation for each Village Corporation shall be subject to the approval of the Regional Corporation for the region in which the village is located. Amendments to the articles of incorporation and the annual budgets of the Village Corporations shall, for a period of five years, be subject to review and approval by the Regional Corporation. The Regional Corporation shall assist and advise Native villages in the preparation of articles of incorporation and other documents necessary to meet the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4c1eaa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1607/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of section 1606</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsections (g), (h) (other than paragraph (4)), and (<i>o</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606">section 1606 of this title</ref> shall apply in all respects to Village Corporations, Urban Corporations, and Group Corporations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca4c1eab-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/203/s8">Pub. L. 92–203, § 8</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/694">85 Stat. 694</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIV/s1401/b">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIV, § 1401(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2492">94 Stat. 2492</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/241/s6">Pub. L. 100–241, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-02-03">Feb. 3, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1795">101 Stat. 1795</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/10/s1/b">Pub. L. 104–10, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-05-18">May 18, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/157">109 Stat. 157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca4c1eac-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca4c1ead-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca4c1eae-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/10">Pub. L. 104–10</ref> substituted “(h) (other than paragraph (4))” for “(h)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/241">Pub. L. 100–241</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “The provisions concerning stock alienation, annual audit, and transfer of stock ownership on death or by court decree provided for regional corporations in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606">section 1606 of this title</ref>, including the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606/h/3">section 1606(h)(3) of this title</ref> shall apply to Village Corporations Urban Corporations and Native Groups; except that audits need not be transmitted to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives or to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref> inserted provision making provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606">section 1606 of this title</ref>, including <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606/h/3">section 1606(h)(3) of this title</ref>, applicable to Village Corporations, Urban Corporations, and Native Groups and substituted provision that audits need not be transmitted to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate for provision that audits need not be transmitted to the Committees on Interior and Insular Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
