<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca4e67cf-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611"><num value="1611">§ 1611.</num><heading> Native land selections</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67d0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acreage limitation; proximity of selections and size of sections and units; waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67d1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> During a period of three years from <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>, the Village Corporation for each Native village identified pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610">section 1610 of this title</ref> shall select, in accordance with rules established by the Secretary, all of the township or townships in which any part of the village is located, plus an area that will make the total selection equal to the acreage to which the village is entitled under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613">section 1613 of this title</ref>. The selection shall be made from lands withdrawn by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a">section 1610(a) of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That no Village Corporation may select more than 69,120 acres from lands withdrawn by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/2">section 1610(a)(2) of this title</ref>, and not more than 69,120 acres from the National Wildlife Refuge System, and not more than 69,120 acres in a National Forest: <i>Provided further</i>, That when a Village Corporation selects the surface estate to lands within the National Wildlife Refuge System or Naval Petroleum Reserve Numbered 4, the Regional Corporation, for that region may select the subsurface estate in an equal acreage from other lands withdrawn in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a">section 1610(a) of this title</ref> within the region, if possible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67d2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Selections made under this subsection (a) shall be contiguous and in reasonably compact tracts, except as separated by bodies of water or by lands which are unavailable for selection, and shall be in whole sections and, wherever feasible, in units of not less than 1,280 acres: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary in his discretion and upon the request of the concerned Village Corporation, may waive the whole section requirement where—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67d3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67d4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a portion of available public lands of a section is separated from other available public lands in the same section by lands unavailable for selection or by a meanderable body of water;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67d5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such waiver will not result in small isolated parcels of available public land remaining after conveyance of selected lands to Native Corporations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67d6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such waiver would result in a better land ownership pattern or improved land or resource management opportunity; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67d7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the remaining available public lands in the section have been selected and will be conveyed to another Native Corporation under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67d8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation; reallocation considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The difference between twenty-two million acres and the total acreage selected by Village Corporations pursuant to subsection (a) shall be allocated by the Secretary among the eleven Regional Corporations (which excludes the Regional Corporation for southeastern Alaska) on the basis of the number of Natives enrolled in each region. Each Regional Corporation shall, not later than <date date="2005-10-01">October 1, 2005</date>, reallocate such acreage among the Native villages within the region on an equitable basis after considering historic use, subsistence needs, and population. The action of the Secretary or the Corporation shall not be subject to judicial review. Each Village Corporation shall select the acreage allocated to it from the lands withdrawn by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a">section 1610(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67d9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Computation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The difference between thirty-eight million acres and the 22 million acres selected by Village Corporations pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be allocated among the eleven Regional Corporations (which excludes the Regional Corporation for southeastern Alaska) as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67da-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of acres each Regional Corporation is entitled to receive shall be computed (A) by determining on the basis of available data the percentages of all land in Alaska (excluding the southeastern region) that is within each of the eleven regions, (B) by applying that percentage to thirty-eight million acres reduced by the acreage in the southeastern region that is to be selected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1615">section 1615 of this title</ref>, and (C) by deducting from the figure so computed the number of acres within that region selected pursuant to subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67db-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the event that the total number of acres selected within a region pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) exceeds the percentage of the reduced thirty-eight million acres allotted to that region pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B), that region shall not be entitled to receive any lands under this subsection (c). For each region so affected the difference between the acreage calculated pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B) and the acreage selected pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be deducted from the acreage calculated under subsection (c)(1)(C) for the remaining regions which will select lands under this subsection (c). The reductions shall be apportioned among the remaining regions so that each region’s share of the total reduction bears the same proportion to the total reduction as the total land area in that region (as calculated pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002115"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by another closing parenthesis.</note> bears to the total land area in all of the regions whose allotments are to be reduced pursuant to this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67dc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Before the end of the fourth year after <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>, each Regional Corporation shall select the acreage allocated to it from the lands within the region withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/1">section 1610(a)(1) of this title</ref>, and from the lands within the region withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/3">section 1610(a)(3) of this title</ref> to the extent lands withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/1">section 1610(a)(1) of this title</ref> are not sufficient to satisfy its allocation: <i>Provided</i>, That within the lands withdrawn by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/1">section 1610(a)(1) of this title</ref> the Regional Corporation may select only even numbered townships in even numbered ranges, and only odd numbered townships in odd numbered ranges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67dd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Where the public lands consist only of the mineral estate, or portion thereof, which is reserved by the United States upon patent of the balance of the estate under one of the public land laws, other than this chapter, the Regional Corporations may select as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67de-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Where such public lands were not withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/3">section 1610(a)(3) of this title</ref>, but are surrounded by or contiguous to lands withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/3">section 1610(a)(3) of this title</ref>, and filed upon for selection by a Regional Corporation, the Corporation may, upon request, have such public land included in its selection and considered by the Secretary to be withdrawn and properly selected.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67df-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Where such public lands were withdrawn pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/1">section 1610(a)(1) of this title</ref> and are required to be selected by paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Regional Corporation may, at its option, exclude such public lands from its selection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Where such public lands are surrounded by or contiguous to subsurface lands obtained by a Regional Corporation under subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002116">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002116"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (a) or (b), the Corporation may, upon request, have such public land conveyed to it.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A Regional Corporation which elects to obtain public lands under subparagraph (C) shall be limited to a total of not more than 12,000 acres. Selection by a Regional Corporation of in lieu surface acres under subparagraph (E) pursuant to an election under subparagraph (C) shall not be made from any lands within a conservation system unit (as that term is defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3102/4">section 3102(4) of title 16</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> An election to obtain the public lands described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) shall include all available parcels within the township in which the public lands are located.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> For purposes of this subparagraph and subparagraph (C), the term “Regional Corporation” shall refer only to Doyon, Limited.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Where the Regional Corporation elects to obtain such public lands under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph, it may select, within ninety days of receipt of notice from the Secretary, the surface estate in an equal acreage from other public lands withdrawn by the Secretary for that purpose. Such selections shall be in units no smaller than a whole section, except where the remaining entitlement is less than six hundred and forty acres, or where an entire section is not available. Where possible, selections shall be of lands from which the subsurface estate was selected by that Regional Corporation pursuant to subsection (a)(1) or <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/h/9">section 1613(h)(9) of this title</ref>, and, where possible, all selections made under this section shall be contiguous to lands already selected by the Regional Corporation or a Village Corporation. The Secretary is authorized, as necessary, to withdraw up to two times the acreage entitlement of the in lieu surface estate from vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved public lands from which the Regional Corporation may select such in lieu surface estate except that the Secretary may withdraw public lands which had been previously withdrawn pursuant to sub<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1616/d/1">section 1616(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67e6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> No mineral estate or in lieu surface estate shall be available for selection within the National Petroleum Reserve—Alaska or within Wildlife Refuges as the boundaries of those refuges exist on <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67e7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (4) shall apply, notwithstanding the failure of the Regional Corporation to have appealed the rejection of a selection during the conveyance of the relevant surface estate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67e8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Village Corporation for Native village at Dutch Harbor; lands and improvements and patent for Village Corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To insure that the Village Corporation for the Native village at Dutch Harbor, if found eligible for land grants under this chapter, has a full opportunity to select lands within and near the village, no federally owned lands, whether improved or not, shall be disposed of pursuant to the Federal surplus property disposal laws for a period of two years from <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>. The Village Corporation may select such lands and improvements and receive patent to them pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/a">section 1613(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67e9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Disputes over land selection rights and boundaries; arbitration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any dispute over the land selection rights and the boundaries of Village Corporations shall be resolved by a board of arbitrators consisting of one person selected by each of the Village Corporations involved, and an additional one or two persons, whichever is needed to make an odd number of arbitrators, such additional person or persons to be selected by the arbitrators selected by the Village Corporations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca4e67ea-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Combining entitlements and reallocations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67eb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The entitlements received by any Village Corporation under subsection (a) and the reallocations made to the Village Corporation under subsection (b) may be combined, at the discretion of the Secretary, without—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67ec-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> increasing or decreasing the combined entitlement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca4e67ed-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> increasing the limitation on selections of Wildlife Refuge System land, National Forest System land, or State-selected land under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67ee-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The combined entitlement under paragraph (1) may be fulfilled from selections under subsection (a) or (b) without regard to the entitlement specified in the selection application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67ef-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> All selections under a combined entitlement under paragraph (1) shall be adjudicated and conveyed in compliance with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca4e67f0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1611/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Except in a case in which a survey has been contracted for <date date="2004-12-10">December 10, 2004</date>, the combination of entitlements under paragraph (1) shall not require separate patents or surveys, to distinguish between conveyances made to a Village Corporation under subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca4e67f1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/203/s12">Pub. L. 92–203, § 12</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/701">85 Stat. 701</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIV">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1402, 1403, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2492">94 Stat. 2492</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s3">Pub. L. 105–333, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3130">112 Stat. 3130</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/452/tII/s202">Pub. L. 108–452, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3582">118 Stat. 3582</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca4e67f2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca4e67f3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca4e67f4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For Federal surplus property disposal laws, referred to in subsec. (d), see, generally, subtitle I of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca4e67f5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/452/s202/1">Pub. L. 108–452, § 202(1)</ref>, substituted “Regional Corporation shall, not later than <date date="2005-10-01">October 1, 2005</date>,” for “Regional Corporation shall” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/452/s202/2">Pub. L. 108–452, § 202(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (c)(4)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 105–333, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (C) and (D). Former subpars. (C) and (D) redesignated (E) and (F), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s3/a">Pub. L. 105–333, § 3(a)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (E) and substituted “(A), (B), or (C)” for “(A) or (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 105–333, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s3/b">Pub. L. 105–333, § 3(b)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/s1402">Pub. L. 96–487, § 1402</ref>, inserted proviso specifying conditions under which Secretary in his discretion and upon request of concerned Village Corporation may waive the whole section requirement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/s1403">Pub. L. 96–487, § 1403</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca4e67f6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idca4e67f7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/178/s3/b">Pub. L. 95–178, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-15">Nov. 15, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1370">91 Stat. 1370</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/178/s3/b">“If any provision of this Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1628">section 1628 of this title</ref>, amending sections 1613 and 1615 of this title, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] or the applicability thereof is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this Act, of <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12">section 12 of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</ref>), as amended [set out below], of the document referred to in section 12(b) thereof, and the duties and obligations of the Secretary of the Interior, the State of Alaska, and Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, with respect thereto, shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca4e67f8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Land Available After Selection Period</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/452/tII/s201">Pub. L. 108–452, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3582">118 Stat. 3582</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/452/tII/s201">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To make certain Federal land available for conveyance to a Native Corporation that has sufficient remaining entitlement, the Secretary [of the Interior] may waive the filing deadlines under sections 12 and 16 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">43 U.S.C. 1611</ref>, 1615) if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the Federal land is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> located in a township in which all or any part of a Native Village is located; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> surrounded by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> land that is owned by the Native Corporation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> selected land that will be conveyed to the Native Corporation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the Federal land—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> became available after the end of the original selection period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> was not selected by the Native Corporation because the Federal land was subject to a competing claim or entry; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the competing claim or entry has lapsed; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> was previously an unavailable Federal enclave within a Native selection withdrawal area;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary provides the Native Corporation with a specific time period in which to decline the Federal land; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Native Corporation does not submit to the Secretary written notice declining the land within the period established under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the State [of Alaska] has voluntarily relinquished any valid State selection or top-filing for the Federal land.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Action</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a parcel of Federal land if Congress has specifically made other provisions for disposition of the parcel of Federal land.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca4e67f9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Settlement of Remaining Entitlement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/452/tII/s209">Pub. L. 108–452, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3586">118 Stat. 3586</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/452/tII/s209">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of the Interior] may enter into a binding written agreement with a Native Corporation relating to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the land remaining to be conveyed to the Native Corporation under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.) from land selected as of <date date="2004-09-01">September 1, 2004</date>, or land made available under section 201 [set out above], 206 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613">section 1613 of this title</ref>], or 208 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1621">section 1621 of this title</ref>] of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the priority in which the land is to be conveyed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the relinquishment of selections which are not to be conveyed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the selection entitlement to which selections are to be charged, regardless of the entitlement under which originally selected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the survey of the exterior boundaries of the land to be conveyed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the additional survey to be performed under section 14(c) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/c">43 U.S.C. 1613(c)</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the resolution of conflicts with Native allotment [an allotment claimed under the Act of <date date="1906-05-17">May 17, 1906</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/34/197">34 Stat. 197</ref>, chapter 2469)] applications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An agreement under subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall be authorized by a resolution of the Native Corporation entering into the agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall include a statement that the entitlement of the Native Corporation shall be considered complete on execution of the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Correction of Conveyance Documents</inline>.—</heading><content>In an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Native Corporation may agree to make technical corrections to the legal description in the conveyance documents for easements previously reserved so that the easements provide the access intended by the original reservation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>Before entering into an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that the concerns or issues identified by the State [of Alaska] and all Federal agencies potentially affected by the agreement are given consideration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Errors</inline>.—</heading><content>Any Native Corporation entering into an agreement under subsection (a) shall receive any gain or bear any loss resulting from errors in prior surveys, protraction diagrams, or computation of the ownership of third parties on any land conveyed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An agreement under subsection (a) shall not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> affect the obligations of Native Corporations under prior agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> result in a Native Corporation relinquishing valid selections of land in order to qualify for the withdrawal of other tracts of land.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on subsurface rights</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms of an agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be binding on a Regional Corporation with respect to the location and quantity of subsurface rights of the Regional Corporation under section 14(f) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/f">43 U.S.C. 1613(f)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on entitlement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section increases the entitlement provided to any Native Corporation under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Boundaries of a Native Village</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement entered into under subsection (a) may not define the boundaries of a Native Village.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Department of the Interior.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca4e67fa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Final Priorities; Conveyance and Survey Plans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/452/tIV">Pub. L. 108–452, title IV</ref>, §§ 401–403, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3591">118 Stat. 3591</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/452/tIV">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="401">“SEC. 401.</num><heading> DEADLINE FOR ESTABLISHMENT OF REGIONAL PLANS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>], the Secretary [of the Interior], in coordination and consultation with Native Corporations, other Federal land management agencies, and the State [of Alaska], shall update and revise the 12 preliminary Regional Conveyance and Survey Plans.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>The updated and revised plans under subsection (a) shall identify any conflicts to be resolved and recommend any actions that should be taken to facilitate the finalization of land conveyances in a region by 2009.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="402">“SEC. 402.</num><heading> DEADLINE FOR ESTABLISHMENT OF VILLAGE PLANS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>], the Secretary, in coordination with affected Federal land management agencies, the State, and Village Corporations, shall complete a final closure plan with respect to the entitlements for each Village Corporation under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="403">“SEC. 403.</num><heading> FINAL PRIORITIZATION OF ANCSA SELECTIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any Native Corporation that has not received its full entitlement or entered into a voluntary, negotiated settlement of final entitlement shall submit the final, irrevocable priorities of the Native Corporation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in the case of a Village, Group, or Urban Corporation entitlement, not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of a Regional Corporation entitlement, not later than 42 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acreage Limitations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The priorities submitted under subsection (a) shall not exceed land that is the greater of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not more than 125 percent of the remaining entitlement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not more than 640 acres in excess of the remaining entitlement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Corrections.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the priorities submitted under subsection (a) may not be revoked, rescinded, or modified by the Native Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Technical corrections</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a notification by the Secretary that there appears to be a technical error in the priorities, the Native Corporation may correct the technical error in accordance with any recommendations of, and in a manner prescribed by or acceptable to, the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relinquishment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As of the date on which the Native Corporation submits its final priorities under subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> any unprioritized, remaining selections of the Native Corporation—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> are relinquished, but any part of the selections may be reinstated for the purpose of correcting a technical error; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> have no further segregative effect; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> all withdrawals under sections 11 and 16 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610">43 U.S.C. 1610</ref>, 1615) under the relinquished selections are terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading><content>All relinquishments under paragraph (1) shall be included in Bureau of Land Management land records.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure To Submit Priorities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a Native Corporation fails to submit priorities by the deadline specified in subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> with respect to a Native Corporation that has priorities on file with the Secretary, the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall convey to the Native Corporation the remaining entitlement of the Native Corporation, as determined based on the most recent priorities of the Native Corporation on file with the Secretary and in accordance with the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may reject any selections not needed to fulfill the entitlement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> with respect to a Native Corporation that does not have priorities on file with the Secretary, the Secretary shall satisfy the entitlement by conveying land selected by the Secretary, in consultation with the appropriate Native Corporation, the Federal land managing agency with administrative jurisdiction over the land to be conveyed, and the State, that, to the maximum extent practicable, is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> contiguous to land previously conveyed to the Native Corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> consistent with the applicable preliminary Regional Conveyance and Survey Plan referred to in section 401.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan of Conveyance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> identify any Native Corporation that does not have sufficient priorities on file;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> develop priorities for the Native Corporation in accordance with subsection (e); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> provide to the Native Corporation a plan of conveyance based on the priorities developed under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Finalized selections</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary provides a plan of conveyance to the affected Village, Group, or Urban Corporation and the Regional Corporation, the Regional Corporation shall finalize any Regional selections that are in conflict with land selected by the Village, Group, or Urban Corporation that has not been prioritized by the deadline under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dissolved or Lapsed Corporations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If a Native Corporation is lapsed or dissolved at the time final priorities are required to be filed under this section and does not have priorities on file with the Secretary, the Secretary shall establish a deadline for the filing of priorities that shall be one year from the provisions of notice of the deadline.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> To fulfill the notice requirement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> publish notice of the deadline to a lapsed or dissolved Native Corporation in a newspaper of general circulation nearest the locality where the affected land is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> seek to notify in writing the last known shareholders of the lapsed or dissolved corporation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> If a Native Corporation does not file priorities with the Secretary before the deadline set pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If a Native Corporation with final priorities on file with the Bureau of Land Management is lapsed or dissolved, the United States—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall continue to administer the prioritized selected land under applicable law; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may reject any selections not needed to fulfill the lapsed or dissolved Native Corporation’s entitlement.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca50d8fb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Availability of Property Account for Purposes Involving Public Sale of Property by Federal Agencies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/j/s127">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(j) [§ 127]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-311">101 Stat. 1329–311</ref>, 1329–318, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/202/s101/j/s127">“In addition to the purposes for which it is now available, the property account established by <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12/b">section 12(b) of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref>, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">43 U.S.C. 1611</ref> note) [<ref href="/us/pl/94/204/s12/b">section 12(b) of Pub. L. 94–204</ref> set out below] shall be available hereafter for purposes involving any public sale of property by any agency of the United States, including the Department of Defense, or any element thereof.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca50d8fc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Convey Lands Under Application for Selection to Cook Inlet Region, Inc., for Reconveyance to Village Corporations; Tender of Conveyance of Described Land to Cook Inlet Region, Inc., Acceptance by Region, and Effect On Entitlement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/456">Pub. L. 94–456</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1935">90 Stat. 1935</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/456">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="4">“Sec. 4.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to convey lands under application for selection by Village Corporations within Cook Inlet Region to the Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, for reconveyance by the Region to such Village Corporations. Such lands shall be conveyed as partial satisfaction of the statutory entitlement of such Village Corporations from lands withdrawn pursuant to section 11(a)(3) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610/a/3">section 1610(a)(3) of this title</ref>] (hereinafter, The Settlement Act’) [this chapter], and with the consent of the Region affected, as provided in <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12">section 12 of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/89/1145">89 Stat. 1145</ref>, 1150) [set out as a note below], from lands outside the boundaries of Cook Inlet Region. This authority shall not be employed to increase or decrease the statutory entitlement of any Village Corporation or Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated. For the purposes of counting acres received in computing statutory entitlement, the Secretary shall count the number of acres or acre selections surrendered by Village Corporations in any exchange for any other lands or selections.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Secretary shall not be required to survey any land conveyed pursuant to subsection 4(a) until the Village Corporation entitlement for all eligible Village Corporations has been conveyed. With respect to the conveyances made by the Secretary in the manner authorized by subsection 4(a), the Secretary shall survey the exterior boundaries of each entire area conveyed to Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, pursuant to subsection 4(a) and monument to boundary lines at angle points and intervals of approximately two miles on straight lines. The Secretary shall not be required to provide ground survey or monumentation along meanderable water boundaries. Each township corner located within the exterior boundary of land conveyed shall be located and monumented. Any areas within such tracts that are to be reconveyed pursuant to section 14(C)(1) and (2) [probably means 14(c)(1) and (2), now 14(c)(1)(A) and (B)] of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/c/1/A">43 U.S.C. 1613(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (B)] shall also be surveyed pursuant to 43 C.F.R. 2650.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Conveyances made under the authority of subsection (a) of this section shall be considered conveyances under the Settlement Act [this chapter] and subject to the provisions of that Act, except as provided by this Act [amending section 1615(a) and (d) of this title and amending provisions set out as a note below].</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="5">“Sec. 5.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The Secretary shall, within sixty days after the effective date of this Act [<date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>], tender conveyance of the land described in subsection (b), subject to valid existing rights, to Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated. If the conveyance is accepted by the Region, such lands shall be considered 1,687.2 acre-equivalents within the meaning of paragraph I(C)(2)(e)(iii) of the Terms and Conditions as clarified <date date="1976-08-31">August 31, 1976</date>, and the Secretary’s obligations under paragraph I(C) of those Terms and Conditions will be reduced accordingly. If, however, said <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12">section 12 of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> [set out as a note below], does not take effect then the entitlement of Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, under section 12(c) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611/c">section 1611(c) of this title</ref>] shall be reduced by 8,346 acres.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The land referred to in subsection (a) is described as a parcel of land located in section 7 of township 13 north, range 2 west of the Seward Meridian, Third Judicial District, State of Alaska; said parcel being all of Government lots 5 and 7 and that portion of the SE¼ NW¼ lying north of the north right-of-way line of the Glenn Highway, State of Alaska, Department of Highways Project No. F–042–1(2), and more particularly described as follows:<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" role="listItem" class="indent1">“Commencing at the north quarter corner of said section 7;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" role="listItem" class="indent1">“thence south 00 degrees 12 minutes east, a distance of 1,320.0 feet, more or less, to the northeast corner of said southeast quarter northwest quarter;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“thence west along the north line of southeast quarter northwest quarter a distance of 94.0 feet, more or less, to the north right-of-way line of the Glenn Highway and the true point of beginning;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“thence south 53 degrees 16 minutes 15 seconds west along said north right-of-way line, a distance of 1,415.0 feet, more or less, to a point of curve being at right angles to centerline Station 216 plus 51.35;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“thence continuing along said north right-of-way line along a curve to the right with a central angle of 12 degrees 51 minutes 34 seconds, having a radius of 5,595.58 feet for an arc distance of 105.0 feet, more or less, to a point of intersection of said north right-of-way line with the west line of said southeast quarter northwest quarter;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“thence north 00 degrees 12 minutes west along said west line, being common with the east line of Government lot 5, a distance of 910.0 feet, more or less, to the northwest corner of said southeast quarter northwest quarter;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“thence east along the north line of said southeast quarter northwest quarter, a distance of 1,225.0 feet, more or less, to the point of beginning; containing 56.24 acres, more or less.”</p>
</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca50d8fd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Settlement of Claims and Consolidation of Ownership Among the United States, the Cook Inlet Region, Inc. and the State of Alaska</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/204/s12">Pub. L. 94–204, § 12</ref>, <date date="1976-01-02">Jan. 2, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1150">89 Stat. 1150</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/94/456/s3">Pub. L. 94–456, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1935">90 Stat. 1935</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/178/s3/a">Pub. L. 95–178, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-15">Nov. 15, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1369">91 Stat. 1369</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/55/s2">Pub. L. 96–55, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/386">93 Stat. 386</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/311">Pub. L. 96–311</ref>, <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/947">94 Stat. 947</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIV/s1435">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIV, § 1435</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2545">94 Stat. 2545</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/468/tVI/s606/d">Pub. L. 97–468, title VI, § 606(d)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2566">96 Stat. 2566</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/h/tIII/s319">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title III, § 319]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–286, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tIII/s319">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title III, § 319]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–287; <ref href="/us/pl/101/511/tVIII/s8133/a">Pub. L. 101–511, title VIII, § 8133(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1909">104 Stat. 1909</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/154/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 102–154, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1036">105 Stat. 1036</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/204/s32/b">Pub. L. 103–204, § 32(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2413">107 Stat. 2413</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/204/s32/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The purpose of this section is to provide for the settlement of certain claims, and in so doing to consolidate ownership among the United States, the Cook Inlet Region Incorporated (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Region’), and the State of Alaska, within the Cook Inlet area of Alaska in order to facilitate land management and to create land ownership patterns which encourage settlement and development in appropriate areas. The provisions of this section shall take effect at such time as all of the following have taken place:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the State of Alaska has conveyed or irrevocably obligated itself to convey lands to the United States for exchange, hereby authorized, with the Region in accordance with the document referred to in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Region and all plaintiffs/appellants have withdrawn from Cook Inlet against Kleppe, numbered 75–2232, ninth circuit, and such proceedings have been dismissed with prejudice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> all Native village selections under section 12 of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">section 1611 of this title</ref>] of the lands within Lake Clark, Lake Kontrashibuna, and Mulchatna River deficiency withdrawals have been irrevocably withdrawn and waived.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The conveyances described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be subject to the provisions of section 6(i) of the Alaska Statehood Act (<ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>) [set out as note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions].</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall make the following conveyances to the Region, in accordance with the specific terms, conditions, procedures, covenants, reservations, and other restrictions set forth in the document entitled ‘Terms and Conditions for Land Consolidation and Management in Cook Inlet Area’, which was submitted to the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs on <date date="1975-12-10">December 10, 1975</date>, and clarified on <date date="1976-08-31">August 31, 1976</date>, the terms of which, as clarified, are hereby incorporated herein and ratified as to the duties and obligations of the United States and the Region, as a matter of Federal law.</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> title to approximately 10,240 acres of land within the Kenai National Moose Range; except that there shall be no conveyance of the bed of Lake Tustamena, or the mineral estate in the waterfront zone described in the document referred to in this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> title to oil and gas and coal in not to exceed 9.5 townships within the Kenai National Moose Range;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> title to Federal interests in township 10 south, range 9 west, F.M., and township 20 north, range 9 east, S.M.;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> title to township 1 south, range 21 west, S.M.: sections 3 to 10, 15 to 22, 29, and 30; and rights to metalliferous minerals in the following sections in township 1 north, range 21 west, S.M.: sections 13, 14, 15, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> title to twenty-nine and sixty-six hundredths townships of land outside the boundaries of Cook Inlet Region: unless pursuant to the document referred to in this subsection a greater or lesser entitlement shall exist, in which case the Secretary shall convey such entitlement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> title to lands selected by the Region from a pool which shall be established by the Secretary and the Administrator of General Services: <i>Provided</i>, That conveyances pursuant to this paragraph shall not be subject to the provisions of section 22(<i>l</i>) of the Settlement Act [section 1621(<i>l</i>) of this title]: <i>Provided further</i>, That conveyances pursuant to this paragraph shall be made in exchange for lands or rights to select lands outside the boundaries of Cook Inlet Region as described in paragraph (5) of this subsection and on the basis of values determined by agreement among the parties, notwithstanding any other provision of law. Effective upon their conveyance, the lands referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection are excluded from the Kenai National Moose Range, but they shall automatically become part of the range and subject to the laws and regulations applicable thereto upon title thereafter vesting in the United States. The Secretary is authorized to acquire lands formerly within the range with the concurrence of the Region so long as the Region owns such lands. Section 22(e) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1621/e">section 1621(e) of this title</ref>], concerning refuge replacement, shall apply with respect to lands conveyed pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, except that the Secretary may designate for replacement land twice the amount of any land conveyed without restriction to a native corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Until the obligations of the Secretary and the Administrator of General Services under section 12(b)(5) and (6) of this Act [subsec. (b)(5), (6) of this note] are otherwise fulfilled: (a) Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, may, by using the account established in subsection 12(b)(7)(iv) [subsec. (b)(7)(iv) of this note], bid, as any other bidder for property as defined in subsection 12(b)(7)(vii) [subsec. (b)(7)(vii) of this note],, [sic] wherever located, in accordance with the applicable laws and regulations of the Federal agency or instrumentality offering such property for sale. No preference right of any type will be offered to Cook Inlet Region Incorporated, for bidding on property under this section 12(b)(7) [subsec. (b)(7) of this note]. There shall be no advertising other than that ordinarily required by such sale. [sic] (b) the Administrator of General Services may, at the discretion of the Administrator, tender to the Secretary any surplus property otherwise to be disposed of pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s484/e/3">40 U.S.C. 484(e)(3)</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s545/b">40 U.S.C. 545(b)</ref>] to be offered Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated for a period of 90 days so as to aid in the fulfillment of the Secretary’s program purposes under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [this chapter]: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in these subsections 12(b)(7)(i)(b) or (ii) [subsec. (b)(7)(i)(b) or (ii) of this note] shall be construed to establish, enlarge or diminish authority of the Administrator or the Secretary within the State of Alaska. Prior to any disposition under subsection 12(b)(7)(i)(b) [subsec. (b)(7)(i)(b) of this note], the Administrator shall notify the governing body of the locality where such property is located and any appropriate state agency, and no such disposition shall be made if such governing body or state agency, within ninety days of such notification formally advises the Administrator that it objects to the proposed disposition.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> Subject to the exceptions stated in section 12(b)(9) [subsec. (b)(9) of this note], and notwithstanding the foregoing subsection 12(b)(7)(i) [subsec. (b)(7)(i) of this note] and any provision of any other law or any implementing regulation inconsistent with this subsection, until the obligations of the Secretary and the Administrator of General Services under section 12(b)(5) and (6) [subsec. (b)(5) and (6) of this note] are otherwise fulfilled:</chapeau><level style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> concurrently with the commencement of screening of any excess real property, wherever located, for utilization by Federal agencies, the Administrator of General Services shall notify the Region that such property may be available for conveyance to the Region upon negotiated sale. Within fifteen days of the date of receipt of such notice, the Region may advise the Administrator that there is a tentative need for the property to fulfill the obligations established under section 12(b)(5) and (6) [subsec. (b)(5) and (6) of this note]. If the Administrator determines the property should be disposed of by transfer to the Region, the Administrator or other appropriate Federal official shall promptly transfer such property;</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> no disposition or conveyance of property under this subsection to the Region shall be made until the Administrator, after notice to affected State and local governments, has provided to them such opportunity to obtain the property as is recognized in title 40, United States Code and the regulations thereunder for the disposition or conveyance of surplus property; and</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> as used in this subsection, ‘real property’ means any land or interests in land owned or held by the United States or any Federal agency, any improvements on such land or rights to their use or exploitation, and any personal property related to the land.</content>
</level>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> If the Region accepts any conveyance under section 12(b)(7)(i) or (ii) [subsec. (b)(7)(i) or (ii) of this note], it shall be in exchange for acres or acre-equivalents as provided in subparagraph I(C)(2)(e) of the document referred to in this section, except that, after the obligation of the Secretary and the Administrator under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g) of that document has been fulfilled, the acre-equivalents under subparagraph I(C)(2)(e)(iii)(A) shall be one-half the valued increment therein stated. The entitlement of the Region under section 12(b) of this Act [subsec. (b) of this note] shall be reduced by the number of acres or acre-equivalents attributed to the Region under this subsection. The Secretary and the Administrator are directed to execute an agreement with the Region which shall conform substantially to the ‘Memorandum of Understanding Regarding the Implementation of Section 12(b)(7)’, dated <date date="1982-09-10">September 10, 1982</date>, and submitted to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. The Secretary, the Administrator and the Region may thereafter otherwise agree to procedures to implement responsibilities under this section 12(b)(7) [subsec. (b)(7) of this note], including establishment of accounting procedures and the delegation or reassignment of duties under this statute.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated property account, which shall be available for the purpose of bidding on property, as defined in subsection 12(b)(7)(vii) [subsec. (b)(7)(vii) of this note], or paying for the conveyance of property pursuant to subsections 12(b)(7)(i) or (ii) [subsec. (b)(7)(i), (ii) of this note]. The balance of the account shall be the sum of (1) the acre-equivalent exchange value established by paragraph I(C)(2)(e)(iii)(A) of the document referred to in this subsection, of the unfulfilled entitlement of Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, [on] <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, to acre or acre-equivalents under paragraph I(C)(2)(g) of the document referred to in this subsection 12(b) [subsec. (b) of this note] and (2) one-half the acre or acre-equivalent exchange value under subparagraph I(C)(2)(e)(iii)(A) of seven townships fewer than the unfulfilled entitlement of the Region on the same date to acres or acre-equivalents under paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section. The balance of the property account shall be adjusted in accordance with subsection 12(b)(7)(iii) [subsec. (b)(7)(iii) of this note] to reflect transfers or successful bids under section 12(b)(5) and (6) of this section [subsec. (b)(5) and (6) of this note] or payments of forfeited deposits, penalties, or other assessments imposed under a valid bid or sales contract on Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> The amount charged against the Treasury account established under subsection 12(b)(7)(iv) [subsec. (b)(7)(iv) of this note] for sales or transfers of property made pursuant to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, 40 U.S.C. sec. 471 et seq. [see chapters 1 to 11 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of Title 41, Public Contracts], or any legislative or executive delegation under that Act, shall be treated as proceeds of dispositions of surplus property for the purpose of determining the basis for calculating direct expenses pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s485/b">40 U.S.C. 485(b)</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s572/a">40 U.S.C. 572(a)</ref>], as amended.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> The basis for computing gain or loss on subsequent sale or other disposition of lands or interests in land conveyed to Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, under this subsection, for purposes of any Federal, State or local tax imposed on or measured by income, shall be the fair value of such land or interest in land at the time of receipt. The amount charged against Cook Inlet’s entitlement under I(C)(2)(e) of the document referred to in subsection (b) of this section [subsec. (b) of this note] shall be prima facie evidence of such fair value.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><content> Notwithstanding the definition of ‘property’ found in the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended [see <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s102/9">40 U.S.C. 102(9)</ref>], as used in this section 12(b)(7) [subsec. (b)(7) of this note], ‘property’ means any property—real, personal (including intangible assets sold or offered by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Resolution Trust Corporation, such as financial instruments, notes, loans, and bonds), or mixed—owned, held, or controlled by the United States (including that in a corporate capacity or as a receiver or conservator, or such other similar fiduciary relationship), and offered for sale by any agency or instrumentality of the United States, including but not limited to the General Services Administration, Department of Defense, Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, Department of Housing and Urban Development, the United States Courts and any Government corporation, agency or instrumentality subject to chapter 91 of title 31, United States Code; real property means any land or interest in land or option to purchase land, any improvements on such lands, or rights to their use or exploitation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="viii">“(viii)</num><content> Any charge against the property account and any transfer of funds from the property account heretofore made for the purpose of consummating any prior sale or making a deposit or other payment to bind any contract of sale or paying any forfeiture of deposit, penalty or assessment is hereby authorized, ratified and affirmed.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><chapeau> Subject to the exceptions stated in section 12(b)(9) [subsec. (b)(9) of this note], and notwithstanding any provisions of law or implementing regulation inconsistent with this section:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> The deadlines in subparagraphs I(C)(2)(a) and (g) of the document referred to in this section shall be extended until the Secretary’s obligations under section 12(b)(5) and (6) [subsec. (b)(5) and (6) of this note] are fulfilled: <i>Provided</i>, That:</chapeau><level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the obligation of the Secretary under subparagraph I(C)(2)(a) of such document shall terminate on such date, after <date date="1984-07-15">July 15, 1984</date>, that the Secretary has fulfilled his obligation under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g) of that document: <i>Provided</i>, That the obligation of the Secretary under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g) of such document shall be fulfilled at such date, after <date date="1984-07-15">July 15, 1984</date>, that the sum of the acres or acre-equivalents identified for and placed in the pool and the acres or acre-equivalents used by the Region in purchasing property under section 12(b)(7) [subsec. (b)(7) of this note] equals or exceeds 138,240 acres or acre-equivalents;</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the authority of the Secretary under subparagraphs I(C)(2)(b) and I(C)(2)(g)(ii) of such document to contribute to the pool created under subparagraph I(C)(2)(a) of such document shall terminate (a) on <date date="1984-07-15">July 15, 1984</date>, if, by that date, the Secretary has fulfilled his obligation under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g), or (b) if not, on such date after <date date="1984-07-15">July 15, 1984</date> as such obligation is fulfilled, or (c) if such obligation remains unfulfilled, on <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>;</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the concurrence by the State as described in subparagraphs I(C)(2)(a)(vi) and I(C)(2)(c) of the document referred to in this section shall be deemed not required after the Secretary has fulfilled his obligation under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g) of that document, but in no event after <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>. In lieu of such concurrence, after 1984 as to military property, and after the Secretary has fulfilled his obligation under subparagraph I(C)(2)(g) of that document or <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>, whichever is earlier, as to any other property, except property of the Alaska Railroad which is governed by subsection 12(b)(6)(i)(D) of this Act [probably means subpar. (i)(D) of this paragraph], the Secretary shall not place any lands in the selection pool referred to in subparagraphs I(C)(2)(a) and (g) of the document referred to in this section without the prior written concurrence of the State. Such concurrence shall be deemed obtained unless the State advises the Secretary within ninety days of receipt of a formal notice from the Secretary that he is considering placing property in the selection pool, that the State, or a municipality of the State which includes all or part of the property in question, requires the property for a public purpose of the State or municipality; and</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> notwithstanding section 606(a)(2) of the Alaska Railroad Transfer Act of 1982 [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1205/a/2">section 1205(a)(2) of Title 45</ref>, Railroads], the Secretary may include property of the Alaska Railroad in the pool of lands to be made available for selection to the extent that he is authorized to do so under a provision of section 12(b) of this Act [subsec. (b) of this note] if the State consents to its inclusion, which consent is not subject to any limitation under subsection 12(b)(8)(i)(C) herein: <i>Provided</i>, That, while the Alaska Railroad is the property of the United States, the Secretary shall obtain the consent of the Secretary of Transportation prior to including such property: <i>And provided further</i>, That, if the transfer of the Alaska Railroad to the State does not occur pursuant to the terms of the Alaska Railroad Transfer Act of 1982 [see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1201">section 1201 of Title 45</ref>] or any amendments thereto, the State’s consent shall be deemed obtained unless the State advises the Secretary in writing, within ninety days of receipt of a formal notice from the Secretary that he is considering placing such property in the selection pool, that the State, or a municipality of the State which includes all or part of the property in question, requires the property for a public purpose of the State or the municipality.</content>
</level>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> In addition to the review required to identify public lands under section 3(e) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/e">43 U.S.C. 1602(e)</ref>), the Secretary shall identify for inclusion in the pool all public lands (as such term is used under section 3(e) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/e">43 U.S.C. 1602(e)</ref>), as described in subparagraph I(C)(2)(a)(v) of the document referred to in this section, and shall, in so doing, review all Federal installations within the boundaries of the Cook Inlet Region whether within or without the areas withdrawn pursuant to section 11 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610">43 U.S.C. 1610</ref>) or by the Secretary acting under authority contained in that section: <i>Provided</i>, That no such additional review under such subparagraph shall be required of military installations or of such other installations as may be mutually excluded from review by the Region and the Secretary: <i>And provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall not review any property of the Alaska Railroad unless such property becomes available for selection pursuant to subsection 12(b)(8)(i)(D) [subsec. (b)(8)(i)(D) of this note].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> The concurrence required of the State as to the inclusion of any property in the pool under subparagraph I(C)(2)(b) of the document referred to in this section shall be deemed obtained unless the State advises the Secretary in writing, within ninety days of receipt of a formal notice from the Secretary that the Secretary is considering placing property in the selection pool, that the State, or a municipality of the State which includes all or part of the property in question requires the property for a public purpose of the State or the municipality.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> The deadlines in subparagraph I(C)(1)(b) of the document referred to in this section shall be extended for an additional twenty-four months beyond the dates established in the Act of <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date> (<ref href="/us/pl/96/311">Public Law 96–311</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/94/947">94 Stat. 947</ref>) [amending this note].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><chapeau> On or before <date date="1985-01-15">January 15, 1985</date>, the Secretary shall report to the Congress with respect to:</chapeau><level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such studies and inquiries as shall have been initiated by the Secretary and the Administrator of General Services, or have been prepared by other holding agencies, to determine what lands, except for lands held by the Alaska Railroad or the State-owned railroad, within the boundaries of the Cook Inlet Region or elsewhere can be made available to the Region, to the extent of its entitlement;</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the feasibility and appropriate nature of reimbursement of the Region for its unfulfilled entitlement as valued in subsection 12(b)(7)(iv) of this Act [subsec. (b)(7)(iv) of this note];</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the extent to which implementation of the mechanisms established in section 12(b)(7) [subsec. (b)(7) of this note] promise to meet such unfulfilled entitlement;</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> such other remedial legislation or administrative action as may be needed; and</content>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the need to terminate any mechanism established by law through which the entitlement of the Region may be completed.</content>
</level>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> No disposition or conveyance of property located within the State to the Region under section 12(b)(6), 12(b)(7) and 12(b)(8), as amended [subsec. (b)(6) to (8) of this note], shall be made if the property is subject to an express waiver of rights under the provisions of subparagraph I(C)(2)(f) of the document referred to in this section, or if such disposition or conveyance violates valid rights, including valid selections or valid authorized agreements, of Native Corporations (as such term is used in section 102(6) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3102/6">16 U.S.C. 3102(6)</ref>) or the State existing at the time of such disposition or conveyance under <ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s6">section 6 of Public Law 85–508</ref>, as amended [set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions] (excepting section 906(e) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1635/e">section 1635(e) of this title</ref>]), sections 12(a), 12(b), 16(b) or 22(f) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [subsec. (a) or (b) of this section or section 1615(b) or 1621(f) of this title, respectively], <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12/h">section 12(h) of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/89/1154">89 Stat. 1154</ref>) [subsec. (h) of this note], or sections 1416, 1418 through 1425 (inclusive), 1427 through 1434 (inclusive), or 1436 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [not classified to the Code]: <i>Provided, however</i>, That nothing within this subsection 12(b)(9) [subsec. (b)(9) of this note] shall diminish such rights and priorities as the Region has under <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12/b">section 12(b) of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/89/1151">89 Stat. 1151</ref>), as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1976-10-04/s4">section 4 of the Act of October 4, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/456">Public Law 94–456</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/90/1935">90 Stat. 1935</ref>), <ref href="/us/act/1977-11-15/s3">section 3 of the Act of November 15, 1977</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/95/178">Public Law 95–178</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/91/1369">91 Stat. 1369</ref>), <ref href="/us/act/1979-08-14/s2">section 2 of the Act of August 14, 1979</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/96/55">Public Law 96–55</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/93/386">93 Stat. 386</ref>), the Act of <date date="1980-07-17">July 17, 1980</date> (<ref href="/us/pl/96/311">Public Law 96–311</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/94/947">94 Stat. 947</ref>), and section 1435 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [subsec. (b) of this note].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> For the purpose of its incorporation into this section, paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section is amended as follows: (1) by striking ‘withdrawn’ and inserting in lieu thereof ‘withdrawn or formerly withdrawn’; (2) by striking ‘17(d)(1)’ and inserting in lieu thereof ‘17(d)(1) and (2)’; and (3) by striking the last sentence of subparagraph I(C)(1)(a) and inserting in lieu thereof the following: ‘Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated shall not nominate any lands within the boundaries of any conservation system unit, national conservation area, national recreation area, national forest, defense withdrawal, or any lands that were made available to the State for selection pursuant to sections 2 and 5 of the State-Federal Agreement of <date date="1972-09-01">September 1, 1972</date>.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 906 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1635">section 1635 of this title</ref>] and section 6(i) of the Alaska Statehood Act (<ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>) [set out in a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions];</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The State is hereby authorized to convey to the United States for reconveyance to the Region, and the Secretary is directed to accept and so reconvey, lands tentatively approved for patent or patented to the State, if the State and the Region enter into an agreement that such lands shall be reconveyed to the Region to fulfill all or part of its entitlement under paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section: <i>Provided</i>, That the acreage of lands conveyed to the United States under this provision shall be added to the State’s unfulfilled entitlement pursuant to section 6 of the Alaska Statehood Act, and the number of townships to be nominated, pooled, struck, selected and conveyed pursuant to paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section shall be reduced accordingly.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The Secretary is directed to convey to the Region lands selected by the State prior to <date date="1973-07-18">July 18, 1973</date> or pursuant to sections 2 and 5 of the State-Federal Agreement of <date date="1972-09-01">September 1, 1972</date>, if the State relinquishes such selections and enters into an agreement with the Region that such lands shall be reconveyed to the Region to fulfill all or part of its entitlement under paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section, and the number of townships to be nominated, pooled, struck, selected and conveyed pursuant to paragraph I(C)(1) of the document referred to in this section shall be reduced accordingly.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> The Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, is authorized to enter into an agreement with the State and the Region to implement the authority contained in this section 12(b)(11) [subsec. (b)(11) of this note], which agreement may provide for conveyances directly from the State to the Region. Conveyances directly conveyed shall be deemed conveyances from the Secretary pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The lands and interests conveyed to the Region under the foregoing subsections of this section and the lands provided by the State exchange under subsection (a)(1) of this section, shall be considered and treated as conveyances under the Settlement Act [this chapter] unless otherwise provided, and shall constitute the Region’s full entitlement under sections 12(c) and 14(h)(8) of the Settlement Act [sections 1611(c) and 1613(h)(8) of this title]. Of such lands, 3.58 townships of oil and gas and coal in the Kenai National Moose Range shall constitute the full surface and subsurface entitlement of the Region under section 14(h)(8) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/h/8">section 1613(h)(8) of this title</ref>]. The lands which would comprise the difference in acreage between the lands actually conveyed under and referred to in the foregoing subsections of this section, and any final determination of what the Region’s acreage rights under sections 12(c) and 14(h)(8) of the Settlement Act [sections 1611(c) and 1613(h)(8) of this title] would have been, if the conveyances set forth in this section to the Region had not been executed, shall be retained by the United States and shall not be available for conveyance to any Regional Corporation or Village Corporation, notwithstanding any provisions of the Settlement Act [this chapter] to the contrary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall convey to the State of Alaska all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to all of the following lands:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> At least 22.8 townships and no more than 27 townships of land from those presently withdrawn under section 17(d)(2) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1616/d/2">section 1616(d)(2) of this title</ref>] in the Lake Iliamna area and within the Nushagak River or Koksetana River drainages near lands heretofore selected by the State, the amount and identities of which shall be determined pursuant to the document referred to in subsection (b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> 26 townships of lands in the Talkeetna Mountains, Kamishak Bay, and Tutna Lake areas, the identities of which are set forth in the document referred to in subsection (b).</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">All lands granted to the State of Alaska pursuant to this subsection shall be regarded for all purposes as if conveyed to the State under and pursuant to section 6 of the Alaska Statehood Act [set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions]: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this grant of lands shall not constitute a charge against the total acreage to which the State is entitled under section 6(b) of the Alaska Statehood Act.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized and directed to convey to the State of Alaska, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to all that tract generally known as the Campbell tract and more particularly identified in the document referred to in subsection (b) except for one compact union of land, which he determines, after consultation with the State of Alaska, is actually needed by the Bureau of Land Management for its present operations: <i>Provided</i>, That in no event shall the unit of land so excepted exceed 1,000 acres in size. The land authorized to be conveyed pursuant to this paragraph shall be used for public parks and recreational purposes and other compatible public purposes. An area encompassing approximately sixty-two acres and depicted on the map entitled ‘Native Heritage Park Proposal’ and on file with the Secretary shall be managed in accordance with the generalized land use plan outlined in the Greater Anchorage Area Borough’s Far North Bicentennial Park Master Development Plan of September 1974. Except as provided otherwise in this paragraph, in making the conveyance authorized and required by this paragraph, the Secretary shall utilize the procedures of the Recreation and Public Purposes Act (<ref href="/us/stat/44/741">44 Stat. 741</ref>), as amended [section 869 et seq. of this title], and regulations developed pursuant to that Act, and the conveyance of such lands shall also contain a provision that, if the lands cease to be used for the purposes for which they were conveyed; the lands and title thereto shall revert to the United States: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the acreage limitation provided by section 1(b) of that Act, as amended by the Act of <date date="1954-06-04">June 4, 1954</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/68/173">68 Stat. 173</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s869/b">section 869(b) of this title</ref>], shall not apply to this conveyance, nor shall the lands conveyed pursuant to this paragraph be counted against that acreage limitation with respect to the State of Alaska or any subdivision thereof: <i>Provided further</i>, That to the extent necessary, any and all conveyance documents executed concerning the conveyance of the lands referred to in this proviso shall be deemed amended accordingly to conform to this proviso.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized and directed to make available for selection by the State, in its discretion, under section 6 of the Alaska Statehood Act [set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions], 12.4 townships of land to be selected from lands within the Talkeetna Mountains and Koksetna River area as described in the document referred to in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, convey title to lands and interests in lands selected by Native corporations within the exterior boundaries of Power Site Classification 443, <date date="1958-02-13">February 13, 1958</date>, to such corporations, subject to the reservations required by section 24 of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s818">section 818 of Title 16</ref>, Conservation]. This conveyance shall be considered and treated as a conveyance under the Settlement Act [this chapter].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> All conveyances of lands made or to be made by the State of Alaska in satisfaction of the terms and conditions of the document referred to in subsection (b) of this section shall pass all of the State’s right, title, and interest in such lands, including the minerals therein, as if those conveyances were made pursuant to section 22(f) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1621/f">section 1621(f) of this title</ref>], except that dedicated or platted section line easements and highway and other rights-of-way may be reserved to the State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><content> The Secretary, through the National Park Service, shall provide financial assistance, not to exceed $25,000, hereby authorized to be appropriated, and technical assistance to the Region for the purpose of developing and implementing a land use plan for the west side of Cook Inlet, including an analysis of alternative uses of such lands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><content> Village Corporations within the Cook Inlet Region shall have until <date date="1976-12-18">December 18, 1976</date>, to file selections under section 12(b) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611/b">section 1611(b) of this title</ref>], notwithstanding any provision of that Act to the contrary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall report to the Congress by <date date="1976-04-15">April 15, 1976</date>, on the implementation of this section. If the State fails to agree to engage in a transfer with the Federal Government, pursuant to subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall prior to <date date="1976-12-18">December 18, 1976</date>, make no conveyance of the lands that were to be conveyed to the Region in this section, nor shall he convey prior to such date the Point Campbell, Point Woronzof, and Campbell tracts, so that the Congress is not precluded from fashioning an appropriate remedy. In the event that the State fails to agree as aforesaid, all rights of the Region that may have been extinguished by this section shall be restored.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca5349fe-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conveyance to Koniag, Inc., a Regional Corporation, of the Subsurface Estate of Lands To Be Selected</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/204/s15">Pub. L. 94–204, § 15</ref>, <date date="1976-01-02">Jan. 2, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1154">89 Stat. 1154</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tIX/s911">Pub. L. 96–487, title IX, § 911</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2447">94 Stat. 2447</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/487/tIX/s911">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary shall convey under section 12(a)(1) and 14(f) of the Settlement Act [sections 1611(a)(1) and 1613(f) of this title] to Koniag, Incorporated, a Regional Corporation established pursuant to section 7 of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1606">section 1606 of this title</ref>], such of the subsurface estate, other than title to or the right to remove gravel and common varieties of minerals and materials, as is selected by said corporation from lands withdrawn by Public Land Order 5397 for identification for selection by it located in the following described area:<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" role="listItem" class="indent1">“Township 36 south, range 52 west, all;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" role="listItem" class="indent1">“Township 37 south, range 51 west, all;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 37 south, range 52 west, all;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 37 south, range 53 west, sections 1 through 4, 9 through 16, 21 through 24, and the north half of sections 25 through 28;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 38 south, range 51 west, sections 1 through 5, 9, 10, 12, 13, 18, 24, and 25;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 38 south, range 52 west, sections 1 through 35;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 38 south, range 53 west, sections 1, 12, 13, 24, 25, and 26;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 39 south, range 51 west, sections 1, 6, 7, 16 through 21, 28 through 33, and 36;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 39 south, range 52 west, sections 1, 2, 11 through 15, and 22 through 24;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 39 south, range 53 west, sections 33 through 36, and the south half of section 26;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 40 south, range 51 west, sections 2 and 6;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 40 south, range 52 west, sections 6 through 10, 15 through 21, and 27 through 36;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 40 south, range 53 west, sections 1 through 19, 21 through 28, and 34 through 36;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 40 south, range 54 west, sections 1 through 34;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 41 south, range 52 west, sections 7, 8, 9, 16, 17, and 18;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 41 south, range 53 west, sections 1, 4, 5, 8, 9, 11, 12, and 16;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 41 south, range 54 west, section 6, S. M., Alaska;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Notwithstanding the withdrawal of such lands by Public Land Order 5179, as amended, pursuant to section 17(d)(2) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1616/d/2">section 1616(d)(2) of this title</ref>]: <i>Provided</i>, That notwithstanding the future designation by Congress as part of the National Park System or other national land system referred to in section 17(d)(2)(A) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1616/d/2/A">section 1616(d)(2)(A) of this title</ref>] of the surface estate overlying any subsurface estate conveyed as provided in this section, and with or without such designation, Koniag, Incorporated, shall have such use of the surface estate, including such right of access thereto, as is reasonably necessary to the exploration for and the removal of oil and gas from said subsurface estate, subject to such regulations by the Secretary as are necessary to protect the ecology from permanent harm.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The United States shall make available to Koniag, its successors and assigns, such sand and gravel as is reasonably necessary for the construction of facilities and rights-of-way appurtenant to the exercise of the rights conveyed under this section, pursuant to the provisions of section 601 et seq., title 30, United States Code, and the regulations implementing that statute which are then in effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The subsurface estate in all lands other than those described in subsection (a) within the Koniag Region and withdrawn under section 17(d)(2)(E) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1616/d/2/E">section 1616(d)(2)(E) of this title</ref>], shall not be available for selection by Koniag Region, Incorporated.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca5349ff-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Selection of Lands by Village Corporation of Tatitlek</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/204/s16">Pub. L. 94–204, § 16</ref>, <date date="1976-01-02">Jan. 2, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1155">89 Stat. 1155</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/204/s16">
<inline>“Within ninety days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1976-01-02">Jan. 2, 1976</date>], the corporation created by the enrolled residents of the Village of Tatitlek may file selections upon any of the following described lands: Copper River Meridian</inline>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 9 south, range 3 east, sections 23, 26, 31–35.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 10 south, range 3 east, sections 2–27, 34–36.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 11 south, range 4 east, sections 5, 6, 8, 9, 16, 17, 20–22, 27–29, 33–35.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 9 south, range 3 east, sections 3–6, 9–11.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“Township 9 south, range 3 east, sections 14–16, 21, 22, 27, 28.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Secretary shall receive and adjudicate such selections as though they were timely filed pursuant to section 12(a) or 12(b) of the Settlement Act [section 1611(a) or 1611(b) of this title], and were withdrawn pursuant to section 11 of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1610">section 1610 of this title</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Secretary shall convey such lands selected pursuant to this authorization which otherwise comply with the applicable statutes and regulations. This section shall not be construed to increase the entitlement of the corporation of the enrolled residents of Tatitlek or to increase the amount of land that may be selected from the National Forest System. The subsurface of any land selected pursuant to this section shall be conveyed to the Regional Corporation for the Chugach Region pursuant to section 14(f) of the Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/f">section 1613(f) of this title</ref>].”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
