<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca559359-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1613a"><num value="1613a">§ 1613a.</num><heading> ANCSA amendment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All land and interests in land in the State of Alaska conveyed by the Federal Government under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.) to a Native Corporation and reconveyed by that Native Corporation, or a successor in interest, in exchange for any other land or interest in land in the State of Alaska and located within the same region (as defined in section 9(a) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1608/a">43 U.S.C. 1608(a)</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002119"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should be preceded by an additional closing parenthesis.</note> to a Native Corporation under an exchange or other conveyance, shall be deemed, notwithstanding the conveyance or exchange, to have been conveyed pursuant to that Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca55935a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/221/tI/s102">Pub. L. 109–221, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2006-05-12">May 12, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/337">120 Stat. 337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca55935b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca55935c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca55935d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca55935e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Native American Technical Corrections Act of 2006, and not as part of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
