<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca617a52-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1632"><num value="1632">§ 1632.</num><heading> Statute of limitations on decisions of Secretary and reconveyance of land by Village Corporation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca617a53-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1632/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except for administrative determinations of navigability for purposes of determining ownership of submerged lands under the Submerged Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq., 1311 et seq.], a decision of the Secretary under this chapter or the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.] shall not be subject to judicial review unless such action is initiated before a court of competent jurisdiction within two years after the day the Secretary’s decision becomes final or <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, whichever is later: <i>Provided</i>, That the party seeking such review shall first exhaust any administrative appeal rights.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca617a54-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1632/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Decisions made by a Village Corporation to reconvey land under section 14(c) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/c">43 U.S.C. 1613(c)</ref>] shall not be subject to judicial review unless such action is initiated before a court of competent jurisdiction within one year after the date of the filing of the map of boundaries as provided for in regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca617a55-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tIX/s902">Pub. L. 96–487, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2433">94 Stat. 2433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca617a56-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca617a57-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca617a58-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Submerged Lands Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1953-05-22/ch65">Act May 22, 1953, ch. 65</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/29">67 Stat. 29</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapters I and II (§§ 1301 et seq., 1311 et seq.) of chapter 29 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this title”, meaning title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2430">94 Stat. 2430</ref>, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 1614 and 1620 of this title, and amended provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">section 1611 of this title</ref> and preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. For complete classification of title IX to the code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1601 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
