<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca665c62-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1640"><num value="1640">§ 1640.</num><heading> Relinquishment of selections partly within conservation units</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a valid State or Native selection is partly in and partly out of the boundary of a conservation system unit, notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the State or any Native Corporation may relinquish its rights in any portion of any validly selected Federal land, including land underneath waters, which lies within the boundary of the conservation system unit. Upon relinquishment, the Federal land (including land underneath waters) so relinquished within the boundary of the conservation system unit shall become, and be administered as, a part of the conservation system unit. The total land entitlement of the State or Native Corporation shall not be affected by such relinquishment. In lieu of the lands and waters relinquished by the State, the State may select pursuant to the Alaska Statehood Act as amended by this Act, an equal acreage of other lands available for such purpose. The Native Corporation may retain an equal acreage from overselection lands on which selection applications were otherwise properly and timely filed. A relinquishment pursuant to this section shall not invalidate an otherwise valid State or Native Corporation land selection outside the boundaries of the conservation system unit, on the grounds that, after such relinquishment, the remaining portion of the land selection no longer meets applicable requirements of size, compactness, or contiguity, or that the portion of the selection retained immediately outside the conservation system unit does not follow section lines along the boundary of the conservation system unit. The validity of the selection outside such boundary shall not be adversely affected by the relinquishment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca665c63-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIV/s1415">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIV, § 1415</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2499">94 Stat. 2499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca665c64-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca665c65-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca665c66-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Statehood Act as amended by this Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref> as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2371">96 Stat. 2371</ref>, which is set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca665c67-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref> which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
