<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca665c84-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1651"><num value="1651">§ 1651.</num><heading> Congressional findings and declaration</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca665c85-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1651/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The early development and delivery of oil and gas from Alaska’s North Slope to domestic markets is in the national interest because of growing domestic shortages and increasing dependence upon insecure foreign sources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca665c86-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1651/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Department of the Interior and other Federal agencies, have, over a long period of time, conducted extensive studies of the technical aspects and of the environmental, social, and economic impacts of the proposed trans-Alaska oil pipeline, including consideration of a trans-Canada pipeline.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca665c87-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1651/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The earliest possible construction of a trans-Alaska oil pipeline from the North Slope of Alaska to Port Valdez in that State will make the extensive proven and potential reserves of low-sulfur oil available for domestic use and will best serve the national interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca665c88-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1651/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A supplemental pipeline to connect the North Slope with a trans-Canada pipeline may be needed later and it should be studied now, but it should not be regarded as an alternative for a trans-Alaska pipeline that does not traverse a foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca665c89-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tII/s202">Pub. L. 93–153, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/584">87 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca665c8a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca665c8b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idca665c8c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/380/tVIII/s8001">Pub. L. 101–380, title VIII, § 8001</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/564">104 Stat. 564</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/380/tVIII/s8001">“This title [enacting sections 1642 and 1656 of this title, amending sections 1350 and 1653 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3145">section 3145 of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1653">section 1653 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Trans-Alaska Pipeline System Reform Act of 1990’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idca665c8d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–153, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/584">87 Stat. 584</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/153/tII/s201">“This title [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idca665c8e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 93–153, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/594">87 Stat. 594</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s411">“If any provision of this Act [enacting this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1456a">section 1456a of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3512">section 3512 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1608">section 1608 of this title</ref>, sections 45, 46, 53, and 56 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s185">section 185 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining, <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3502">section 3502 of Title 44</ref>, and section 391a of former Title 46, Shipping, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 1608 and 1651 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1904">section 1904 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking, <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">section 45 of Title 15</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, and <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1221">section 1221 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters] or the applicability thereof is held invalid the remainder of this Act shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca665c8f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Task Force</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/380/tVIII/s8103">Pub. L. 101–380, title VIII, § 8103</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/567">104 Stat. 567</ref>, established a Presidential Task Force on the Trans-Alaska Pipeline System, to conduct an audit of the Trans-Alaska Pipeline System and make recommendations to the President, Congress, and the Governor of Alaska, authorized appropriations for the Task Force, and required it to transmit its final report to the President, Congress, and the Governor no later than 2 years after the date on which funding was made available.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca665c90-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">North Slope Crude Oil; Report on Equitable Allocation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/586/s18">Pub. L. 94–586, § 18</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2916">90 Stat. 2916</ref>, directed that the President, within 6 months of <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, determine special expediting procedures necessary to insure the equitable allocation of North Slope crude oil to the Northern Tier States of Washington, Oregon, Idaho, Montana, Illinois, Indiana, and Idaho to carry out the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/93/153/s410">section 410 of Pub. L. 93–153</ref> [set out below], and to report his findings to Congress, such report to include a statement demonstrating the impact that the delivery system would have on reducing the dependency of New England and the Middle Atlantic States on foreign oil imports.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca665c91-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Trans-Canada Pipeline; Negotiations With Canada; Feasibility Study</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tIII">Pub. L. 93–153, title III</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/588">87 Stat. 588</ref>, authorized the President to enter into negotiations with the Government of Canada to determine Canadian willingness to permit construction of pipelines or other transportation systems across its territory to bring gas and oil from Alaska’s North Slope to the United States; the need for intergovernmental agreements to protect interests of any parties involved with construction, operation, and maintenance of such natural gas or oil transportation systems; terms and conditions for construction across Canadian territory; desirability of joint studies to insure environmental protection, reduce regulatory uncertainty, and insure meeting energy requirements; quantity of oil and gas for which Canada would guarantee transit; and acquisition of other energy sources so as to make unnecessary the shipment of oil from the Alaska pipeline by tanker into the Puget Sound area. The President was to report to Congress on actions taken and recommendations for further action. In addition, the Secretary of the Interior was to investigate, and to report to Congress within 2 years of <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, as to the feasibility of oil or gas pipelines from the North Slope of Alaska to connect with a pipeline through Canada that would deliver oil or gas to United States markets. Nothing in title III was to limit the authority of the Secretary or any other Federal official to grant a gas or oil pipeline right-of-way or permit, which that official was otherwise authorized by law to grant.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca68a682-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exclusion of Persons From Trans-Alaska Pipeline Activities on Basis of Race, Creed, Color, National Origin, or Sex Prohibited</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 93–153, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/590">87 Stat. 590</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s403">“The Secretary of the Interior shall take such affirmative action as he deems necessary to assure that no person shall, on the grounds of race, creed, color, national origin, or sex, be excluded from receiving, or participating in any activity conducted under, any permit, right-of-way, public land order, or other Federal authorization granted or issued under title II [this chapter]. The Secretary of the Interior shall promulgate such rules as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection and may enforce this subsection, and any rules promulgated under this subsection, through agency and department provisions and rules which shall be similar to those established and in effect under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [section 2000d et seq. of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idca68a683-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Equitable Allocation of North Slope Crude Oil</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 93–153, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/594">87 Stat. 594</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s410">“The Congress declares that the crude oil on the North Slope of Alaska is an important part of the Nation’s oil resources, and that the benefits of such crude oil should be equitably shared, directly or indirectly, by all regions of the country. The President shall use any authority he may have to insure an equitable allocation of available North Slope and other crude oil resources and petroleum products among all regions and all of the several States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
