<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca724382-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744"><num value="1744">§ 1744.</num><heading> Recordation of mining claims</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca724383-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The owner of an unpatented lode or placer mining claim located prior to <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, shall, within the three-year period following <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> and prior to December 31 of each year thereafter, file the instruments required by paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection. The owner of an unpatented lode or placer mining claim located after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> shall, prior to December 31 of each year following the calendar year in which the said claim was located, file the instruments required by paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca724384-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> File for record in the office where the location notice or certificate is recorded either a notice of intention to hold the mining claim (including but not limited to such notices as are provided by law to be filed when there has been a suspension or deferment of annual assessment work), an affidavit of assessment work performed thereon, on <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002147">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002147"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “or”.</note> a detailed report provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s28–1">section 28–1 of title 30</ref>, relating thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca724385-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> File in the office of the Bureau designated by the Secretary a copy of the official record of the instrument filed or recorded pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, including a description of the location of the mining claim sufficient to locate the claimed lands on the ground.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca724386-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional filing requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The owner of an unpatented lode or placer mining claim or mill or tunnel site located prior to <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> shall, within the three-year period following <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, file in the office of the Bureau designated by the Secretary a copy of the official record of the notice of location or certificate of location, including a description of the location of the mining claim or mill or tunnel site sufficient to locate the claimed lands on the ground. The owner of an unpatented lode or placer mining claim or mill or tunnel site located after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> shall, within ninety days after the date of location of such claim, file in the office of the Bureau designated by the Secretary a copy of the official record of the notice of location or certificate of location, including a description of the location of the mining claim or mill or tunnel site sufficient to locate the claimed lands on the ground.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca724387-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to file as constituting abandonment; defective or untimely filing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The failure to file such instruments as required by subsections (a) and (b) shall be deemed conclusively to constitute an abandonment of the mining claim or mill or tunnel site by the owner; but it shall not be considered a failure to file if the instrument is defective or not timely filed for record under other Federal laws permitting filing or recording thereof, or if the instrument is filed for record by or on behalf of some but not all of the owners of the mining claim or mill or tunnel site.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca724388-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1744/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Validity of claims, waiver of assessment, etc., as unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such recordation or application by itself shall not render valid any claim which would not be otherwise valid under applicable law. Nothing in this section shall be construed as a waiver of the assessment and other requirements of such law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca724389-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/579/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 94–579, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2769">90 Stat. 2769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
