<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca7bb8c5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770"><num value="1770">§ 1770.</num><heading> Applicability of provisions to other Federal laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7bb8c6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Right-of-way</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective on and after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, no right-of-way for the purposes listed in this subchapter shall be granted, issued, or renewed over, upon, under, or through such lands except under and subject to the provisions, limitations, and conditions of this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting or modifying the provisions of sections 532 to 538 of title 16 and in the event of conflict with, or inconsistency between, this subchapter and sections 532 to 538 of title 16, the latter shall prevail: <i>Provided further</i>, That nothing in this Act should be construed as making it mandatory that, with respect to forest roads, the Secretary of Agriculture limit rights-of-way grants or their term of years or require disclosure pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1761/b">section 1761(b) of this title</ref> or impose any other condition contemplated by this Act that is contrary to present practices of that Secretary under sections 532 to 538 of title 16. Any pending application for a right-of-way under any other law on the effective date of this section shall be considered as an application under this subchapter. The Secretary concerned may require the applicant to submit any additional information he deems necessary to comply with the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7bb8c7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Highway use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to preclude the use of lands covered by this subchapter for highway purposes pursuant to sections 107 and 317 of title 23.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7bb8c8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of antitrust laws</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca7bb8c9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as exempting any holder of a right-of-way issued under this subchapter from any provision of the antitrust laws of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca7bb8ca-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1770/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “antitrust laws” includes the Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date> (26 Stat.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002157"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “209”.</note> <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">15 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.); the Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">15 U.S.C. 12</ref> et seq.); the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.); and sections 73 and 74 of the Act of <date date="1894-08-27">August 27, 1894</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">15 U.S.C. 8</ref>, 9].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca7bb8cb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/579/tV/s510">Pub. L. 94–579, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2782">90 Stat. 2782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca7bb8cc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca7bb8cd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca7bb8ce-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>, known as the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this section, referred to in subsec. (a), probably means the date of enactment of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, which was approved <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-07-02/ch647">act July 2, 1890, ch. 647</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/209">26 Stat. 209</ref>, known as the Sherman Act, which is classified to sections 1 to 7 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">section 1 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date>, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323">act Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>, known as the Clayton Act, which is classified generally to sections 12, 13, 14 to 19, 21, and 22 to 27 of Title 15, and sections 52 and 53 of Title 29, Labor. For further details and complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 73 and 74 of the Act of <date date="1894-08-27">August 27, 1894</date>, referred to in subsec. (c), are sections 73 and 74 of <ref href="/us/act/1894-08-27/ch349">act Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/570">28 Stat. 570</ref>, which are classified to sections 8 and 9 of Title 15.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca7bb8cf-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca7bb8d0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1763">section 1763 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
