<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca7e2a60-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1782"><num value="1782">§ 1782.</num><heading> Bureau of Land Management Wilderness Study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7e2a61-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1782/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Lands subject to review and designation as wilderness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within fifteen years after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, the Secretary shall review those roadless areas of five thousand acres or more and roadless islands of the public lands, identified during the inventory required by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1711/a">section 1711(a) of this title</ref> as having wilderness characteristics described in the Wilderness Act of <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.) and shall from time to time report to the President his recommendation as to the suitability or nonsuitability of each such area or island for preservation as wilderness: <i>Provided</i>, That prior to any recommendations for the designation of an area as wilderness the Secretary shall cause mineral surveys to be conducted by the United States Geological Survey and the United States Bureau of Mines to determine the mineral values, if any, that may be present in such areas: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall report to the President by <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, his recommendations on those areas which the Secretary has prior to <date date="1975-11-01">November 1, 1975</date>, formally identified as natural or primitive areas. The review required by this subsection shall be conducted in accordance with the procedure specified in section 3(d) of the Wilderness Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132/d">16 U.S.C. 1132(d)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7e2a62-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1782/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential recommendation for designation as wilderness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall advise the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives of his recommendations with respect to designation as wilderness of each such area, together with a map thereof and a definition of its boundaries. Such advice by the President shall be given within two years of the receipt of each report from the Secretary. A recommendation of the President for designation as wilderness shall become effective only if so provided by an Act of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca7e2a63-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1782/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Status of lands during period of review and determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During the period of review of such areas and until Congress has determined otherwise, the Secretary shall continue to manage such lands according to his authority under this Act and other applicable law in a manner so as not to impair the suitability of such areas for preservation as wilderness, subject, however, to the continuation of existing mining and grazing uses and mineral leasing in the manner and degree in which the same was being conducted on <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That, in managing the public lands the Secretary shall by regulation or otherwise take any action required to prevent unnecessary or undue degradation of the lands and their resources or to afford environmental protection. Unless previously withdrawn from appropriation under the mining laws, such lands shall continue to be subject to such appropriation during the period of review unless withdrawn by the Secretary under the procedures of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1714">section 1714 of this title</ref> for reasons other than preservation of their wilderness character. Once an area has been designated for preservation as wilderness, the provisions of the Wilderness Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.] which apply to national forest wilderness areas shall apply with respect to the administration and use of such designated area, including mineral surveys required by section 4(d)(2) of the Wilderness Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1133/d/2">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(2)</ref>], and mineral development, access, exchange of lands, and ingress and egress for mining claimants and occupants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca7e2a64-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/579/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 94–579, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2785">90 Stat. 2785</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/154/tI">Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1000">105 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/172">106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca7e2a65-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca7e2a66-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca7e2a67-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilderness Act of <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date>, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/577">Pub. L. 88–577</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">section 1131 of Title 16</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>, known as the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca7e2a68-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idca7e2a69-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Geological Survey” substituted for “Geological Survey” in subsec. (a) pursuant to provision of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/102/154">Pub. L. 102–154</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Bureau of Mines” substituted for “Bureau of Mines” in subsec. (a) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">section 10(b) of Pub. L. 102–285</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining. For provisions relating to closure and transfer of functions of the United States Bureau of Mines, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/c/tI">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-156">110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–165; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">“That the authority granted to the United States Bureau of Mines to conduct mineral surveys and to determine mineral values by <ref href="/us/pl/94/579/s603">section 603 of Public Law 94–579</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1782">43 U.S.C. 1782</ref>] is hereby transferred to, and vested in, the Director of the United States Geological Survey.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
