<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca82e572-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842"><num value="1842">§ 1842.</num><heading> Fishermen’s Contingency Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca82e573-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; availability; source of deposits; limitation on amount; interest-bearing accounts; litigation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e574-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> There is established in the Treasury of the United States a Fishermen’s Contingency Fund. The Fund shall be available to the Secretary without fiscal year limitations as a revolving fund for the purpose of making payments pursuant to this section. The Fund shall consist of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e575-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> revenues received from investments made under paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e576-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> amounts collected under subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e577-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> amounts recovered by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1845/h/2">section 1845(h)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The total amount in the Fund that is collected under subsection (b) may at no time exceed $2,000,000; and the total amount in the Fund which is attributable to revenue received under paragraph (3) or recovered by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1845/h/2">section 1845(h)(2) of this title</ref> shall be expended prior to amounts collected under subsection (b). Not more than 8 percent of the total amount in the Fund may be expended in any fiscal year for paying the administrative and personnel expenses referred to in paragraph (2)(A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e578-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Fund shall be available, as provided for in appropriation Acts solely for the payment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e579-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the personnel and administrative expenses incurred in carrying out this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e57a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any claim, in accordance with procedures established under this section, for damages that are compensable under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca82e57b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> attorney and other fees awarded under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1845/e">section 1845(e) of this title</ref> with respect to any such claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e57c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Sums in the Fund that are not currently needed for the purposes of the Fund shall be kept on deposit in appropriate interest-bearing accounts that shall be established by the Secretary of the Treasury or invested in obligations of, or guaranteed by, the United States. Any revenue accruing from such deposits and investments shall be deposited into the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e57d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Fund may sue and be sued in its own name. All litigation by or against the Fund shall be referred to the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca82e57e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments by each holder of lease, permit, easement, or right-of-way</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e57f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), each holder of a lease that is issued or maintained under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.] and each holder of an exploration permit, or an easement or right-of-way for the construction of a pipeline in any area of the Outer Continental Shelf, shall pay an amount specified by the Secretary. The Secretary of the Interior shall collect such amount and deposit it into the Fund. In any calendar year, no holder of a lease, permit, easement, or right-of-way shall be required to pay an amount in excess of $5,000 per lease, permit, easement, or right-of-way.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca82e580-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1842/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Payments may not be required under paragraph (1) by the Secretary of the Interior with respect to geological permits and geophysical permits, other than prelease exploratory drilling permits issued under section 11 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1340">43 U.S.C. 1340</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca82e581-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 95–372, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/686">92 Stat. 686</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/212/s2">Pub. L. 97–212, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-06-30">June 30, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/143">96 Stat. 143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca82e582-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca82e583-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca82e584-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345">act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1331 et seq.) of chapter 29 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idca82e585-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> redesignated subsec. (a) as subsec. (a)(1) and substituted provisions relating to the source of funds, that the total amount of the Fund would not exceed $2,000,000, that the total amount in the Fund which is attributable to revenue received under par. (3) as amended or recovered by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1845/h/2">section 1845(h)(2) of this title</ref> be expended prior to amounts collected under subsec. (b) as amended, and that not more than 8 percent of the total amount in the Fund be expended in any fiscal year for the paying of administrative and personnel expenses, for provisions that the amounts paid pursuant to former subsecs. (c) and (d) of this section be deposited in the Fund, and that the total amount in the Fund not exceed $1,000,000, redesignated as subsec. (a)(2) former subsec. (e), and struck out provision that the amounts disbursed for administrative or personnel expenses not exceed 15 percent of the amounts deposited in a revolving account for that fiscal year, added as subsec. (a)(3) provisions that the sums of the Fund be kept on deposit in interest-bearing accounts, and added as subsec. (a)(4) provision that all litigation be referred to the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> redesignated as subsec. (b)(1) provisions of former subsec. (c) and added as subsec. (b)(2) provision that payments not be required under par. (1) by the Secretary of the Interior with respect to geological and geophysical permits other than prelease exploratory drilling permits issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1340">section 1340 of this title</ref>. Former subsec. (b) relating to the establishment and maintenance of an area account within the Fund was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> redesignated subsec. (c) as (b)(1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> struck out subsec. (d) which related to level of area account funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (a)(2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idca82e586-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idca82e587-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/212">Pub. L. 97–212</ref> applicable with respect to claims for damages filed on or after <date date="1982-06-30">June 30, 1982</date>, with the Secretary of Commerce under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1845/a">section 1845(a) of this title</ref>, with provision for the refiling of previously filed claims under certain circumstances, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/212/s9">section 9 of Pub. L. 97–212</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1841">section 1841 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
