<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca8555d3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862"><num value="1862">§ 1862.</num><heading> Natural gas distribution</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca8555d4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Expanded participation by local distribution companies in acquisition of leases and development of natural gas resources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to encourage expanded participation by local distribution companies in acquisition of leases and development of natural gas resources on the Outer Continental Shelf by facilitating the transportation in interstate commerce of natural gas, which is produced from a lease located on the Outer Continental Shelf and owned, in whole or in part, by a local distribution company, from such lease to the service area of such local distribution company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca8555d5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application and issuance of certificates of public convenience and necessity for transportation of natural gas</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall, after opportunity for presentation of written and oral views, promulgate and publish in the Federal Register a statement of Commission policy which carries out the purpose of this section and sets forth the standards under which the Commission will consider applications for, and, as appropriate, issue certificates of public convenience and necessity, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s717f">section 717f of title 15</ref>, for the transportation in interstate commerce of natural gas, which is produced from a lease located on the Outer Continental Shelf and owned, in whole or in part, by a local distribution company, from such lease to the service area of such local distribution company. Such statement of policy shall specify the criteria, limitations, or requirements the Commission will apply in determing— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002169">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002169"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “determining—”.</note></chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca8555d6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> whether the application of any local distribution company qualifies for consideration under the statement of policy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca8555d7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> whether the public convenience and necessity will be served by the issuance of the requested certificate of transportation.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such statement of policy shall also set forth the terms or limitations on which the Commission may condition, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s717f">section 717f of title 15</ref>, the issuance of a certificate of transportation under such statement of policy. To the maximum extent practicable, such statement shall be promulgated and published within one year after <date date="1978-09-18">September 18, 1978</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca8555d8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca8555d9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “local distribution company” means any person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca8555da-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> engaged in the distribution of natural gas at retail, including any subsidiary or affiliate thereof engaged in the exploration and production of natural gas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idca8555db-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> regulated, or operated as a public utility, by a State or local government or agency thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca8555dc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “interstate commerce” shall have the same meaning as such term has under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s717a/7">section 717a(7) of title 15</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca8555dd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1862/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “Commission” means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca8555de-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 95–372, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/694">92 Stat. 694</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
