<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca8555df-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1863"><num value="1863">§ 1863.</num><heading> Unlawful employment practices; regulations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each agency or department given responsibility for the promulgation or enforcement of regulations under this chapter or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> et seq.] shall take such affirmative action as deemed necessary to prohibit all unlawful employment practices and to assure that no person shall, on the grounds of race, creed, color, national origin, or sex, be excluded from receiving or participating in any activity, sale, or employment, conducted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. The agency or department shall promulgate such rules as it deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, and any rules promulgated under this section, whether through agency and department provisions or rules, shall be similar to those established and in effect under title VI and title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq., 2000e et seq.].</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca8555e0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/372/tVI/s604">Pub. L. 95–372, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/695">92 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca8555e1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca8555e2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca8555e3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/372">Pub. L. 95–372</ref>, <date date="1978-09-18">Sept. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/629">92 Stat. 629</ref>, known as the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act Amendments of 1978, which enacted this chapter, sections 1344 to 1356 of this title, and <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s237">section 237 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining, amended sections 1331 to 1334, 1337, 1340, and 1343 of this title, sections 1456, 1456a, and 1464 of Title 16, Conservation, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6213">section 6213 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1348 and 1811 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-07/ch345">act Aug. 7, 1953, ch. 345</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/462">67 Stat. 462</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1331 et seq.) of chapter 29 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Civil Rights Act of 1964, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/88/352">Pub. L. 88–352</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/241">78 Stat. 241</ref>. Title VI and VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 are classified generally to subchapters V (§ 2000d et seq.) and VI (§ 2000e et seq.) of chapter 21 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000a">section 2000a of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
