<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca87a027-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s1905"><num value="1905">§ 1905.</num><heading> Grazing fees; economic value of use of land; fair market value components; annual percentage change limitation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the grazing years 1979 through 1985, the Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall charge the fee for domestic livestock grazing on the public rangelands which Congress finds represents the economic value of the use of the land to the user, and under which Congress finds fair market value for public grazing equals the $1.23 base established by the 1966 Western Livestock Grazing Survey multiplied by the result of the Forage Value Index (computed annually from data supplied by the Economic Research Service) added to the Combined Index (Beef Cattle Price Index minus the Price Paid Index) and divided by 100: <i>Provided</i>, That the annual increase or decrease in such fee for any given year shall be limited to not more than plus or minus 25 per centum of the previous year’s fee.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca87a028-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/514/s6/a">Pub. L. 95–514, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1806">92 Stat. 1806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca87a029-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca87a02a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idca87a02b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12548. Grazing Fees</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12548, <date date="1986-02-14">Feb. 14, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 5985, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and laws of the United States of America, and in order to provide for establishment of appropriate fees for the grazing of domestic livestock on public rangelands, it is ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Determination of Fees</i>. The Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior are directed to exercise their authority, to the extent permitted by law under the various statutes they administer, to establish fees for domestic livestock grazing on the public rangelands which annually equals the $1.23 base established by the 1966 Western Livestock Grazing Survey multiplied by the result of the Forage Value Index (computed annually from data supplied by the Statistical Reporting Service) added to the Combined Index (Beef Cattle Price Index minus the Prices Paid Index) and divided by 100; <i>provided</i>, that the annual increase or decrease in such fee for any given year shall be limited to not more than plus or minus 25 percent of the previous year’s fee, and <i>provided further</i>, that the fee shall not be less than $1.35 per animal unit month.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Definitions</i>. As used in this Order, the term:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) “Public rangelands” has the same meaning as in the Public Rangelands Improvement Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/pl/95/514">Public Law 95–514</ref>) [this chapter];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) “Forage Value Index” means the weighted average estimate of the annual rental charge per head per month for pasturing cattle on private rangelands in the 11 Western States (Montana, Idaho, Wyoming, Colorado, New Mexico, Arizona, Utah, Nevada, Washington, Oregon, and California) (computed by the Statistical Reporting Service from the June Enumerative Survey) divided by $3.65 and multiplied by 100;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) “Beef Cattle Price Index” means the weighted average annual selling price for beef cattle (excluding calves) in the 11 Western States (Montana, Idaho, Wyoming, Colorado, New Mexico, Arizona, Utah, Nevada, Washington, Oregon, and California) for November through October (computed by the Statistical Reporting Service) divided by $22.04 per hundred weight and multiplied by 100; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) “Prices Paid Index” means the following selected components from the Statistical Reporting Service’s Annual National Index of Prices Paid by Farmers for Goods and Services adjusted by the weights indicated in parentheses to reflect livestock production costs in the Western States: 1. Fuels and Energy (14.5); 2. Farm and Motor Supplies (12.0); 3. Autos and Trucks (4.5); 4. Tractors and Self-Propelled Machinery (4.5); 5. Other Machinery (12.0); 6. Building and Fencing Materials (14.5); 7. Interest (6.0); 8. Farm Wage Rates (14.0); 9. Farm Services (18.0).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. Any and all existing rules, practices, policies, and regulations relating to the administration of the formula for grazing fees in section 6(a) of the Public Rangelands Improvement Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1905">43 U.S.C. 1905</ref>] shall continue in full force and effect.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. This Order shall be effective immediately.</p>
<signature>
<name>Ronald Reagan.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
