<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca87a082-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007"><num value="2007">§ 2007.</num><heading> Decision of President</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca87a083-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Decision concerning approval or disapproval of proposed systems</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca87a084-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> After reviewing all the information submitted to him concerning the various proposed crude oil transportation systems eligible for consideration under this chapter (including environmental impact statements, comments, reports, recommendations, and other information submitted to him at any time before he makes his decision) and after consulting the Secretaries of Energy, the Interior, and Transportation, the President shall decide which, if any, of such systems shall be approved for the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s2008">section 2008 of this title</ref> (relating to procedures for waiver of law), <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s2009">section 2009 of this title</ref> (relating to expedited procedures for issuance of permits), <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s2010">section 2010 of this title</ref> (relating to negotiations with the Government of Canada), and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> (relating to judicial review). A decision approving a crude oil transportation system may include such modifications and alterations in such system as the President finds appropriate. The President shall issue his decision within 45 days after receiving recommendations and comments submitted to him under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s2005/c">section 2005(c) of this title</ref>, except that the President, for such period as he deems necessary, but not to exceed 60 days, may delay his decision and its issuance if he determines that additional time is otherwise necessary to enable him to make a decision. If the President so delays his decision, he shall promptly notify the House of Representatives and the Senate of such delay and shall submit a full explanation of the basis for such delay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca87a085-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any decision made under this subsection approving a system proposed under this chapter shall include a determination that construction and operation of such system is in the national interest and shall be based upon the criteria specified in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca87a086-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca87a087-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The criteria for making a decision under this subsection shall include findings of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a088-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> environmental impacts of the proposed systems and the capability of such systems to minimize environmental risks resulting from transportation of crude oil;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a089-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of crude oil available to northern tier States and inland States and the projected demand in those States under each of such systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> transportation costs and delivered prices of crude oil by region under each of such systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> construction schedules for each of such systems and possibilities for delay in such schedules;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> feasibility of financing for each of such systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> capital and operating costs of each of such systems, including an analysis of the reliability of cost estimates and the risk of cost overruns;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> net national economic costs and benefits of each such system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a08f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> the extent to which each system complies with the provisions of section 410 of the Act approved <date date="1973-11-16">November 16, 1973</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/87/594">87 Stat. 594</ref>), commonly known as the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a090-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the effect of each such system on international relations, including the status and time schedule for any necessary Canadian approvals and plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a091-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> impact upon competition by each system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a092-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> degree of safety and efficiency of design and operation of each system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a093-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> potential for interruption of deliveries of crude oil from the west coast under each such system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a094-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> capacity and cost of expanding such system to transport additional volumes of crude oil in excess of initial system capacity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a095-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><content> national security considerations under each such system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a096-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> relationship of each such system to national energy policy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idca87a097-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/1/P"><num value="P">(P)</num><content> such other factors as the President deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idca87a098-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The period of time for which such findings shall be made shall be the useful life of the crude oil transportation system involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idca87a099-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s2007/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of findings and decision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall make available to the public at the time of issuance of a decision under this section a written statement setting forth findings with respect to each of the criteria specified in subsection (b) and describing the nature and route of crude oil transportation systems, if any, which are approved in the decision. If the President’s decision is to approve a system, each statement shall set forth his reasons for approving such system over other proposed systems (if any) eligible for consideration under this chapter. Such statement along with notification of such decision shall be published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idca87a09a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tV/s507">Pub. L. 95–617, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3160">92 Stat. 3160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca87a09b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca87a09c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca87a09d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 410 of the Act approved <date date="1973-11-16">November 16, 1973</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/87/594">87 Stat. 594</ref>), commonly known as the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(H), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/153/s410">section 410 of Pub. L. 93–153</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/594">87 Stat. 594</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1651">section 1651 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
