<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9bcfcd4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s315f"><num value="315f">§ 315f.</num><heading> Homestead entry within district or withdrawn lands; classification; preferences</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion, to examine and classify any lands withdrawn or reserved by Executive order of <date date="1934-11-26">November 26, 1934</date> (numbered 6910), and amendments thereto, and Executive order of <date date="1935-02-05">February 5, 1935</date> (numbered 6964), or within a grazing district, which are more valuable or suitable for the production of agricultural crops than for the production of native grasses and forage plants, or more valuable or suitable for any other use than for the use provided for under this subchapter or proper for acquisition in satisfaction of any outstanding lieu, exchange or script <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002007"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “scrip”.</note> rights or land grant, and to open such lands to entry, selection, or location for disposal in accordance with such classification under applicable public-land laws, except that homestead entries shall not be allowed for tracts exceeding three hundred and twenty acres in area. Such lands shall not be subject to disposition, settlement, or occupation until after the same have been classified and opened to entry: <i>Provided</i>, That locations and entries under the mining laws including the Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s181">30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], may be made upon such withdrawn and reserved areas without regard to classification and without restrictions or limitation by any provision of this subchapter. Where such lands are located within grazing districts reasonable notice shall be given by the Secretary of the Interior to any grazing permittee of such lands. The applicant, after his entry, selection, or location is allowed, shall be entitled to the possession and use of such lands: <i>Provided</i>, That upon the application of any applicant qualified to make entry, selection, or location, under the public-land laws, filed in the land office of the proper district, the Secretary of the Interior shall cause any tract to be classified, and such application, if allowed by the Secretary of the Interior, shall entitle the applicant to a preference right to enter, select, or locate such lands if opened to entry as herein provided.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9bcfcd5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-28/ch865/s7">June 28, 1934, ch. 865, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1272">48 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-26/ch842">June 26, 1936, ch. 842</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1976">49 Stat. 1976</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9bcfcd6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9bcfcd7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9bcfcd8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1920-02-25">February 25, 1920</date>, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1920-02-25/ch85">act Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/437">41 Stat. 437</ref>, as amended, known as the Mineral Leasing Act, which is classified generally to chapter 3A (§ 181 et seq.) of Title 30. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s181">section 181 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9bcfcd9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1936—Act <date date="1936-06-26">June 26, 1936</date>, amended section generally.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
