<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9bcfcf5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s315l"><num value="315l">§ 315l.</num><heading> Lands under national-forest administration</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States is authorized to reserve by proclamation and place under national-forest administration in any State where national forests may be created or enlarged by Executive order any unappropriated public lands lying within watersheds forming a part of the national forests which, in his opinion, can best be administered in connection with existing national-forest administration units, and to place under the Interior Department administration any lands within national forests, principally valuable for grazing, which, in his opinion, can best be administered under the provisions of this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That such reservations or transfers shall not interfere with legal rights acquired under any public-land laws so long as such rights are legally maintained. Lands placed under the national-forest administration under the authority of this subchapter shall be subject to all the laws and regulations relating to national forests, and lands placed under the Interior Department administration shall be subject to all public-land laws and regulations applicable to grazing districts created under authority of this subchapter. Nothing in this section shall be construed so as to limit the powers of the President (relating to reorganizations in the executive departments) granted by sections 124 to 132 of title 5.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002009"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9bcfcf6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-28/ch865/s13">June 28, 1934, ch. 865, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1274">48 Stat. 1274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9bcfcf7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9bcfcf8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9bcfcf9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 124 to 132 of title 5, referred to in text, was in the original “title 4 of the Act entitled ‘An Act making appropriations for the Treasury and Post Office Departments for the fiscal year ending <date date="1934-06-30">June 30, 1934</date>, and for other purposes’, approved <date date="1933-03-03">March 3, 1933</date>”, meaning Title IV of Part II (§§ 401–409) of the Legislative Appropriation Act, fiscal year 1933, as amended generally by section 16 of <ref href="/us/act/1933-03-03/ch212">act Mar. 3, 1933, ch. 212</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/1517">47 Stat. 1517</ref>, which was classified to sections 124 to 132 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees. Sections 124 to 131 of former Title 5 were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and section 132 of former Title 5 was omitted as executed pursuant to its own terms.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
