<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9bf6e3e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s316"><num value="316">§ 316.</num><heading> Declaration of policy</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is declared to be the policy of Congress in promoting the conservation of the natural resources of Alaska to provide for the protection and development of forage plants and for the beneficial utilization thereof for grazing by livestock under such regulations as may be considered necessary and consistent with the purposes and provisions of this subchapter. In effectuating this policy the use of these lands for grazing shall be subordinated (a) to the development of their mineral resources, (b) to the protection, development, and utilization of their forests, (c) to the protection, development, and utilization of their water resources, (d) to their use for agriculture, and (e) to the protection, development, and utilization of such other resources as may be of greater benefit to the public.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9bf6e3f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch513/s1">Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 513, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1452">44 Stat. 1452</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9bf6e40-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9bf6e41-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9bf6e42-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s471">section 471 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idc9bf6e43-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch513">Act Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 513</ref>, which is classified to this subchapter, is popularly known as the “Alaska Livestock Grazing Act”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
