<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9c8e3fd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s377b"><num value="377b">§ 377b.</num><heading> Availability of appropriations for Bureau of Reclamation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation in this Act or in subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts shall on and after <date date="1992-10-02">October 2, 1992</date>, be available for payment of claims for damages to or loss of property, personal injury, or death arising out of activities of the Bureau of Reclamation, not to exceed $5,000,000 for each causal event giving rise to a claim or claims; payment, except as otherwise provided for, of compensation and expenses of persons on the rolls of the Bureau of Reclamation appointed as authorized by law to represent the United States in the negotiations and administration of interstate compacts without reimbursement or return under the reclamation laws; services as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>, in total not to exceed $500,000 per year; rewards for information or evidence concerning violations of law involving property under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Reclamation; performance of the functions specified under the head “Operation and Maintenance Administration”, Bureau of Reclamation, in the Interior Department Appropriations Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002014"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> 1945; preparation and dissemination of useful information including recordings, photographs, and photographic prints; and studies of recreational uses of reservoir areas, and investigation and recovery of archeological and paleontological remains in such areas in the same manner as provided for in chapters 3125 and 3201 of title 54: <i>Provided</i>, That on and after <date date="1992-10-02">October 2, 1992</date>, no part of any appropriation made in this Act or in subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts shall be available pursuant to the Act of <date date="1945-04-19">April 19, 1945</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s377">43 U.S.C. 377</ref>), for expenses other than those incurred on behalf of specific reclamation projects except “General Administrative Expenses”, amounts provided for plan formulation investigations under the head “General Investigations”, and amounts provided for science and technology under the head “Construction Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Sums appropriated in this Act or in subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts which are expended in the performance of reimbursable functions of the Bureau of Reclamation shall be returnable to the extent and in the manner provided by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No part of any appropriation for the Bureau of Reclamation, contained in this Act, in any prior Act, or in subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts which represents amounts earned under the terms of a contract but remaining unpaid, shall be obligated for any other purpose, regardless of when such amounts are to be paid: <i>Provided</i>, That the incurring of any obligation prohibited by this paragraph shall be deemed a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1341">section 1341 of title 31</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">None of the funds made available by this or any other Act or by any subsequent Act shall on and after <date date="1992-10-02">October 2, 1992</date>, be used by the Bureau of Reclamation for contracts for surveying and mapping services unless such contracts for which a solicitation is issued after the date of this Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002015"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> are awarded in accordance with title IX of the Federal Property and Administrative Service <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002016"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “Services”.</note> Act of 1949.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">2</ref></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9c8e3fe-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/377/tII">Pub. L. 102–377, title II</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1330">106 Stat. 1330</ref>, 1331; <ref href="/us/pl/108/137/tII/s206">Pub. L. 108–137, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2003-12-01">Dec. 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1849">117 Stat. 1849</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3270">128 Stat. 3270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9c8e3ff-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9c8e400-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9c8e401-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Interior Department Appropriations Act 1945, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1944-06-28/ch298">act June 28, 1944, ch. 298</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/463">58 Stat. 463</ref>, which is not classified to the Code. The heading “Operation and maintenance administration” appears at <ref href="/us/stat/58/487">58 Stat. 487</ref> following the heading “Bureau of Reclamation” which appears at <ref href="/us/stat/58/486">58 Stat. 486</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1945-04-19">April 19, 1945</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s377">43 U.S.C. 377</ref>), referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1945-04-19/ch80">act April 19, 1945, ch. 80</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/54">59 Stat. 54</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s377">section 377 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of this Act, referred to in text, probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/102/377">Pub. L. 102–377</ref>, which enacted this section, and which was approved <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1949-06-30/ch288">act June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/377">63 Stat. 377</ref>. Title IX of the Act, which was classified generally to subchapter VI (§ 541 et seq.) of chapter 10 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, was repealed and reenacted by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, §§ 1, 6(b), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>, 1304, as chapter 11 (§ 1101 et seq.) of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. For disposition of sections of former Title 40 to revised Title 40, see Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s101">section 101 of Title 40</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9c8e402-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of the second, third, fourth, and sixth undesignated pars. under headings “<inline class="small-caps">Bureau of Reclamation</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">administrative provisions</inline>” in title II of <ref href="/us/pl/102/377">Pub. L. 102–377</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1330">106 Stat. 1330</ref>, 1331.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9c8e403-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, which directed that the second paragraph under the heading “administrative provisions” under the heading “Bureau of Reclamation” (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s377b">43 U.S.C. 377b</ref>), be amended by substituting “chapters 3125 and 3201 of title 54” for “the Acts of <date date="1935-08-21">August 21, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s461–467">16 U.S.C. 461–467</ref>) and June 27 1960 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s469">16 U.S.C. 469</ref>)” without specifying a public law, was executed by making the substitution for “the Acts of <date date="1935-08-21">August 21, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s461–467">16 U.S.C. 461–467</ref>) and <date date="1960-06-27">June 27, 1960</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s469">16 U.S.C. 469</ref>)” in the first paragraph of this section, which is the second undesignated par. under the headings “<inline class="small-caps">Bureau of Reclamation</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">administrative provisions</inline>” in title II of <ref href="/us/pl/102/377">Pub. L. 102–377</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1330">106 Stat. 1330</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/137">Pub. L. 108–137</ref> inserted in first par. “, not to exceed $5,000,000 for each causal event giving rise to a claim or claims” after “activities of the Bureau of Reclamation”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9c8e404-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9c8e405-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Operations and Maintenance Costs of Certain Bureau of Reclamation Dams and Dikes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tIV/s4309">Pub. L. 115–270, title IV, § 4309</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3889">132 Stat. 3889</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLIX/s5944">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5944</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3472">136 Stat. 3472</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLIX/s5944">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), effective during the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Federal share of the dam safety modifications costs of a dam or dike described in subsection (b), including repairing or replacing a gate or ancillary gate components, shall be 100 percent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Description of Dams and Dikes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A dam or dike referred to in subsection (a) is a dam or dike—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> that is owned by the Bureau of Reclamation on the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the construction of which was completed not later than <date date="1948-12-31">December 31, 1948</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a corrective action study for which was completed not later than <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the construction of which was authorized by the Act of <date date="1938-06-28">June 28, 1938</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/1215">52 Stat. 1215</ref>, chapter 795).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
