<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9c8e424-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s384"><num value="384">§ 384.</num><heading> Extension of time for payment of charges accrued prior to <date date="1924-03-02">March 2, 1924</date>, and <date date="1925-01-01">January 1, 1925</date></heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc9c8e425-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s384/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and empowered, in his discretion, to defer the dates of payments of any charges, rentals, and penalties which have accrued prior to the 2d day of March, 1924, under the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>), and amendatory and supplemental acts or prior to that date, as against water users on any irrigation project being constructed or operated and maintained under the direction of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, as may, in his judgment, be necessary in or concerning any irrigation project existing on <date date="1924-05-09">May 9, 1924</date>, under said act: <i>Provided</i>, That no payment shall be deferred under this section in any particular case beyond <date date="1927-03-01">March 1, 1927</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That upon such adjustment being made, any penalties or interest which may have accrued in connection with such unpaid construction and operation and maintenance charges shall be canceled, and in lieu thereof the amount so due, and the payment of which is hereby extended, shall draw interest at the rate of 5 per centum per annum, paid annually from the time said amount became due to date of payment: <i>And provided further</i>, That in case the principal and interest herein provided for are not paid in the manner and at the time provided by this section, any penalty provided by the law in effect on <date date="1924-05-09">May 9, 1924</date>, shall thereupon attach from the date of such default.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc9c8e426-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s384/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Where an individual water user, or individual applicant for a water right under a Federal irrigation project constructed or being constructed under the Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>), or any act amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto, makes application prior to <date date="1925-01-01">January 1, 1925</date>, alleging that he will be unable to make the payments as required in subsection (a) hereof, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized in his discretion prior to <date date="1925-03-01">March 1, 1925</date>, to add such accrued and unpaid charges to the construction charge of the land of such water user or applicant, and to distribute such accumulated charges equally over each of the subsequent years, beginning with the year 1925, or, in the discretion of the Secretary, distribute a total of one-fourth over the first half of the remaining years of the 20-year period beginning with the year 1925, and three-fourths over the second half of such period, so as to complete the payment during the remaining years of the 20-year period of payment of the original construction charge: <i>Provided</i>, That upon such adjustment being made, any penalties or interest which may have accrued in connection with such unpaid construction and operation and maintenance charges shall be canceled, and in lieu thereof the amount so due, and the payment of which is extended, shall draw interest at the rate of 5 per centum per annum, paid annually from the time said amount became due to the date of payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the applicant for the extension shall first show to the satisfaction of the Secretary of the Interior detailed statement of his assets and liabilities and probable inability to make payment at the time required in subsection (a): <i>And provided further</i>, That in case the principal and interest herein provided for are not paid in the manner and at the time provided by this section, any penalty provided by law, prior to <date date="1924-05-09">May 9, 1924</date>, shall thereupon attach from the date of such default: <i>And provided further</i>, That similar relief in whole or in part may be extended by the Secretary of the Interior to a legally organized group of water users of a project, upon presentation of a sufficient number of individual showings made in accordance with the foregoing proviso to satisfy the Secretary of the Interior that such extension is necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc9c8e427-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1924-05-09/ch150">May 9, 1924, ch. 150</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/43/116">43 Stat. 116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9c8e428-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9c8e429-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9c8e42a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idc9c8e42b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idc9c8e42c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
