<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9cb5551-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390"><num value="390">§ 390.</num><heading> Utilization of dams and reservoir projects for irrigation purposes; additional construction; necessity of authorization; apportionment of cost; limitation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="1944-12-22">December 22, 1944</date>, whenever the Secretary of the Army determines, upon recommendation by the Secretary of the Interior that any dam and reservoir project operated under the direction of the Secretary of the Army may be utilized for irrigation purposes, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain, under the provisions of the Federal reclamation laws (Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), such additional works in connection therewith as he may deem necessary for irrigation purposes. Such irrigation works may be undertaken only after a report and findings thereon have been made by the Secretary of the Interior as provided in said Federal reclamation laws and after subsequent specific authorization of the Congress by an authorization Act; and, within the limits of the water users’ repayment ability such report may be predicated on the allocation to irrigation of an appropriate portion of the cost of structures and facilities used for irrigation and other purposes. Dams and reservoirs operated under the direction of the Secretary of the Army may be utilized after <date date="1944-12-22">December 22, 1944</date>, for irrigation purposes only in conformity with the provisions of this section, but the foregoing requirement shall not prejudice lawful uses now existing: <i>Provided</i>, That this section shall not apply to any dam or reservoir heretofore constructed in whole or in part by the Army engineers, which provides conservation storage of water for irrigation purposes. In the case of any reservoir project constructed and operated by the Corps of Engineers, the Secretary of the Army is authorized to allocate water which was allocated in the project purpose for municipal and industrial water supply and which is not under contract for delivery, for such periods as he may deem reasonable, for the interim use for irrigation purposes of such storage until such storage is required for municipal and industrial water supply. No contracts for the interim use of such storage shall be entered into which would significantly affect then-existing uses of such storage.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9cb5552-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-12-22/ch665/s8">Dec. 22, 1944, ch. 665, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/891">58 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/662/tIX/s931">Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 931</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4196">100 Stat. 4196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9cb5553-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9cb5554-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9cb5555-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9cb5556-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/662">Pub. L. 99–662</ref> inserted at end “In the case of any reservoir project constructed and operated by the Corps of Engineers, the Secretary of the Army is authorized to allocate water which was allocated in the project purpose for municipal and industrial water supply and which is not under contract for delivery, for such periods as he may deem reasonable, for the interim use for irrigation purposes of such storage until such storage is required for municipal and industrial water supply. No contracts for the interim use of such storage shall be entered into which would significantly affect then-existing uses of such storage.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9cb5557-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idc9cb5558-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9cb5559-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Variable Payment Plan</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority of Secretary to extend benefits of variable payment plan to organizations with which he contracts or has contracted for the repayment of construction costs allocated to irrigation on any project undertaken by the United States, including contracts for the storage of water or for the use of stored water under this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/611/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 85–611</ref>, <date date="1958-08-08">Aug. 8, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/542">72 Stat. 542</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s485h">section 485h of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9cb555a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Section as Unaffected by Submerged Lands Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section as not amended, modified or repealed by the Submerged Lands Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idc9cb555b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idc9cb555c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain real property and functions relating to real property, insofar as they pertain to Air Force, from Secretary of the Army and Department of the Army to Secretary of the Air Force and Department of the Air Force, see Secretary of Defense Transfer Order Nos. 14, eff. <date date="1948-07-01">July 1, 1948</date>, and 40 [App. B(133)], <date date="1949-07-22">July 22, 1949</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
