<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9d4cb9a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww"><num value="390ww">§ 390ww.</num><heading> Administrative provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cb9b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing Federal reclamation law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of Federal reclamation law shall remain in full force and effect, except to the extent such law is amended by, or is inconsistent with, this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cb9c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing statutory exemptions from ownership or pricing limitations of Federal reclamation law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall repeal or amend any existing statutory exemptions from the ownership or pricing limitations of Federal reclamation law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cb9d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations; collection of necessary data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may prescribe regulations and shall collect all data necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter and other provisions of Federal reclamation law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cb9e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cb9f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of nonexcess land acquired into excess status pursuant to involuntary process of law, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any nonexcess land which is acquired into excess status pursuant to involuntary foreclosure or similar involuntary process of law, conveyance in satisfaction of a debt (including, but not limited to, a mortgage, real estate contract, or deed of trust), inheritance, or devise, may be sold at its fair market value without regard to any other provision of this subchapter or to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s423e">section 423e of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That if the status of mortgaged land changes from nonexcess into excess after the mortgage is recorded and is subsequently acquired by the lender by involuntary foreclosure or similar involuntary process of law, by bona fide conveyance in satisfaction of the mortgage, such land may be sold at its fair market value.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cba0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cba1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual audit of compliance with reclamation laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other audit or compliance activities which may otherwise be undertaken, the Secretary of the Interior, or his designee, shall conduct a thorough audit of the compliance with the reclamation law of the United States, specifically including this subchapter, by legal entities and individuals subject to such law. At a minimum, the Secretary shall complete audits of those legal entities and individuals whose landholdings or operations exceed 960 acres within 3 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cba2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordable contracts executed prior to <date date="1982-10-12">October 12, 1982</date></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390ee/c">section 390ee(c) of this title</ref> are and have been applicable to all recordable contracts executed prior to <date date="1982-10-12">October 12, 1982</date>, and any decision, rule, or regulation promulgated by the Department of the Interior to the contrary is hereby revoked: <i>Provided</i>, That notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (i), the Secretary shall not seek reimbursement for any amounts due under this subsection or <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390ee/c">section 390ee(c) of this title</ref> which was due prior to <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc9d4cba3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s390ww/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of underpayment with interest for irrigation water</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the Secretary finds that any individual or legal entity subject to reclamation law, including this subchapter, has not paid the required amount for irrigation water delivered to a landholding pursuant to reclamation law, including this subchapter, he shall collect the amount of any underpayment with interest accruing from the date the required payment was due until paid. The interest rate shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury on the basis of the weighted average yield of all interest bearing marketable issues sold by the Treasury during the period of underpayment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc9d4cba4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/293/tII/s224">Pub. L. 97–293, title II, § 224</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1272">96 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tV/s5302/a">Pub. L. 100–203, title V, § 5302(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-268">101 Stat. 1330–268</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s16/a/3">Pub. L. 103–437, § 16(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4594">108 Stat. 4594</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1081/d">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1081(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/721">109 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9d4cba5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9d4cba6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9d4cba7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal reclamation law, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c), is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390aa">section 390aa of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c) and (e), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II (§§ 201–230) of <ref href="/us/pl/97/293">Pub. L. 97–293</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1263">96 Stat. 1263</ref>, known as the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982, which enacted this subchapter, amended sections 373a, 422e, 425b, and 485h of this title, and repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s383">section 383 of Title 25</ref>, Indians. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (g) and (i), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”. See note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9d4cba8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/97/293/s224">section 224 of Pub. L. 97–293</ref>. Subsec. (d) of section 224 amended <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s425">section 425 of this title</ref>. Subsec. (f) of section 224 repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s383">section 383 of Title 25</ref>, Indians, and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s385">section 385 of Title 25</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9d4cba9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out at end “The Secretary shall submit an annual written report to the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the House Committee on Natural Resources. Such report shall summarize the legal entities and individuals audited, the results of such audits, and the actions taken by the Secretary to correct any instances of noncompliance with the reclamation law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “House Committee on”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> added subsecs. (g) to (i).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
