<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9d9ac70-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s414"><num value="414">§ 414.</num><heading> Appropriation for projects essential</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Expenditures shall not be made for carrying out the purposes of the reclamation law except out of appropriations made annually by Congress therefor, and there shall annually, in the Budget, be submitted to Congress estimates of the amount of money necessary to be expended for carrying out any or all of the purposes authorized by the reclamation law, including the extension and completion of existing projects and units thereof and the construction of new projects. The annual appropriations made hereunder by Congress for such purposes shall be paid out of the reclamation fund provided for by the reclamation law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9d9ac71-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-08-13/ch247/s16">Aug. 13, 1914, ch. 247, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/690">38 Stat. 690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9d9ac72-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9d9ac73-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9d9ac74-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reclamation law, referred to in text, is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s472">section 472 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9d9ac75-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “there shall annually, in the Budget, be submitted to Congress” substituted for “the Secretary of the Interior shall annually in the regular Book of Estimates, submit to Congress” in view of the Budget and Accounting Act, 1921, <ref href="/us/act/1921-06-10/ch18">act June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/20">42 Stat. 20</ref>. See sections 1104 and 1105 of Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
