<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9d9ac91-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s419"><num value="419">§ 419.</num><heading> Contract for irrigation project; notice as to lands irrigable, unit of entry, and construction charges</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the determination that any irrigation project is practicable, the Secretary of the Interior may cause to be let contracts for the construction of the same, in such portions or sections as it may be practicable to construct and complete as parts of the whole project, providing the necessary funds for such portions or sections are available, and thereupon he shall give public notice of the lands irrigable under such project, and limit of area per entry, which limit shall represent the acreage which, in the opinion of the Secretary, may be reasonably required for the support of a family upon the lands in question; also of the charges which shall be made per acre upon the said entries, and upon lands in private ownership which may be irrigated by the waters of the said irrigation project, and the number of annual installments in which such charges shall be paid and the time when such payments shall commence: <i>Provided</i>, That in all construction work eight hours shall constitute a day’s work.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9d9ac92-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093/s4">June 17, 1902, ch. 1093, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/389">32 Stat. 389</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-05-10/ch256">May 10, 1956, ch. 256</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/151">70 Stat. 151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9d9ac93-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9d9ac94-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9d9ac95-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of part of section 4 of act <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>. Remainder of such section 4 is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9d9ac96-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Act <date date="1956-05-10">May 10, 1956</date>, substituted a period for the comma after “work” in proviso, and struck out “and no Mongolian labor shall be employed thereon.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9d9ac97-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9d9ac98-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Section as Unaffected by Submerged Lands Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section as not amended, modified, or repealed by the Submerged Lands Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
