<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9d9ac9f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s421"><num value="421">§ 421.</num><heading> Acquisition of lands for irrigation project; eminent domain</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where, in carrying out the provisions of this Act, it becomes necessary to acquire any rights or property, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire the same for the United States by purchase or by condemnation under judicial process, and to pay from the reclamation fund the sums which may be needed for that purpose, and it shall be the duty of the Attorney General of the United States upon every application of the Secretary of the Interior, under this Act, to cause proceedings to be commenced for condemnation within thirty days from the receipt of the application at the Department of Justice.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9d9aca0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093/s7">June 17, 1902, ch. 1093, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/389">32 Stat. 389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9d9aca1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9d9aca2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9d9aca3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is act <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this Title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9d9aca4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9d9aca5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Section as Unaffected by Submerged Lands Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section as not amended, modified, or repealed by the Submerged Lands Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
