<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9dbf6ed-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e"><num value="422e">§ 422e.</num><heading> Contract requirements</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon approval of any project proposal by the Secretary under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422d">section 422d of this title</ref>, he may negotiate a contract which shall set out, among other things—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6ee-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> the maximum amount of any loan to be made to the organization and the time and method of making the same available to the organization. Said loan shall not exceed the lesser of (1) two-thirds of the maximum allowable estimated total project cost as determined by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422b/f">section 422b(f) of this title</ref>, or (2) the estimated total cost of the project minus the contribution of the local organization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422d/b">section 422d(b) of this title</ref> and the amount of the grant approved;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6ef-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> the maximum amount of any grant to be accorded the organization. Said grant shall not exceed the sum of the following: (1) the costs of investigations, surveys, and engineering and other services necessary to the preparation of proposals and plans for the project allocable to fish and wildlife enhancement or public recreation; (2) one-half the costs of acquiring lands or interests therein to serve exclusively the purposes of fish and wildlife enhancement or public recreation, plus the costs of acquiring joint use lands and interests therein properly allocable to fish and wildlife enhancement and public recreation; (3) one-half the costs of basic public outdoor recreation facilities or facilities serving fish and wildlife enhancement purposes exclusively; (4) one-half the costs of construction of joint use facilities properly allocable to fish and wildlife enhancement or public recreation; (5) that portion of the estimated cost of constructing the project which, if it were constructed as a Federal reclamation project, would be properly allocable to functions, other than recreation and fish and wildlife enhancement and flood control, which are nonreimbursable under general provisions of law applicable to such projects; and (6) that portion of the estimated cost of constructing the project which is allocable to flood control and which would be nonreimbursable under general provisions of law applicable to projects constructed by the Secretary of the Army.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002026"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6f0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> a plan of repayment by the organization of (1) the sums lent to it in not more than forty years from the date when the principal benefits of the project first become available; (2) interest, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, as of the beginning of the fiscal year in which the contract is executed, on the basis of the average market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods of maturity comparable to the applicable reimbursement period of the project, adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 percent on the unamortized balance of any portion of the loan—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc9dbf6f1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/c/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which is attributable to furnishing irrigation benefits in each particular year to land held in private ownership by a qualified recipient or by a limited recipient, as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390bb">section 390bb of this title</ref>, in excess of three hundred and twenty irrigable acres; or,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc9dbf6f2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/c/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which is allocated to domestic, industrial, or municipal water supply, commercial power, fish and wildlife enhancement, or public recreation except that portion of such allocation attributable to furnishing benefits to a facility operated by an agency of the United States, which portion shall bear no interest.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6f3-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> provision for operation of the project, if a grant predicated upon its performance of nonreimbursable functions is made, in accordance with regulations with respect thereto prescribed by the head of the Federal department or agency primarily concerned with those functions and, in the event of noncompliance with such regulations, for operation by the United States or for repayment to the United States of the amount of any such grant;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6f4-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> such provisions as the Secretary shall deem necessary or proper to provide assurance of and security for prompt repayment of the loan and interest as aforesaid. The liability of the United States under any contract entered into pursuant to this subchapter shall be contingent upon the availability of appropriations to carry out the same, and every such contract shall so recite; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc9dbf6f5-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s422e/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> provisions conforming to the preference requirements contained in the proviso to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s485h/c">section 485h(c) of this title</ref>, if the project produces electric power for sale.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc9dbf6f6-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-06/ch972/s5">Aug. 6, 1956, ch. 972, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/1046">70 Stat. 1046</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/47/s1/c">Pub. L. 85–47, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1957-06-05">June 5, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/49">71 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/553/s1/4">Pub. L. 89–553, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-02">Sept. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/376">80 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/167/s1/3">Pub. L. 92–167, § 1(3)</ref>–(6), <date date="1971-11-24">Nov. 24, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/488">85 Stat. 488</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/181/s1/f">Pub. L. 94–181, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-27">Dec. 27, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1050">89 Stat. 1050</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/336/s8/b">Pub. L. 96–336, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-04">Sept. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1065">94 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/293/tII/s223">Pub. L. 97–293, title II, § 223</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1272">96 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/tIII">Pub. L. 99–546, title III</ref>, §§ 306, 307, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3054">100 Stat. 3054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9dbf6f7-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9dbf6f8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9dbf6f9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/s306">Pub. L. 99–546, § 306</ref>, struck out “and” before “(5)” and substituted “and flood control, which are nonreimbursable under general provisions of law applicable to such projects; and (6) that portion of the estimated cost of constructing the project which is allocable to flood control and which would be nonreimbursable under general provisions of law applicable to projects constructed by the Secretary of the Army.” for “, which are nonreimbursable under general provisions of law applicable to such projects: <i>Provided</i>, That the cost of constructing the project as used in this subsection shall be exclusive of the cost of lands and interests in land;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/s307/a">Pub. L. 99–546, § 307(a)</ref>, substituted “forty” for “fifty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/s307/b">Pub. L. 99–546, § 307(b)</ref>, amended cl. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (2) read as follows: “interest, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, as of the beginning of the fiscal year in which the contract is executed, on the basis of the computed average interest rate payable by the Treasury upon its outstanding marketable public obligations, which are neither due nor callable for redemption for fifteen years from date of issue, and by adjusting such average rate to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum, on that portion of the loan which is attributable to furnishing irrigation benefits in each particular year to land held in private ownership by a qualified recipient, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390bb">section 390bb of this title</ref>, in excess of nine hundred and sixty irrigable acres, or by a limited recipient, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390bb">section 390bb of this title</ref>, in excess of three hundred and twenty irrigable acres; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/s307/c">Pub. L. 99–546, § 307(c)</ref>, struck out cl. (3) which read as follows: “in the case of any project involving an allocation to domestic, industrial, or municipal water supply, commercial power, fish and wildlife enhancement, or public recreation, interest on the unamortized balance of an appropriate portion of the loan at a rate as determined in (2) above; Except that portion of said allocation attributable to furnishing benefits to a facility operated by an agency of the United States, which portion shall bear no interest;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/293">Pub. L. 97–293</ref> substituted “by a qualified recipient, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390bb">section 390bb of this title</ref>, in excess of nine hundred and sixty irrigable acres, or by a limited recipient, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390bb">section 390bb of this title</ref>, in excess of three hundred and twenty irrigable acres” for “by any one owner in excess of one hundred and sixty irrigable acres”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/336">Pub. L. 96–336</ref> inserted “Except that portion of said allocation attributable to furnishing benefits to a facility operated by an agency of the United States, which portion shall bear no interest;” at end of subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/181">Pub. L. 94–181</ref> substituted “two-thirds of the maximum allowable estimated total project cost as determined by <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422b/f">section 422b(f) of this title</ref>,” for “$10,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/92/167/s1/3">Pub. L. 92–167, § 1(3)</ref>, substituted “$10,000,000” for “$6,500,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/92/167/s1/4">Pub. L. 92–167, § 1(4)</ref>, substituted provision for inclusion of one-half of land acquisition costs to serve exclusively the purposes of fish and wildlife enhancement and public recreation, for prior inclusion of such costs for a reservoir or other area to be operated for fish and wildlife enhancement and public recreation purposes and provided for inclusion of costs of acquiring joint use lands and interests therein properly allocable to fish and wildlife enhancement and public recreation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/92/167/s1/5">Pub. L. 92–167, § 1(5)</ref>, inserted proviso excluding from cost of constructing projects, as used in this subsection, cost of lands and interests in land.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/92/167/s1/6">Pub. L. 92–167, § 1(6)</ref>, required reimbursable fish and wildlife and recreation costs to be repaid with interest at rate determined by formula set forth in subsec. (c)(2) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/553">Pub. L. 89–553</ref> substituted the lesser of $6,500,000 or the estimated total cost of the project minus the contribution of the local organization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422d/b">section 422d(b) of this title</ref> and the amount of the grant for the portion of the estimated cost of constructing the project which, if it were being constructed as a Federal reclamation project, would be properly allocable to reimbursable functions under general provisions of law applicable to such projects as the maximum amount of the loan, struck out the time and method of paying a grant to an organization from the list of contract terms, added factors involving fish and wildlife enhancement and public recreation to the factors adding up to the figure comprising the maximum allowable grant, and altered the requirements of the interest term by substituting the computed average interest rate payable by the Treasury upon its outstanding marketable public obligations which are neither due nor callable for redemption for fifteen years from date of issue for the estimate of the average annual yield to maturity, on the basis of daily closing market bid quotations or prices during the month of May preceding the fiscal year in which the loan is made, on all outstanding marketable obligations of the United States having a maturity date of fifteen or more years from May 1 of the year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—<ref href="/us/pl/85/47">Pub. L. 85–47</ref> substituted “Upon approval of any project proposal by the Secretary under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422d">section 422d of this title</ref>, he may negotiate a contract which” for “Any contract authorized to be negotiated under the provisions of subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422d">section 422d of this title</ref>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9dbf6fa-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc9dbf6fb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/546">Pub. L. 99–546</ref> applicable to all proposals for which draft applications are received by Secretary after <date date="1986-08-15">Aug. 15, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/546/s310">section 310 of Pub. L. 99–546</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422a">section 422a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="retroactiveDate" id="idc9dbf6fc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retroactive Effect of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/553">Pub. L. 89–553</ref> not to be applicable to or affect in any way the terms on which any loan or grant was made prior to the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/89/553">Pub. L. 89–553</ref>, <date date="1966-09-02">Sept. 2, 1966</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/553/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 89–553</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s422b">section 422b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
