<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9de678f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s434"><num value="434">§ 434.</num><heading> Amount of land for which entry may be made; farm unit; subdivision of lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Public lands which it is proposed to irrigate by means of any contemplated works shall be subject to entry in tracts of not less than forty nor more than one hundred and sixty acres: <i>Provided</i>, That whenever, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Interior, by reason of market conditions and the special fitness of the soil and climate for the growth of fruit and garden produce, a lesser area than forty acres may be sufficient for the support of a family on lands to be irrigated under the provisions of the Act of June seventeenth, nineteen hundred and two, known as the reclamation Act, he may fix a lesser area than forty acres as the minimum entry and may establish farm units of not less than ten nor more than one hundred and sixty acres. Wherever it may be necessary, for the purpose of accurate description, to further subdivide lands to be irrigated under the provisions of said reclamation Act, the Secretary of the Interior may cause subdivision surveys to be made by the officers of the reclamation service, which subdivisions shall be rectangular in form, except in cases where irregular subdivisions may be necessary in order to provide for practicable and economical irrigation. Such subdivision surveys shall be noted upon the tract books in the Bureau of Land Management, and they shall be paid for from the reclamation fund: <i>Provided</i>, That an entryman may elect to enter under said reclamation Act a lesser area than the minimum limit in any State or Territory.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9de6790-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093/s3">June 17, 1902, ch. 1093, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1906-06-27/ch3559/s1">June 27, 1906, ch. 3559, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/519">34 Stat. 519</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9de6791-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9de6792-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9de6793-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of June seventeenth, nineteen hundred and two, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093">act June 17, 1902, ch. 1093</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9de6794-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of a part of section 3 of act <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, and section 1 of act <date date="1906-06-27">June 27, 1906</date>. Remainder of section 3 of act <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, is classified to sections 416 and 432 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9de6795-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9de6796-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Section as Unaffected by Submerged Lands Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section as not amended, modified or repealed by the Submerged Lands Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idc9de6797-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idc9de6798-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Reclamation Service, established in July 1902, changed to the Bureau of Reclamation on <date date="1923-06-20">June 20, 1923</date>, then to the Water and Power Resources Service on <date date="1979-11-06">Nov. 6, 1979</date>, and then to the Bureau of Reclamation on <date date="1981-05-18">May 18, 1981</date>. See 155 Dep’t of the Interior, Departmental Manual 1.1 (2008 repl.); Sec’y Hubert Work, Dep’t of the Interior, Order (<date date="1923-06-20">June 20, 1923</date>); Sec’y Cecil D. Andrus, Dep’t of the Interior, Secretarial Order 3042, §§ 1, 4 (<date date="1979-11-06">Nov. 6, 1979</date>); Sec’y James G. Watt, Dep’t of the Interior, Secretarial Order 3064, §§ 3, 5 (<date date="1981-05-18">May 18, 1981</date>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idc9de6799-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Bureau of Land Management” substituted in text for “General Land Office” on authority of section 403 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1946, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
