<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9ea4f66-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s505"><num value="505">§ 505.</num><heading> Drainage facilities and minor construction in irrigation works; contracts with repayment organizations; limitation on costs; submission of contract to Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds appropriated for the construction of irrigation works authorized to be undertaken pursuant to the Federal reclamation laws (Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), the Act of <date date="1939-08-11">August 11, 1939</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/53/1418">53 Stat. 1418</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590y">16 U.S.C. 590y</ref> et seq.], or other Acts of Congress may, insofar as such funds are available for the construction of drainage facilities and other minor items, be utilized by the Secretary of the Interior to accomplish such work by contract, by force account or, notwithstanding any other law and subject only to such reasonable terms and conditions as the Secretary shall deem appropriate for the protection of the United States, by contract entered into with the repayment organization concerned whereby said organization shall perform such work: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event construction work to be accomplished by any one repayment organization, pursuant to contract with the United States, exceeds a total cost of $200,000, such contract shall not be executed by the Secretary prior to the expiration of sixty calendar days (which sixty days, however, shall not include days on which either the House of Representatives or the Senate is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain) from the date on which it has been submitted to the Speaker of the House and the President of the Senate for reference to the appropriate Committees, except that such contract may be executed prior to expiration of such sixty days in any case in which both such Committees approve said contract and notify the Secretary in writing of such approval.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9ecbf67-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-06-13/ch382">June 13, 1956, ch. 382</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/274">70 Stat. 274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9ecbf68-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9ecbf69-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9ecbf6a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1939-08-11">August 11, 1939</date>, referred to in text, is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 590y et seq.) of chapter 3C of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
