<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9aea5ac-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s50c"><num value="50c">§ 50c.</num><heading> Payment of costs incidental to utilization of services of volunteers</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appropriations herein and on and after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, made shall be available for paying costs incidental to the utilization of services contributed by individuals who serve without compensation as volunteers in aid of work of the United States Geological Survey, and that within appropriations herein and on and after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, provided, United States Geological Survey officials may authorize either direct procurement of or reimbursement for expenses incidental to the effective use of volunteers such as, but not limited to, training, transportation, lodging, subsistence, equipment, and supplies: <i>Provided further</i>, That provision for such expenses or services is in accord with volunteer or cooperative agreements made with such individuals, private organizations, educational institutions, or State or local government.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9aea5ad-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/g/tI">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(g) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-213">101 Stat. 1329–213</ref>, 1329–224; <ref href="/us/pl/102/154/tI">Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1000">105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9aea5ae-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9aea5af-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9aea5b0-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Appropriations herein, referred to in text, probably means appropriations under the headings “<inline class="small-caps">Geological Survey”, “surveys, investigations, and research</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">administrative provisions</inline>”, of the annual Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9aea5b1-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idc9aea5b2-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Geological Survey” substituted in text for “Geological Survey” pursuant to provision of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/102/154">Pub. L. 102–154</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
