<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9f3eb23-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s600b"><num value="600b">§ 600b.</num><heading> Canadian River project, Texas</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of irrigating land, delivering water for industrial and municipal use, controlling floods, providing recreation and fish and wildlife benefits, and controlling and catching silt, the Secretary of the Interior, acting pursuant to the Federal reclamation laws (Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain the Canadian River reclamation project, Texas, described in the report of the Commissioner of Reclamation approved by the Secretary <date date="1950-05-03">May 3, 1950</date>, entitled “Plan for Development, Canadian River Project, Texas”, Project Planning Report Number 5–12.22–1, at an estimated cost of $86,656,000, the impounding works whereof shall be located at a suitable site on the Canadian River in that area known as the Panhandle of Texas. In addition to the impounding works, the project shall include such main canals, pumping plants, distribution and drainage systems, and other works as are necessary to accomplish the purposes of sections 600b and 600c of this title. The use by the project of waters arising in Ute and Pajarito Creeks, New Mexico, shall be only such use as does not conflict with use, present or potential, of such waters for beneficial consumptive purposes in New Mexico.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9f3eb24-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-12-29/ch1183/s1">Dec. 29, 1950, ch. 1183, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1124">64 Stat. 1124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9f3eb25-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9f3eb26-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc9f3eb27-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9f3eb28-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9f3eb29-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization of Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1950-12-29/ch1183/s3">Act Dec. 29, 1950, ch. 1183, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1125">64 Stat. 1125</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1950-12-29/ch1183/s3">“There are hereby authorized to be appropriated, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be required to carry out the purposes of this Act [enacting this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s600c">section 600c of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9f3eb2a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Canadian River Project Prepayment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/316">Pub. L. 105–316</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2999">112 Stat. 2999</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/316">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Canadian River Project Prepayment Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For the purposes of this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Authority’ means the Canadian River Municipal Water Authority, a conservation and reclamation district of the State of Texas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Canadian River Project Authorization Act’ means the Act entitled ‘An Act to authorize the construction, operation, and maintenance by the Secretary of the Interior of the Canadian River reclamation project, Texas’, approved <date date="1950-12-29">December 29, 1950</date> (ch. 1183; <ref href="/us/stat/64/1124">64 Stat. 1124</ref>) [enacting this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s600c">section 600c of this title</ref>, and provisions set out as a note above].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘Project’ means all of the right, title and interest in and to all land and improvements comprising the pipeline and related facilities of the Canadian River Project authorized by the Canadian River Project Authorization Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> PREPAYMENT AND CONVEYANCE OF PROJECT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In consideration of the Authority accepting the obligation of the Federal Government for the Project and subject to the payment by the Authority of the applicable amount under paragraph (2) within the 360-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>], the Secretary shall convey the Project to the Authority, as provided in section 2(c)(3) of the Canadian River Project Authorization Act (<ref href="/us/stat/64/1124">64 Stat. 1124</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s600c/c/3">section 600c(c)(3) of this title</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the applicable amount shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> $34,806,731, if payment is made by the Authority within the 270-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the amount specified in subparagraph (A) adjusted to include interest on that amount since the date of the enactment of this Act at the appropriate Treasury bill rate for an equivalent term, if payment is made by the Authority after the period referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> If payment under paragraph (1) is not made by the Authority within the period specified in paragraph (1), this Act shall have no force or effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financing</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the right of the Authority to use a particular type of financing.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> RELATIONSHIP TO EXISTING OPERATIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as significantly expanding or otherwise changing the use or operation of the Project from its current use and operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Future Alterations</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Authority alters the operations or uses of the Project it shall comply with all applicable laws or regulations governing such alteration at that time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recreation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the National Park Service, shall continue to operate the Lake Meredith National Recreation Area at Lake Meredith.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Flood Control</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Corps of Engineers, shall continue to prescribe regulations for the use of storage allocated to flood control at Lake Meredith as prescribed in the Letter of Understanding entered into between the Corps, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Authority in March and May 1980.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sanford Dam Property</inline>.—</heading><content>The Authority shall have the right to occupy and use without payment of lease or rental charges or license or use fees the property retained by the Bureau of Reclamation at Sanford Dam and all buildings constructed by the United States thereon for use as the Authority’s headquarters and maintenance facility. Buildings constructed by the Authority on such property, or past and future additions to Government constructed buildings, shall be allowed to remain on the property. The Authority shall operate and maintain such property and facilities without cost to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> RELATIONSHIP TO CERTAIN CONTRACT OBLIGATIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment Obligations Extinguished</inline>.—</heading><content>Provision of consideration by the Authority in accordance with section 3(b) shall extinguish all payment obligations under contract numbered 14–06–500–485 between the Authority and the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operation and Maintenance Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>After completion of the conveyance provided for in section 3, the Authority shall have full responsibility for the cost of operation and maintenance of Sanford Dam, and shall continue to have full responsibility for operation and maintenance of the Project pipeline and related facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Rights and obligations under the existing contract No. 14–06–500–485 between the Authority and the United States, other than provisions regarding repayment of construction charge obligation by the Authority and provisions relating to the Project aqueduct, shall remain in full force and effect for the remaining term of the contract.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> RELATIONSHIP TO OTHER LAWS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Upon conveyance of the Project under this Act, the Reclamation Act of 1902 (<ref href="/us/stat/82/388">82 Stat. 388</ref>) [probably means <ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093">act June 17, 1902, ch. 1093</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of this title</ref>] and all Acts amendatory thereof or supplemental thereto shall not apply to the Project.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> LIABILITY.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Except as otherwise provided by law, effective on the date of conveyance of the Project under this Act, the United States shall not be liable under any law for damages of any kind arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to the conveyed property.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
