<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc9ffd21a-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s620"><num value="620">§ 620.</num><heading> Upper Colorado River Basin; purpose of development of water resources; initial units; construction of Wayne N. Aspinall unit contingent upon certification; participating projects; Rainbow Bridge National Monument</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to initiate the comprehensive development of the water resources of the Upper Colorado River Basin, for the purposes, among others, of regulating the flow of the Colorado River, storing water for beneficial consumptive use, making it possible for the States of the Upper Basin to utilize, consistently with the provisions of the Colorado River Compact, the apportionments made to and among them in the Colorado River Compact and the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact, respectively, providing for the reclamation of arid and semiarid land, for the control of floods, and for the generation of hydroelectric power, as an incident of the foregoing purposes, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized (1) to construct, operate, and maintain the following initial units of the Colorado River storage project, consisting of dams, reservoirs, powerplants, transmission facilities and appurtenant works: Wayne N. Aspinall, Flaming Gorge, Navajo (dam and reservoir only), and Glen Canyon: <i>Provided</i>, That the Wayne N. Aspinall Dam shall be constructed to a height which will impound not less than nine hundred and forty thousand acre-feet of water or will create a reservoir of such greater capacity as can be obtained by a high waterline located at seven thousand five hundred and twenty feet above mean sea level, and that construction thereof shall not be undertaken until the Secretary has, on the basis of further engineering and economic investigations, reexamined the economic justification of such unit and, accompanied by appropriate documentation in the form of a supplemental report, has certified to the Congress and to the President that, in his judgment, the benefits of such unit will exceed its costs; and (2) to construct, operate, and maintain the following additional reclamation projects (including power-generating and transmission facilities related thereto), hereinafter referred to as participating projects: Central Utah (initial phase and the Uintah unit), San Juan-Chama (initial stage), Emery County, Florida, Hammond, La Barge, Lyman, Navajo Indian, Paonia (including the Minnesota unit, a dam and reservoir on Muddy Creek just above its confluence with the North Fork of the Gunnison River, and other necessary works), Animas-La Plata, Dolores, Dallas Creek, West Divide, San Miguel, Seedskadee, Savery-Pot Hook, Bostwick Park, Fruitland Mesa, the Navajo-Gallup Water Supply Project, Silt and Smith Fork: <i>Provided further</i>, That as part of the Glen Canyon Unit the Secretary of the Interior shall take adequate protective measures to preclude impairment of the Rainbow Bridge National Monument.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc9ffd21b-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-04-11/ch203/s1">Apr. 11, 1956, ch. 203, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/105">70 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/483/s18">Pub. L. 87–483, § 18</ref>, <date date="1962-06-13">June 13, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/102">76 Stat. 102</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/568/s1">Pub. L. 88–568, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-09-02">Sept. 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/852">78 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/537/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 90–537, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-09-30">Sept. 30, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/896">82 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/375/s7">Pub. L. 96–375, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1507">94 Stat. 1507</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/470/tI/s108/c">Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 108(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2239">94 Stat. 2239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tX/s10401/a">Pub. L. 111–11, title X, § 10401(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1371">123 Stat. 1371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc9ffd21c-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idc9ffd21d-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For termination of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10701/e/2">section 10701(e)(2) of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, see Termination Date of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc9ffd21e-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc9ffd21f-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions of subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/pl/90/537/s501">section 501 of Pub. L. 90–537</ref> which amended this section are only a part of said subsec. (a). The remainder of said subsec. (a) amended <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620a">section 620a of this title</ref> and enacted provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620k">section 620k of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc9ffd220-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—<ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, §§ 10401(a), 10701(e)(2), temporarily inserted “the Navajo-Gallup Water Supply Project,” after “Fruitland Mesa,” in cl. (2). See Termination Date of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/470">Pub. L. 96–470</ref> struck out proviso that construction of Uintah unit of Central Utah proj­ect not be undertaken by the Secretary until he has completed a feasibility report on such unit and submitted it to Congress, along with his certification that, in his judgment, the benefits of such unit or segment will exceed the cost and that such unit is physically and financially feasible, and that the Congress has authorized appropriations for construction thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/375">Pub. L. 96–375</ref> substituted “Wayne N. Aspinall” for “Curecanti”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/537">Pub. L. 90–537</ref> added Uintah unit to initial phase in Central Utah project, substituted “Animas-La Plata, Dolores, Dallas Creek, West Divide, San Miguel” for “Pine River Extension”, and inserted proviso prohibiting construction of Uintah unit of Central Utah project until a feasibility study is made, a determination is made that its benefits will exceed its costs and an authorization for appropriations is made by Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/568">Pub. L. 88–568</ref> included Savery-Pot Hook, Bostwick Park, and Fruitland Mesa as participating projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/483">Pub. L. 87–483</ref> included San Juan-Chama (initial stage) and Navajo Indian as participating projects in cl. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc9ffd221-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="idc9ffd222-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref> to be null and void on issuance of a court order terminating a certain Agreement between New Mexico, the Navajo Nation, and the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10701/e/2">section 10701(e)(2) of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out as an Agreement note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idc9ffd223-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1956-04-11">Apr. 11, 1956</date>, which enacted this chapter, is popularly known as the “Colorado River Storage Project Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9ffd224-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Purpose of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/90/537/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 90–537, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-09-30">Sept. 30, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/896">82 Stat. 896</ref>, provided that the amendment of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620a">section 620a of this title</ref> by section 501(a) were made in order to provide for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the Animas-La Plata Federal reclamation project, Colorado-New Mexico; the Dolores, Dallas Creek, West Divide, and San Miguel Federal reclamation projects, Colorado; and the Central Utah project (Uintah Unit), Utah, as participating projects under the Colorado River Storage Project Act, and to provide for the completion of planning reports on other participating projects.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9ffd225-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Projects To Increase Colorado River System Water To Address Effects of Historic Drought Conditions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dD/tII/s206">Pub. L. 113–235, div. D, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2312">128 Stat. 2312</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/244/dA/tII/s205/a">Pub. L. 115–244, div. A, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2906">132 Stat. 2906</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dCC/s102">Pub. L. 117–328, div. CC, § 102</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5573">136 Stat. 5573</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dCC/s102">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Interior may fund or participate in pilot projects to increase Colorado River System water in Lake Mead and the initial units of Colorado River Storage Project reservoirs, as authorized by the first section of the Act of <date date="1956-04-11">April 11, 1956</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620">43 U.S.C. 620</ref>), to address the effects of historic drought conditions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Pilot projects under this section are authorized to be funded through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> grants by the Secretary to public entities that use water from the Colorado River Basin for municipal purposes for projects that are implemented by 1 or more non-Federal entities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> grants or other appropriate financial agreements to provide funds for new water conservation agreements or for renewing or implementing water conservation agreements that are in existence on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Funds in the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund established by section 5 of the Colorado River Storage Project Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620d">43 U.S.C. 620d</ref>) and the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund established by section 403 of the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1543">43 U.S.C. 1543</ref>) shall not be used to carry out this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the authority to fund these pilot projects through grants shall terminate on <date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall not fund pilot projects in the Upper Colorado River Basin without the participation of the Upper Colorado River Division States, acting through the Upper Colorado River Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and Recommendation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report evaluating the effectiveness of the pilot projects described in subsection (a) and a recommendation to Congress whether the activities undertaken by the pilot projects should be continued.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9ffd226-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Federal Water Law</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tX/s10403">Pub. L. 111–11, title X, § 10403</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1375">123 Stat. 1375</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/11/tX/s10403">
<inline>“Unless expressly provided in this subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 10301–10704) of title X of <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, enacting section 407, former section 615jj, and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620n–1">section 620n–1 of this title</ref>, amending this section, former section 615ss, and section 620<i>o</i> of this title, repealing former <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s615jj">section 615jj of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s407">section 407 of this title</ref>], nothing in this subtitle modifies, conflicts with, preempts, or otherwise affects—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s617">43 U.S.C. 617</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/stat/54/774">54 Stat. 774</ref>, chapter 643) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s618">43 U.S.C. 618</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Act of <date date="1956-04-11">April 11, 1956</date> (commonly known as the ‘Colorado River Storage Project Act’) (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620">43 U.S.C. 620</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Act of <date date="1968-09-30">September 30, 1968</date> (commonly known as the ‘Colorado River Basin Project Act’) (<ref href="/us/stat/82/885">82 Stat. 885</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1501">43 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> <ref href="/us/pl/87/483">Public Law 87–483</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/76/96">76 Stat. 96</ref>) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s615ii">43 U.S.C. 615ii</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the Treaty between the United States of America and Mexico respecting utilization of waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, signed at Washington <date date="1944-02-03">February 3, 1944</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/59/1219">59 Stat. 1219</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the Colorado River Compact of 1922, as approved by the Presidential Proclamation of <date date="1929-06-25">June 25, 1929</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/46/3000">46 Stat. 3000</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> the Compact;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> the Act of <date date="1949-04-06">April 6, 1949</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/63/31">63 Stat. 31</ref>, chapter 48);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> the Jicarilla Apache Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/stat/106/2237">106 Stat. 2237</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> section 205 of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2005 (<ref href="/us/stat/118/2949">118 Stat. 2949</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Section 10403 <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out above, to be null and void on issuance of a court order terminating a certain Agreement between New Mexico, the Navajo Nation, and the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10701/e/2">section 10701(e)(2) of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out as an Agreement note below.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of Compact, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10302">section 10302 of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out as a Definitions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s407">section 407 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc9ffd227-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Agreement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tX/s10701">Pub. L. 111–11, title X, § 10701</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1396">123 Stat. 1396</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/57/s2/e">Pub. L. 114–57, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/528">129 Stat. 528</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/57/s2/e">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement Approval.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approval by congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Except to the extent that any provision of the Agreement conflicts with this subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 10301–10704) of title X of <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, see Effect on Federal Water Law note above], Congress approves, ratifies, and confirms the Agreement (including any amendments to the Agreement that are executed to make the Agreement consistent with this subtitle).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Execution by secretary</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall enter into the Agreement to the extent that the Agreement does not conflict with this subtitle, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any exhibits to the Agreement requiring the signature of the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any amendments to the Agreement necessary to make the Agreement consistent with this subtitle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may carry out any action that the Secretary determines is necessary or appropriate to implement the Agreement, the Contract, and this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration of navajo reservoir releases</inline>.—</heading><content>The State of New Mexico may administer water that has been released from storage in Navajo Reservoir in accordance with subparagraph 9.1 of the Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Water Available Under Contract.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quantities of water available.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Water shall be made available annually under the Contract for projects in the State of New Mexico supplied from the Navajo Reservoir and the San Juan River (including tributaries of the River) under New Mexico State Engineer File Numbers 2849, 2883, and 3215 in the quantities described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Water quantities</inline>.—</heading><content>The quantities of water referred to in subparagraph (A) are as follows:<html:table width="100%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2(4,4,4,4,0,0),tp0,p7,7/8,s100,7,7n,tp0,p7,7/8,s100,7,7n; " id="idc9ffd228-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 297pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 297.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:0.0pt solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"> </html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:0.0pt solid black; border-left:0.0pt solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Diversion (acre-feet/year)</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:0.0pt solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Depletion (acre-feet/year)</html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">Navajo Indian Irrigation Project</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">508,000</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">270,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">Navajo-Gallup Water Supply Project</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">22,650</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">20,780</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">Animas-La Plata Project</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">4,680</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">2,340</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">Total</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-right:0.0pt solid black; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">535,330</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; border-left:0.0pt solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">293,120</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum quantity</inline>.—</heading><content>A diversion of water to the Nation under the Contract for a project described in subparagraph (B) shall not exceed the quantity of water necessary to supply the amount of depletion for the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms, conditions, and limitations</inline>.—</heading><content>The diversion and use of water under the Contract shall be subject to and consistent with the terms, conditions, and limitations of the Agreement, this subtitle, and any other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments to contract</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary, with the consent of the Nation, may amend the Contract if the Secretary determines that the amendment is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> consistent with the Agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in the interest of conserving water or facilitating beneficial use by the Nation or a subcontractor of the Nation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rights of the nation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Nation may, under the Contract—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> use tail water, wastewater, and return flows attributable to a use of the water by the Nation or a subcontractor of the Nation if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the depletion of water does not exceed the quantities described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the use of tail water, wastewater, or return flows is consistent with the terms, conditions, and limitations of the Agreement, and any other applicable law; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> change a point of diversion, change a purpose or place of use, and transfer a right for depletion under this subtitle (except for a point of diversion, purpose or place of use, or right for depletion for use in the State of Arizona under section 10603(b)(2)(D) [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1383">123 Stat. 1383</ref>]), to another use, purpose, place, or depletion in the State of New Mexico to meet a water resource or economic need of the Nation if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the change or transfer is subject to and consistent with the terms of the Agreement, the Partial Final Decree described in paragraph 3.0 of the Agreement, the Contract, and any other applicable law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a change or transfer of water use by the Nation does not alter any obligation of the United States, the Nation, or another party to pay or repay project construction, operation, maintenance, or replacement costs under this subtitle and the Contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subcontracts.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subcontracts between nation and third parties</inline>.—</heading><content>The Nation may enter into subcontracts for the delivery of Project water under the Contract to third parties for any beneficial use in the State of New Mexico (on or off land held by the United States in trust for the Nation or a member of the Nation or land held in fee by the Nation).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approval required</inline>.—</heading><content>A subcontract entered into under subparagraph (A) shall not be effective until approved by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection and the Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submittal</inline>.—</heading><content>The Nation shall submit to the Secretary for approval or disapproval any subcontract entered into under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall approve or disapprove a subcontract submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (C) not later than the later of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the date that is 180 days after the date on which the subcontract is submitted to the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> the date that is 60 days after the date on which a subcontractor complies with—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332/2/C">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</ref>); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> any other requirement of Federal law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading><content>A party to a subcontract may enforce the deadline described in subparagraph (D) under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1361">section 1361 of title 28</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance with other law</inline>.—</heading><content>A subcontract described in subparagraph (A) shall comply with the Agreement, the Partial Final Decree described in paragraph 3.0 of the Agreement, and any other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No liability</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not be liable to any party, including the Nation, for any term of, or any loss or other detriment resulting from, a lease, contract, or other agreement entered into pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alienation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Permanent alienation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Nation shall not permanently alienate any right granted to the Nation under the Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum term</inline>.—</heading><content>The term of any water use subcontract (including a renewal) under this subsection shall be not more than 99 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonintercourse act compliance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> provides congressional authorization for the subcontracting rights of the Nation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is deemed to fulfill any requirement that may be imposed by section 2116 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s177">25 U.S.C. 177</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading><content>The nonuse of the water supply secured by a subcontractor of the Nation under this subsection shall not result in forfeiture, abandonment, relinquishment, or other loss of any part of a right decreed to the Nation under the Contract or this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No per capita payments</inline>.—</heading><content>No part of the revenue from a water use subcontract under this subsection shall be distributed to any member of the Nation on a per capita basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Water Leases Not Requiring Subcontracts.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority of nation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Nation may lease, contract, or otherwise transfer to another party or to another purpose or place of use in the State of New Mexico (on or off land that is held by the United States in trust for the Nation or a member of the Nation or held in fee by the Nation) a water right that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> is decreed to the Nation under the Agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> is not subject to the Contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance with other law</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out an action under this subsection, the Nation shall comply with the Agreement, the Partial Final Decree described in paragraph 3.0 of the Agreement, the Supplemental Partial Final Decree described in paragraph 4.0 of the Agreement, and any other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alienation; maximum term.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alienation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Nation shall not permanently alienate any right granted to the Nation under the Agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum term</inline>.—</heading><content>The term of any water use lease, contract, or other arrangement (including a renewal) under this subsection shall be not more than 99 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No liability</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not be liable to any party, including the Nation, for any term of, or any loss or other detriment resulting from, a lease, contract, or other agreement entered into pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonintercourse act compliance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> provides congressional authorization for the lease, contracting, and transfer of any water right described in paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is deemed to fulfill any requirement that may be imposed by the provisions of section 2116 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s177">25 U.S.C. 177</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading><content>The nonuse of a water right of the Nation by a lessee or contractor to the Nation under this subsection shall not result in forfeiture, abandonment, relinquishment, or other loss of any part of a right decreed to the Nation under the Contract or this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nullification.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadlines.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out this section, the following deadlines apply with respect to implementation of the Agreement:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall execute the Agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contract</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, the Secretary and the Nation shall execute the Contract.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Partial final decree</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2013-12-31">December 31, 2013</date>, the court in the stream adjudication shall have entered the Partial Final Decree described in paragraph 3.0 of the Agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fruitland-cambridge irrigation project</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>, the rehabilitation construction of the Fruitland-Cambridge Irrigation Project authorized under section 10607(a)(1) [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1394">123 Stat. 1394</ref>] shall be completed.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Supplemental partial final decree</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>, the court in the stream adjudication shall enter the Supplemental Partial Final Decree described in subparagraph 4.0 of the Agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hogback-cudei irrigation project</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>, the rehabilitation construction of the Hogback-Cudei Irrigation Project authorized under section 10607(a)(2) [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1394">123 Stat. 1394</ref>] shall be completed.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trust fund</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>, the United States shall make all deposits into the Trust Fund under section 10702 [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1402">123 Stat. 1402</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="viii">“(viii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conjunctive wells</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>, the funds authorized to be appropriated under section 10609(b)(1) [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1395">123 Stat. 1395</ref>] for the conjunctive use wells authorized under section 10606(b) [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1393">123 Stat. 1393</ref>] should be appropriated.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ix">“(ix)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Navajo-gallup water supply project</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-12-31">December 31, 2024</date>, the construction of all Project facilities shall be completed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading><content>A deadline described in subparagraph (A) may be extended if the Nation, the United States (acting through the Secretary), and the State of New Mexico (acting through the New Mexico Interstate Stream Commission) agree that an extension is reasonably necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revocability of agreement, contract and authorizations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Petition</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Nation determines that a deadline described in paragraph (1)(A) is not substantially met, the Nation may submit to the court in the stream adjudication a petition to enter an order terminating the Agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>On issuance of an order to terminate the Agreement under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Trust Fund shall be terminated;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the balance of the Trust Fund shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the authorizations for construction and rehabilitation of water projects under this subtitle shall be revoked and any Federal activity related to that construction and rehabilitation shall be suspended; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> this part and parts I and III [parts IV (§§ 10701–10704), I (§§ 10401–10403), and III (§§ 10601–10609) of subtitle B of title X of <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, enacting former section 615jj and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s620n–1">section 620n–1 of this title</ref>, amending this section, former section 615ss, and section 620<i>o</i> of this title, repealing former <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s615jj">section 615jj of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] shall be null and void.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions not causing nullification of settlement.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If a condition described in subparagraph (B) occurs, the Agreement shall not be nullified or terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The conditions referred to in subparagraph (A) are as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> A lack of right to divert at the capacities of conjunctive use wells constructed or rehabilitated under section 10606 [<ref href="/us/stat/123/1392">123 Stat. 1392</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> A failure—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> to determine or resolve an accounting of the use of water under this subtitle in the State of Arizona;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> to obtain a necessary water right for the consumptive use of water in Arizona;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> to contract for the delivery of water for use in Arizona; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="IV">     “(IV)</num><content> to construct and operate a lateral facility to deliver water to a community of the Nation in Arizona, under the Project.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on Rights of Indian Tribes.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in the Agreement, the Contract, or this section quantifies or adversely affects the land and water rights, or claims or entitlements to water, of any Indian tribe or community other than the rights, claims, or entitlements of the Nation in, to, and from the San Juan River Basin in the State of New Mexico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The right of the Nation to use water under water rights the Nation has in other river basins in the State of New Mexico shall be forborne to the extent that the Nation supplies the uses for which the water rights exist by diversions of water from the San Juan River Basin under the Project consistent with subparagraph 9.13 of the Agreement.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10701">section 10701 of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/s10302">section 10302 of Pub. L. 111–11</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s407">section 407 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
