<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca021c80-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s620m"><num value="620m">§ 620m.</num><heading> Compliance with law required in operation of facilities; enforcement of provisions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the operation and maintenance of all facilities, authorized by Federal law and under the jurisdiction and supervision of the Secretary of the Interior, in the basin of the Colorado River, the Secretary of the Interior is directed to comply with the applicable provisions of the Colorado River Compact, the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact, the Boulder Canyon Project Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s617">43 U.S.C. 617</ref> et seq.], the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s618">43 U.S.C. 618</ref> et seq.], and the Treaty with the United Mexican States, in the storage and release of water from reservoirs in the Colorado River Basin. In the event of the failure of the Secretary of the Interior to so comply, any State of the Colorado River Basin may maintain an action in the Supreme Court of the United States to enforce the provisions of this section, and consent is given to the joinder of the United States as a party in such suit or suites, as a defendant or otherwise.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca021c81-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-04-11/ch203/s14">Apr. 11, 1956, ch. 203, § 14</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/110">70 Stat. 110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca021c82-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca021c83-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca021c84-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Boulder Canyon Project Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1928-12-21/ch42">act Dec. 21, 1928, ch. 42</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1057">45 Stat. 1057</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 617 et seq.) of chapter 12A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s617t">section 617t of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1940-07-19/ch643">act July 19, 1940, ch. 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/774">54 Stat. 774</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 618 et seq.) of chapter 12A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 618<i>o</i> of this title and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
