<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idca1a11b8-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598" identifier="/us/usc/t43/s981"><num value="981">§ 981.</num><heading> Indemnity to States on sale of lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon proof by the authorized agent of the State, before the Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate, that any of the lands purchased by any person from the United States, prior to <date date="1855-03-02">March 2, 1855</date>, were “swamp lands”, within the true intent and meaning of the Act entitled “An Act to enable the State of Arkansas and other States to reclaim the swamp lands within their limits”, approved <date date="1850-09-28">September 28, 1850</date>, the purchase money shall be paid over to the State wherein said land is situate; and when the lands have been located by warrant or scrip, the said State shall be authorized to locate a like quantity of any of the public lands subject to entry, at $1.25 per acre, or less, and patents shall issue therefor. The decision of the Secretary or such officer shall be first approved by the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idca1a11b9-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">(R.S. § 2482; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7876, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idca1a11ba-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idca1a11bb-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idca1a11bc-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act approved <date date="1850-09-28">September 28, 1850</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1850-09-28/ch84">act Sept. 28, 1850, ch. 84</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/9/519">9 Stat. 519</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idca1a11bd-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2482 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1855-03-02/ch147/s2">act Mar. 2, 1855, ch. 147, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/10/634">10 Stat. 634</ref>, 635.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idca1a11be-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idca1a11bf-3a70-11f1-bde1-a5140e158598">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate” substituted for “Commissioner of the General Land Office” on authority of section 403 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1946, which abolished General Land Office and Commissioner thereof and transferred functions of General Land Office to a new agency in Department of the Interior to be known as Bureau of Land Management. See section 403 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1946, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
