<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78ecc30e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1152"><num value="1152">§ 1152.</num><heading> Prohibitions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful, except as provided in this chapter or by regulation of the Secretary, for any person or vessel subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to engage in the taking of fur seals in the North Pacific Ocean or on lands or waters under the jurisdiction of the United States, or to use any port or harbor or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States for any purpose connected in any way with such taking, or for any person to transport, import, offer for sale, or possess at any port or place or on any vessel, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, fur seals or the parts thereof, including, but not limited to, raw, dressed, or dyed fur seal skins, taken contrary to the provisions of this chapter or the Convention, or for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to refuse to permit, except within the Exclusive Economic Zone of the United States, a duly authorized official of Canada, Japan, or Russia to board and search any vessel which is outfitted for the harvesting of living marine resources and which is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to determine whether such vessel is engaged in sealing contrary to the provisions of said Convention.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78ecc30f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/702/tI/s102">Pub. L. 89–702, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1091">80 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/129/s2">Pub. L. 98–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-10-14">Oct. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/836">97 Stat. 836</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/tVI/s602/2">Pub. L. 103–199, title VI, § 602(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2327">107 Stat. 2327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78ecc310-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78ecc311-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78ecc312-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/199">Pub. L. 103–199</ref> substituted “Russia” for “the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/129">Pub. L. 98–129</ref> amended section generally, substituting provisions enumerating the activities prohibited under this chapter, which were previously contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref>, for provisions authorizing sealing by Aleuts, Eskimos, and Indians. See <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1153">section 1153 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
