<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78ef344e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1162"><num value="1162">§ 1162.</num><heading> Authority of Secretary to operate, maintain, and repair Government-owned property; necessary facilities, services, and equipment for Federal employees and dependents</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78ef344f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1162/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to operate, maintain, and repair such Government-owned property, both real and personal, and other facilities held by the Secretary on the Pribilof Islands as may be necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78ef3450-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1162/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to provide the employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies and their dependents, at reasonable rates to be determined by the Secretary, with such facilities, services, and equipment as he deems necessary, including, but not limited to, food, fuel, shelter, and transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id78ef3451-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/702/tII/s202">Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1093">80 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/129/s2">Pub. L. 98–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-10-14">Oct. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/838">97 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78ef3452-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78ef3453-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78ef3454-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/129">Pub. L. 98–129</ref> substituted provisions authorizing the Secretary to operate, maintain, and repair such Government-owned property, both real and personal, and other facilities held by the Secretary on the Pribilof Islands as may be necessary, and to provide the employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies and their dependents, at reasonable rates to be determined by the Secretary, with such facilities, services, and equipment as he deems necessary, including, but not limited to, food, fuel, shelter, and transportation, for provisions authorizing the Secretary to enter into contracts or agreements or leases with, or to issue permits to, public or private agencies or persons, including the natives of the Pribilof Islands, in accordance with such terms and conditions as he deemed desirable for the use of any Government-owned real or personal property located on the islands, for the furnishing of accommodations for tourists and other visitors, for educational, recreational, residential, or commercial purposes, for the operation, maintenance, and repair of Government-owned facilities and utilities, for the transportation and storage of food and other supplies, and for such other purposes as the Secretary deemed desirable.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
