<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78ef345a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1164"><num value="1164">§ 1164.</num><heading> Responsibility of Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide medical and dental care to Pribilof Islands natives</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide medical and dental care to the Natives of the Pribilof Islands with or without reimbursement, as provided by other law. He is authorized to provide such care to Federal employees and their dependents and tourists and other persons in the Pribilof Islands at reasonable rates to be determined by him. He may purchase, lease, construct, operate, and maintain such facilities, supplies, and equipment as he deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this section; and the costs of such items, including medical and dental care, shall be charged to the budget of the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as superseding or limiting the authority and responsibility of the Secretary of Health and Human Services under the Act of <date date="1954-08-05">August 5, 1954</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2001">42 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.], or any other law with respect to medical and dental care of natives or other persons in the Pribilof Islands.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78ef345b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/702/tII/s204">Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1094">80 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/129/s2">Pub. L. 98–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-10-14">Oct. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/839">97 Stat. 839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78ef345c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78ef345d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78ef345e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1954-08-05">August 5, 1954</date>, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-05/ch658">act Aug. 5, 1954, ch. 658</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/674">68 Stat. 674</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 2001 et seq.) of chapter 22 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78ef345f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/129">Pub. L. 98–129</ref> substituted provisions formerly set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1165">section 1165 of this title</ref> relating to medical and dental care of the natives of the Pribilof Islands for provisions which had authorized the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Governor of the State of Alaska pursuant to which the State assumed full responsibility for furnishing education to the natives of the Pribilof Islands and also to enter into agreements with said Governor pursuant to which the State furnished to such natives adequate food, shelter, transportation, and such other facilities, services, and equipment as the Secretary deemed necessary, with the State of Alaska, in assuming such responsibility, to meet the educational needs of the said natives in the same manner as the State met the educational needs of all of its citizens, including the furnishing of necessary facilities therefor.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
