<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78f17e34-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1222"><num value="1222">§ 1222.</num><heading> General study and inventory of estuaries and their natural resources</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78f17e35-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1222/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Estuaries included; considerations; other applicable studies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation and in cooperation with the States, the Secretary of the Army, and other Federal agencies, shall conduct directly or by contract a study and inventory of the Nation’s estuaries, including without limitation coastal marshlands, bays, sounds, seaward areas, lagoons, and land and waters of the Great Lakes. For the purpose of this study, the Secretary shall consider, among other matters, (1) their wildlife and recreational potential, their ecology, their value to the marine, anadromous, and shell fisheries and their esthetic value, (2) their importance to navigation, their value for flood, hurricane, and erosion control, their mineral value, and the value of submerged lands underlying the waters of the estuaries, and (3) the value of such areas for more intensive development for economic use as part of urban developments and for commercial and industrial developments. This study and inventory shall be carried out in conjunction with the comprehensive estuarine pollution study authorized by section 5(g) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254/n">33 U.S.C. 1254(n)</ref>], and other applicable studies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78f17e36-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1222/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal or State land acquisition or administration; other protective methods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The study shall focus attention on whether any land or water area within an estuary and the Great Lakes should be acquired or administered by the Secretary or by a State or local subdivision thereof, or whether such land or water area may be protected adequately through local, State, or Federal laws or other methods without Federal land acquisition or administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78f17e37-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1222/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress; recommendations; authorization for acquisition of lands; consultation with States and Federal agencies; accompanying statement of views, probable effects, and major trends</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall, not later than <date date="1970-01-30">January 30, 1970</date>, submit to the Congress through the President a report of the study conducted pursuant to this section, together with any legislative recommendations, including recommendations on the feasibility and desirability of establishing a nationwide system of estuarine areas, the terms, conditions, and authorities to govern such system, and the designation and acquisition of any specific estuarine areas of national significance which he believes should be acquired by the United States. No lands within such area may be acquired until authorized by subsequent Act of Congress. Recommendations made by the Secretary for the acquisition of any estuarine area shall be developed in consultation with the States, municipalities, and other interested Federal agencies. Each such recommendation shall be accompanied by (1) expressions of any views which the interested States, municipalities, and other Federal agencies and river basin commissions may submit within sixty days after having been notified of the proposed recommendations, (2) a statement setting forth the probable effect of the recommended action on any comprehensive river basin plan that may have been adopted by Congress or that is serving as a guide for coordinating Federal programs in the basin wherein such area is located, (3) in the absence of such a plan, a statement indicating the probable effect of the recommended action on alternative beneficial users of the resources of the proposed estuarine area, and (4) a discussion of the major economic, social, and ecological trends occurring in such area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78f17e38-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1222/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $250,000 for fiscal year 1969 and $250,000 for fiscal year 1970 to carry out the provisions of this section. Such sums shall be available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78f17e39-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/454/s2">Pub. L. 90–454, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-08-03">Aug. 3, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/626">82 Stat. 626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78f17e3a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78f17e3b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78f17e3c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5(g) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, referred to in text, was originally classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s466c/g">section 466c(g) of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters. Section 5(g) of the Act was redesignated as section 5(m) by sec. 105(<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/pl/91/224">Pub. L. 91–224</ref>, <date date="1970-04-03">Apr. 3, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/111">84 Stat. 111</ref>, and was reclassified to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1155/m">section 1155(m) of Title 33</ref>. The Federal Water Pollution Control Act was amended generally by sec. 2 of <ref href="/us/pl/92/500">Pub. L. 92–500</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/816">86 Stat. 816</ref>, and the provisions relating to comprehensive estuarine pollution study are contained in section 104(n), which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254/n">section 1254(n) of Title 33</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
