<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78fd6534-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1251"><num value="1251">§ 1251.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78fd6535-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1251/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “high potential historic sites” means those historic sites related to the route, or sites in close proximity thereto, which provide opportunity to interpret the historic significance of the trail during the period of its major use. Criteria for consideration as high potential sites include historic significance, presence of visible historic remnants, scenic quality, and relative freedom from intrusion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78fd6536-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1251/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “high potential route segments” means those segments of a trail which would afford high quality recreation experience in a portion of the route having greater than average scenic values or affording an opportunity to vicariously share the experience of the original users of a historic route.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78fd6537-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1251/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78fd6538-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1251/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “without expense to the United States” means that no funds may be expended by Federal agencies for the development of trail related facilities or for the acquisition of lands or interests in lands outside the exterior boundaries of Federal areas. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, amounts made available to any State or political subdivision under chapter 2003 of title 54 or any other provision of law shall not be treated as an expense to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id78fd6539-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/543/s12">Pub. L. 90–543, § 12</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/11/tII/s210">Pub. L. 98–11, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1983-03-28">Mar. 28, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/50">97 Stat. 50</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5/d/28">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(28)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3267">128 Stat. 3267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78fd653a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78fd653b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78fd653c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref> substituted “chapter 2003 of title 54” for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78fd653d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78fd653e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
