<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7912e890-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280"><num value="1280">§ 1280.</num><heading> Federal mining and mineral leasing laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e891-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability to components of system</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall affect the applicability of the United States mining and mineral leasing laws within components of the national wild and scenic rivers system except that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7912e892-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280/a/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> all prospecting, mining operations, and other activities on mining claims which, in the case of a component of the system designated in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1274">section 1274 of this title</ref>, have not heretofore been perfected or which, in the case of a component hereafter designated pursuant to this chapter or any other Act of Congress, are not perfected before its inclusion in the system and all mining operations and other activities under a mineral lease, license, or permit issued or renewed after inclusion of a component in the system shall be subject to such regulations as the Secretary of the Interior or, in the case of national forest lands, the Secretary of Agriculture may prescribe to effectuate the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7912e893-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280/a/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subject to valid existing rights, the perfection of, or issuance of a patent to, any mining claim affecting lands within the system shall confer or convey a right or title only to the mineral deposits and such rights only to the use of the surface and the surface resources as are reasonably required to carrying on prospecting or mining operations and are consistent with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior or, in the case of national forest lands, by the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7912e894-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280/a/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> subject to valid existing rights, the minerals in Federal lands which are part of the system and constitute the bed or bank or are situated within one-quarter mile of the bank of any river designated a wild river under this chapter or any subsequent Act are hereby withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the mining laws and from operation of the mineral leasing laws including, in both cases, amendments thereto.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Regulations issued pursuant to paragraphs (i) and (ii) of this subsection shall, among other things, provide safeguards against pollution of the river involved and unnecessary impairment of the scenery within the component in question.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e895-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1280/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal from appropriation of minerals in Federal river beds or bank areas; prospecting, leases, licenses, and permits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The minerals in any Federal lands which constitute the bed or bank or are situated within one-quarter mile of the bank of any river which is listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1276/a">section 1276(a) of this title</ref> are hereby withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the mining laws during the periods specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278/b">section 1278(b) of this title</ref>. Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed to forbid prospecting or the issuance of leases, licenses, and permits under the mineral leasing laws subject to such conditions as the Secretary of the Interior and, in the case of national forest lands, the Secretary of Agriculture find appropriate to safeguard the area in the event it is subsequently included in the system. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subsection or any other provision of this chapter, all public lands which constitute the bed or bank, or are within an area extending two miles from the bank of the river channel on both sides of the river segments referred to in paragraphs (77) through (88) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1276/a">section 1276(a) of this title</ref> are hereby withdrawn subject to valid existing rights, from all forms of appropriation under the mining laws and from operation of the mineral leasing laws including, in both cases, amendments thereto, during the periods specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278/b">section 1278(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7912e896-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/542/s9">Pub. L. 90–542, § 9</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/915">82 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tVI/s606/b">Pub. L. 96–487, title VI, § 606(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2416">94 Stat. 2416</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/590/tV/s507">Pub. L. 99–590, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3336">100 Stat. 3336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7912e897-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7912e898-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7912e899-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/590">Pub. L. 99–590</ref> substituted “issuance of leases” for “issuance or leases”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref> inserted provision withdrawing, subject to valid existing rights, all public lands which constitute the bed or bank, or are within an area extending two miles from the bank of the river channel or both sides of the river segments referred to in section 1276(a)(77) through (88) of this title, from all forms of appropriations under the mining laws and operation of the mineral leasing laws during the periods specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278/b">section 1278(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
