<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7912e89a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281"><num value="1281">§ 1281.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e89b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Public use and enjoyment of components; protection of features; management plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each component of the national wild and scenic rivers system shall be administered in such manner as to protect and enhance the values which caused it to be included in said system without, insofar as is consistent therewith, limiting other uses that do not substantially interfere with public use and enjoyment of these values. In such administration primary emphasis shall be given to protecting its esthetic, scenic, historic, archeologic, and scientific features. Management plans for any such component may establish varying degrees of intensity for its protection and development, based on the special attributes of the area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e89c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Wilderness areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any portion of a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system that is within the national wilderness preservation system, as established by or pursuant to the Wilderness Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.], shall be subject to the provisions of both the Wilderness Act and this chapter with respect to preservation of such river and its immediate environment, and in case of conflict between the provisions of the Wilderness Act and this chapter the more restrictive provisions shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e89d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Areas administered by National Park Service and Fish and Wildlife Service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any component of the national wild and scenic rivers system that is administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the National Park Service shall become a part of the national park system, and any such component that is administered by the Secretary through the Fish and Wildlife Service shall become a part of the national wildlife refuge system. The lands involved shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter and the Acts under which the national park system or national wildlife system, as the case may be, is administered, and in case of conflict between the provisions of this chapter and such Acts, the more restrictive provisions shall apply. The Secretary of the Interior, in his administration of any component of the national wild and scenic rivers system, may utilize such general statutory authorities relating to areas of the national park system and such general statutory authorities otherwise available to him for recreation and preservation purposes and for the conservation and management of natural resources as he deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e89e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Statutory authorities relating to national forests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture, in his administration of any component of the national wild and scenic rivers system area, may utilize the general statutory authorities relating to the national forests in such manner as he deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7912e89f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1281/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements with State and local governments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal agency charged with the administration of any component of the national wild and scenic rivers system may enter into written cooperative agreements with the Governor of a State, the head of any State agency, or the appropriate official of a political subdivision of a State for State or local governmental participation in the administration of the component. The States and their political subdivisions shall be encouraged to cooperate in the planning and administration of components of the system which include or adjoin State- or county-owned lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7912e8a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/542/s10">Pub. L. 90–542, § 10</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/916">82 Stat. 916</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7912e8a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7912e8a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7912e8a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilderness Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/577">Pub. L. 88–577</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">section 1131 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Acts under which the national park system and the national wildlife system are administered, referred to in subsec. (c), are classified generally to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7912e8a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first reference to the Wilderness Act in subsec. (b) was in the original a reference to the Act of <date date="1964-09-03">September 3, 1964</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7912e8a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7912e8a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Management of Segment of Salmon River Designated as Component of Wild and Scenic River System Located Within Frank Church—River of No Return Wilderness or Gospel-Hump Wilderness</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/312/s9/b">Pub. L. 96–312, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-23">July 23, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/953">94 Stat. 953</ref>, as amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/231/s1">Pub. L. 98–231, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-03-14">Mar. 14, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/60">98 Stat. 60</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/231/s1">“That segment of the main Salmon River designated as a component of the Wild and Scenic Rivers System by this Act [see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1274/a/24">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)(24)</ref>], which lies within the Frank Church—River of No Return Wilderness or the Gospel-Hump Wilderness designated by <ref href="/us/pl/95/237">Public Law 95–237</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/95/237/s4">Pub. L. 95–237, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-02-24">Feb. 24, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/43">92 Stat. 43</ref>], shall be managed under the provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1271">16 U.S.C. 1271</ref> et seq], and the regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, notwithstanding section 10(b) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1281/b">16 U.S.C. 1281(b)</ref>] or any provisions of the Wilderness Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.] to the contrary.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7912e8a7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7912e8a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of the Interior and Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278">section 1278 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
