<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id791559ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1305"><num value="1305">§ 1305.</num><heading> Renewal or extension of agreement; participation of subsequent owner or operator in program</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any agreement may be renewed or extended at the end of the agreement period for an additional period of ten years by mutual agreement of the Secretary and the owner or operator, subject to any rate redetermination by the Secretary. If during the agreement period the owner or operator sells or otherwise divests himself of the ownership or right of occupancy of such land, the new owner or operator may continue such agreement under the same terms or conditions, or enter into a new agreement in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, including the provisions for renewal and adjustment of payment rates, or he may choose not to participate in such program.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id79155a00-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/559/s6">Pub. L. 91–559, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1471">84 Stat. 1471</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79155a01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79155a02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79155a03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">One-Year Extension of Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/393">Pub. L. 103–393</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4105">108 Stat. 4105</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/393">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Water Bank Extension Act of 1994’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> SPECIAL AUTHORITY TO EXTEND WATER BANK ACT AGREEMENTS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Subject to subsection (b), any agreement entered into under the Water Bank Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1301">16 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.) and due to expire on <date date="1994-12-31">December 31, 1994</date>, may be extended for 1 year under section 6 of the Water Bank Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1305">16 U.S.C. 1305</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The authority to extend Water Bank Act agreements under this Act may only be exercised to the extent that the amount available for obligation under the Wetlands Reserve Program (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1637">16 U.S.C. 1637</ref> et seq.) [probably meant former <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3837">16 U.S.C. 3837</ref> et seq.], and the amount used for the extension of Water Bank Act agreements under subsection (a), does not exceed $93,200,000 as provided for the Wetlands Reserve Program under the Agricultural, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995 [<ref href="/us/pl/103/330">Pub. L. 103–330</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2453">108 Stat. 2453</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
