<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7925fc9e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389"><num value="1389">§ 1389.</num><heading> Pacific Coast Task Force; Gulf of Maine</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7925fc9f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Pinniped removal authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary may permit the intentional lethal taking of pinnipeds in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7925fca0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fca1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A State may apply to the Secretary to authorize the intentional lethal taking of individually identifiable pinnipeds which are having a significant negative impact on the decline or recovery of salmonid fishery stocks which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7925fca2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> have been listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7925fca3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary finds are approaching threatened species or endangered species status (as those terms are defined in that Act); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7925fca4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> migrate through the Ballard Locks at Seattle, Washington.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fca5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any such application shall include a means of identifying the individual pinniped or pinnipeds, and shall include a detailed description of the problem interaction and expected benefits of the taking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7925fca6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions in response to application</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fca7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 15 days of receiving an application, the Secretary shall determine whether the application has produced sufficient evidence to warrant establishing a Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force to address the situation described in the application. If the Secretary determines sufficient evidence has been provided, the Secretary shall establish a Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force and publish a notice in the Federal Register requesting public comment on the application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fca8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force established under paragraph (1) shall consist of designated employees of the Department of Commerce, scientists who are knowledgeable about the pinniped interaction that the application addresses, representatives of affected conservation and fishing community organizations, Indian Treaty tribes, the States, and such other organizations as the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fca9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Within 60 days after establishment, and after reviewing public comments in response to the Federal Register notice under paragraph (1), the Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7925fcaa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> recommend to the Secretary whether to approve or deny the proposed intentional lethal taking of the pinniped or pinnipeds, including along with the recommendation a description of the specific pinniped individual or individuals, the proposed location, time, and method of such taking, criteria for evaluating the success of the action, and the duration of the intentional lethal taking authority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7925fcab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> suggest nonlethal alternatives, if available and practicable, including a recommended course of action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7925fcac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Within 30 days after receipt of recommendations from the Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force, the Secretary shall either approve or deny the application. If such application is approved, the Secretary shall immediately take steps to implement the intentional lethal taking, which shall be performed by Federal or State agencies, or qualified individuals under contract to such agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286cad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> After implementation of an approved application, the Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force shall evaluate the effectiveness of the permitted intentional lethal taking or alternative actions implemented. If implementation was ineffective in eliminating the problem interaction, the Task Force shall recommend additional actions. If the implementation was effective, the Task Force shall so advise the Secretary, and the Secretary shall disband the Task Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In considering whether an application should be approved or denied, the Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force and the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286caf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> population trends, feeding habits, the location of the pinniped interaction, how and when the interaction occurs, and how many individual pinnipeds are involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> past efforts to nonlethally deter such pinnipeds, and whether the applicant has demonstrated that no feasible and prudent alternatives exist and that the applicant has taken all reasonable nonlethal steps without success;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the extent to which such pinnipeds are causing undue injury or impact to, or imbalance with, other species in the ecosystem, including fish populations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the extent to which such pinnipeds are exhibiting behavior that presents an ongoing threat to public safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cb3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall not approve the intentional lethal taking of any pinniped from a species or stock that is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> listed as a threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> depleted under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cb6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a strategic stock.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cb7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary marine mammal removal authority on the waters of the Columbia River or its tributaries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cb8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary may issue a permit to an eligible entity to authorize the intentional lethal taking on the waters of the Columbia River and its tributaries of individually identifiable sea lions that are part of a population or stock that is not categorized under this chapter as depleted or strategic for the purpose of protecting—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79286cb9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> species of salmon, steelhead, or eulachon that are listed as endangered species or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79286cba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> species of lamprey or sturgeon that are not so listed as endangered or threatened but are listed as a species of concern.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cbb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit process</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cbc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An eligible entity may apply to the Secretary for a permit under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cbd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Timelines and procedures of application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The timelines and procedures described in subsection (c) shall apply to applications for permits under this subsection in the same manner such timelines apply to applications under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cbe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish procedures to coordinate issuance of permits under this subsection, including application procedures and timelines, delegation and revocation of permits to and between eligible entities, monitoring, periodic review, and geographic, seasonal take, and species-specific considerations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cbf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration of permit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A permit under this subsection shall be effective for a period of not more than 5 years, and may be renewed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cc0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on annual takings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall apply the process for determining limitations on annual take of sea lions under subsection (c) to determinations on limitations under this subsection, and the cumulative number of sea lions authorized to be taken each year under all permits in effect under this subsection shall not exceed 10 percent of the annual potential biological removal level for sea lions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cc1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Intentional lethal takings under this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79286cc2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be humane within the meaning of such term under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1362/4">section 1362(4) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79286cc3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> require that capture, husbandry, transportation, and euthanasia protocols are based on standards propagated by an Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee and that primary euthanasia be limited to humane chemical methods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79286cc4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> be implemented by agencies or qualified individuals described in subsection (c)(4), or by individuals employed by the eligible entities described in paragraph (6).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cc5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of permitting authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, 5 years after <date date="2018-12-18">December 18, 2018</date>, the Secretary, after consulting with State and tribal fishery managers, determines that lethal removal authority is no longer necessary to protect salmonid and other fish species from sea lion predation, the Secretary shall suspend the issuance of permits under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cc6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entity defined</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cc7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this subsection, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79286cc8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> with respect to removal in the mainstem of the Columbia River, from river mile 112 to the McNary Dam and its tributaries in the State of Washington, and its tributaries in the State of Oregon above Bonneville Dam, the State of Washington, the State of Oregon, and the State of Idaho;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79286cc9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to removal in the mainstem Columbia River from river mile 112 to the McNary Dam and its tributaries within the State of Washington and in any of its tributaries above Bonneville Dam within the State of Oregon, the Nez Perce Tribe, the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs Reservation of Oregon, and the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Nation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79286cca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> with respect to removal in the Willamette River and other tributaries of the Columbia River within the State of Oregon below Bonneville Dam, a committee recognized by the Secretary under subparagraph (D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ccb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may allow eligible entities described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) to delegate their authority under a permit under this subsection to the Columbia River Intertribal Fish Commission for removal in the mainstem of the Columbia River above river mile 112 and below McNary Dam, in the Columbia River tributaries in the State of Washington, or in tributaries within the State of Oregon above Bonneville Dam and below McNary Dam.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ccc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional delegation authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may allow an eligible entity described in subparagraph (A)(i) to delegate its authority under a permit under this subsection to any entity described in subclause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) with respect to removal in the mainstem of the Columbia River above river mile 112 and below McNary Dam, in the Columbia River tributaries in the State of Washington, or in tributaries in the State of Oregon above Bonneville Dam and below McNary Dam.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ccd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Committee requirements</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall recognize a committee established in accordance with this subparagraph as being eligible for a permit under this subsection, for purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ccf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A committee established under this subparagraph shall consist of the State of Oregon and each of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79286cd0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The Confederated Tribes of Siletz Indians or the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community, or both.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79286cd1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs or the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Reservation, or both.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Majority agreement required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A committee established under this subparagraph may take action with respect to a permit application and removal under this subsection only with majority agreement by the committee members.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/6/D/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of FACA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002633">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002633"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> shall not apply to a committee established under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Individual exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, any sea lion located upstream of river mile 112 and downstream of McNary Dam, or in any tributary to the Columbia River that includes spawning habitat of threatened or endangered salmon or steelhead is deemed to be individually identifiable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Significant negative impact exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, any sea lion located in the mainstem of the Columbia River upstream of river mile 112 and downstream of McNary Dam, or in any tributary to the Columbia River that includes spawning habitat of threatened or endangered salmon or steelhead is deemed to be having a significant negative impact, within the meaning of subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/f/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cd7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Regionwide pinniped-fishery interaction study</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286cd8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may conduct a study, of not less than three high predation areas in anadromous fish migration corridors within the Northwest Region of the National Marine Fisheries Service, on the interaction between fish and pinnipeds. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consult with other State and Federal agencies with expertise in pinniped-fishery interaction. The study shall evaluate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cd9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> fish behavior in the presence of predators generally;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cda-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> holding times and passage rates of anadromous fish stocks in areas where such fish are vulnerable to predation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cdb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whether additional facilities exist, or could be reasonably developed, that could improve escapement for anadromous fish; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286cdc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> other issues the Secretary considers relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286cdd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may, not later than 18 months after the commencement of the study under this subsection, transmit a report on the results of the study to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286cde-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The study conducted under this subsection may not be used by the Secretary as a reason for delaying or deferring a determination or consideration under subsection (c) or (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286cdf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Gulf of Maine Task Force</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force to advise the Secretary on issues or problems regarding pinnipeds interacting in a dangerous or damaging manner with aquaculture resources in the Gulf of Maine. No later than 2 years from <date date="1994-04-30">April 30, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall after notice and opportunity for public comment submit to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing recommended available alternatives to mitigate such interactions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ce0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements applicable to task forces</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286ce1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any task force established under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286ce2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall to the maximum extent practicable, consist of an equitable balance among representatives of resource user interests and nonuser interests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79286ce3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286ce4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Meetings of any task force established under this section shall be open to the public, and prior notice of those meetings shall be given to the public by the task force in a timely fashion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79286ce5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Gulf of Maine harbor porpoise</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286ce6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1386">section 1386 of this title</ref> shall prevent the Secretary from publishing a stock assessment for Gulf of Maine harbor porpoise in an expedited fashion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79286ce7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1389/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In developing and implementing a take reduction plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1387">section 1387 of this title</ref> for Gulf of Maine harbor porpoise, the Secretary shall consider all actions already taken to reduce incidental mortality and serious injury of such stock, and may, based on the recommendations of the take reduction team for such stock, modify the time period required for compliance with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1387/f/5/A">section 1387(f)(5)(A) of this title</ref>, but in no case may such modification extend the date of compliance beyond <date date="1997-04-01">April 1, 1997</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79286ce8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/522/tI/s120">Pub. L. 92–522, title I, § 120</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/238/s23">Pub. L. 103–238, § 23</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/562">108 Stat. 562</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/329/s3">Pub. L. 115–329, § 3</ref>, <date date="2018-12-18">Dec. 18, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4475">132 Stat. 4475</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/110">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(110)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4317">136 Stat. 4317</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79286ce9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79286cea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79286ceb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Endangered Species Act of 1973, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1)(A), (B), (e)(1), and (f)(1)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/884">87 Stat. 884</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 1531 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Advisory Committee Act, referred to in subsec. (f)(6)(D)(iv), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/463">Pub. L. 92–463</ref>, <date date="1972-10-06">Oct. 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/770">86 Stat. 770</ref>, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was substantially repealed and restated in chapter 10 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 5 by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref>, §§ 3(a), 7, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4197">136 Stat. 4197</ref>, 4361. For disposition of sections of the Act into chapter 10 of Title 5, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s101">section 101 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79286cec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (i)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 App. U.S.C.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/329">Pub. L. 115–329</ref> amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) related to a scientific investigation and report on the impact of California sea lions and Pacific harbor seals.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79286ced-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79286cee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives abolished and its jurisdiction transferred by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Resources of House of Representatives in case of provisions relating to fisheries, wildlife, international fishing agreements, marine affairs (including coastal zone management) except for measures relating to oil and other pollution of navigable waters, or oceanography by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b/3">section 1(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Resources of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79286cef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treaty Rights of Federally Recognized Indian Tribes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/329/s4">Pub. L. 115–329, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-12-18">Dec. 18, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4478">132 Stat. 4478</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/329/s4">“Nothing in this Act [see Short Title of 2018 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1361">section 1361 of this title</ref>] or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to enlarge, confirm, adjudicate, affect, or modify any treaty or other right of an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</ref>)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
