<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id792ab69d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1403"><num value="1403">§ 1403.</num><heading> Committee of Scientific Advisors on Marine Mammals</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792ab69e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1403/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; membership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall establish, within ninety days after its establishment, a Committee of Scientific Advisors on Marine Mammals (hereafter referred to in this subchapter as the “Committee”). Such Committee shall consist of nine scientists knowledgeable in marine ecology and marine mammal affairs appointed by the Chairman after consultation with the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Chairman of the National Academy of Sciences.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792ab69f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1403/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation; reimbursement for travel expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except for United States Government employees, members of the Committee shall each be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, for each day such member is engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Committee. Each member shall be reimbursed for travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792ab6a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1403/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with Commission on studies and recommendations; explanation for nonadoption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall consult with the Committee on all studies and recommendations which it may propose to make or has made, on research programs conducted or proposed to be conducted under the authority of this chapter, and on all applications for permits for scientific research. Any recommendations made by the Committee or any of its members which are not adopted by the Commission shall be transmitted by the Commission to the appropriate Federal agency and to the appropriate committees of Congress with a detailed explanation of the Commission’s reasons for not accepting such recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id792ab6a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/522/tII/s203">Pub. L. 92–522, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1972-10-21">Oct. 21, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1044">86 Stat. 1044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id792ab6a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id792ab6a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id792ab6a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of the sixty-day period following <date date="1972-10-21">Oct. 21, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/522/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 92–522</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1361">section 1361 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id792ab6a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id792ab6a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
