<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7708c133-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s141a"><num value="141a">§ 141a.</num><heading> Revision of boundaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The boundary of the Wind Cave National Park is established as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning at the southeast corner of section 13, township 6 south, range 5 east; thence west to the southwest corner of section 15, township 6 south, range 5 east; thence north to the west quarter corner of section 10, township 6 south, range 5 east; thence to the north quarter corner of section 10, township 6 south, range 5 east; thence to the west quarter corner of section 2, township 6 south, range 5 east; thence north to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of the northwest quarter of section 11, township 5 south, range 5 east; thence to the north quarter corner of section 11, township 5 south, range 5 east; thence to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the southeast quarter of section 2, township 5 south, range 5 east; thence east to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of section 6, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence in a southeasterly direction to the southeast corner of the northeast quarter of section 7, township 5 south, range 6 east along a line to be mutually acceptable to the South Dakota Game, Fish, and Parks Commission and the Secretary of the Interior; thence from the southeast corner of the northeast quarter of section 7, township 5 south, range 6 east; east to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of section 12, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence south to the northeast corner of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of section 12, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence east to the northeast corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of section 7, township 5 south, range 7 east, thence south to the southeast corner of the southwest quarter of the southwest quarter of section 18, township 5 south, range 7 east; thence west to the northeast corner of section 24, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence south to the southeast corner of section 24, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence west to the southwest corner of section 24, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence south to the southeast corner of the northeast quarter of the southeast quarter of section 35, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence west to the southwest corner of the northwest quarter of the southwest quarter of section 35, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence south to the southeast corner of section 34, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence west to the southwest corner of the southeast quarter of the southwest quarter of section 33, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence north to the northeast corner of the northwest quarter of the southwest quarter of section 28, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence west to the northwest corner of the southwest quarter of section 29, township 5 south, range 6 east; thence south to the southeast corner of section 7, township 6 south, range 6 east; thence west to the southwest corner of section 7, township 6 south, range 6 east; thence south to the southeast corner of section 13, township 6 south, range 5 east; the point of beginning, and all of those lands lying within the boundary above described, together with the south half of the northeast quarter and the west half of the northeast quarter of the northeast quarter of section 32, township 5 south, range 5 east, are included in and made a part of the Wind Cave National Park and shall be subject to all laws and regulations applicable thereto.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7708c134-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1931-03-04/ch496">Mar. 4, 1931, ch. 496</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1518">46 Stat. 1518</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-09/ch935/s1">Aug. 9, 1946, ch. 935, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/970">60 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7708c135-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7708c136-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7708c137-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-08-09">Aug. 9, 1946</date>, revised the boundaries of the park.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7708c138-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7708c139-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Wind Cave National Park Boundary Revision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/71">Pub. L. 109–71</ref>, <date date="2005-09-21">Sept. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2011">119 Stat. 2011</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/71">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Wind Cave National Park Boundary Revision Act of 2005’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Map</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘map’ means the map entitled ‘Wind Cave National Park Boundary Revision’, numbered 108/80,030, and dated June 2002.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Park</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Park’ means the Wind Cave National Park in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ means the State of South Dakota.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> LAND ACQUISITION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may acquire the land or interest in land described in subsection (b)(1) for addition to the Park.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Means</inline>.—</heading><content>An acquisition of land under paragraph (1) may be made by donation, purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Boundary.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Map and acreage</inline>.—</heading><content>The land referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall consist of approximately 5,675 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of map</inline>.—</heading><content>The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision</inline>.—</heading><content>The boundary of the Park shall be adjusted to reflect the acquisition of land under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> ADMINISTRATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall administer any land acquired under section 3(a)(1) as part of the Park in accordance with laws (including regulations) applicable to the Park.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Administrative Jurisdiction.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall transfer from the Director of the Bureau of Land Management to the Director of the National Park Service administrative jurisdiction over the land described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Map and acreage</inline>.—</heading><content>The land referred to in paragraph (1) consists of the approximately 80 acres of land identified on the map as ‘Bureau of Land Management land’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> GRAZING.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grazing Permitted</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to any permits or leases in existence as of the date of acquisition, the Secretary may permit the continuation of livestock grazing on land acquired under section 3(a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Grazing under subsection (a) shall be at not more than the level existing on the date on which the land is acquired under section 3(a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purchase of Permit or Lease</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may purchase the outstanding portion of a grazing permit or lease on any land acquired under section 3(a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Leases or Permits</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may accept the voluntary termination of a permit or lease for grazing on any acquired land.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
