<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id792d277f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421"><num value="1421">§ 1421.</num><heading> Establishment of Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792d2780-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Marine Mammal Commission, and individuals with knowledge and experience in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, including stranding network participants, establish a program to be known as the “Marine Mammal Health and Stranding Response Program”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792d2781-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of the Program shall be to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id792d2782-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> facilitate the collection and dissemination of reference data on the health of marine mammals and health trends of marine mammal populations in the wild;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id792d2783-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> correlate the health of marine mammals and marine mammal populations, in the wild, with available data on physical, chemical, and biological environmental parameters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id792d2784-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1421/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> coordinate effective responses to unusual mortality events by establishing a process in the Department of Commerce in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1421c">section 1421c of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id792d2785-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/522/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 92–522, title IV, § 401</ref>, formerly title III, § 301, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/587/tIII/s3003/a">Pub. L. 102–587, title III, § 3003(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5060">106 Stat. 5060</ref>; renumbered title IV, § 401, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/238/s24/b">Pub. L. 103–238, § 24(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/565">108 Stat. 565</ref>, 566.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id792d2786-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id792d2787-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id792d2788-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/238/s24/c/1">Pub. L. 103–238, § 24(c)(1)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1421c">section 1421c of this title</ref> to reflect renumbering of corresponding section of original act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id792d2789-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id792d278a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/587/tIII/s3002">Pub. L. 102–587, title III, § 3002</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5060">106 Stat. 5060</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/587/tIII/s3002">
<inline>“The Congress finds the following:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Current stranding network participants have performed an undeniably valuable and ceaseless job of responding to marine mammal strandings over the last 15 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Insufficient understanding of the connection between marine mammal health and the physical, chemical, and biological parameters of their environment prevents an adequate understanding of the causes of marine mammal unusual mortality events.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An accurate assessment of marine mammal health, health trends in marine mammal populations in the wild, and causes of marine mammal unusual mortality events cannot be made without adequate reference data on marine mammals and the environment in which they live.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A systematic assessment of the sources, presence, levels, and effects of potentially harmful contaminants on marine mammals would provide a better understanding of some of the causes of marine mammal unusual mortality events and may serve as an indicator of the general health of our coastal and marine environments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Responses to marine mammal unusual mortality events are often uncoordinated, due to the lack of sufficient contingency planning.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Standardized methods for the reporting of dying, dead, or otherwise incapacitated marine mammals in the wild would greatly assist in the determination of the causes of marine mammal unusual mortality events and enhance general knowledge of marine mammal species.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> A formal system for collection, preparation, and archiving of, and providing access to, marine mammal tissues will enhance efforts to investigate the health of marine mammals and health trends of marine mammal populations, and to develop reference data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Information on marine mammals, including results of analyses of marine mammal tissues, should be broadly available to the scientific community, including stranding network participants, through a marine mammal data base.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
