<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79369e4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e"><num value="1447e">§ 1447e.</num><heading> Report on research program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79369e4e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation and submission of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Board receiving a grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1447d">section 1447d of this title</ref> shall, not later than 2 years after the approval of its comprehensive plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1447d">section 1447d of this title</ref> and at 2-year intervals thereafter, prepare and submit to the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency a report describing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79369e4f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the findings and conclusions of research projects conducted in the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79369e50-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> recommendations for improvements in the design or implementation of programs for the protection of the marine environment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79369e51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> available data and information concerning ecosystem health within the region.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79369e52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1447e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of a report prepared by a Board under subsection (a), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall transmit a copy of such report to the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79369e53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/532/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 92–532, title IV, § 406</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/593/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 101–593, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2969">104 Stat. 2969</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79369e54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79369e55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79369e56-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives abolished and its jurisdiction transferred by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Science of House of Representatives in case of provisions relating to marine research by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b/3">section 1(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Science of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Science and Technology of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Science and Technology of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Twelfth Congress, <date date="2011-01-05">Jan. 5, 2011</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
