<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79390ebc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1454"><num value="1454">§ 1454.</num><heading> Submittal of State program for approval</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any coastal state which has completed the development of its management program shall submit such program to the Secretary for review and approval pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">section 1455 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id79390ebd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/454/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 89–454, title III, § 305</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1282">86 Stat. 1282</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/612/s1/1">Pub. L. 93–612, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1974">88 Stat. 1974</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/370/s4">Pub. L. 94–370, § 4</ref>, <date date="1976-07-26">July 26, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1015">90 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVI/s6205">Pub. L. 101–508, title VI, § 6205</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-302">104 Stat. 1388–302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/587/tII/s2205/b/1/A">Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2205(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5050">106 Stat. 5050</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/150/s2/a">Pub. L. 104–150, § 2(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1996-06-03">June 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1380">110 Stat. 1380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79390ebe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79390ebf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79390ec0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/150/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 104–150, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Submittal of State program for approval” for “Management program development grants” in section catchline, struck out “(b)” before “Any coastal state”, and struck out subsec. (a) which read as follows: “In fiscal years 1997, 1998, and 1999, the Secretary may make a grant annually to any coastal state without an approved program if the coastal state demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the grant will be used to develop a management program consistent with the requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">section 1455 of this title</ref>. The amount of any such grant shall not exceed $200,000 in any fiscal year, and shall require State matching funds according to a 4-to-1 ratio of Federal-to-State contributions. After an initial grant is made to a coastal state pursuant to this subsection, no subsequent grant shall be made to that coastal state pursuant to this subsection unless the Secretary finds that the coastal state is satisfactorily developing its management program. No coastal state is eligible to receive more than four grants pursuant to this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/150/s2/a">Pub. L. 104–150, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted “1997, 1998, and 1999” for “1991, 1992, and 1993” and “four grants” for “two grants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/587">Pub. L. 102–587</ref> substituted “coastal state” for “coastal State” in last sentence of subsec. (a) and in subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> amended section generally, substituting present provisions for provisions which authorized management program development grants, established program requirements, set limits on grants, provided for grants for completion of development and implementation of management programs, provided for allocation of grants, reversion of unobligated grants, and grants to other political subdivisions, required submission of program for review and approval, and set forth an expiration date of grant authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> incorporated existing provisions into par. (1), limiting applicability of such provisions to subsec. (c), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> added pars. (7) to (9) and effective date provisions of such paragraphs after par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> substituted provision that grant should not exceed 80 per centum of a coastal state’s costs for purposes described in subsection (a)(1) of this section for provision that grant should not exceed 66⅔ per centum of the costs of the program in any one year, expanded to four the number of grants a state is eligible to receive pursuant to this subsection, and struck out provision that Federal funds received from other sources shall not be used to match such grants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> substituted provisions authorizing Secretary to make grants annually to any coastal state for purposes described in subsection (a)(2) and setting forth eligibility prerequisites for initial implementation grants for provisions, which were incorporated into subsec. (h), authorizing Secretary to review and approve the state’s submitted management program which on final approval terminates state’s eligibility under this section, but commences state’s eligibility under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">section 1455 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> restructured existing provisions into pars. (1) and (2), and as so restructured, substituted in provisions preceding par. (1) reference to shall be made to, and allocated among, the coastal states for reference to shall be allocated to the states, and in par. (1) inserted proviso relating to the waiver at the option of the Secretary of the 10 per centum maximum requirement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> substituted “The amount of any grant” for “Grant” and “the coastal state” for “a state”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> substituted “any coastal state” for “the state” and inserted “received by it” before “under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref> added subsec. (h) which incorporated provisions of former subsec. (d), redesignated former subsec. (h) as (i), and substituted “<date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/612">Pub. L. 93–612</ref> inserted proviso relating to the waiver by the Secretary of the 1 per centum minimum requirement upon request by the coastal state.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79390ec1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79390ec2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/150/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 104–150, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-06-03">June 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1380">110 Stat. 1380</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/150/s2/b/3">“This subsection [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1456a">section 1456a of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
