<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id793b8022-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b"><num value="1455b">§ 1455b.</num><heading> Protecting coastal waters</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8023-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8024-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Program development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 30 months after the date of the publication of final guidance under subsection (g), each State for which a management program has been approved pursuant to section 306 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</ref>] shall prepare and submit to the Secretary and the Administrator a Coastal Nonpoint Pollution Control Program for approval pursuant to this section. The purpose of the program shall be to develop and implement management measures for nonpoint source pollution to restore and protect coastal waters, working in close conjunction with other State and local authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8025-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Program coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State program under this section shall be coordinated closely with State and local water quality plans and programs developed pursuant to sections 1288, 1313, 1329, and 1330 of title 33 and with State plans developed pursuant to the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, as amended by this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.]. The program shall serve as an update and expansion of the State nonpoint source management program developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">section 1329 of title 33</ref>, as the program under that section relates to land and water uses affecting coastal waters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8026-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Program contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State program under this section shall provide for the implementation, at a minimum, of management measures in conformity with the guidance published under subsection (g), to protect coastal waters generally, and shall also contain the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8027-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Identifying land uses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The identification of, and a continuing process for identifying, land uses which, individually or cumulatively, may cause or contribute significantly to a degradation of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8028-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> those coastal waters where there is a failure to attain or maintain applicable water quality standards or protect designated uses, as determined by the State pursuant to its water quality planning processes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8029-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> those coastal waters that are threatened by reasonably foreseeable increases in pollution loadings from new or expanding sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Identifying critical coastal areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The identification of, and a continuing process for identifying, critical coastal areas adjacent to coastal waters referred to in paragraph (1)(A) and (B), within which any new land uses or substantial expansion of existing land uses shall be subject to management measures in addition to those provided for in subsection (g).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Management measures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The implementation and continuing revision from time to time of additional management measures applicable to the land uses and areas identified pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) that are necessary to achieve and maintain applicable water quality standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1313">section 1313 of title 33</ref> and protect designated uses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provision of technical and other assistance to local governments and the public for implementing the measures referred to in paragraph (3), which may include assistance in developing ordinances and regulations, technical guidance, and modeling to predict and assess the effectiveness of such measures, training, financial incentives, demonstration projects, and other innovations to protect coastal water quality and designated uses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Opportunities for public participation in all aspects of the program, including the use of public notices and opportunities for comment, nomination procedures, public hearings, technical and financial assistance, public education, and other means.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The establishment of mechanisms to improve coordination among State agencies and between State and local officials responsible for land use programs and permitting, water quality permitting and enforcement, habitat protection, and public health and safety, through the use of joint project review, memoranda of agreement, or other mechanisms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b802f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> State coastal zone boundary modification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A proposal to modify the boundaries of the State coastal zone as the coastal management agency of the State determines is necessary to implement the recommendations made pursuant to subsection (e). If the coastal management agency does not have the authority to modify such boundaries, the program shall include recommendations for such modifications to the appropriate State authority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8030-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Program submission, approval, and implementation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8031-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and approval</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 6 months after the date of submission by a State of a program pursuant to this section, the Secretary and the Administrator shall jointly review the program. The program shall be approved if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8032-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary determines that the portions of the program under the authority of the Secretary meet the requirements of this section and the Administrator concurs with that determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8033-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Administrator determines that the portions of the program under the authority of the Administrator meet the requirements of this section and the Secretary concurs with that determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8034-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of approved program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the program of a State is approved in accordance with paragraph (1), the State shall implement the program, including the management measures included in the program pursuant to subsection (b), through—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8035-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> changes to the State plan for control of nonpoint source pollution approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">section 1329 of title 33</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8036-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> changes to the State coastal zone management program developed under section 306 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, as amended by this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8037-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Withholding coastal management assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary finds that a coastal State has failed to submit an approvable program as required by this section, the Secretary shall withhold for each fiscal year until such a program is submitted a portion of grants otherwise available to the State for the fiscal year under section 306 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</ref>], as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8038-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 10 percent for fiscal year 1996.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8039-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 15 percent for fiscal year 1997.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b803a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 20 percent for fiscal year 1998.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b803b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> 30 percent for fiscal year 1999 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall make amounts withheld under this paragraph available to coastal States having programs approved under this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b803c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Withholding water pollution control assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Administrator finds that a coastal State has failed to submit an approvable program as required by this section, the Administrator shall withhold from grants available to the State under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">section 1329 of title 33</ref>, for each fiscal year until such a program is submitted, an amount equal to a percentage of the grants awarded to the State for the preceding fiscal year under that section, as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b803d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For fiscal year 1996, 10 percent of the amount awarded for fiscal year 1995.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b803e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For fiscal year 1997, 15 percent of the amount awarded for fiscal year 1996.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b803f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For fiscal year 1998, 20 percent of the amount awarded for fiscal year 1997.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8040-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> For fiscal year 1999 and each fiscal year thereafter, 30 percent of the amount awarded for fiscal year 1998 or other preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Administrator shall make amounts withheld under this paragraph available to States having programs approved pursuant to this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8041-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide technical assistance to coastal States and local governments in developing and implementing programs under this section. Such assistance shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8042-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> methods for assessing water quality impacts associated with coastal land uses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8043-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> methods for assessing the cumulative water quality effects of coastal development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8044-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> maintaining and from time to time revising an inventory of model ordinances, and providing other assistance to coastal States and local governments in identifying, developing, and implementing pollution control measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8045-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> methods to predict and assess the effects of coastal land use management measures on coastal water quality and designated uses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8046-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Inland coastal zone boundaries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8047-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall, within 18 months after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, review the inland coastal zone boundary of each coastal State program which has been approved or is proposed for approval under section 306 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</ref>], and evaluate whether the State’s coastal zone boundary extends inland to the extent necessary to control the land and water uses that have a significant impact on coastal waters of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8048-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, finds that modifications to the inland boundaries of a State’s coastal zone are necessary for that State to more effectively manage land and water uses to protect coastal waters, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall recommend appropriate modifications in writing to the affected State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8049-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon request of a State having a program approved under section 306 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</ref>], the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, may provide grants to the State for use for developing a State program under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The total amount of grants to a State under this subsection shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost to the State of developing a program under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> State share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The State share of the cost of an activity carried out with a grant under this subsection shall be paid from amounts from non-Federal sources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts available for grants under this subsection shall be allocated among States in accordance with regulations issued pursuant to section 306(c) of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455/c">16 U.S.C. 1455(c)</ref>], except that the Secretary may use not more than 25 percent of amounts available for such grants to assist States which the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, determines are making exemplary progress in preparing a State program under this section or have extreme needs with respect to coastal water quality.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance for coastal nonpoint source pollution control</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b804f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and other Federal agencies, shall publish (and periodically revise thereafter) guidance for specifying management measures for sources of nonpoint pollution in coastal waters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8050-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Content</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Guidance under this subsection shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8051-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of a range of methods, measures, or practices, including structural and nonstructural controls and operation and maintenance procedures, that constitute each measure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8052-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the categories and subcategories of activities and locations for which each measure may be suitable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8053-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an identification of the individual pollutants or categories or classes of pollutants that may be controlled by the measures and the water quality effects of the measures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8054-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> quantitative estimates of the pollution reduction effects and costs of the measures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8055-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a description of the factors which should be taken into account in adapting the measures to specific sites or locations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8056-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any necessary monitoring techniques to accompany the measures to assess over time the success of the measures in reducing pollution loads and improving water quality.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8057-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall publish—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8058-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> proposed guidance pursuant to this subsection not later than 6 months after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8059-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> final guidance pursuant to this subsection not later than 18 months after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b805a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and comment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall provide to coastal States and other interested persons an opportunity to provide written comments on proposed guidance under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b805b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Management measures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “management measures” means economically achievable measures for the control of the addition of pollutants from existing and new categories and classes of nonpoint sources of pollution, which reflect the greatest degree of pollutant reduction achievable through the application of the best available nonpoint pollution control practices, technologies, processes, siting criteria, operating methods, or other alternatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b805c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b805d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator for use for carrying out this section not more than $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1992, 1993, and 1994.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id793b805e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b805f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Of amounts appropriated to the Secretary for a fiscal year under section 318(a)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002653">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002653"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, as amended by this Act, not more than $1,000,000 shall be available for use by the Secretary for carrying out this section for that fiscal year, other than for providing in the form of grants under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8060-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for use for providing in the form of grants under subsection (f) not more than—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8061-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> $6,000,000 for fiscal year 1992;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8062-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> $12,000,000 for fiscal year 1993;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8063-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> $12,000,000 for fiscal year 1994; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id793b8064-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/h/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> $12,000,000 for fiscal year 1995.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793b8065-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8066-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8067-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “coastal State” has the meaning given the term “coastal state” under section 304 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8068-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> each of the terms “coastal waters” and “coastal zone” has the meaning that term has in the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b8069-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “coastal management agency” means a State agency designated pursuant to section 306(d)(6) of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455/d/6">16 U.S.C. 1455(d)(6)</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b806a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “land use” includes a use of waters adjacent to coastal waters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793b806b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/i/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id793b806c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVI/s6217">Pub. L. 101–508, title VI, § 6217</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-314">104 Stat. 1388–314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/587/tII/s2205/b/24">Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2205(b)(24)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5052">106 Stat. 5052</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id793b806d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id793b806e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id793b806f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (i)(3), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref> as added by <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1280">86 Stat. 1280</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 1451 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (c)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388">104 Stat. 1388</ref>, known as the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 318(a) of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, referred to in subsec. (h)(2)(A), which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1464/a">section 1464(a) of this title</ref>, was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/150/s4/1">Pub. L. 104–150, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-06-03">June 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1381">110 Stat. 1381</ref>, and, as so amended, does not contain a par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id793b8070-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Coastal Zone Act Reauthorization Amendments of 1990 and also as part of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990, and not as part of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id793b8071-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/587">Pub. L. 102–587</ref> struck out comma after “ ‘coastal waters’ ” and inserted “Zone” before “Management”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
