<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79403a64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462"><num value="1462">§ 1462.</num><heading> Coastal zone management reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79403a65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Biennial reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall consult with the Congress on a regular basis concerning the administration of this chapter and shall prepare and submit to the President for transmittal to the Congress a report summarizing the administration of this chapter during each period of two consecutive fiscal years. Each report, which shall be transmitted to the Congress not later than April 1 of the year following the close of the biennial period to which it pertains, shall include, but not be restricted to (1) an identification of the state programs approved pursuant to this chapter during the preceding Federal fiscal year and a description of those programs; (2) a listing of the states participating in the provisions of this chapter and a description of the status of each state’s programs and its accomplishments during the preceding Federal fiscal year; (3) an itemization of the allocation of funds to the various coastal states and a breakdown of the major projects and areas on which these funds were expended; (4) an identification of any state programs which have been reviewed and disapproved, and a statement of the reasons for such actions; (5) a summary of evaluation findings prepared in accordance with subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1458">section 1458 of this title</ref>, and a description of any sanctions imposed under subsections (c) and (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1458">section 1458 of this title</ref>; (6) a listing of all activities and projects which, pursuant to the provisions of subsection (c) or subsection (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1456">section 1456 of this title</ref>, are not consistent with an applicable approved state management program; (7) a summary of the regulations issued by the Secretary or in effect during the preceding Federal fiscal year; (8) a summary of a coordinated national strategy and program for the Nation’s coastal zone including identification and discussion of Federal, regional, state, and local responsibilities and functions therein; (9) a summary of outstanding problems arising in the administration of this chapter in order of priority; (10) a description of the economic, environmental, and social consequences of energy activity affecting the coastal zone and an evaluation of the effectiveness of financial assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1456a">section 1456a of this title</ref> in dealing with such consequences; (11) a description and evaluation of applicable interstate and regional planning and coordination mechanisms developed by the coastal states; (12) a summary and evaluation of the research, studies, and training conducted in support of coastal zone management; and (13) such other information as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79403a66-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations for legislation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall contain such recommendations for additional legislation as the Secretary deems necessary to achieve the objectives of this chapter and enhance its effective operation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79403a67-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of other Federal programs; report to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79403a68-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall conduct a systematic review of Federal programs, other than this chapter, that affect coastal resources for purposes of identifying conflicts between the objectives and administration of such programs and the purposes and policies of this chapter. Not later than 1 year after <date date="1980-10-17">October 17, 1980</date>, the Secretary shall notify each Federal agency having appropriate jurisdiction of any conflict between its program and the purposes and policies of this chapter identified as a result of such review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79403a69-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1462/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall promptly submit a report to the Congress consisting of the information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection. Such report shall include recommendations for changes necessary to resolve existing conflicts among Federal laws and programs that affect the uses of coastal resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79403a6a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/454/tIII/s316">Pub. L. 89–454, title III, § 316</ref>, formerly § 313, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1288">86 Stat. 1288</ref>; renumbered § 316 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/370">Pub. L. 94–370</ref>, §§ 7, 13, <date date="1976-07-26">July 26, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1019">90 Stat. 1019</ref>, 1030; <ref href="/us/pl/96/464/s10">Pub. L. 96–464, § 10</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2066">94 Stat. 2066</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/587/tII/s2205/b/23">Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2205(b)(23)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5052">106 Stat. 5052</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79403a6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79403a6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79403a6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/587">Pub. L. 102–587</ref> substituted “subsections (c) and (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1458">section 1458 of this title</ref>” for “subsections (c) and (d) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/464/s10/2">Pub. L. 96–464, § 10(2)</ref>, in provision preceding opening sentence, substituted provisions that the Secretary consult with Congress concerning the administration of this chapter and prepare and submit a biennial report to the President for transmittal to Congress for provisions that the Secretary prepare and submit to the President for transmittal to Congress an annual report for the preceding year not later than November 1 of each year, in cl. (4), substituted “reviewed and disapproved and a” for “reviewed and disapproved or with respect to which grants have been terminated under this chapter, and a”, added cl. (5), and redesignated cls. (5) to (12) as (6) to (13) respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/464/s10/3">Pub. L. 96–464, § 10(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/370/s13">Pub. L. 94–370, § 13</ref>, added cls. (9) to (11) and redesignated former cl. (9) as (12).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79403a6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79403a6f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (a) of this section relating to transmittal to Congress of a biennial report summarizing the administration of this chapter, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 53 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79403a70-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Shellfish Sanitation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/370/s16">Pub. L. 94–370, § 16</ref>, <date date="1976-07-26">July 26, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1032">90 Stat. 1032</ref>, required the Secretary of Commerce to undertake a comprehensive review of the molluscan shellfish industry, and evaluate the impact of Federal law concerning water quality on the industry, with a report due to Congress by <date date="1977-04-30">Apr. 30, 1977</date>, of the findings, comments, and recommendations from the review, with final regulations to be promulgated not before <date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7942ab71-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7942ab72-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Assignment of Reporting Function</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-08-05">Aug. 5, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 46397, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of Commerce</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby assign to you the functions of the President under section 316 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">16 U.S.C. 1451</ref>, <i>et seq</i>.).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
