<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7944f59d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533"><num value="1533">§ 1533.</num><heading> Determination of endangered species and threatened species</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7944f59e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Generally</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f59f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall by regulation promulgated in accordance with subsection (b) determine whether any species is an endangered species or a threatened species because of any of the following factors:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the present or threatened destruction, modification, or curtailment of its habitat or range;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> overutilization for commercial, recreational, scientific, or educational purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> disease or predation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the inadequacy of existing regulatory mechanisms; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> other natural or manmade factors affecting its continued existence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> With respect to any species over which program responsibilities have been vested in the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to Reorganization Plan Numbered 4 of 1970—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> in any case in which the Secretary of Commerce determines that such species should—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5a7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be listed as an endangered species or a threatened species, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be changed in status from a threatened species to an endangered species,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">he shall so inform the Secretary of the Interior; who shall list such species in accordance with this section;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> in any case in which the Secretary of Commerce determines that such species should—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be removed from any list published pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be changed in status from an endangered species to a threatened species,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">he shall recommend such action to the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of the Interior, if he concurs in the recommendation, shall implement such action; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Secretary of the Interior may not list or remove from any list any such species, and may not change the status of any such species which are listed, without a prior favorable determination made pursuant to this section by the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5ae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, by regulation promulgated in accordance with subsection (b) and to the maximum extent prudent and determinable—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall, concurrently with making a determination under paragraph (1) that a species is an endangered species or a threatened species, designate any habitat of such species which is then considered to be critical habitat; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may, from time-to-time thereafter as appropriate, revise such designation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall not designate as critical habitat any lands or other geographical areas owned or controlled by the Department of Defense, or designated for its use, that are subject to an integrated natural resources management plan prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s670a">section 670a of this title</ref>, if the Secretary determines in writing that such plan provides a benefit to the species for which critical habitat is proposed for designation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph affects the requirement to consult under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1536/a/2">section 1536(a)(2) of this title</ref> with respect to an agency action (as that term is defined in that section).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/a/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph affects the obligation of the Department of Defense to comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1538">section 1538 of this title</ref>, including the prohibition preventing extinction and taking of endangered species and threatened species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7944f5b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis for determinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall make determinations required by subsection (a)(1) solely on the basis of the best scientific and commercial data available to him after conducting a review of the status of the species and after taking into account those efforts, if any, being made by any State or foreign nation, or any political subdivision of a State or foreign nation, to protect such species, whether by predator control, protection of habitat and food supply, or other conservation practices, within any area under its jurisdiction; or on the high seas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give consideration to species which have been—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> designated as requiring protection from unrestricted commerce by any foreign nation, or pursuant to any international agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> identified as in danger of extinction, or likely to become so within the foreseeable future, by any State agency or by any agency of a foreign nation that is responsible for the conservation of fish or wildlife or plants.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall designate critical habitat, and make revisions thereto, under subsection (a)(3) on the basis of the best scientific data available and after taking into consideration the economic impact, the impact on national security, and any other relevant impact, of specifying any particular area as critical habitat. The Secretary may exclude any area from critical habitat if he determines that the benefits of such exclusion outweigh the benefits of specifying such area as part of the critical habitat, unless he determines, based on the best scientific and commercial data available, that the failure to designate such area as critical habitat will result in the extinction of the species concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5bc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5bd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To the maximum extent practicable, within 90 days after receiving the petition of an interested person under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553/e">section 553(e) of title 5</ref>, to add a species to, or to remove a species from, either of the lists published under subsection (c), the Secretary shall make a finding as to whether the petition presents substantial scientific or commercial information indicating that the petitioned action may be warranted. If such a petition is found to present such information, the Secretary shall promptly commence a review of the status of the species concerned. The Secretary shall promptly publish each finding made under this subparagraph in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5be-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Within 12 months after receiving a petition that is found under subparagraph (A) to present substantial information indicating that the petitioned action may be warranted, the Secretary shall make one of the following findings:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5bf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The petitioned action is not warranted, in which case the Secretary shall promptly publish such finding in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5c0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The petitioned action is warranted, in which case the Secretary shall promptly publish in the Federal Register a general notice and the complete text of a proposed regulation to implement such action in accordance with paragraph (5).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> The petitioned action is warranted, but that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the immediate proposal and timely promulgation of a final regulation implementing the petitioned action in accordance with paragraphs (5) and (6) is precluded by pending proposals to determine whether any species is an endangered species or a threatened species, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> expeditious progress is being made to add qualified species to either of the lists published under subsection (c) and to remove from such lists species for which the protections of this chapter are no longer necessary,</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">in which case the Secretary shall promptly publish such finding in the Federal Register, together with a description and evaluation of the reasons and data on which the finding is based.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A petition with respect to which a finding is made under subparagraph (B)(iii) shall be treated as a petition that is resubmitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A) on the date of such finding and that presents substantial scientific or commercial information that the petitioned action may be warranted.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any negative finding described in subparagraph (A) and any finding described in subparagraph (B)(i) or (iii) shall be subject to judicial review.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Secretary shall implement a system to monitor effectively the status of all species with respect to which a finding is made under subparagraph (B)(iii) and shall make prompt use of the authority under paragraph 7 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002658">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002658"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be paragraph “(7)”.</note> to prevent a significant risk to the well being of any such species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> To the maximum extent practicable, within 90 days after receiving the petition of an interested person under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553/e">section 553(e) of title 5</ref>, to revise a critical habitat designation, the Secretary shall make a finding as to whether the petition presents substantial scientific information indicating that the revision may be warranted. The Secretary shall promptly publish such finding in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Within 12 months after receiving a petition that is found under clause (i) to present substantial information indicating that the requested revision may be warranted, the Secretary shall determine how he intends to proceed with the requested revision, and shall promptly publish notice of such intention in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraphs (5) and (6) of this subsection, the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref> (relating to rulemaking procedures), shall apply to any regulation promulgated to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> With respect to any regulation proposed by the Secretary to implement a determination, designation, or revision referred to in subsection (a)(1) or (3), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> not less than 90 days before the effective date of the regulation—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> publish a general notice and the complete text of the proposed regulation in the Federal Register, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> give actual notice of the proposed regulation (including the complete text of the regulation) to the State agency in each State in which the species is believed to occur, and to each county, or equivalent jurisdiction in which the species is believed to occur, and invite the comment of such agency, and each such jurisdiction, thereon;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> insofar as practical, and in cooperation with the Secretary of State, give notice of the proposed regulation to each foreign nation in which the species is believed to occur or whose citizens harvest the species on the high seas, and invite the comment of such nation thereon;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> give notice of the proposed regulation to such professional scientific organizations as he deems appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> publish a summary of the proposed regulation in a newspaper of general circulation in each area of the United States in which the species is believed to occur; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> promptly hold one public hearing on the proposed regulation if any person files a request for such a hearing within 45 days after the date of publication of general notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Within the one-year period beginning on the date on which general notice is published in accordance with paragraph (5)(A)(i) regarding a proposed regulation, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> if a determination as to whether a species is an endangered species or a threatened species, or a revision of critical habitat, is involved, either—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a final regulation to implement such determination,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a final regulation to implement such revision or a finding that such revision should not be made,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> notice that such one-year period is being extended under subparagraph (B)(i), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> notice that the proposed regulation is being withdrawn under subparagraph (B)(ii), together with the finding on which such withdrawal is based; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7944f5db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> subject to subparagraph (C), if a designation of critical habitat is involved, either—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a final regulation to implement such designation, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7944f5dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> notice that such one-year period is being extended under such subparagraph.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5df-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> If the Secretary finds with respect to a proposed regulation referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) that there is substantial disagreement regarding the sufficiency or accuracy of the available data relevant to the determination or revision concerned, the Secretary may extend the one-year period specified in subparagraph (A) for not more than six months for purposes of soliciting additional data.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7944f5e0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If a proposed regulation referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) is not promulgated as a final regulation within such one-year period (or longer period if extension under clause (i) applies) because the Secretary finds that there is not sufficient evidence to justify the action proposed by the regulation, the Secretary shall immediately withdraw the regulation. The finding on which a withdrawal is based shall be subject to judicial review. The Secretary may not propose a regulation that has previously been withdrawn under this clause unless he determines that sufficient new information is available to warrant such proposal.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765e1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> If the one-year period specified in subparagraph (A) is extended under clause (i) with respect to a proposed regulation, then before the close of such extended period the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register either a final regulation to implement the determination or revision concerned, a finding that the revision should not be made, or a notice of withdrawal of the regulation under clause (ii), together with the finding on which the withdrawal is based.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> A final regulation designating critical habitat of an endangered species or a threatened species shall be published concurrently with the final regulation implementing the determination that such species is endangered or threatened, unless the Secretary deems that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> it is essential to the conservation of such species that the regulation implementing such determination be promptly published; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/6/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> critical habitat of such species is not then determinable, in which case the Secretary, with respect to the proposed regulation to designate such habitat, may extend the one-year period specified in subparagraph (A) by not more than one additional year, but not later than the close of such additional year the Secretary must publish a final regulation, based on such data as may be available at that time, designating, to the maximum extent prudent, such habitat.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> Neither paragraph (4), (5), or (6) of this subsection nor <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref> shall apply to any regulation issued by the Secretary in regard to any emergency posing a significant risk to the well-being of any species of fish or wildlife or plants, but only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> at the time of publication of the regulation in the Federal Register the Secretary publishes therein detailed reasons why such regulation is necessary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case such regulation applies to resident species of fish or wildlife, or plants, the Secretary gives actual notice of such regulation to the State agency in each State in which such species is believed to occur.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such regulation shall, at the discretion of the Secretary, take effect immediately upon the publication of the regulation in the Federal Register. Any regulation promulgated under the authority of this paragraph shall cease to have force and effect at the close of the 240-day period following the date of publication unless, during such 240-day period, the rulemaking procedures which would apply to such regulation without regard to this paragraph are complied with. If at any time after issuing an emergency regulation the Secretary determines, on the basis of the best appropriate data available to him, that substantial evidence does not exist to warrant such regulation, he shall withdraw it.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The publication in the Federal Register of any proposed or final regulation which is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter shall include a summary by the Secretary of the data on which such regulation is based and shall show the relationship of such data to such regulation; and if such regulation designates or revises critical habitat, such summary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, also include a brief description and evaluation of those activities (whether public or private) which, in the opinion of the Secretary, if undertaken may adversely modify such habitat, or may be affected by such designation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794765e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Lists</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior shall publish in the Federal Register a list of all species determined by him or the Secretary of Commerce to be endangered species and a list of all species determined by him or the Secretary of Commerce to be threatened species. Each list shall refer to the species contained therein by scientific and common name or names, if any, specify with respect to each such species over what portion of its range it is endangered or threatened, and specify any critical habitat within such range. The Secretary shall from time to time revise each list published under the authority of this subsection to reflect recent determinations, designations, and revisions made in accordance with subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct, at least once every five years, a review of all species included in a list which is published pursuant to paragraph (1) and which is in effect at the time of such review; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> determine on the basis of such review whether any such species should—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be removed from such list;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be changed in status from an endangered species to a threatened species; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> be changed in status from a threatened species to an endangered species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each determination under subparagraph (B) shall be made in accordance with the provisions of subsections (a) and (b).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794765f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Protective regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever any species is listed as a threatened species pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as he deems necessary and advisable to provide for the conservation of such species. The Secretary may by regulation prohibit with respect to any threatened species any act prohibited under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1">section 1538(a)(1) of this title</ref>, in the case of fish or wildlife, or <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2">section 1538(a)(2) of this title</ref>, in the case of plants, with respect to endangered species; except that with respect to the taking of resident species of fish or wildlife, such regulations shall apply in any State which has entered into a cooperative agreement pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1535/c">section 1535(c) of this title</ref> only to the extent that such regulations have also been adopted by such State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794765f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Similarity of appearance cases</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may, by regulation of commerce or taking, and to the extent he deems advisable, treat any species as an endangered species or threatened species even though it is not listed pursuant to this section if he finds that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/e/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such species so closely resembles in appearance, at the point in question, a species which has been listed pursuant to such section that enforcement personnel would have substantial difficulty in attempting to differentiate between the listed and unlisted species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/e/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the effect of this substantial difficulty is an additional threat to an endangered or threatened species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/e/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such treatment of an unlisted species will substantially facilitate the enforcement and further the policy of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794765f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall develop and implement plans (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as “recovery plans”) for the conservation and survival of endangered species and threatened species listed pursuant to this section, unless he finds that such a plan will not promote the conservation of the species. The Secretary, in developing and implementing recovery plans, shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> give priority to those endangered species or threatened species, without regard to taxonomic classification, that are most likely to benefit from such plans, particularly those species that are, or may be, in conflict with construction or other development projects or other forms of economic activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794765f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> incorporate in each plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a description of such site-specific management actions as may be necessary to achieve the plan’s goal for the conservation and survival of the species;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> objective, measurable criteria which, when met, would result in a determination, in accordance with the provisions of this section, that the species be removed from the list; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794765fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> estimates of the time required and the cost to carry out those measures needed to achieve the plan’s goal and to achieve intermediate steps toward that goal.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary, in developing and implementing recovery plans, may procure the services of appropriate public and private agencies and institutions, and other qualified persons. Recovery teams appointed pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall report every two years to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives on the status of efforts to develop and implement recovery plans for all species listed pursuant to this section and on the status of all species for which such plans have been developed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794765ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall, prior to final approval of a new or revised recovery plan, provide public notice and an opportunity for public review and comment on such plan. The Secretary shall consider all information presented during the public comment period prior to approval of the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79476600-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Each Federal agency shall, prior to implementation of a new or revised recovery plan, consider all information presented during the public comment period under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79476601-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79476602-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall implement a system in cooperation with the States to monitor effectively for not less than five years the status of all species which have recovered to the point at which the measures provided pursuant to this chapter are no longer necessary and which, in accordance with the provisions of this section, have been removed from either of the lists published under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79476603-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall make prompt use of the authority under paragraph 7 <sup>1</sup> of subsection (b) of this section to prevent a significant risk to the well being of any such recovered species.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79476604-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency guidelines; publication in Federal Register; scope; proposals and amendments: notice and opportunity for comments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish, and publish in the Federal Register, agency guidelines to insure that the purposes of this section are achieved efficiently and effectively. Such guidelines shall include, but are not limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79476605-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> procedures for recording the receipt and the disposition of petitions submitted under subsection (b)(3) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79476606-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> criteria for making the findings required under such subsection with respect to petitions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79476607-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a ranking system to assist in the identification of species that should receive priority review under subsection (a)(1) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79476608-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a system for developing and implementing, on a priority basis, recovery plans under subsection (f) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall provide to the public notice of, and opportunity to submit written comments on, any guideline (including any amendment thereto) proposed to be established under this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79476609-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1533/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to State agency of justification for regulations inconsistent with State agency’s comments or petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, in the case of any regulation proposed by the Secretary under the authority of this section, a State agency to which notice thereof was given in accordance with subsection (b)(5)(A)(ii) files comments disagreeing with all or part of the proposed regulation, and the Secretary issues a final regulation which is in conflict with such comments, or if the Secretary fails to adopt a regulation pursuant to an action petitioned by a State agency under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary shall submit to the State agency a written justification for his failure to adopt regulations consistent with the agency’s comments or petition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7947660a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/205/s4">Pub. L. 93–205, § 4</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/886">87 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/359/s1">Pub. L. 94–359, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-07-12">July 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/911">90 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/632">Pub. L. 95–632</ref>, §§ 11, 13, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3764">92 Stat. 3764</ref>, 3766; <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3</ref>, <date date="1979-12-28">Dec. 28, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1225">93 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1411">96 Stat. 1411</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/tI">Pub. L. 100–478, title I</ref>, §§ 1002–1004, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2306">102 Stat. 2306</ref>, 2307; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIII/s318">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1433">117 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/113">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(113)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4318">136 Stat. 4318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7947660b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7947660c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7947660d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 4 of 1970, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>, which is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(4), (8), (e)(C), and (g)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/884">81 Stat. 884</ref>, known as the Endangered Species Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II), was in the original “the Act” and was translated as if it read “this Act”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7947660e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s318/a">Pub. L. 108–136, § 318(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s318/b">Pub. L. 108–136, § 318(b)</ref>, inserted “the impact on national security,” after “the economic impact,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(3)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s1002/a">Pub. L. 100–478, § 1002(a)</ref>, added subcl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s1002/b">Pub. L. 100–478, § 1002(b)</ref>, substituted “regulation of commerce or taking,” for “regulation,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s1003">Pub. L. 100–478, § 1003</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) read as follows: “The Secretary shall develop and implement plans (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as ‘recovery plans’) for the conservation and survival of endangered species and threatened species listed pursuant to this section, unless he finds that such a plan will not promote the conservation of the species. The Secretary, in developing and implementing recovery plans (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, give priority to those endangered species or threatened species most likely to benefit from such plans, particularly those species that are, or may be, in conflict with construction or other developmental projects or other forms of economic activity, and (2) may procure the services of appropriate public and private agencies and institutions, and other qualified persons. Recovery teams appointed pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s1004">Pub. L. 100–478, § 1004</ref>, added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsecs. (g) and (h) as (h) and (i), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/1/B">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (D), inserted “promulgated in accordance with subsection (b)” after “shall by regulation” in introductory provisions preceding subpar. (A), and struck out provision following subpar. (E), which directed the Secretary, at the time regulations were proposed, to specify any habitat of a species considered to be a critical habitat but that such specification of critical habitats not apply to species listed prior to <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/1/A">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (1) as (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/1/A">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (C), redesignated subpar. (2) as (B) and substituted “recreational,” for “sporting,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/1/A">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (3), (4), and (5) as (C), (D), and (E), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/1/E">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(1)(E)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, completely revised subsec. (b) by, among other changes, requiring the Secretary to base determinations regarding the listing or delisting of species “solely” on the basis of the best scientific and commercial data available, streamlining the listing process by reducing the time periods for rulemaking, consolidating public meetings and hearing requirements, and establishing virtually identical procedures for the listing and delisting of species and for the designation of critical habitat, and altering the evidentiary standard which petitioners must satisfy to warrant a status review of the species proposed for listing or delisting.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/3/A">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(3)(A)</ref>, struck out “, and from time to time he may by regulation revise,” after “Federal Register” and inserted at end “The Secretary shall from time to time revise each list published under the authority of this subsection to reflect recent determinations, designations, and revisions made in accordance with subsections (a) and (b).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/3/B">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(3)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (4) as (2). Former par. (2), directing the Secretary, within 90 days of the receipt of the petition of an interested person under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553/e">section 553(e) of title 5</ref>, to conduct and publish in the Federal Register a review of the status of any listed or unlisted species proposed to be removed from or added to either of the lists published pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, but only if he made and published a finding that such person had presented substantial evidence which in his judgment warranted such a review, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/3/B">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(3)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which had provided that any list in effect on <date date="1973-12-27">Dec. 27, 1973</date>, of species of fish or wildlife determined by the Secretary of the Interior, pursuant to the Endangered Species Conservation Act of 1969, to be threatened with extinction be republished to conform to the classification for endangered species or threatened species, as the case might be, provided for in this chapter, but until such republication, any such species so listed was to be deemed an endangered species within the meaning of this chapter, and that the republication of any species pursuant to this paragraph did not require public hearing or comment under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/3/C">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(3)(C)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/4/A">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1535/c">section 1535(c) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1535/a">section 1535(a) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/4/B">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(4)(B)</ref>, (C), (D), redesignated subsec. (g) as (f) and substituted “recovery plans (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, give priority to those endangered species or threatened species most likely to benefit from such plans, particularly those species that are, or may be, in conflict with construction or other developmental projects or other forms of economic activity, and (2)” for “recovery plans,”. Former subsec. (f), relating to the promulgation of regulations, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/4/C">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(4)(C)</ref>, (E), redesignated subsec. (h) as (g), substituted reference to subsection (b)(3) of this section for reference to subsection (c)(2) of this section in par. (1), substituted “under subsection (a)(1) of this section” for “for listing” in par. (3), and substituted “subsection (f) of this section” for “subsection (g) of this section” in par. (4). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/a/4/C">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(a)(4)(C)</ref>, (F), added subsec. (h) and redesignated former subsec. (h) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3/1">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3(1)</ref>, required the Secretary’s determinations to be preceded with a review of the status of the species.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3/2">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3(2)</ref>, required publication of summary of text rather than of the complete text of proposed regulation specifying any critical habitat and inclusion of a map of the proposed critical habitat.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(B)(iv)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3/3">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3(3)</ref>, substituted “if requested within 15 days after the date on which the public meeting is conducted,” for “if requested,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3/4">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3(4)</ref>, (5), inserted in introductory text “, subsection (b)(4) of this section,”; and in cl. (ii), included reference to significant risk to wellbeing of any species of plants, inserted in item (II) reference to regulation applicable to resident species of plants, extended the statutory period to a “240-day period” from a “120-day period”, and provided for withdrawal of an emergency regulation without substantial evidence to warrant it, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s3/6">Pub. L. 96–159, § 3(6)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/1">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(1)</ref>, inserted provision requiring the Secretary, at the time a regulation is proposed, to specify by regulation any habitat of the species involved which is considered a critical habitat providing the species was listed subsequent to <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/7">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(7)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/2">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(2)</ref>, struck out “and shall” after “if any” and inserted “, and specify any critical habitat within such range” after “endangered or threatened”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/6">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(6)</ref>, substituted “within 90 days of the receipt of” for “upon” and “conduct and publish in the Federal Register a review of the status of” for “conduct a review of” and inserted a provision requiring that the review and findings be made and published prior to initiation of any procedures under subsec. (b)(1) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/3">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/4/A">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in” for “In”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/4/B">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(4)(B)</ref>, (C), added subpar. (B), redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C), and as so redesignated, substituted “Neither subparagraph (A) or (B)” for “Neither subparagraph (A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s13">Pub. L. 95–632, § 13</ref>, substituted “a summary by the Secretary of the data on which such regulation is based and shall show the relationship of such data to such regulations” for “a statement by the Secretary of the facts on which such regulation is based and the relationship of such facts to such regulation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/4/D">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(4)(D)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s11/5">Pub. L. 95–632, § 11(5)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (f)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/94/359">Pub. L. 94–359</ref> substituted “subsection (b)(1)(A)” for “subsection (b)(A), (B), and (C)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7947660f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79476610-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s2/b">Pub. L. 97–304, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1416">96 Stat. 1416</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/304/s2/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Any petition filed under section 4(c)(2) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 [subsec. (c)(2) of this section] (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>]) and any regulation proposed under section 4(f) of such Act of 1973 [subsec. (f) of this section] (as in effect on such day) that is pending on such date of enactment [<date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>] shall be treated as having been filed or proposed on such date of enactment under section 4(b) of such Act of 1973 [subsec. (b) of this section] (as amended by subsection (a)); and the procedural requirements specified in such section 4(b) [subsec. (b) of this section] (as so amended) regarding such petition or proposed regulation shall be deemed to be complied with to the extent that like requirements under such section 4 [this section] (as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act) were complied with before such date of enactment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any regulation proposed after, or pending on, the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>] to designate critical habitat for a species that was determined before such date of enactment to be endangered or threatened shall be subject to the procedures set forth in section 4 of such Act of 1973 [this section] (as amended by subsection (a)) for regulations proposing revisions to critical habitat instead of those for regulations proposing the designation of critical habitat.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any list of endangered species or threatened species (as in effect under section 4(c) of such Act of 1973 [subsec. (c) of this section] on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>]) shall remain in effect unless and until determinations regarding species and designations and revisions of critical habitats that require changes to such list are made in accordance with subsection (b)(5) of such Act of 1973 [subsec. (b)(5) of this section] (as added by subsection (a)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Section 4(a)(3)(A) of such Act of 1973 [subsec. (a)(3)(A) of this section] (as added by subsection (a)) shall not apply with respect to any species which was listed as an endangered species or a threatened species before <date date="1978-11-10">November 10, 1978</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79476611-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives abolished and its jurisdiction transferred by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Resources of House of Representatives in case of provisions relating to fisheries, wildlife, international fishing agreements, marine affairs (including coastal zone management) except for measures relating to oil and other pollution of navigable waters, or oceanography by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b/3">section 1(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Resources of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
