<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id794c21b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537"><num value="1537">§ 1537.</num><heading> International cooperation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794c21b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a demonstration of the commitment of the United States to the worldwide protection of endangered species and threatened species, the President may, subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1306">section 1306 of title 31</ref>, use foreign currencies accruing to the United States Government under the Food for Peace Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1691">7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.] or any other law to provide to any foreign country (with its consent) assistance in the development and management of programs in that country which the Secretary determines to be necessary or useful for the conservation of any endangered species or threatened species listed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>. The President shall provide assistance (which includes, but is not limited to, the acquisition, by lease or otherwise, of lands, waters, or interests therein) to foreign countries under this section under such terms and conditions as he deems appropriate. Whenever foreign currencies are available for the provision of assistance under this section, such currencies shall be used in preference to funds appropriated under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1542">section 1542 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794c21b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Encouragement of foreign programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out further the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary, through the Secretary of State, shall encourage—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794c21b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> foreign countries to provide for the conservation of fish or wildlife and plants including endangered species and threatened species listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794c21ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the entering into of bilateral or multilateral agreements with foreign countries to provide for such conservation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794c21bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> foreign persons who directly or indirectly take fish or wildlife or plants in foreign countries or on the high seas for importation into the United States for commercial or other purposes to develop and carry out with such assistance as he may provide, conservation practices designed to enhance such fish or wildlife or plants and their habitat.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794c21bc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794c21bd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assign or otherwise make available any officer or employee of his department for the purpose of cooperating with foreign countries and international organizations in developing personnel resources and programs which promote the conservation of fish or wildlife or plants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794c21be-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> conduct or provide financial assistance for the educational training of foreign personnel, in this country or abroad, in fish, wildlife, or plant management, research and law enforcement and to render professional assistance abroad in such matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794c21bf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1537/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate, the Secretary may conduct or cause to be conducted such law enforcement investigations and research abroad as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id794c21c0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/205/s8">Pub. L. 93–205, § 8</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/892">87 Stat. 892</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s5">Pub. L. 96–159, § 5</ref>, <date date="1979-12-28">Dec. 28, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1228">93 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/tIII/s3001/b/1/A">Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(N), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1820">122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id794c21c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id794c21c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id794c21c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Food for Peace Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1954-07-10/ch469">act July 10, 1954, ch. 469</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/454">68 Stat. 454</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 41 (§ 1691 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1691">section 1691 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (d), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/884">81 Stat. 884</ref>, known as the Endangered Species Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id794c21c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1306">section 1306 of title 31</ref>” substituted for “section 1415 of the Supplemental Appropriation Act, 1953 (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s724">31 U.S.C. 724</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id794c21c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> substituted “Food for Peace Act” for “Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s5/1">Pub. L. 96–159, § 5(1)</ref>, encouraged conservation of plants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s5/2">Pub. L. 96–159, § 5(2)</ref>, encouraged conservation practices for enhancement of plants taken for importation into the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s5/3">Pub. L. 96–159, § 5(3)</ref>, made personnel available for plant conservation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/159/s5/4">Pub. L. 96–159, § 5(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) relating to Convention implementation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id794c21c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id794c21c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/b">section 4(b) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id794c21c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conservation of Sea Turtles; Importation of Shrimp</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/162/tVI/s609">Pub. L. 101–162, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1037">103 Stat. 1037</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/162/tVI/s609">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall, with respect to those species of sea turtles the conservation of which is the subject of regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Commerce on <date date="1987-06-29">June 29, 1987</date>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> initiate negotiations as soon as possible for the development of bilateral or multilateral agreements with other nations for the protection and conservation of such species of sea turtles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> initiate negotiations as soon as possible with all foreign governments which are engaged in, or which have persons or companies engaged in, commercial fishing operations which, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce, may affect adversely such species of sea turtles, for the purpose of entering into bilateral and multilateral treaties with such countries to protect such species of sea turtles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> encourage such other agreements to promote the purposes of this section with other nations for the protection of specific ocean and land regions which are of special significance to the health and stability of such species of sea turtles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> initiate the amendment of any existing international treaty for the protection and conservation of such species of sea turtles to which the United States is a party in order to make such treaty consistent with the purposes and policies of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> provide to the Congress by not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>]—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a list of each nation which conducts commercial shrimp fishing operations within the geographic range of distribution of such sea turtles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a list of each nation which conducts commercial shrimp fishing operations which may affect adversely such species of sea turtles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> a full report on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the results of his efforts under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the status of measures taken by each nation listed pursuant to paragraph (A) or (B) to protect and conserve such sea turtles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The importation of shrimp or products from shrimp which have been harvested with commercial fishing technology which may affect adversely such species of sea turtles shall be prohibited not later than <date date="1991-05-01">May 1, 1991</date>, except as provided in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification Procedure</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The ban on importation of shrimp or products from shrimp pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not apply if the President shall determine and certify to the Congress not later than <date date="1991-05-01">May 1, 1991</date>, and annually thereafter that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the government of the harvesting nation has provided documentary evidence of the adoption of a regulatory program governing the incidental taking of such sea turtles in the course of such harvesting that is comparable to that of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the average rate of that incidental taking by the vessels of the harvesting nation is comparable to the average rate of incidental taking of sea turtles by United States vessels in the course of such harvesting; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the particular fishing environment of the harvesting nation does not pose a threat of the incidental taking of such sea turtles in the course of such harvesting.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id794c21c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id794c21ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11911</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11911, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, 41 F.R. 15683, which provided that for purposes of the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora the Secretary of the Interior be designated as the Management Authority and established the Endangered Species Scientific Authority as the Scientific Authority, with the Secretary of the Interior designated to act on behalf of the United States in all regards as required by the Convention on Nature Protection and Wildlife Preservation in the Western Hemisphere, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12608, <date date="1987-09-09">Sept. 9, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 34617.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id794c21cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority Regarding Certification of Countries Exporting Shrimp to United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of the President of the United States, <date date="1990-12-19">Dec. 19, 1990</date>, 56 F.R. 357, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States of America, including section 609 of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1990 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/162">Public Law 101–162</ref>) [set out above], and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the functions vested in me by section 609(b) of that Act. The authority delegated by this memorandum may be further redelegated within the Department of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
