<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id794e92e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538"><num value="1538">§ 1538.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e92e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Generally</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in sections 1535(g)(2) and 1539 of this title, with respect to any endangered species of fish or wildlife listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> it is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> import any such species into, or export any such species from the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> take any such species within the United States or the territorial sea of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> take any such species upon the high seas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> possess, sell, deliver, carry, transport, or ship, by any means whatsoever, any such species taken in violation of subparagraphs (B) and (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> deliver, receive, carry, transport, or ship in interstate or foreign commerce, by any means whatsoever and in the course of a commercial activity, any such species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> sell or offer for sale in interstate or foreign commerce any such species; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> violate any regulation pertaining to such species or to any threatened species of fish or wildlife listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> and promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to authority provided by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in sections 1535(g)(2) and 1539 of this title, with respect to any endangered species of plants listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>, it is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> import any such species into, or export any such species from, the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> remove and reduce to possession any such species from areas under Federal jurisdiction; maliciously damage or destroy any such species on any such area; or remove, cut, dig up, or damage or destroy any such species on any other area in knowing violation of any law or regulation of any State or in the course of any violation of a State criminal trespass law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> deliver, receive, carry, transport, or ship in interstate or foreign commerce, by any means whatsoever and in the course of a commercial activity, any such species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> sell or offer for sale in interstate or foreign commerce any such species; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> violate any regulation pertaining to such species or to any threatened species of plants listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> and promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to authority provided by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e92f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Species held in captivity or controlled environment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The provisions of subsections (a)(1)(A) and (a)(1)(G) of this section shall not apply to any fish or wildlife which was held in captivity or in a controlled environment on (A) <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, or (B) the date of the publication in the Federal Register of a final regulation adding such fish or wildlife species to any list published pursuant to subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That such holding and any subsequent holding or use of the fish or wildlife was not in the course of a commercial activity. With respect to any act prohibited by subsections (a)(1)(A) and (a)(1)(G) of this section which occurs after a period of 180 days from (i) <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, or (ii) the date of publication in the Federal Register of a final regulation adding such fish or wildlife species to any list published pursuant to subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the fish or wildlife involved in such act is not entitled to the exemption contained in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The provisions of subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any raptor legally held in captivity or in a controlled environment on <date date="1978-11-10">November 10, 1978</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any progeny of any raptor described in clause (i);</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">until such time as any such raptor or progeny is intentionally returned to a wild state.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any person holding any raptor or progeny described in subparagraph (A) must be able to demonstrate that the raptor or progeny does, in fact, qualify under the provisions of this paragraph, and shall maintain and submit to the Secretary, on request, such inventories, documentation, and records as the Secretary may by regulation require as being reasonably appropriate to carry out the purposes of this paragraph. Such requirements shall not unnecessarily duplicate the requirements of other rules and regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e92fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Violation of Convention</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to engage in any trade in any specimens contrary to the provisions of the Convention, or to possess any specimens traded contrary to the provisions of the Convention, including the definitions of terms in article I thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e92fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any importation into the United States of fish or wildlife shall, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such fish or wildlife is not an endangered species listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> but is listed in Appendix II to the Convention,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the taking and exportation of such fish or wildlife is not contrary to the provisions of the Convention and all other applicable requirements of the Convention have been satisfied,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e92ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the applicable requirements of subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section have been satisfied, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794e9300-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such importation is not made in the course of a commercial activity,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">be presumed to be an importation not in violation of any provision of this chapter or any regulation issued pursuant to this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e9301-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Imports and exports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id794e9302-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It is unlawful for any person, without first having obtained permission from the Secretary, to engage in business—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794e9303-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as an importer or exporter of fish or wildlife (other than shellfish and fishery products which (i) are not listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> as endangered species or threatened species, and (ii) are imported for purposes of human or animal consumption or taken in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States or on the high seas for recreational purposes) or plants; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794e9304-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as an importer or exporter of any amount of raw or worked African elephant ivory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id794e9305-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person required to obtain permission under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794e9306-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> keep such records as will fully and correctly disclose each importation or exportation of fish, wildlife, plants, or African elephant ivory made by him and the subsequent disposition made by him with respect to such fish, wildlife, plants, or ivory;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794e9307-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at all reasonable times upon notice by a duly authorized representative of the Secretary, afford such representative access to his place of business, an opportunity to examine his inventory of imported fish, wildlife, plants, or African elephant ivory and the records required to be kept under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, and to copy such records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id794e9308-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> file such reports as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id794e9309-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id794e930a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on consideration of value or amount of African elephant ivory imported or exported</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In granting permission under this subsection for importation or exportation of African elephant ivory, the Secretary shall not vary the requirements for obtaining such permission on the basis of the value or amount of ivory imported or exported under such permission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e930b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person importing or exporting fish or wildlife (other than shellfish and fishery products which (1) are not listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> as endangered or threatened species, and (2) are imported for purposes of human or animal consumption or taken in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States or on the high seas for recreational purposes) or plants to fail to file any declaration or report as the Secretary deems necessary to facilitate enforcement of this chapter or to meet the obligations of the Convention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e930c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of ports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e930d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to import into or export from the United States any fish or wildlife (other than shellfish and fishery products which (A) are not listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref> as endangered species or threatened species, and (B) are imported for purposes of human or animal consumption or taken in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States or on the high seas for recreational purposes) or plants, except at a port or ports designated by the Secretary of the Interior. For the purpose of facilitating enforcement of this chapter and reducing the costs thereof, the Secretary of the Interior, with approval of the Secretary of the Treasury and after notice and opportunity for public hearing, may, by regulation, designate ports and change such designations. The Secretary of the Interior, under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, may permit the importation or exportation at nondesignated ports in the interest of the health or safety of the fish or wildlife or plants, or for other reasons, if, in his discretion, he deems it appropriate and consistent with the purpose of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id794e930e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any port designated by the Secretary of the Interior under the authority of section 668cc–4(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002659">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002659"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, shall, if such designation is in effect on <date date="1973-12-27">December 27, 1973</date>, be deemed to be a port designated by the Secretary under paragraph (1) of this subsection until such time as the Secretary otherwise provides.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794e930f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1538/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to attempt to commit, solicit another to commit, or cause to be committed, any offense defined in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id794e9310-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/205/s9">Pub. L. 93–205, § 9</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/893">87 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/632/s4">Pub. L. 95–632, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3760">92 Stat. 3760</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s9/b">Pub. L. 97–304, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-13">Oct. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1426">96 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/tI/s1006">Pub. L. 100–478, title I, § 1006</ref>, title II, § 2301, <date date="1988-10-07">Oct. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2308">102 Stat. 2308</ref>, 2321; <ref href="/us/pl/100/653/tIX/s905">Pub. L. 100–653, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3835">102 Stat. 3835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id794e9311-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id794e9312-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id794e9313-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(G), (2)(E), (c)(2), (e), and (f)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/884">81 Stat. 884</ref>, known as the Endangered Species Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s668cc–4">Section 668cc–4 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f)(2), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/93/205/s14">Pub. L. 93–205, § 14</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/903">87 Stat. 903</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id794e9314-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s1006">Pub. L. 100–478, § 1006</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “remove and reduce to possession any such species from areas under Federal jurisdiction;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/478/s2301">Pub. L. 100–478, § 2301</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally, revising and restating as pars. (1) to (4) provisions of former pars. (1) to (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/653">Pub. L. 100–653</ref> inserted “or plants” after “purposes)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(2)(B) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s9/b/1">Pub. L. 97–304, § 9(b)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpars. (B), (C), and (D) as (C), (D), and (E), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s9/b/2">Pub. L. 97–304, § 9(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “The provisions of subsections (a)(1)(A) and (a)(1)(G) of this section shall not apply to any fish or wildlife which was held in captivity or in a controlled environment on (A) <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, or (B) the date of the publication in the Federal Register of a final regulation adding such fish or wildlife species to any list published pursuant to subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That such holding and any subsequent holding or use of the fish or wildlife was not in the course of a commercial activity. With respect to any act prohibited by subsections (a)(1)(A) and (a)(1)(G) of this section which occurs after a period of 180 days from (i) <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, or (ii) the date of publication in the Federal Register of a final regulation adding such fish or wildlife species to any list published pursuant to subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1533">section 1533 of this title</ref>, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the fish or wildlife involved in such act is not entitled to the exemption contained in this subsection” for “The provisions of this section shall not apply to any fish or wildlife held in captivity or in a controlled environment on <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, if the purposes of such holding are not contrary to the purposes of this chapter; except that this subsection shall not apply in the case of any fish or wildlife held in the course of a commercial activity. With respect to any act prohibited by this section which occurs after a period of 180 days from <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the fish or wildlife involved in such act was not held in captivity or in a controlled environment on <date date="1973-12-28">December 28, 1973</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/97/304/s9/b/3">Pub. L. 97–304, § 9(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “The provisions of subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to” for “This section shall not apply to” in provisions preceding cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/632">Pub. L. 95–632</ref> designated existing provision as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id794e9315-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id794e9316-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exemption of Exportation of Certain Echinoderms From Permission and Licensing Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12617">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12617</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5016">132 Stat. 5016</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12617">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conservation and management</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘conservation and management’ has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Marine Fisheries Commission</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Marine Fisheries Commission’ means an interstate commission (as that term is used in the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986 (16 USC [U.S.C.] 4101 et seq.)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State jurisdiction’ means areas under the jurisdiction and authority of a State as described in section 306(a)(2) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2">16 U.S.C. 1856(a)(2)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>], the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall amend section 14.92 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, to clarify that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> except as provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (d)(2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> fish and wildlife described in subsection (c) are fishery products exempt from the export permission requirements of section 9(d)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/1">16 U.S.C. 1538(d)(1)</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> any person may engage in business as an exporter of fish or wildlife described in subsection (c) without procuring—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> permission under section 9(d)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1538/d/1">16 U.S.C. 1538(d)(1)</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> an export license under subpart I of part 14 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> notwithstanding paragraph (1), unless the person has qualified for and obtained an export license described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii), any person that has been convicted of 1 or more violations of a Federal law relating to the importation, transportation, or exportation of wildlife shall not be permitted, during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the most recent conviction, to engage in business as an exporter of fish or wildlife described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Fish or Wildlife</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The fish or wildlife referred to in subsection (b) are members of the species <i>Strongylocentrotus droebachiensis</i> (commonly known as the ‘green sea urchin’), including any products of that species, that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> do not require a permit under part 16, 17, or 23 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> are harvested in waters under State jurisdiction; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> are imported for processing in the United States pursuant to an import license as required under section 14.91 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and not exempt from import license requirements under section 14.92 of that title (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> are exported for purposes of human or animal consumption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Collection on Exports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The State agency that regulates or otherwise oversees a State fishery in which the fish and wildlife described in subsection (c) are harvested shall annually transmit the conservation and management data (as defined in subsection (a)) to the Interstate Fisheries Management Program Policy Board of the applicable Marine Fisheries Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Privacy</inline>.—</heading><content>Such data thereafter shall not be released and shall be maintained as confidential by such applicable Marine Fisheries Commission, including data requested under the [sic] <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, unless disclosure is required under court order or unless the data is essential for an enforcement action under Federal wildlife management laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The exemption under subsection (b)(1) shall not apply in a State if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the State fails to transmit the data required under paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the applicable Marine Fisheries Commission determines, in consultation with the primary research agency of such Commission, after notice and an opportunity to comment, that the data required under paragraph (1) fails to prove that the State agency or official is engaged in conservation and management of the fish or wildlife described in subsection (c).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id794e9317-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Human Activities Within Proximity of Whales</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/238/s17">Pub. L. 103–238, § 17</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/559">108 Stat. 559</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/238/s17">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lawful Approaches</inline>.—</heading><content>In waters of the United States surrounding the State of Hawaii, it is lawful for a person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to approach, by any means other than an aircraft, no closer than 100 yards to a humpback whale, regardless of whether the approach is made in waters designated under section 222.31 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, as cow/calf waters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Legal Effect of Certain Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (b) of section 222.31 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, shall cease to be in force and effect.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id794e9318-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id794e9319-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Territorial Sea of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For extension of territorial sea of United States, see Proc. No. 5928, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">section 1331 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
