<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79534d36-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604"><num value="1604">§ 1604.</num><heading> National Forest System land and resource management plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d37-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development, maintenance, and revision by Secretary as part of program; coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a part of the Program provided for by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1602">section 1602 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall develop, maintain, and, as appropriate, revise land and resource management plans for units of the National Forest System, coordinated with the land and resource management planning processes of State and local governments and other Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d38-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the development and maintenance of land management plans for use on units of the National Forest System, the Secretary shall use a systematic interdisciplinary approach to achieve integrated consideration of physical, biological, economic, and other sciences.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d39-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Incorporation of standards and guidelines by Secretary; time of completion; progress reports; existing management plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall begin to incorporate the standards and guidelines required by this section in plans for units of the National Forest System as soon as practicable after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, and shall attempt to complete such incorporation for all such units by no later than <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>. The Secretary shall report to the Congress on the progress of such incorporation in the annual report required by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1606/c">section 1606(c) of this title</ref>. Until such time as a unit of the National Forest System is managed under plans developed in accordance with this subchapter, the management of such unit may continue under existing land and resource management plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d3a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation and consultation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d3b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for public participation in the development, review, and revision of land management plans including, but not limited to, making the plans or revisions available to the public at convenient locations in the vicinity of the affected unit for a period of at least three months before final adoption, during which period the Secretary shall publicize and hold public meetings or comparable processes at locations that foster public participation in the review of such plans or revisions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d3c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> No additional consultation required after approval of land management plans</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d3d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not be required to engage in consultation under this section or any other provision of law (including <ref href="/us/pl/93/205/s7">section 7 of Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</ref>) and section 402.16 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) with respect to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d3e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of critical habitat pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), if a land management plan has been adopted by the Secretary as of the date of listing or designation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d3f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any provision of a land management plan adopted as described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d40-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d41-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 15 years have passed since the date on which the Secretary adopted the land management plan described in clause (i) of that subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d42-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 5 years have passed since the date of enactment of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002666">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002666"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or the date of the listing of a species as threatened or endangered for a species known to occur on the unit or the designation of critical habitat within the unit as described in clause (i) of that subparagraph, whichever is later.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d43-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of paragraph</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph affects any applicable requirement of the Secretary to consult with the head of any other Federal department or agency—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d44-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> regarding any project carried out, or proposed to be carried out, to implement a land management plan pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Public Law 93–205</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), including any requirement to consult regarding the consideration of cumulative impacts of completed, ongoing, and planned projects; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d45-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> with respect to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79534d46-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the development of a modification to a land management plan; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79534d47-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/d/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an amendment or revision to a land management plan in accordance with paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (f).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Required assurances</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing, maintaining, and revising plans for units of the National Forest System pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall assure that such plans—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide for multiple use and sustained yield of the products and services obtained therefrom in accordance with the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s528–531">16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>], and, in particular, include coordination of outdoor recreation, range, timber, watershed, wildlife and fish, and wilderness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> determine forest management systems, harvesting levels, and procedures in the light of all of the uses set forth in subsection (c)(1), the definition of the terms “multiple use” and “sustained yield” as provided in the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960, and the availability of lands and their suitability for resource management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Required provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Plans developed in accordance with this section shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d4c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> form one integrated plan for each unit of the National Forest System, incorporating in one document or one set of documents, available to the public at convenient locations, all of the features required by this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be embodied in appropriate written material, including maps and other descriptive documents, reflecting proposed and possible actions, including the planned timber sale program and the proportion of probable methods of timber harvest within the unit necessary to fulfill the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d4e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> be prepared by an interdisciplinary team. Each team shall prepare its plan based on inventories of the applicable resources of the forest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d4f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> be amended in any manner whatsoever after final adoption after public notice, and, if such amendment would result in a significant change in such plan, in accordance with the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section and public involvement comparable to that required by subsection (d) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d50-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> be revised (A) from time to time when the Secretary finds conditions in a unit have significantly changed, but at least every fifteen years, and (B) in accordance with the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section and public involvement comparable to that required by subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of regulations for development and revision of plans; environmental considerations; resource management guidelines; guidelines for land management plans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable, but not later than two years after <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, the Secretary shall in accordance with the procedures set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, promulgate regulations, under the principles of the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s528–531">16 U.S.C. 528–531</ref>] that set out the process for the development and revision of the land management plans, and the guidelines and standards prescribed by this subsection. The regulations shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> specifying procedures to insure that land management plans are prepared in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.], including, but not limited to, direction on when and for what plans an environmental impact statement required under section 102(2)(C) of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332/2/C">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</ref>] shall be prepared;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> specifying guidelines which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require the identification of the suitability of lands for resource management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide for obtaining inventory data on the various renewable resources, and soil and water, including pertinent maps, graphic material, and explanatory aids; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d56-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide for methods to identify special conditions or situations involving hazards to the various resources and their relationship to alternative activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79534d57-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> specifying guidelines for land management plans developed to achieve the goals of the Program which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d58-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> insure consideration of the economic and environmental aspects of various systems of renewable resource management, including the related systems of silviculture and protection of forest resources, to provide for outdoor recreation (including wilderness), range, timber, watershed, wildlife, and fish;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d59-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide for diversity of plant and animal communities based on the suitability and capability of the specific land area in order to meet overall multiple-use objectives, and within the multiple-use objectives of a land management plan adopted pursuant to this section, provide, where appropriate, to the degree practicable, for steps to be taken to preserve the diversity of tree species similar to that existing in the region controlled by the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d5a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> insure research on and (based on continuous monitoring and assessment in the field) evaluation of the effects of each management system to the end that it will not produce substantial and permanent impairment of the productivity of the land;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d5b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> permit increases in harvest levels based on intensified management practices, such as reforestation, thinning, and tree improvement if (i) such practices justify increasing the harvests in accordance with the Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960, and (ii) such harvest levels are decreased at the end of each planning period if such practices cannot be successfully implemented or funds are not received to permit such practices to continue substantially as planned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d5c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> insure that timber will be harvested from National Forest System lands only where—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d5d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> soil, slope, or other watershed conditions will not be irreversibly damaged;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d5e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> there is assurance that such lands can be adequately restocked within five years after harvest;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d5f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> protection is provided for streams, streambanks, shorelines, lakes, wetlands, and other bodies of water from detrimental changes in water temperatures, blockages of water courses, and deposits of sediment, where harvests are likely to seriously and adversely affect water conditions or fish habitat; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d60-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the harvesting system to be used is not selected primarily because it will give the greatest dollar return or the greatest unit output of timber; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79534d61-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> insure that clearcutting, seed tree cutting, shelterwood cutting, and other cuts designed to regenerate an evenaged stand of timber will be used as a cutting method on National Forest System lands only where—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for clearcutting, it is determined to be the optimum method, and for other such cuts it is determined to be appropriate, to meet the objectives and requirements of the relevant land management plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the interdisciplinary review as determined by the Secretary has been completed and the potential environmental, biological, esthetic, engineering, and economic impacts on each advertised sale area have been assessed, as well as the consistency of the sale with the multiple use of the general area;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> cut blocks, patches, or strips are shaped and blended to the extent practicable with the natural terrain;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> there are established according to geographic areas, forest types, or other suitable classifications the maximum size limits for areas to be cut in one harvest operation, including provision to exceed the established limits after appropriate public notice and review by the responsible Forest Service officer one level above the Forest Service officer who normally would approve the harvest proposal: <i>Provided</i>, That such limits shall not apply to the size of areas harvested as a result of natural catastrophic conditions such as fire, insect and disease attack, or windstorm; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79534d66-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/g/3/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> such cuts are carried out in a manner consistent with the protection of soil, watershed, fish, wildlife, recreation, and esthetic resources, and the regeneration of the timber resource.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d67-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Scientific committee to aid in promulgation of regulations; termination; revision committees; clerical and technical assistance; compensation of committee members</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79534d68-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out the purposes of subsection (g) of this section, the Secretary shall appoint a committee of scientists who are not officers or employees of the Forest Service. The committee shall provide scientific and technical advice and counsel on proposed guidelines and procedures to assure that an effective interdisciplinary approach is proposed and adopted. The committee shall terminate upon promulgation of the regulations, but the Secretary may, from time to time, appoint similar committees when considering revisions of the regulations. The views of the committees shall be included in the public information supplied when the regulations are proposed for adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79534d69-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Clerical and technical assistance, as may be necessary to discharge the duties of the committee, shall be provided from the personnel of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79534d6a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> While attending meetings of the committee, the members shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate of $100 per diem, including traveltime, and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79534d6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Consistency of resource plans, permits, contracts, and other instruments with land management plans; revision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Resource plans and permits, contracts, and other instruments for the use and occupancy of National Forest System lands shall be consistent with the land management plans. Those resource plans and permits, contracts, and other such instruments currently in existence shall be revised as soon as practicable to be made consistent with such plans. When land management plans are revised, resource plans and permits, contracts, and other instruments, when necessary, shall be revised as soon as practicable. Any revision in present or future permits, contracts, and other instruments made pursuant to this section shall be subject to valid existing rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7955be6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date of land management plans and revisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Land management plans and revisions shall become effective thirty days after completion of public participation and publication of notification by the Secretary as required under subsection (d) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7955be6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of land management plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing land management plans pursuant to this subchapter, the Secretary shall identify lands within the management area which are not suited for timber production, considering physical, economic, and other pertinent factors to the extent feasible, as determined by the Secretary, and shall assure that, except for salvage sales or sales necessitated to protect other multiple-use values, no timber harvesting shall occur on such lands for a period of 10 years. Lands once identified as unsuitable for timber production shall continue to be treated for reforestation purposes, particularly with regard to the protection of other multiple-use values. The Secretary shall review his decision to classify these lands as not suited for timber production at least every 10 years and shall return these lands to timber production whenever he determines that conditions have changed so that they have become suitable for timber production.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7955be6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Program evaluation; process for estimating long-term costs and benefits; summary of data included in annual report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7955be6f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> formulate and implement, as soon as practicable, a process for estimating long-terms <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002667">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002667"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “long-term”.</note> costs and benefits to support the program evaluation requirements of this subchapter. This process shall include requirements to provide information on a representative sample basis of estimated expenditures associated with the reforestation, timber stand improvement, and sale of timber from the National Forest System, and shall provide a comparison of these expenditures to the return to the Government resulting from the sale of timber; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7955be70-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include a summary of data and findings resulting from these estimates as a part of the annual report required pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1606/c">section 1606(c) of this title</ref>, including an identification on a representative sample basis of those advertised timber sales made below the estimated expenditures for such timber as determined by the above cost process; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002668">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002668"><num>3</num> So in original. The “; and” probably should be a period.</note></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7955be71-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of standards to ensure culmination of mean annual increment of growth; silvicultural practices; salvage harvesting; exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7955be72-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> standards to insure that, prior to harvest, stands of trees throughout the National Forest System shall generally have reached the culmination of mean annual increment of growth (calculated on the basis of cubic measurement or other methods of calculation at the discretion of the Secretary): <i>Provided</i>, That these standards shall not preclude the use of sound silvicultural practices, such as thinning or other stand improvement measures: <i>Provided further</i>, That these standards shall not preclude the Secretary from salvage or sanitation harvesting of timber stands which are substantially damaged by fire, windthrow or other catastrophe, or which are in imminent danger from insect or disease attack; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7955be73-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1604/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> exceptions to these standards for the harvest of particular species of trees in management units after consideration has been given to the multiple uses of the forest including, but not limited to, recreation, wildlife habitat, and range and after completion of public participation processes utilizing the procedures of subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7955be74-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/378/s6">Pub. L. 93–378, § 6</ref>, formerly, § 5, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/477">88 Stat. 477</ref>, renumbered § 6 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, §§ 2, 6, 12(a), <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2949">90 Stat. 2949</ref>, 2952, 2958; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dO/tII/s208/a">Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1065">132 Stat. 1065</ref>, 1066.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7955be75-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7955be76-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7955be77-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Public Law 93–205</ref>, referred to subsec. (d)(2)(A)(i), (C)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/884">87 Stat. 884</ref>, known as the Endangered Species Act of 1973, which is classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 1531 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref>, which added subsec. (d)(2) and was approved <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Multiple-Use Sustained-Yield Act of 1960, referred to in subsecs. (e) and (g), is <ref href="/us/pl/86/517">Pub. L. 86–517</ref>, <date date="1960-06-12">June 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/215">74 Stat. 215</ref>, which is classified generally to sections 528 to 531 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s528">section 528 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (g)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7955be78-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s208/b/2">Pub. L. 115–141, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s208/a">Pub. L. 115–141, § 208(a)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted par. heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s208/b/2">Pub. L. 115–141, § 208(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary shall appoint” for “Secretary of Agriculture shall appoint”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/588/s12/a">Pub. L. 94–588, § 12(a)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original Act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1602">section 1602 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/94/588/s6">Pub. L. 94–588, § 6</ref>, added subsecs. (c) to (m).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7955be79-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7955be7a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Revision of Forest Plans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 119–74, div. C, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2026-01-23">Jan. 23, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/158">140 Stat. 158</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tIV/s407">“The Secretary of Agriculture shall not be considered to be in violation of section 6(f)(5)(A) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604/f/5/A">16 U.S.C. 1604(f)(5)(A)</ref>) solely because more than 15 years have passed without revision of the plan for a unit of the National Forest System. Nothing in this section exempts the Secretary from any other requirement of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act [of 1974] (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.) or any other law: <i>Provided</i>, That if the Secretary is not acting expeditiously and in good faith, within the funding available, to revise a plan for a unit of the National Forest System, this section shall be void with respect to such plan and a court of proper jurisdiction may order completion of the plan on an accelerated basis.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dE/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/285">138 Stat. 285</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4821">136 Stat. 4821</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 117–103, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/410">136 Stat. 410</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 116–260, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1536">134 Stat. 1536</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dD/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 116–94, div. D, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2743">133 Stat. 2743</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dE/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 116–6, div. E, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/259">133 Stat. 259</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 115–141, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/688">132 Stat. 688</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 115–31, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/495">131 Stat. 495</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 114–113, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2575">129 Stat. 2575</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dF/tIV/s408">Pub. L. 113–235, div. F, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2445">128 Stat. 2445</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dG/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 113–76, div. G, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/338">128 Stat. 338</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dE/tIV/s409">Pub. L. 112–74, div. E, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1039">125 Stat. 1039</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/88/dA/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 111–88, div. A, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="2009-10-30">Oct. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2957">123 Stat. 2957</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dE/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 111–8, div. E, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/746">123 Stat. 746</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dF/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 110–161, div. F, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2146">121 Stat. 2146</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/54/tIV/s415">Pub. L. 109–54, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/551">119 Stat. 551</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dE/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 108–447, div. E, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3097">118 Stat. 3097</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/108/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 108–108, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="2003-11-10">Nov. 10, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1306">117 Stat. 1306</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dF/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, 117 Stat 274.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/63/tIII/s327">Pub. L. 107–63, title III, § 327</ref>, <date date="2001-11-05">Nov. 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/470">115 Stat. 470</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7955be7b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expeditious Completion of Management Plans of Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management; Continuation of Existing Plans; Judicial Review</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/121/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 101–121, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/743">103 Stat. 743</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/121/tIII/s312">“The Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management are to continue to complete as expeditiously as possible development of their respective Forest Land and Resource Management Plans to meet all applicable statutory requirements. Notwithstanding the date in section 6(c) of the NFMA (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604/c">16 U.S.C. 1604(c)</ref>], the Forest Service, and the Bureau of Land Management under separate authority, may continue the management of lands within their jurisdiction under existing land and resource management plans pending the completion of new plans. Nothing shall limit judicial review of particular activities on these lands: <i>Provided, however</i>, That there shall be no challenges to any existing plan on the sole basis that the plan in its entirety is outdated, or in the case of the Bureau of Land Management, solely on the basis that the plan does not incorporate information available subsequent to the completion of the existing plan: <i>Provided further</i>, That any and all particular activities to be carried out under existing plans may nevertheless be challenged.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/446/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 100–446, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1825">102 Stat. 1825</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/g/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(g) [title III, § 314]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-213">101 Stat. 1329–213</ref>, 1329–254.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–268, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–268.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7955be7c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7955be7d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture under this subchapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
