<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id770d7c0d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s161"><num value="161">§ 161.</num><heading> Establishment; boundaries; trespassers; claims and rights under land laws not affected; reclamation projects; indemnity selections of lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The tract of land in the State of Montana particularly described by metes and bounds as follows, to wit: Commencing at a point on the international boundary between the United States and the Dominion of Canada at the middle of the Flathead River; thence following southerly along and with the middle of the Flathead River to its confluence with the Middle Fork of the Flathead River; thence following the north bank of said Middle Fork of the Flathead River to where it is crossed by the north boundary of the right-of-way of the Great Northern Railroad; thence following the said right-of-way to where it intersects the west boundary of the Blackfeet Indian Reservation; thence northerly along said west boundary to its intersection with the international boundary; thence along said international boundary to the place of beginning, is reserved and withdrawn from settlement, occupancy, or disposal under the laws of the United States, and dedicated and set apart as a public park or pleasure ground for the benefit and enjoyment of the people of the United States under the name of “The Glacier National Park.” All persons who shall locate or settle upon or occupy the same, or any part thereof, except as hereinafter provided, shall be considered trespassers and removed therefrom. Nothing herein contained shall affect any valid claim, location, or entry existing under the land laws of the United States before <date date="1910-05-11">May 11, 1910</date>, or the rights of any such claimant, locator, or entryman to the full use and enjoyment of his land. The United States Reclamation Service may enter upon and utilize for flowage or other purposes any area within said park which may be necessary for the development and maintenance of a Government reclamation project. No lands within the limits of Glacier National Park belonging to or claimed by any railroad or other corporation having or claiming before <date date="1910-05-11">May 11, 1910</date>, the right of indemnity selection by virtue of any law or contract whatsoever shall be used as a basis for indemnity selection in any State or Territory whatsoever for any loss sustained by reason of the creation of Glacier National Park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id770d7c0e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1910-05-11/ch226/s1">May 11, 1910, ch. 226, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/354">36 Stat. 354</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1931-01-26/ch47/s5">Jan. 26, 1931, ch. 47, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1043">46 Stat. 1043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id770d7c0f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id770d7c10-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id770d7c11-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The land laws of the United States, referred to in text, are classified generally to Title 43, Public Lands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Herein, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/act/1910-05-11/ch226">act May 11, 1910, ch. 226</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/354">36 Stat. 354</ref>, which is classified to this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s162">section 162 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id770d7c12-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In sentence beginning “Nothing herein contained”, the words “before <date date="1910-05-11">May 11, 1910</date>” were inserted to give effect to the preceding word “existing”, and in the last sentence the words “having or claiming before <date date="1910-05-11">May 11, 1910</date>” are a translation of the words “now having or claiming” of the original text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id770d7c13-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1931—Act <date date="1931-01-26">Jan. 26, 1931</date>, struck out provision that right of way through the valleys of the North and Middle Forks of the Flathead River might be acquired within Glacier National Park for steam or electric railways.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id770d7c14-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id770d7c15-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Permits for Existing Natural Gas Pipelines</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/268/s1">Pub. L. 112–268, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2441">126 Stat. 2441</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/268/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Interior may issue right-of-way permits for each natural gas pipeline (including all appurtenances used in the operation of the natural gas pipeline) that, as of <date date="2012-03-01">March 1, 2012</date>, is located within the boundary of Glacier National Park.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A permit issued under subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> issued as a right-of-way renewal, consistent with laws (including regulations) generally applicable to utility rights-of-way within units of the National Park System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> for a width of not more than 25 feet on either side of the centerline of the natural gas pipeline; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> subject to any terms and conditions that the Secretary of the Interior determines to be necessary.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id770d7c16-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id770d7c17-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Reclamation Service, established in July 1902, changed to the Bureau of Reclamation on <date date="1923-06-20">June 20, 1923</date>, then to the Water and Power Resources Service on <date date="1979-11-06">Nov. 6, 1979</date>, and then back to the Bureau of Reclamation on <date date="1981-05-18">May 18, 1981</date>. See 155 Dep’t of the Interior, Departmental Manual 1.1 (2008 repl.); Sec’y Hubert Work, Dep’t of the Interior, Order (<date date="1923-06-20">June 20, 1923</date>); Sec’y Cecil D. Andrus, Dep’t of the Interior, Secretarial Order 3042, §§ 1, 4 (<date date="1979-11-06">Nov. 6, 1979</date>); Sec’y James G. Watt, Dep’t of the Interior, Secretarial Order 3064, §§ 3, 5 (<date date="1981-05-18">May 18, 1981</date>).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
