<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id770d7c1e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s161d"><num value="161d">§ 161d.</num><heading> Elimination of fish hatchery; transfer of administration of hatchery to Fish and Wildlife Service</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The property at Creston, Montana, acquired by the United States for the establishment of a fish hatchery for restocking the waters of Glacier National Park and administered as a part of the park pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s161c">section 161c of this title</ref>, together with the improvements and equipment utilized in connection with the hatchery property, is eliminated from the park.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The functions of the National Park Service with regard to the administration of the aforesaid properties for the benefit of the park are transferred to and shall be exercised by the Fish and Wildlife Service for the same purposes: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such fish propagated at the hatchery as may be in excess of the number necessary to restock and maintain an optimum fish population in the waters of the park at all times may be utilized for the re­stocking of other waters.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id770d7c1f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-12-13/ch555">Dec. 13, 1944, ch. 555</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/801">58 Stat. 801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id770d7c20-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id770d7c21-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id770d7c22-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Fish and Wildlife Service, created by Reorg. Plan No. III of 1940, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2107, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1231">54 Stat. 1231</ref>, succeeded by United States Fish and Wildlife Service established by <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-08/ch1036/s3">act Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/1120">70 Stat. 1120</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s742b">section 742b of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
