<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id795a7983-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650"><num value="1650">§ 1650.</num><heading> Hardwood technology transfer and applied research</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a7984-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter the “Secretary”) is hereby and hereafter authorized to conduct technology transfer and development, training, dissemination of information and applied research in the management, processing and utilization of the hardwood forest resource. This authority is in addition to any other authorities which may be available to the Secretary including, but not limited to, the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2101">16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.), and the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Act of 1978, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600–161">16 U.S.C. 1600–161</ref>4).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002670">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002670"><num>1</num> So in original.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a7985-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements; gifts and donations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this authority, the Secretary may enter into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements with public and private agencies, organizations, corporations, institutions and individuals. The Secretary may accept gifts and donations pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2269">section 2269 of title 7</ref> including gifts and donations from a donor that conducts business with any agency of the Department of Agriculture or is regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a7986-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of assets of Wood Education and Resource Center; establishment of Institute of Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby and hereafter authorized to operate and utilize the assets of the Wood Education and Resource Center (previously named the Robert C. Byrd Hardwood Technology Center in West Virginia) as part of a newly formed “Institute of Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research” (hereinafter the “Institute”). The Institute, in addition to the Wood Education and Resource Center, will consist of a Director, technology transfer specialists from State and Private Forestry, the Forestry Sciences Laboratory in Princeton, West Virginia, and any other organizational unit of the Department of Agriculture as the Secretary deems appropriate. The overall management of the Institute will be the responsibility of the Forest Service, State and Private Forestry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a7987-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Generation of revenue; deposit into Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is hereby and hereafter authorized to generate revenue using the authorities provided herein. Any revenue received as part of the operation of the Institute shall be deposited into a special fund in the Treasury of the United States, known as the “Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research Fund”, which shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further appropriation, in furtherance of the purposes of this section, including upkeep, management, and operation of the Institute and the payment of salaries and expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a7988-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1650/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are hereby and hereafter authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id795a7989-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tIII/s332">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 332]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–197.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id795a798a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id795a798b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id795a798c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/313">Pub. L. 95–313</ref>, <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/365">92 Stat. 365</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 41 (§ 2101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id795a798d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000, and not as part of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Research Act of 1978 which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id795a798e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id795a798f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/e/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 343]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-231">112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–297, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/e/tIII/s343">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter the ‘Secretary’) is hereby authorized to conduct technology transfer and development, training, dissemination of information and applied research in the management, processing and utilization of the hardwood forest resource. This authority is in addition to any other authorities which may be available to the Secretary including, but not limited to, the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2101">16 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et. seq.), and the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Act of 1978, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600–161">16 U.S.C. 1600–161</ref>4).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> In carrying out this authority, the Secretary may enter into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements with public and private agencies, organizations, corporations, institutions and individuals. The Secretary may accept gifts and donations pursuant to the Act of <date date="1978-10-10">October 10, 1978</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2269">7 U.S.C. 2269</ref>) including gifts and donations from a donor that conducts business with any agency of the Department of Agriculture or is regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, to assume all rights, title, and interest, including all outstanding assets, of the Robert C. Byrd Hardwood Technology Center, Inc. (hereinafter the ‘Center’), a non-profit corporation existing under the laws of the State of West Virginia: <i>Provided</i>, That the Board of Directors of the Center requests such an action and dissolves the corporation consistent with the Articles of Incorporation and the laws of the State of West Virginia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to operate and utilize the assets of the Center as part of a newly formed ‘Institute of Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research’ (hereinafter the ‘Institute’). The Institute, in addition to the Center, will consist of a Director, technology transfer specialists from State and Private Forestry, the Forestry Sciences Laboratory in Princeton, West Virginia, and any other organizational unit of the Department of Agriculture as the Secretary deems appropriate. The overall management of the Institute will be the responsibility of the USDA Forest Service, State and Private Forestry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to generate revenue using the authorities provided herein. Any revenue received as part of the operation of the Institute shall be deposited into a special fund in the Treasury of the United States, known as the ‘Hardwood Technology Transfer and Applied Research Fund’, which shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further appropriation, in furtherance of the purposes of this section, including upkeep, management, and operation of the Institute and the payment of salaries and expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
