<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id795a79b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673"><num value="1673">§ 1673.</num><heading> State programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a79b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development by State program director, etc., of comprehensive and coordinated program by mutual agreement; consultations; review procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State director of cooperative extension programs (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “State director”) and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in each State shall jointly develop, by mutual agreement, a single comprehensive and coordinated renewable resources extension program in which the role of each eligible college and university is well-defined. In meeting this responsibility, the State director and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities shall consult and seek agreement with the administrative technical representatives and the forestry representatives provided for by the Secretary in implementation of the Act of <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/76/806-807">76 Stat. 806–807</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s582a">16 U.S.C. 582a</ref>, 582a–1—582a–7), in the State. Each State’s renewable resources extension program shall be submitted to the Secretary annually. The National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3123">section 3123 of title 7</ref> shall review and make recommendations to the Secretary pertaining to programs conducted under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a79b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Encouragement by State director, etc., of cooperation between county and State extension staffs and appropriate Federal and State agencies and organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State director and the administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in each State shall encourage close cooperation between extension staffs at the county and State levels, and State and Federal research organizations dealing with renewable resources, State and Federal agencies that manage forests and rangelands and their associated renewable resources, State and Federal agencies that have responsibilities associated with the processing or use of renewable resources, and other agencies or organizations the State director and administrative heads of extension deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a79b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration and coordination of program by State director; exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State renewable resources extension program shall be administered and coordinated by the State director, except that, in States having colleges eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/26/417-419">26 Stat. 417–419</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321–326">7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref>, 328), including Tuskegee Institute, the State renewable resources extension program shall be administered by the State director and the administrative head or heads of extension for the college or colleges eligible to receive such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a79b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and use of advisory committees by State director, etc.; composition of advisory committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In meeting the provisions of this section, each State director and administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities shall appoint and use one or more advisory committees comprised of forest and range landowners, professionally trained individuals in fish and wildlife, forest, range, and watershed management, and related fields, as appropriate, and other suitable persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795a79b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1673/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “State” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “State” means any one of the fifty States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the District of Columbia, and the Virgin Islands of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id795a79b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/306/s4">Pub. L. 95–306, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/350">92 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVIII/s802/b/3">Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 802(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1159">110 Stat. 1159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id795a79b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id795a79b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id795a79ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1962-10-10">October 10, 1962</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/76/806-807">76 Stat. 806–807</ref>, as amended), referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/788">Pub. L. 87–788</ref>, <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/806">76 Stat. 806</ref>, popularly known as the “McIntire-Stennis Act of 1962” and also as the “McIntire-Stennis Cooperative Forestry Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 582a et seq.) of chapter 3 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s582a">section 582a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/26/417-419">26 Stat. 417–419</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321–326">7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref>, 328), referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-08-30/ch841">act Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/417">26 Stat. 417</ref>, popularly known as the Agricultural College Act of 1890 and also as the Second Morrill Act, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 321 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321">section 321 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id795a79bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127">Pub. L. 104–127</ref> substituted “National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board” for “National Agricultural Research and Extension Users Advisory Board”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
