<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id795cea2f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703"><num value="1703">§ 1703.</num><heading> Duties and functions of Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795cea30-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs and projects; conditions of employment; regulations; use of facilities by educational institutions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea31-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> determine the areas under their administrative jurisdictions which are appropriate for carrying out the programs using employees of the Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea32-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> determine with other Federal agencies the areas under the administrative jurisdiction of these agencies which are appropriate for carrying out programs using members of the Corps, and determine and select appropriate work and education programs and projects for participation by members of the Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea33-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> determine the rates of pay, hours, and other conditions of employment in the Corps, except that all members of the Corps shall not be deemed to be Federal employees other than for the purpose of chapter 171 of title 28, and chapter 81 of title 5.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002671">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002671"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea34-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide for such transportation, lodging, subsistence, and other services and equipment as they may deem necessary or appropriate for the needs of members of the Corps in their duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea35-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> promulgate regulation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002672">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002672"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “regulations”.</note> to insure the safety, health, and welfare of the Corps members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795cea36-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> provide to the extent possible, that permanent or semipermanent facilities used as Corps camps be made available to local schools, school districts, State junior colleges and universities, and other education institutions for use as environmental/ecological education camps during periods of nonuse by the Corps program.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Costs for operations maintenance, and staffing of Corps camp facilities during periods of use by non-Corps programs as well as any liability for personal injury or property damage stemming from such use shall be the responsibility of the entity or organization using the facility and shall not be a responsibility of the Secretaries or the Corps.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795cea37-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of unoccupied Federal facilities and equipment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Existing but unoccupied Federal facilities and surplus or unused equipment (or both), of all types including military facilities and equipment, shall be utilized for the purposes of the Corps, where appropriate and with the approval of the Federal agency involved. To minimize transportation costs, Corps members shall be employed on conservation projects as near to their places of residence as is feasible.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795cea38-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1703/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts for the operation of projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may contract with any public agency or organization or any private nonprofit agency or organization which has been in existence for at least five years for the operation of any Youth Conservation Corps project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id795cea39-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/378/tI/s103">Pub. L. 91–378, title I, § 103</ref>, formerly § 3, <date date="1970-08-13">Aug. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/795">84 Stat. 795</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/597">Pub. L. 92–597</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1319">86 Stat. 1319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/408">Pub. L. 93–408</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1067">88 Stat. 1067</ref>; renumbered title I, § 103, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tI/s105/1">Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 105(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/848">107 Stat. 848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id795cea3a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id795cea3b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id795cea3c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s105/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 105(2)</ref>, substituted “subchapter” for “chapter” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/408">Pub. L. 93–408</ref> reenacted existing provisions with minor changes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/597">Pub. L. 92–597</ref> substantially reenacted existing provisions and inserted provisions requiring the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to determine and select appropriate work and education programs and projects for participation by members of the Corps and to provide that permanent or semipermanent facilities used as Corps camps be made available to local schools, school districts, and such other institutions for use as environmental education camps during periods of nonuse by the Corps program, that the costs of operation, maintenance, and staffing of Corps camp facilities during periods of use by non-Corps programs and liabilities arising from such use shall be the responsibility of the organization using the facility and, struck out provisions requiring preparation and submission to the President of a report not later than <date date="1971-08-13">Aug. 13, 1971</date>, for transmittal to the Congress for review and appropriate action, and that the provisions of Title II of the Revenue and Expenditure Control Act of 1968 shall not apply to appointments made to the Corps, to temporary supervisory personnel, or to temporary program support staff.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id795cea3d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id795cea3e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1993-10-01">Oct. 1, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s123">section 123 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
