<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id770d7c50-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s171"><num value="171">§ 171.</num><heading> Forfeitures and seizures of guns, traps, teams, etc.</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All guns, traps, teams, horses, or means of transportation of every nature or description, used by any person or persons within said park limits when engaged in killing, trapping, ensnaring, or capturing such wild beasts, birds, or wild animals shall be forfeited to the United States and may be seized by the officers in said park and held pending the prosecution of any person or persons arrested under charge of violating the provisions of this Act, and upon conviction under this Act of such person or persons using said guns, traps, teams, horses, or other means of transportation, such forfeiture shall be adjudicated as a penalty in addition to the other punishment provided under this Act. Such forfeited property shall be disposed of and accounted for by and under the authority of the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id770d7c51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-08-22/ch264/s5">Aug. 22, 1914, ch. 264, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/700">38 Stat. 700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id770d7c52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id770d7c53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id770d7c54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is act <date date="1914-08-22">Aug. 22, 1914</date>, which is classified to sections 163 and 168 to 177 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
