<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id795cead1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1725"><num value="1725">§ 1725.</num><heading> Resource assistants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795cead2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1725/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may provide individual placements of resource assistants to carry out research or resource protection activities on behalf of the Secretary. To be eligible for selection as a resource assistant, an individual must be at least 17 years of age. The Secretary may select resource assistants without regard to the civil service and classification laws, rules, or regulations of the United States. The Secretary shall give a preference to the selection of individuals who are enrolled in an institution of higher education or are recent graduates from an institution of higher education, with particular attention given to ensure full representation of women and participants from historically black, Hispanic, and Native American schools.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795cead3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1725/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of existing nonprofit organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever one or more existing nonprofit organizations can provide, in the judgment of the the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002673">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002673"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> Secretary, appropriate recruitment and placement services to fulfill the requirements of this section, the Secretary may implement this section through such existing organizations. Participating nonprofit organizations shall contribute to the expenses of providing and supporting the resource assistants, through private sources of funding, at a level equal to 25 percent of the total costs of each participant in the Resource Assistant program who has been recruited and placed through that organization. Any such participating nonprofit conservation service organization shall be required, by the respective land managing agency, to submit an annual report evaluating the scope, size, and quality of the program, including the value of work contributed by the Resource Assistants, to the mission of the agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id795cead4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/378/tII/s206">Pub. L. 91–378, title II, § 206</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tI/s105/6">Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 105(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/852">107 Stat. 852</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/154/s2/g/3">Pub. L. 109–154, § 2(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2893">119 Stat. 2893</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/9/tIX/s9003/d/1">Pub. L. 116–9, title IX, § 9003(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/833">133 Stat. 833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id795cead5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id795cead6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id795cead7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/9">Pub. L. 116–9</ref> substituted “The Secretary may provide individual placements of resource assistants to carry out research or resource protection activities on behalf of the Secretary.” for “The Secretary is authorized to provide individual placements of resource assistants with any Federal land managing agency under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to carry out research or resource protection activities on behalf of the agency.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/154/s2/g/3/A">Pub. L. 109–154, § 2(g)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “Secretary is” for “Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture are each”, “the Secretary to carry out” for “such Secretary to carry out”, “Secretary may” for “Secretaries may”, and “Secretary shall” for “Secretaries shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/154/s2/g/3/B">Pub. L. 109–154, § 2(g)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “the Secretary, appropriate” for “Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, appropriate”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id795cead8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id795cead9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1993-10-01">Oct. 1, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s123">section 123 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
