<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id796d8b89-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1826d"><num value="1826d">§ 1826d.</num><heading> Prohibition</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States, or any agency or official acting on behalf of the United States, may not enter into any international agreement with respect to the conservation and management of living marine resources or the use of the high seas by fishing vessels that would prevent full implementation of the global moratorium on large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas, as such moratorium is expressed in Resolution 46/215 of the United Nations General Assembly.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id796d8b8a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/43/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 104–43, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1995-11-03">Nov. 3, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/392">109 Stat. 392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id796d8b8b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id796d8b8c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id796d8b8d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act, and also as part of the Fisheries Act of 1995, and not as part of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id796d8b8e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id796d8b8f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/43/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 104–43, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1995-11-03">Nov. 3, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/391">109 Stat. 391</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/43/tVI/s602">
<inline>“The Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Congress has enacted and the President has signed into law numerous Acts to control or prohibit large-scale driftnet fishing both within the jurisdiction of the United States and beyond the exclusive economic zone of any nation, including the Driftnet Impact Monitoring, Assessment, and Control Act of 1987 (title IV, <ref href="/us/pl/100/220">Public Law 100–220</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1822">16 U.S.C. 1822</ref> note], the Driftnet Act Amendments of 1990 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/627">Public Law 101–627</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1826">16 U.S.C. 1826</ref>], and the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/582">Public Law 102–582</ref>) [see Short Title of 1992 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the United States is a party to the Convention for the Prohibition of Fishing with Long Driftnets in the South Pacific, also known as the Wellington Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the General Assembly of the United Nations has adopted three resolutions and three decisions which established and reaffirm a global moratorium on large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas, beginning with Resolution 44/225 in 1989 and most recently in Decision 48/445 in 1993;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the General Assembly of the United Nations adopted these resolutions and decisions at the request of the United States and other concerned nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the best scientific information demonstrates the wastefulness and potentially destructive impacts of large-scale driftnet fishing on living marine resources and seabirds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Resolution 46/215 of the United Nations General Assembly calls on all nations, both individually and collectively, to prevent large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
