<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id796ffd9b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829"><num value="1829">§ 1829.</num><heading> International monitoring and compliance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id796ffd9c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may undertake activities to promote improved monitoring and compliance for high seas fisheries, or fisheries governed by international fishery management agreements, and to implement the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id796ffd9d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific authorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffd9e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> share information on harvesting and processing capacity and illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing on the high seas, in areas covered by international fishery management agreements, and by vessels of other nations within the United States exclusive economic zone, with relevant law enforcement organizations of foreign nations and relevant international organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffd9f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> further develop real time information sharing capabilities, particularly on harvesting and processing capacity and illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffda0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> participate in global and regional efforts to build an international network for monitoring, control, and surveillance of high seas fishing and fishing under regional or global agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffda1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> support efforts to create an international registry or database of fishing vessels, including by building on or enhancing registries developed by international fishery management organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffda2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> enhance enforcement capabilities through the application of commercial or governmental remote sensing technology to locate or identify vessels engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing on the high seas, including encroachments into the exclusive economic zone by fishing vessels of other nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffda3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> provide technical or other assistance to developing countries to improve their monitoring, control, and surveillance capabilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id796ffda4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1829/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> support coordinated international efforts to ensure that all large-scale fishing vessels operating on the high seas are required by their flag State to be fitted with vessel monitoring systems no later than <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, or earlier if so decided by the relevant flag State or any relevant international fishery management organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id796ffda5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/265/tII/s207">Pub. L. 94–265, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 109–479, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3625">120 Stat. 3625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
