<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7979731e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854"><num value="1854">§ 1854.</num><heading> Action by Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7979731f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797320-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon transmittal by the Council to the Secretary of a fishery management plan or plan amendment, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797321-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> immediately commence a review of the plan or amendment to determine whether it is consistent with the national standards, the other provisions of this chapter, and any other applicable law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797322-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> immediately publish in the Federal Register a notice stating that the plan or amendment is available and that written information, views, or comments of interested persons on the plan or amendment may be submitted to the Secretary during the 60-day period beginning on the date the notice is published.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797323-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In undertaking the review required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797324-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> take into account the information, views, and comments received from interested persons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797325-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> consult with the Secretary of State with respect to foreign fishing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797326-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> consult with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating with respect to enforcement at sea and to fishery access adjustments referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/a/6">section 1853(a)(6) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797327-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall approve, disapprove, or partially approve a plan or amendment within 30 days of the end of the comment period under paragraph (1) by written notice to the Council. A notice of disapproval or partial approval shall specify—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797328-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the applicable law with which the plan or amendment is inconsistent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797329-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the nature of such inconsistencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7979732a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> recommendations concerning the actions that could be taken by the Council to conform such plan or amendment to the requirements of applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the Secretary does not notify a Council within 30 days of the end of the comment period of the approval, disapproval, or partial approval of a plan or amendment, then such plan or amendment shall take effect as if approved.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7979732b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the Secretary disapproves or partially approves a plan or amendment, the Council may submit a revised plan or amendment to the Secretary for review under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7979732c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection and subsection (b), the term “immediately” means on or before the 5th day after the day on which a Council transmits to the Secretary a fishery management plan, plan amendment, or proposed regulation that the Council characterizes as final.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7979732d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7979732e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon transmittal by the Council to the Secretary of proposed regulations prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/c">section 1853(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall immediately initiate an evaluation of the proposed regulations to determine whether they are consistent with the fishery management plan, plan amendment, this chapter and other applicable law. Within 15 days of initiating such evaluation the Secretary shall make a determination and—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7979732f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if that determination is affirmative, the Secretary shall publish such regulations in the Federal Register, with such technical changes as may be necessary for clarity and an explanation of those changes, for a public comment period of 15 to 60 days; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797330-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if that determination is negative, the Secretary shall notify the Council in writing of the inconsistencies and provide recommendations on revisions that would make the proposed regulations consistent with the fishery management plan, plan amendment, this chapter, and other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797331-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon receiving a notification under paragraph (1)(B), the Council may revise the proposed regulations and submit them to the Secretary for reevaluation under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797332-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall promulgate final regulations within 30 days after the end of the comment period under paragraph (1)(A). The Secretary shall consult with the Council before making any revisions to the proposed regulations, and must publish in the Federal Register an explanation of any differences between the proposed and final regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79797333-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation and review of Secretarial plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79797334-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may prepare a fishery management plan, with respect to any fishery, or any amendment to any such plan, in accordance with the national standards, the other provisions of this chapter, and any other applicable law, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79797335-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the appropriate Council fails to develop and submit to the Secretary, after a reasonable period of time, a fishery management plan for such fishery, or any necessary amendment to such a plan, if such fishery requires conservation and management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be436-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary disapproves or partially disapproves any such plan or amendment, or disapproves a revised plan or amendment, and the Council involved fails to submit a revised or further revised plan or amendment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be437-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Secretary is given authority to prepare such plan or amendment under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be438-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In preparing any plan or amendment under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be439-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct public hearings, at appropriate times and locations in the geographical areas concerned, so as to allow interested persons an opportunity to be heard in the preparation and amendment of the plan and any regulations implementing the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be43a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> consult with the Secretary of State with respect to foreign fishing and with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating with respect to enforcement at sea.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be43b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) for a fishery under the authority of a Council, the Secretary may not include in any fishery management plan, or any amendment to any such plan, prepared by him, a provision establishing a limited access system, including any limited access privilege program, unless such system is first approved by a majority of the voting members, present and voting, of each appropriate Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be43c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Whenever the Secretary prepares a fishery management plan or plan amendment under this section, the Secretary shall immediately—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be43d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for a plan or amendment for a fishery under the authority of a Council, submit such plan or amendment to the appropriate Council for consideration and comment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be43e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> publish in the Federal Register a notice stating that the plan or amendment is available and that written information, views, or comments of interested persons on the plan or amendment may be submitted to the Secretary during the 60-day period beginning on the date the notice is published.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be43f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Whenever a plan or amendment is submitted under paragraph (4)(A), the appropriate Council must submit its comments and recommendations, if any, regarding the plan or amendment to the Secretary before the close of the 60-day period referred to in paragraph (4)(B). After the close of such 60-day period, the Secretary, after taking into account any such comments and recommendations, as well as any views, information, or comments submitted under paragraph (4)(B), may adopt such plan or amendment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be440-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Secretary may propose regulations in the Federal Register to implement any plan or amendment prepared by the Secretary. In the case of a plan or amendment to which paragraph (4)(A) applies, such regulations shall be submitted to the Council with such plan or amendment. The comment period on proposed regulations shall be 60 days, except that the Secretary may shorten the comment period on minor revisions to existing regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be441-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The Secretary shall promulgate final regulations within 30 days after the end of the comment period under paragraph (6). The Secretary must publish in the Federal Register an explanation of any substantive differences between the proposed and final rules. All final regulations must be consistent with the fishery management plan, with the national standards and other provisions of this chapter, and with any other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be442-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be443-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall by regulation establish the level of any fees which are authorized to be charged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/b/1">section 1853(b)(1) of this title</ref>. The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the States concerned under which the States administer the permit system and the agreement may provide that all or part of the fees collected under the system shall accrue to the States. The level of fees charged under this subsection shall not exceed the administrative costs incurred in issuing the permits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be444-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be445-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary is authorized and shall collect a fee to recover the actual costs directly related to the management, data collection, and enforcement of any—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be446-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> limited access privilege program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be447-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> community development quota program that allocates a percentage of the total allowable catch of a fishery to such program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be448-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such fee shall not exceed 3 percent of the ex-vessel value of fish harvested under any such program, and shall be collected at either the time of the landing, filing of a landing report, or sale of such fish during a fishing season or in the last quarter of the calendar year in which the fish is harvested.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be449-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be44a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Fees collected under this paragraph shall be in addition to any other fees charged under this chapter and shall be deposited in the Limited Access System Administration Fund established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1855/h/5/B">section 1855(h)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be44b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Upon application by a State, the Secretary shall transfer to such State up to 33 percent of any fee collected pursuant to subparagraph (A) under a community development quota program and deposited in the Limited Access System Administration Fund in order to reimburse such State for actual costs directly incurred in the management and enforcement of such program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be44c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rebuilding overfished fisheries</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be44d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall report annually to the Congress and the Councils on the status of fisheries within each Council’s geographical area of authority and identify those fisheries that are overfished or are approaching a condition of being overfished. For those fisheries managed under a fishery management plan or international agreement, the status shall be determined using the criteria for overfishing specified in such plan or agreement. A fishery shall be classified as approaching a condition of being overfished if, based on trends in fishing effort, fishery resource size, and other appropriate factors, the Secretary estimates that the fishery will become overfished within two years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be44e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary determines at any time that a fishery is overfished, the Secretary shall immediately notify the appropriate Council and request that action be taken to end overfishing in the fishery and to implement conservation and management measures to rebuild affected stocks of fish. The Secretary shall publish each notice under this paragraph in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be44f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Within 2 years after an identification under paragraph (1) or notification under paragraphs (2) or (7), the appropriate Council (or the Secretary, for fisheries under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/a/3">section 1852(a)(3) of this title</ref>) shall prepare and implement a fishery management plan, plan amendment, or proposed regulations for the fishery to which the identification or notice applies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be450-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to end overfishing immediately in the fishery and to rebuild affected stocks of fish; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be451-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to prevent overfishing from occurring in the fishery whenever such fishery is identified as approaching an overfished condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be452-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For a fishery that is overfished, any fishery management plan, amendment, or proposed regulations prepared pursuant to paragraph (3) or paragraph (5) for such fishery shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be453-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> specify a time period for rebuilding the fishery that shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be454-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be as short as possible, taking into account the status and biology of any overfished stocks of fish, the needs of fishing communities, recommendations by international organizations in which the United States participates, and the interaction of the overfished stock of fish within the marine ecosystem; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be455-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> not exceed 10 years, except in cases where the biology of the stock of fish, other environmental conditions, or management measures under an international agreement in which the United States participates dictate otherwise;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be456-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> allocate both overfishing restrictions and recovery benefits fairly and equitably among sectors of the fishery; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be457-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for fisheries managed under an international agreement, reflect traditional participation in the fishery, relative to other nations, by fishermen of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be458-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If, within the 2-year period beginning on the date of identification or notification that a fishery is overfished, the Council does not submit to the Secretary a fishery management plan, plan amendment, or proposed regulations required by paragraph (3)(A), the Secretary shall prepare a fishery management plan or plan amendment and any accompanying regulations to stop overfishing and rebuild affected stocks of fish within 9 months under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be459-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> During the development of a fishery management plan, a plan amendment, or proposed regulations required by this subsection, the Council may request the Secretary to implement interim measures to reduce overfishing under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1855/c">section 1855(c) of this title</ref> until such measures can be replaced by such plan, amendment, or regulations. Such measures, if otherwise in compliance with the provisions of this chapter, may be implemented even though they are not sufficient by themselves to stop overfishing of a fishery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be45a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall review any fishery management plan, plan amendment, or regulations required by this subsection at routine intervals that may not exceed two years. If the Secretary finds as a result of the review that such plan, amendment, or regulations have not resulted in adequate progress toward ending overfishing and rebuilding affected fish stocks, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be45b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a fishery to which <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/a/3">section 1852(a)(3) of this title</ref> applies, immediately make revisions necessary to achieve adequate progress; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be45c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for all other fisheries, immediately notify the appropriate Council. Such notification shall recommend further conservation and management measures which the Council should consider under paragraph (3) to achieve adequate progress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be45d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Fisheries under authority of more than one Council</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be45e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (3),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002692">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002692"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> if any fishery extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council, the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be45f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> designate which Council shall prepare the fishery management plan for such fishery and any amendment to such plan; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be460-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may require that the plan and amendment be prepared jointly by the Councils concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">No jointly prepared plan or amendment may be submitted to the Secretary unless it is approved by a majority of the voting members, present and voting, of each Council concerned.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797be461-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish the boundaries between the geographical areas of authority of adjacent Councils.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be462-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Atlantic highly migratory species</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be463-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation and implementation of plan or plan amendment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prepare a fishery management plan or plan amendment under subsection (c) with respect to any highly migratory species fishery to which <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/a/3">section 1852(a)(3) of this title</ref> applies. In preparing and implementing any such plan or amendment, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be464-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> consult with and consider the comments and views of affected Councils, commissioners and advisory groups appointed under Acts implementing relevant international fishery agreements pertaining to highly migratory species, and the advisory panel established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/g">section 1852(g) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be465-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> establish an advisory panel under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/g">section 1852(g) of this title</ref> for each fishery management plan to be prepared under this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be466-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> evaluate the likely effects, if any, of conservation and management measures on participants in the affected fisheries and minimize, to the extent practicable, any disadvantage to United States fishermen in relation to foreign competitors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be467-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> with respect to a highly migratory species for which the United States is authorized to harvest an allocation, quota, or at a fishing mortality level under a relevant international fishery agreement, provide fishing vessels of the United States with a reasonable opportunity to harvest such allocation, quota, or at such fishing mortality level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be468-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> review, on a continuing basis (and promptly whenever a recommendation pertaining to fishing for highly migratory species has been made under a relevant international fishery agreement), and revise as appropriate, the conservation and management measures included in the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be469-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> diligently pursue, through international entities (such as the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas), comparable international fishery management measures with respect to fishing for highly migratory species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be46a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> ensure that conservation and management measures under this subsection—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id797be46b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> promote international conservation of the affected fishery;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id797be46c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> take into consideration traditional fishing patterns of fishing vessels of the United States and the operating requirements of the fisheries;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id797be46d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> are fair and equitable in allocating fishing privileges among United States fishermen and do not have economic allocation as the sole purpose; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id797be46e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/1/G/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> promote, to the extent practicable, implementation of scientific research programs that include the tagging and release of Atlantic highly migratory species.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be46f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain fish excluded from “bycatch” definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1802/2">section 1802(2) of this title</ref>, fish harvested in a commercial fishery managed by the Secretary under this subsection or the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971d">16 U.S.C. 971d</ref>), or highly migratory species harvested in a commercial fishery managed by a Council under this chapter or the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s6901">16 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.], that are not regulatory discards and that are tagged and released alive under a scientific tagging and release program established by the Secretary shall not be considered bycatch for purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be470-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Repeal or revocation of a fishery management plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may repeal or revoke a fishery management plan for a fishery under the authority of a Council only if the Council approves the repeal or revocation by a three-quarters majority of the voting members of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be471-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002693">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002693"><num>2</num> So in original. Two subsecs. (i) have been enacted.</note> Environmental review process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be472-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Councils and the Council on Environmental Quality, revise and update agency procedures for compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4231">42 U.S.C. 4231</ref> et seq.). The procedures shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be473-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conform to the time lines for review and approval of fishery management plans and plan amendments under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be474-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> integrate applicable environmental analytical procedures, including the time frames for public input, with the procedure for the preparation and dissemination of fishery management plans, plan amendments, and other actions taken or approved pursuant to this chapter in order to provide for timely, clear and concise analysis that is useful to decision makers and the public, reduce extraneous paperwork, and effectively involve the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be475-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Usage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The updated agency procedures promulgated in accordance with this section used by the Councils or the Secretary shall be the sole environmental impact assessment procedure for fishery management plans, amendments, regulations, or other actions taken or approved pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be476-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule for promulgation of final procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be477-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> propose revised procedures within 6 months after <date date="2007-01-12">January 12, 2007</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be478-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide 90 days for public review and comments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be479-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> promulgate final procedures no later than 12 months after <date date="2007-01-12">January 12, 2007</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id797be47a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized and directed, in cooperation with the Council on Environmental Quality and the Councils, to involve the affected public in the development of revised procedures, including workshops or other appropriate means of public involvement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797be47b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> <sup>2</sup> International overfishing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this subsection shall apply in lieu of subsection (e) to a fishery that the Secretary determines is overfished or approaching a condition of being overfished due to excessive international fishing pressure, and for which there are no management measures to end overfishing under an international agreement to which the United States is a party. For such fisheries—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be47c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of State,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002694">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002694"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “shall”.</note> immediately take appropriate action at the international level to end the overfishing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797be47d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> within 1 year after the Secretary’s determination, the appropriate Council, or Secretary, for fisheries under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/a/3">section 1852(a)(3) of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be47e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> develop recommendations for domestic regulations to address the relative impact of fishing vessels of the United States on the stock and, if developed by a Council, the Council shall submit such recommendations to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797be47f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1854/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> develop and submit recommendations to the Secretary of State, and to the Congress, for international actions that will end overfishing in the fishery and rebuild the affected stocks, taking into account the relative impact of vessels of other nations and vessels of the United States on the relevant stock.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id797be480-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/265/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 94–265, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/352">90 Stat. 352</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2487">96 Stat. 2487</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/tI/s106">Pub. L. 99–659, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3712">100 Stat. 3712</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/tI">Pub. L. 101–627, title I</ref>, §§ 110(a), (b)(1), (c), 111(a)(2), 120(d), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4449-4452">104 Stat. 4449–4452</ref>, 4459; <ref href="/us/pl/102/567/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 102–567, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4283">106 Stat. 4283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/206/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 103–206, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2446">107 Stat. 2446</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s109/a">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 109(a)</ref>–(c), (e)–(g), (i), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3581-3585">110 Stat. 3581–3585</ref>, 3587; <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s3/d/2">Pub. L. 109–479, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, title I, §§ 104(c), 106(b), (d), 107, title IV, § 406, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3578">120 Stat. 3578</ref>, 3584, 3593, 3594, 3633.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id797be481-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id797be482-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id797be483-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/265">Pub. L. 94–265</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/331">90 Stat. 331</ref>, known as the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (3), referred to in subsec. (f)(1), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s109/f">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 109(f)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3585">110 Stat. 3585</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975, referred to in subsec. (g)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/70">Pub. L. 94–70</ref>, <date date="1975-08-05">Aug. 5, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/385">89 Stat. 385</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16A (§ 971 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971">section 971 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(2), is title V of <ref href="/us/pl/109/479">Pub. L. 109–479</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3635">120 Stat. 3635</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 88 (§ 6901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s6901">section 6901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act, referred to in subsec. (i)(1), probably means the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id797e2d74-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s3/d/2/A">Pub. L. 109–479, § 3(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “limited access privilege” for “individual fishing quota”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s106/b">Pub. L. 109–479, § 106(b)</ref>, substituted “management, data collection, and enforcement” for “management and enforcement” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s3/d/2/B">Pub. L. 109–479, § 3(d)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “limited access privilege” for “individual fishing quota”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s106/d">Pub. L. 109–479, § 106(d)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1855/h/5/B">section 1855(h)(5)(B) of this title</ref>.” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1855/h/5/B">section 1855(h)(5)(B) of this title</ref>, except that the portion of any such fees reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/d/4/A">section 1853(d)(4)(A) of this title</ref> shall be deposited in the Treasury and available, subject to annual appropriations, to cover the costs of new direct loan obligations and new loan guarantee commitments as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661c/b/1">section 661c(b)(1) of title 2</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s104/c/1">Pub. L. 109–479, § 104(c)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “2 years after” for “one year of” and inserted “and implement” after “prepare” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s104/c/3">Pub. L. 109–479, § 104(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “immediately” after “overfishing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s104/c/4">Pub. L. 109–479, § 104(c)(4)</ref>, struck out “ending overfishing and” before “rebuilding” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s104/c/5">Pub. L. 109–479, § 104(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “2-year” for “one-year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s406/b">Pub. L. 109–479, § 406(b)</ref>, substituted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971d">16 U.S.C. 971d</ref>), or highly migratory species harvested in a commercial fishery managed by a Council under this Act or the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act,” for “(<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971d">16 U.S.C. 971d</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s406/a">Pub. L. 109–479, § 406(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i) relating to international overfishing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/479/s107">Pub. L. 109–479, § 107</ref>, added subsec. (i) relating to environmental review process.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/a">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(a)</ref>, added subsecs. (a) and (b) and struck out former subsecs. (a) which related to actions by Secretary after receipt of a fishery management plan or amendment to a plan and (b) which related to implementation of approved plans and amendments and submission and review of revised plans and amendments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/b/1">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(b)(1)</ref>, amended heading to read “Preparation and review of Secretarial plans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/b/2">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(b)(2)</ref>–(4), struck out “or” at end of subpar. (A), substituted “or amendment; or” for “or amendment, as the case may be.” in subpar. (B), added subpar. (C), and struck out concluding provisions which read as follows: “In preparing any such plan or amendment, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of State with respect to foreign fishing and with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating with respect to enforcement at sea. The Secretary shall also prepare such proposed regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to carry out each plan or amendment prepared by him under this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/b/5">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(b)(5)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which related to procedures for making fishery management plans and amendments available for review and comment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/b/6">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(b)(6)</ref>, (7), inserted “for a fishery under the authority of a Council” after “paragraph (1)” and substituted “system, including any individual fishing quota program” for “system described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/b/6">section 1853(b)(6) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/b/8">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(b)(8)</ref>, added pars. (4) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/c">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(c)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/e">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(e)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) required Secretary to initiate and maintain a comprehensive program of fishery research.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/f">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(f)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which related to authority of Secretary over any highly migratory species fishery that is within the area of authority of more than one of certain Councils and to the preparation and amendment of fishery management plans with respect to such fishery.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/g">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(g)</ref>, added subsec. (g) and struck out former subsec. (g) which required the Secretary to establish a 3-year program to assess the impact on fishery resources of incidental harvest by the shrimp trawl fishery within the authority of the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council and the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s109/i">Pub. L. 104–297, § 109(i)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (g)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/206">Pub. L. 103–206</ref> substituted “<date date="1994-04-01">April 1, 1994</date>” for “<date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/567">Pub. L. 102–567</ref> added par. (1). Former par. (1) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/567">Pub. L. 102–567</ref> redesignated par. (1) as (2) and substituted “(3)” for “(2)” in subpar. (A). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/567">Pub. L. 102–567</ref> redesignated par. (2) as (3) and substituted “(2)” for “(1)” in introductory provisions. Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/567">Pub. L. 102–567</ref> redesignated par. (3) as (4) and substituted “(2)” for “(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(1), (3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s111/a/2/A">Pub. L. 101–627, § 111(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), substituted “section 1855(a)” for “section 1855(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s120/d">Pub. L. 101–627, § 120(d)</ref>, substituted “appropriate Council” for “appropriate council”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s111/a/2/C">Pub. L. 101–627, § 111(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “section 1855(a)” for “section 1855(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s110/a">Pub. L. 101–627, § 110(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “The Secretary shall initiate and maintain, in cooperation with the Councils, a comprehensive program of fishery research to carry out and further the purposes, policy, and provisions of this chapter. Such program shall be designed to acquire knowledge and information, including statistics, on fishery conservation and management and on the economics of the fisheries, including, but not limited to, biological research concerning the interdependence of fisheries or stocks of fish, the impact of pollution on fish, the impact of wetland and estuarine degradation, and other matters bearing upon the abundance and availability of fish. The Secretary shall annually review and update the comprehensive program and make the results of the review and update available to the Councils.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s110/b/1">Pub. L. 101–627, § 110(b)(1)</ref>, in heading substituted “Fisheries under authority of more than one Council” for “Miscellaneous duties”, in par. (1) substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (3), if” for “If”, and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s110/c">Pub. L. 101–627, § 110(c)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/A">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “(the date of receipt of which is hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘receipt date’)” after “by a Council” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/B">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(B)</ref>, (C), added subpar. (A) and redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as (B) and (C), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/B">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(B)</ref>, (D), redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C) and substituted “60-day” for “75-day”. Former subpar. (C) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/B">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(B)</ref>, (E), redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D) and substituted “15th day” for “30th day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/F">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(B)” for “paragraph (1)(A)” in introductory provisions and inserted “and to fishery access adjustments referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1853/a/6">section 1853(a)(6) of this title</ref>” in subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/1/G">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(1)(G)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/2/A">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(2)(A)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “the Secretary does not notify the Council in writing of his disapproval, or partial disapproval, under paragraph (2), of the plan or amendment before the close of the 95th day after the receipt date; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/2/B">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “60th day” for “75th day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/2/C">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(B)” for “paragraph (1)(A)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/2/D/i">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(2)(D)(i)</ref>, inserted “disapproves a proposed plan or amendment under subsection (a)(1)(A)(ii) of this section, or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(i), (C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/2/D/ii">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(2)(D)(ii)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a)(1)(B)” for “subsection (a)(1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/3/A">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “60-day” for “75-day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/3/B">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “15th day” for “30th day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/3/C">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “60-day” for “75-day” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/s106/4">Pub. L. 99–659, § 106(4)</ref>, inserted “, in cooperation with the Councils,”, “and on the economics of the fisheries”, and “The Secretary shall annually review and update the comprehensive program and make the results of the review and update available to the Councils.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a/1">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally, which had provided that within 60 days after the Secretary received any fishery management plan, or any amendment to any such plan, which was prepared by any Council, the Secretary was to review such plan or amendment pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, notify such Council in writing of his approval, disapproval, or partial disapproval of such plan or amendment, and that in the case of disapproval or partial disapproval, the Secretary was to include in such notification a statement and explanation of the Secretary’s objections and the reasons therefor, suggestions for improvement, a request to such Council to change such plan or amendment to satisfy the objections, and a request to resubmit the plan or amendment, as so modified, to the Secretary within 45 days after the date on which the Council received such notification.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a/1">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally, which had provided that the Secretary was to review any fishery management plan, and any amendment to any such plan, prepared by any Council and submitted to him to determine whether it was consistent with the national standards, the other provisions of this chapter, and any other applicable law, and that in carrying out such review, the Secretary was to consult with the Secretary of State with respect to foreign fishing, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard was operating with respect to enforcement at sea.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a/2/A">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)(2)(A)</ref>, in subpar. (B) substituted “or disapproves a revised plan or amendment, and the Council involved fails to submit a revised or further revised plan or amendment, as the case may be” for “and the Council involved fails to change such plan or amendment in accordance with the notification made under subsection (a)(2) of this section”, and added to the provisions following subpar. (B) a requirement that the Secretary also prepare such proposed regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to carry out each plan or amendment prepared by him under this paragraph.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a/2/B">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)(2)(B)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally, which had provided that whenever, pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary prepared a fishery management plan or amendment, the Secretary was to promptly transmit such plan or amendment to the appropriate Council for consideration and comment, that within 45 days after the date of receipt of such plan or amendment, the appropriate Council could recommend, to the Secretary, changes in such plan or amendment, consistent with the national standards, the other provisions of this chapter, and any other applicable law, and that after the expiration of such 45-day period, the Secretary could implement such plan or amendment pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1855">section 1855 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/a/3">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(a)(3)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to agreements with the States for the administration of the permit system and the permissible accrual to the States of fees collected under the system.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id797e2d75-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id797e2d76-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/479/tI/s104/d">Pub. L. 109–479, title I, § 104(d)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3585">120 Stat. 3585</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/479/tI/s104/d">“The amendments made by subsection (c) [amending this section] shall take effect 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id797e2d77-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s7/b">Pub. L. 97–453, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2489">96 Stat. 2489</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/453/s7/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall only apply with respect to fishery management plans and amendments thereto that are initially submitted to the Secretary of Commerce on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>] for action under section 304 [this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id797e2d78-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d79-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives abolished and its jurisdiction transferred by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. For treatment of references to Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b/3">section 1(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d7a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Fisheries Agreement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/348/tII">Pub. L. 111–348, title II</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3671">124 Stat. 3671</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/348/tII">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="201">“SEC. 201.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title may be cited as the ‘International Fisheries Agreement Clarification Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="202">“SEC. 202.</num><heading> INTERNATIONAL FISHERY AGREEMENT.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Consistent with the intent of provisions of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery and Conservation and Management Act [Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.] relating to international agreements, the Secretary of Commerce and the New England Fishery Management Council may, for the purpose of rebuilding those portions of fish stocks covered by the United States-Canada Transboundary Resource Sharing Understanding on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> take into account the Understanding and decisions made under that Understanding in the application of section 304(e)(4)(A)(i) of the Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/A/i">16 U.S.C. 1854(e)(4)(A)(i)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> consider decisions made under that Understanding as ‘management measures under an international agreement’ that ‘dictate otherwise’ for purposes of section 304(e)(4)(A)(ii) of the Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854/e/4/A/ii">16 U.S.C. 1854(e)(4)(A)(ii)</ref>[)]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> establish catch levels for those portions of fish stocks within their respective geographic areas covered by the Understanding on the date of enactment of this Act that exceed the catch levels otherwise required under the Northeast Multispecies Fishery Management Plan if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> overfishing is ended immediately;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the fishing mortality level ensures rebuilding within a time period for rebuilding specified taking into account the Understanding pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> such catch levels are consistent with that Understanding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="203">“SEC. 203.</num><heading> APPLICATION WITH OTHER LAWS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Nothing in this title shall be construed to amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1851">16 U.S.C. 1851</ref> [1801] et seq.) or to limit or otherwise alter the authority of the Secretary of Commerce under that Act concerning other species.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="204">“SEC. 204.</num><heading> EFFECTIVE DATE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), section 202 shall apply with respect to fishing years beginning after <date date="2010-04-30">April 30, 2010</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 202(3)(B) shall only apply with respect to fishing years beginning after <date date="2012-04-30">April 30, 2012</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d7b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Delay of Collection of Fees in Quahog and Wreckfish Fisheries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s109/d">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 109(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3584">110 Stat. 3584</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 211(b)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–41, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not begin the collection of fees under section 304(d)(2) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854/d/2">16 U.S.C. 1854(d)(2)</ref>], as amended by this Act, in the surf clam and ocean (including mahogany) quahog fishery or in the wreckfish fishery until after <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d7c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comprehensive Management System for Atlantic Pelagic Longline Fishery</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s109/h">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 109(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3586">110 Stat. 3586</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 211(b)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–41, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Commerce shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish an advisory panel under section 302(g)(4) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852/g/4">16 U.S.C. 1852(g)(4)</ref>], as amended by this Act, for pelagic longline fishing vessels that participate in fisheries for Atlantic highly migratory species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> conduct surveys and workshops with affected fishery participants to provide information and identify options for future management programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to the extent practicable and necessary for the evaluation of options for a comprehensive management system, recover vessel production records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> complete by <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>, a comprehensive study on the feasibility of implementing a comprehensive management system for pelagic longline fishing vessels that participate in fisheries for Atlantic highly migratory species, including, but not limited to, individual fishing quota programs and other limited access systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Based on the study under paragraph (1)(D) and consistent with the requirements of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), in cooperation with affected participants in the fishery, the United States Commissioners on the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas, and the advisory panel established under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary of Commerce may, after <date date="1998-10-01">October 1, 1998</date>, implement a comprehensive management system pursuant to section 304 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854">16 U.S.C. 1854</ref>) for pelagic longline fishing vessels that participate in fisheries for Atlantic highly migratory species. Such a system may not implement an individual fishing quota program until after <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d7d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Subsection (h) to American Lobster Fishery Management Plan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s109/j">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 109(j)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3587">110 Stat. 3587</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 211(b)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–41, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">“Section 304(h) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854/h">16 U.S.C. 1854(h)</ref>], as amended by this Act, shall not apply to the American Lobster Fishery Management Plan.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797e2d7e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interim Management of Highly Migratory Species Fisheries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/627/tI/s108/k">Pub. L. 101–627, title I, § 108(k)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4447">104 Stat. 4447</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 211(b)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–41, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“Notwithstanding the amendments made by subsections (a) and (g) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1852">section 1852 of this title</ref>], any fishery management plan or amendment which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> addresses a highly migratory species fishery to which section 304(f)(3) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1854/f/3">16 U.S.C. 1854(f)(3)</ref>] (as amended by this Act) applies,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> was prepared by one or more Regional Fishery Management Councils, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> was in force and effect on <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall remain in force and effect until superseded by a fishery management plan prepared by the Secretary, and regulations implementing that plan.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
