<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79809f21-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856"><num value="1856">§ 1856.</num><heading> State jurisdiction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79809f22-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f23-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (b), nothing in this chapter shall be construed as extending or diminishing the jurisdiction or authority of any State within its boundaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f24-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this chapter, except as provided in subsection (b), the jurisdiction and authority of a State shall extend—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f25-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to any pocket of waters that is adjacent to the State and totally enclosed by lines delimiting the territorial sea of the United States pursuant to the Geneva Convention on the Territorial Sea and Contiguous Zone or any successor convention to which the United States is a party;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f26-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to the body of water commonly known as Nantucket Sound, to the pocket of water west of the seventieth meridian west of Greenwich; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f27-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> to the waters of southeastern Alaska (for the purpose of regulating fishing for other than any species of crab) that are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79809f28-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> north of the line representing the international boundary at Dixon Entrance and the westward extension of that line; east of 138 degrees west longitude; and not more than three nautical miles seaward from the coast, from the lines extending from headland to headland across all bays, inlets, straits, passes, sounds, and entrances, and from any island or group of islands, including the islands of the Alexander Archipelago (except Forrester Island); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79809f29-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> between the islands referred to in clause (i) (except Forrester Island) and the mainland.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f2a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A State may regulate a fishing vessel outside the boundaries of the State in the following circumstances:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f2b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The fishing vessel is registered under the law of that State, and (i) there is no fishery management plan or other applicable Federal fishing regulations for the fishery in which the vessel is operating; or (ii) the State’s laws and regulations are consistent with the fishery management plan and applicable Federal fishing regulations for the fishery in which the vessel is operating.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f2c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The fishery management plan for the fishery in which the fishing vessel is operating delegates management of the fishery to a State and the State’s laws and regulations are consistent with such fishery management plan. If at any time the Secretary determines that a State law or regulation applicable to a fishing vessel under this circumstance is not consistent with the fishery management plan, the Secretary shall promptly notify the State and the appropriate Council of such determination and provide an opportunity for the State to correct any inconsistencies identified in the notification. If, after notice and opportunity for corrective action, the State does not correct the inconsistencies identified by the Secretary, the authority granted to the State under this subparagraph shall not apply until the Secretary and the appropriate Council find that the State has corrected the inconsistencies. For a fishery for which there was a fishery management plan in place on <date date="1996-08-01">August 1, 1996</date> that did not delegate management of the fishery to a State as of that date, the authority provided by this subparagraph applies only if the Council approves the delegation of management of the fishery to the State by a three-quarters majority vote of the voting members of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f2d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The fishing vessel is not registered under the law of the State of Alaska and is operating in a fishery in the exclusive economic zone off Alaska for which there was no fishery management plan in place on <date date="1996-08-01">August 1, 1996</date>, and the Secretary and the North Pacific Council find that there is a legitimate interest of the State of Alaska in the conservation and management of such fishery. The authority provided under this subparagraph shall terminate when a fishery management plan under this chapter is approved and implemented for such fishery.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79809f2e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f2f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary finds, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f30-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the fishing in a fishery, which is covered by a fishery management plan implemented under this chapter, is engaged in predominately within the exclusive economic zone and beyond such zone; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f31-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any State has taken any action, or omitted to take any action, the results of which will substantially and adversely affect the carrying out of such fishery management plan;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall promptly notify such State and the appropriate Council of such finding and of his intention to regulate the applicable fishery within the boundaries of such State (other than its internal waters), pursuant to such fishery management plan and the regulations promulgated to implement such plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f32-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary, pursuant to this subsection, assumes responsibility for the regulation of any fishery, the State involved may at any time thereafter apply to the Secretary for reinstatement of its authority over such fishery. If the Secretary finds that the reasons for which he assumed such regulation no longer prevail, he shall promptly terminate such regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f33-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the State involved requests that a hearing be held pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct such hearing prior to taking any action under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79809f34-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception regarding foreign fish processing in internal waters</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f35-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A foreign fishing vessel may engage in fish processing within the internal waters of a State if, and only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f36-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the vessel is qualified for purposes of this paragraph pursuant to paragraph (4)(C) or has received a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1824/d">section 1824(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f37-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the owner or operator of the vessel applies to the Governor of the State for, and (subject to paragraph (2)) is granted, permission for the vessel to engage in such processing and the application specifies the species to be processed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f38-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the owner or operator of the vessel submits reports on the tonnage of fish received from vessels of the United States and the locations from which such fish were harvested, in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary by regulation shall prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f39-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Governor of a State may not grant permission for a foreign fishing vessel to engage in fish processing under paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f3a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> for a fishery which occurs in the waters of more than one State or in the exclusive economic zone, except after—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79809f3b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consulting with the appropriate Council and Marine Fisheries Commission, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79809f3c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> considering any comments received from the Governor of any other State where the fishery occurs; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f3d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the Governor determines that fish processors within the State have adequate capacity, and will utilize such capacity, to process all of the United States harvested fish from the fishery concerned that are landed in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f3e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection may be construed as relieving a foreign fishing vessel from the duty to comply with all applicable Federal and State laws while operating within the internal waters of a State incident to permission obtained under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79809f3f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f40-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “fish processing” includes, in addition to processing, the performance of any other activity relating to fishing, including, but not limited to, preparation, supply, storage, refrigeration, or transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f41-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The phrase “internal waters of a State” means all waters within the boundaries of a State except those seaward of the baseline from which the territorial sea is measured.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79809f42-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s1856/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A foreign fishing vessel shall be treated as qualified for purposes of paragraph (1) if the foreign nation under which it is flagged will be a party to (i) a governing international fishery agreement or (ii) a treaty described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1821/b">section 1821(b) of this title</ref> during the time the vessel will engage in the fish processing for which permission is sought under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79809f43-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/265/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 94–265, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/355">90 Stat. 355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/191/s1">Pub. L. 97–191, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-06-01">June 1, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/107">96 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/453/s9">Pub. L. 97–453, § 9</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2491">96 Stat. 2491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tIV/s404/4">Pub. L. 98–623, title IV, § 404(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3408">98 Stat. 3408</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/659/tI/s101/c/2">Pub. L. 99–659, title I, § 101(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3707">100 Stat. 3707</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/tI/s112">Pub. L. 101–627, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4453">104 Stat. 4453</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s112/a">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 112(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3595">110 Stat. 3595</ref>, 3596.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79809f44-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79809f45-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79809f46-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (2), (3)(C) and (b)(1)(A), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/265">Pub. L. 94–265</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/331">90 Stat. 331</ref>, known as the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79809f47-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s112/a">Pub. L. 104–297, § 112(a)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “Except as otherwise provided by paragraph (2), a State may not directly or indirectly regulate any fishing vessel outside its boundaries, unless the vessel is registered under the law of that State.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s112/b">Pub. L. 104–297, § 112(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 104–297, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “(4)(C) or has received a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1824/d">section 1824(d) of this title</ref>;” for “(4)(C); and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s112/c/2">Pub. L. 104–297, § 112(c)(2)</ref>, (3), added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s112/1">Pub. L. 101–627, § 112(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and the application specifies the species to be processed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/627/s112/2">Pub. L. 101–627, § 112(2)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The Governor of a State may not grant permission for a foreign fishing vessel to engage in fish processing under paragraph (1)(B) if he determines that fish processors within the State have adequate capacity, and will utilize such capacity, to process all of the United States harvested fish from the fishery concerned that are landed in the State.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/659">Pub. L. 99–659</ref> substituted “exclusive economic zone” for “fishery conservation zone”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/623">Pub. L. 98–623</ref> designated existing provisions as pars. (1) to (3), in par. (2), as so designated, redesignated cls. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, and added subpar. (C), and in par. (3), as so designated, inserted exception relating to par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/453">Pub. L. 97–453</ref> inserted provision delineating the jurisdiction and authority of a State over waters adjacent to the State and over Nantucket Sound.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/191">Pub. L. 97–191</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79809f48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79809f49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/191/s3">Pub. L. 97–191, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-06-01">June 1, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/108">96 Stat. 108</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/191/s3">“This Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1857">section 1857 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1982-06-01">June 1, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79809f4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of States of Washington, Oregon, and California To Manage Dungeness Crab Fishery</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/384/tII/s203">Pub. L. 105–384, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3453">112 Stat. 3453</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/tVI/s624">Pub. L. 107–77, title VI, § 624</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/803">115 Stat. 803</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/479/tIII/s302/e">Pub. L. 109–479, title III, § 302(e)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3624">120 Stat. 3624</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/49/s1">Pub. L. 115–49, § 1</ref>, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1000">131 Stat. 1000</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/49/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of this section and notwithstanding section 306(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1856/a">16 U.S.C. 1856(a)</ref>), each of the States of Washington, Oregon, and California may adopt and enforce State laws and regulations governing fishing and processing in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to that State in any Dungeness crab (Cancer magister) fishery for which there is no fishery management plan in effect under that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for State Management</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any law or regulation adopted by a State under this section for a Dungeness crab fishery—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> except as provided in paragraph (2), shall apply equally to vessels engaged in the fishery in the exclusive economic zone and vessels engaged in the fishery in the waters of the State, and without regard to the State that issued the permit under which a vessel is operating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall not apply to any fishing by a vessel in exercise of tribal treaty rights except as provided in United States v. Washington, D.C. No. CV–70–09213, United States District Court for the Western District of Washington; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> shall include any provisions necessary to implement tribal treaty rights pursuant to the decision in United States v. Washington, D.C. No. CV–70–09213.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Enforcement of State Limited Access Systems</inline>.—</heading><content>Any law of the State of Washington, Oregon, or California that establishes or implements a limited access system for a Dungeness crab fishery may not be enforced against a vessel that is otherwise legally fishing in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to that State and that is not registered under the laws of that State, except a law regulating landings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State Permit or Treaty Right Required</inline>.—</heading><content>No vessel may harvest or process Dungeness crab in the exclusive economic zone adjacent to the State of Washington, Oregon, or California, except as authorized by a permit issued by any of those States or pursuant to any tribal treaty rights to Dungeness crab pursuant to the decision in United States v. Washington, D.C. No. CV–70–09213.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State Authority Otherwise Preserved</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as expressly provided in this section, nothing in this section reduces the authority of any State under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.) to regulate fishing, fish processing, or landing of fish.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority of the States of Washington, Oregon, and California under this section with respect to a Dungeness crab fishery shall expire on the effective date of a fishery management plan for the fishery under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repeal</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="id79809f4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<p>[Repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/297/s112/d">section 112(d) of Pub. L. 104–297</ref>, see below.]</p></note>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>The definitions set forth in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</ref>) shall apply to this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Pacific State Marine Fisheries Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Resources [now Committee on Natural Resources] of the House of Representatives a report on the status and management of the Dungeness Crab fishery located off the coasts of the States of Washington, Oregon, and California, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> stock status and trends throughout its range;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a description of applicable research and scientific review processes used to determine stock status and trends; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> measures implemented or planned that are designed to prevent or end overfishing in the fishery.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/297/tI/s112/d">Pub. L. 104–297, title I, § 112(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3596">110 Stat. 3596</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 211(b)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–41, which provided interim authority to the States of Washington, Oregon, and California to enforce State laws and regulations governing fish harvesting and processing against any vessel operating in the exclusive economic zone off each respective State in a fishery for Dungeness crab (Cancer magister) for which there is no fishery management plan implemented under this chapter, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/384/tII/s203/g">Pub. L. 105–384, title II, § 203(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3454">112 Stat. 3454</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79809f4c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Foreign Fish Processing in Norton Sound</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tV/s5004">Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1912">100 Stat. 1912</ref>, provided that for purposes of processing pink salmon within the internal waters of the State of Alaska, the geographic area bounded on the north by a parallel of latitude of 64 degrees, 23 minutes, on the south by a parallel of latitude of 63 degrees, 51 minutes, on the east by the baseline from which the territorial sea was measured, and on the west by the outer limit of the territorial sea, was to be considered to be internal waters of the State of Alaska for the purposes of subsec. (c)(4)(B) of this section until <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79809f4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79809f4e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Territorial Sea and Contiguous Zone of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For extension of territorial sea and contiguous zone of United States, see Proc. No. 5928 and Proc. No. 7219, respectively, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">section 1331 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
