<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id798c8622-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003"><num value="2003">§ 2003.</num><heading> Congressional policy and declaration of purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id798c8623-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsiveness to long-term needs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to further the conservation of soil, water, and related resources, it is declared to be the policy of the United States and purpose of this chapter that the conduct of programs administered by the Secretary of Agriculture for the conservation of such resources shall be responsive to the long-term needs of the Nation, as determined under the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id798c8624-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Full utilization of cooperative arrangements with State and tribal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Recognizing that the arrangements under which the Federal Government cooperates with State and tribal soil and water conservation agencies and other appropriate State and tribal natural resource agencies such as those concerned with forestry and fish and wildlife and, through conservation districts, with other local units of government and land users, have effectively aided in the protection and improvement of the Nation’s basic resources, including the restoration and maintenance of resources damaged by improper use, it is declared to be the policy of the United States that these arrangements and similar cooperative arrangements should be utilized to the fullest extent practicable to achieve the purpose of this chapter consistent with the roles and responsibilities of the non-Federal agencies, landowners and land users.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id798c8625-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Attainment of policies and purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall promote the attainment of the policies and purposes expressed in this chapter by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id798c8626-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> appraising on a continuing basis the soil, water, and related resources of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id798c8627-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> developing and updating periodically a program for furthering the conservation, protection, and enhancement of the soil, water, and related resources of the Nation consistent with the roles and program responsibilities of other Federal agencies and State, tribal, and local governments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id798c8628-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2003/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> providing to Congress and the public, through reports, the information developed pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, and by providing Congress with an annual evaluation report as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2006">section 2006 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id798c8629-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/192/s4">Pub. L. 95–192, § 4</ref>, <date date="1977-11-18">Nov. 18, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1407">91 Stat. 1407</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tII/s2508/a">Pub. L. 113–79, title II, § 2508(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/756">128 Stat. 756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id798c862a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id798c862b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id798c862c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s2508/a/1">Pub. L. 113–79, § 2508(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and tribal” after “State” in two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s2508/a/2">Pub. L. 113–79, § 2508(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “, tribal,” after “State”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id798c862d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id798c862e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
