<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7716f169-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s221b"><num value="221b">§ 221b.</num><heading> Various laws made applicable to added lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of the Act of <date date="1919-02-26">February 26, 1919</date>, entitled “An Act to establish the Grand Canyon National Park in the State of Arizona,” the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date>, entitled “An Act to establish a national park service, and for other purposes,” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002036"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and all acts supplementary to and amendatory of said Acts are made applicable to and extended over the lands hereby added to the park: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.] shall not apply to or extend over such lands.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7716f16a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-02-25/ch197/s2">Feb. 25, 1927, ch. 197, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1240">44 Stat. 1240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7716f16b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7716f16c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7716f16d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1919-02-26">February 26, 1919</date>, entitled “An Act to establish the Grand Canyon National Park in the State of Arizona,”, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1919-02-26/ch44">act Feb. 26, 1919, ch. 44</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1175">40 Stat. 1175</ref>, which is classified to sections 221, 222 to 228, and 687 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date>, entitled “An Act to establish a national park service, and for other purposes”, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Act, referred to in text, was in the original the “Act of <date date="1920-06-10">June 10, 1920</date>, entitled ‘an Act to create a Federal power commission; to provide for the improvement of navigation, the development of water power; the use of the public lands in relation thereto; and to repeal section 18 of the River and Harbor Appropriation Act, approved <date date="1917-08-08">August 8, 1917</date>, and for other purposes’ ”, and was redesignated the Federal Power Act by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref>. The Federal Power Act is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">act June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>, and is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
