<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7716f1af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s228g"><num value="228g">§ 228g.</num><heading> Aircraft or helicopter regulation within enlarged boundaries; procedure for promulgation of administrative rules and regulations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that any aircraft or helicopter activity or operation may be occurring or about to occur within the Grand Canyon National Park, as enlarged by sections 228a to 228j of this title, including the airspace below the rims of the canyon, which is likely to cause an injury to the health, welfare, or safety of visitors to the park or to cause a significant adverse effect on the natural quiet and experience of the park, the Secretary shall submit to the Federal Aviation Administration, the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to the Noise Control Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4901">42 U.S.C. 4901</ref> et seq.], or any other responsible agency or agencies such complaints, information, or recommendations for rules and regulations or other actions as he believes appropriate to protect the public health, welfare, and safety or the natural environment within the park. After reviewing the submission of the Secretary, the responsible agency shall consider the matter, and after consultation with the Secretary, shall take appropriate action to protect the park and visitors.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7716f1b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/620/s8">Pub. L. 93–620, § 8</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2091">88 Stat. 2091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7716f1b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7716f1b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7716f1b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Noise Control Act of 1972, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/92/574">Pub. L. 92–574</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1234">86 Stat. 1234</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 65 (§ 4901 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4901">section 4901 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7716f1b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7716f1b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Federal Aviation Administration” substituted in text for “Federal Aviation Agency” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/89/670">Pub. L. 89–670</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/931">80 Stat. 931</ref>, which transferred functions, powers, and duties of Federal Aviation Agency and of Administrator and other offices and officers thereof to Secretary of Transportation and established Federal Aviation Administration in Department of Transportation. See <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
