<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id771e1d71-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s241e"><num value="241e">§ 241e.</num><heading> Authority to make further adjustments</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make further adjustments in the boundaries of the park along United States Highways Numbered 10 and 85 as he deems advisable and in the public interest if and when the alinement of these highways is changed: <i>Provided</i>, That not to exceed five hundred acres may be added to the park and not to exceed two thousand acres may be excluded from the park by such adjustments. Boundary adjustments made pursuant to this section shall be effective upon publication thereof in the Federal Register and all Federal land excluded from the park pursuant to sections 241c to 241f of this title shall be transferred to the Secretary of Agriculture for administration or disposition in accordance with title III of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1010">7 U.S.C. 1010</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id771e1d72-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-03-24/ch94/s3">Mar. 24, 1956, ch. 94, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/56">70 Stat. 56</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id771e1d73-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id771e1d74-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id771e1d75-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1937-07-22/ch517">act July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/522">50 Stat. 522</ref>. Title III of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1010 et seq.) of chapter 33 of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1000">section 1000 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id771e1d76-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/act/1947-04-25/ch41">act Apr. 25, 1947, ch. 41</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/52">61 Stat. 52</ref>, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
