<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id771e1da4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s251"><num value="251">§ 251.</num><heading> Establishment; boundaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Mount Olympus National Monument established pursuant to proclamation of the President dated <date date="1909-03-02">March 2, 1909</date>, is abolished, and the tracts of land in the State of Washington particularly described as follows, to wit: Township 25 north, range 4 west, sections 5 to 8, 17 to 20, and 29 to 32, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 26 north, range 4 west, sections 1 to 12, 17 to 20, and 29 to 32, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 27 north, range 4 west, sections 5 to 8, 17 to 20, and 29 to 36, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 28 north, range 4 west, sections 17 to 22, and 27 to 34, inclusive (unsurveyed); townships 25, 26, and 27 north, range 5 west (unsurveyed), township 28 north, range 5 west, sections 7 to 36, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 24 north, range 6 west, sections 3 to 10, 15 to 22, and 27 to 34, inclusive (unsurveyed); townships 25, 26, and 27 north, range 6 west (unsurveyed); township 28 north, range 6 west, sections 7 to 36, inclusive (unsurveyed); townships 24, 25, 26, and 27 north range 7 west (unsurveyed); township 28 north, range 7 west, sections 5 to 36, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 24 north, range 8 west, sections 1 to 18, inclusive (partly surveyed); townships 25, 26, 27, and 28 north, range 8 west (unsurveyed); township 29 north, range 8 west, sections 6, 7, 18, 19 to 21, and 28 to 33, inclusive (unsurveyed); township 30 north, range 8 west, sections 18, 19, 30, and 31 (partly surveyed); township 24 north, range 9 west, sections 1 2, 11, 12, 13, and 14 (partly surveyed); township 25 north, range 9 west (unsurveyed); township 26 north, range 9 west, sections 1 to 18, inclusive (unsurveyed) each half of section 19 (unsurveyed), sections 20 to 29, and 32 to 36, inclusive (surveyed); townships 27 and 28 north, range 9 west (unsurveyed); township 29 north, range 9 west (partly surveyed); township 30 north, range 9 west, sections 13, 14, and 23 to 36, inclusive (partly surveyed); township 26 north, range 10 west, sections 1, 12, and 13 (surveyed); township 27 north, range 10 west, sections 1 to 6, inclusive, 12, 13, 24, 25, and 36 (surveyed); township 28 north, range 10 west, south half section 7, south half section 8, south half section 9, south half section 10, south half section 11, south half section 12, sections 13 to 36, inclusive (unsurveyed) all west of the Willamette meridian, in Washington, are reserved and withdrawn from settlement, occupancy, or disposal under the laws of the United States and dedicated and set apart as a public park for the benefit and enjoyment of the people and shall be known as the Olympic National Park, and all lands formerly included in the Mount Olympus National Monument and not included in the above description are transferred to and made a part of the Olympic National Forest.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id771e1da5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-29/ch812/s1">June 29, 1938, ch. 812, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1241">52 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id771e1da6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id771e1da7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id771e1da8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/323/s1">Pub. L. 111–323, § 1</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3532">124 Stat. 3532</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/323/s1">“This Act [enacting provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Hoh Indian Tribe Safe Homelands Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id771e1da9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Quileute Tribe—Redesignations and Conveyances</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/97">Pub. L. 112–97</ref>, <date date="2012-02-27">Feb. 27, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/257">126 Stat. 257</ref>, provided for removal of certain Federal land in the Olympic National Park from the National Wilderness Preservation System and placement of certain land in trust for the benefit of the Quileute Indian Tribe to grant the Tribe access to land outside the tsunami zone and resolve a dispute over the northern boundary of their Reservation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id771e1daa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Hoh Indian Tribe Safe Homelands</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/323">Pub. L. 111–323</ref>, §§ 2, 3(a)(1), <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3532">124 Stat. 3532</ref>, provided that, effective <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, a parcel of Federal land of approximately 37 acres, administered by the National Park Service, and depicted on the Hoh Indian Tribe Safe Homelands Act Land Acquisition Map, is considered held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe and shall be excluded from the boundaries of Olympic National Park.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id771e1dab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Land Exchange With City of Tacoma, Washington</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/436/tI">Pub. L. 102–436, title I</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2217">106 Stat. 2217</ref>, provided that if the city of Tacoma offered to convey to the United States approximately 45 acres of land located in the Soleduck and Quileute areas within the boundary of Olympic National Park, in exchange for approximately 30 acres of land adjacent to Lake Cushman as depicted on a map entitled “Proposed Boundary Revision Olympic National Park” and dated <date date="1991-07-29">July 29, 1991</date>, then the Secretary of the Interior was to carry out such exchange, provided Tacoma could deliver clear and unencumbered title, and subject to the laws and regulations applicable to exchanges of land in the National Park System, adjustment of the Olympic National Park boundaries, and additional provisions excluding such exchange from affecting the operating level of Cushman Reservoir, rights of possible intervenors in the Cushman Project, or fishing rights of the Skokomish Tribe or any other Indian tribe.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/c/tI/s116">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title I, § 116]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-156">110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–178; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>, required the Department of the Interior to issue a specific schedule for the completion of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/102/436">Pub. L. 102–436</ref> (formerly set out above) within 30 days after <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, and to complete the land exchange not later than <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id771e1dac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition of Certain Buildings, Etc.; Appropriation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1944-12-06/ch506">Act Dec. 6, 1944, ch. 506</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/793">58 Stat. 793</ref>, authorized the Secretary of the Interior to purchase buildings and fixtures of the Olympic Recreation Company and the Olympic Chalet Company, and appropriated $35,000 for that purpose.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
