<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799d4ef9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602"><num value="2602">§ 2602.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this Act, except as otherwise specifically provided—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4efa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “antitrust laws” includes the Sherman Antitrust Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">15 U.S.C. 1</ref> and following), the Clayton Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">15 U.S.C. 12</ref> and following), the Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s14">15 U.S.C. 14</ref>[41] and following), the Wilson Tariff Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">15 U.S.C. 8</ref> and 9), and the Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, chapter 592 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">15 U.S.C. 13</ref>, 13a, 13b, and 21A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4efb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “class” means, with respect to electric consumers, any group of such consumers who have similar characteristics of electric energy use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4efc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “Commission” means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4efd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “electric utility” means any person, State agency, or Federal agency, which sells electric energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4efe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “electric consumer” means any person, State agency, or Federal agency, to which electric energy is sold other than for purposes of resale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4eff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The term “evidentiary hearing” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799d4f00-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a State agency, a proceeding which (i) is open to the public, (ii) includes notice to participants and an opportunity for such participants to present direct and rebuttal evidence and to cross-examine witnesses, (iii) includes a written decision, based upon evidence appearing in a written record of the proceeding, and (iv) is subject to judicial review;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799d4f01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a Federal agency, a proceeding conducted as provided in sections 554, 556, and 557 of title 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799d4f02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of a proceeding conducted by any entity other than a State or Federal agency, a proceeding which conforms, to the extent appropriate, with the requirements of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Federal agency” means an executive agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f04-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “load management technique” means any technique (other than a time-of-day or seasonal rate) to reduce the maximum kilowatt demand on the electric utility, including ripple or radio control mechanisms, and other types of interruptible electric service, energy storage devices, and load-limiting devices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “nonregulated electric utility” means any electric utility other than a State regulated electric utility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “rate” means (A) any price, rate, charge, or classification made, demanded, observed, or received with respect to sale of electric energy by an electric utility to an electric consumer, (B) any rule, regulation, or practice respecting any such rate, charge, or classification, and (C) any contract pertaining to the sale of electric energy to an electric consumer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f07-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “ratemaking authority” means authority to fix, modify, approve, or disapprove rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f08-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “rate schedule” means the designation of the rates which an electric utility charges for electric energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f09-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The term “sale” when used with respect to electric energy includes any exchange of electric energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> The term “State agency” means a State, political subdivision thereof, and any agency or instrumentality of either.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> The term “State regulatory authority” means any State agency which has ratemaking authority with respect to the sale of electric energy by any electric utility (other than such State agency), and in the case of an electric utility with respect to which the Tennessee Valley Authority has ratemaking authority, such term means the Tennessee Valley Authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> The term “State regulated electric utility” means any electric utility with respect to which a State regulatory authority has ratemaking authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f0f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> The term “integrated resource planning” means, in the case of an electric utility, a planning and selection process for new energy resources that evaluates the full range of alternatives, including new generating capacity, power purchases, energy conservation and efficiency, cogeneration and district heating and cooling applications, and renewable energy resources, in order to provide adequate and reliable service to its electric customers at the lowest system cost. The process shall take into account necessary features for system operation, such as diversity, reliability, dispatchability, and other factors of risk; shall take into account the ability to verify energy savings achieved through energy conservation and efficiency and the projected durability of such savings measured over time; and shall treat demand and supply resources on a consistent and integrated basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f10-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> The term “system cost” means all direct and quantifiable net costs for an energy resource over its available life, including the cost of production, distribution, transportation, utilization, waste management, and environmental compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799d4f11-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2602/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content> The term “demand side management” includes load management techniques.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id799d4f12-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/s3">Pub. L. 95–617, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3119">92 Stat. 3119</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s111/d">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 111(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2796">106 Stat. 2796</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id799d4f13-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id799d4f14-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id799d4f15-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/95/617">Pub. L. 95–617</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3117">92 Stat. 3117</ref>, known as the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2601">section 2601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Sherman Antitrust Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">15 U.S.C. 1</ref> and following), referred to in par. (1), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-07-02/ch647">act July 2, 1890, ch. 647</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/209">26 Stat. 209</ref>, which enacted sections 1 to 7 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">section 1 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clayton Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">15 U.S.C. 12</ref> and following), referred to in par. (1), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323">act Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>, which is classified generally to sections 12, 13, 14 to 19, 21, and 22 to 27 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and sections 52 and 53 of Title 29, Labor. For further details and complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s14">15 U.S.C. 14</ref> and following), referred to in par. (1), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilson Tariff Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">15 U.S.C. 8</ref> and 9), referred to in par. (1), is sections 73 to 77 of <ref href="/us/act/1894-08-27/ch349">act Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/570">28 Stat. 570</ref>. Sections 73 to 76 enacted sections 8 to 11 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. Section 77 of said Act was not classified to the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">section 8 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, chapter 592 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">15 U.S.C. 13</ref>, 13a, 13b, and 21A), referred to in par. (1), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-19/ch592">act June 19, 1936, ch. 592</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1526">49 Stat. 1526</ref>, popularly known as the Robinson-Patman Antidiscrimination Act and also as the Robinson-Patman Price Discrimination Act, which enacted sections 13a, 13b, and 21a of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of Title 15</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id799d4f16-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section was not enacted as part of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/95/617">Pub. L. 95–617</ref> which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id799d4f17-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Pars. (19) to (21). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> added pars. (19) to (21).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
