<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799f98e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625"><num value="2625">§ 2625.</num><heading> Special rules for standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost of service</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In undertaking the consideration and making the determination under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621">section 2621 of this title</ref> with respect to the standard concerning cost of service established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/1">section 2621(d)(1) of this title</ref>, the costs of providing electric service to each class of electric consumers shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be determined on the basis of methods prescribed by the State regulatory authority (in the case of a State regulated electric utility) or by the electric utility (in the case of a nonregulated electric utility). Such methods shall to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> permit identification of differences in cost-incurrence, for each such class of electric consumers, attributable to daily and seasonal time of use of service and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> permit identification of differences in cost-incurrence attributable to differences in customer demand, and energy components of cost. In prescribing such methods, such State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility shall take into account the extent to which total costs to an electric utility are likely to change if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f98e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> additional capacity is added to meet peak demand relative to base demand; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f98e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> additional kilowatt-hours of electric energy are delivered to electric consumers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Time-of-day rates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In undertaking the consideration and making the determination required under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621">section 2621 of this title</ref> with respect to the standard for time-of-day rates established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/3">section 2621(d)(3) of this title</ref> and the standard for time-based metering and communications established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/14">section 2621(d)(14) of this title</ref>, a time-of-day rate charged by an electric utility for providing electric service to each class of electric consumers shall be determined to be cost-effective with respect to each such class if the long-run benefits of such rate to the electric utility and its electric consumers in the class concerned are likely to exceed the metering and communications costs and other costs associated with the use of such rates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Load management techniques</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In undertaking the consideration and making the determination required under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621">section 2621 of this title</ref> with respect to the standard for load management techniques established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/6">section 2621(d)(6) of this title</ref>, a load management technique shall be determined, by the State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility, to be cost-effective if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such technique is likely to reduce maximum kilowatt demand on the electric utility, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the long-run cost-savings to the utility of such reduction are likely to exceed the long-run costs to the utility associated with implementation of such technique.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Master metering</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Separate metering shall be determined appropriate for any new building for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/1">section 2623(b)(1) of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> there is more than one unit in such building,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the occupant of each such unit has control over a portion of the electric energy used in such unit, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with respect to such portion of electric energy used in such unit, the long-run benefits to the electric consumers in such building exceed the costs of purchasing and installing separate meters in such building.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Automatic adjustment clauses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An automatic adjustment clause of an electric utility meets the requirements of this subsection if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such clause is determined, not less often than every four years, by the State regulatory authority (with respect to an electric utility for which it has ratemaking authority) or by the electric utility (in the case of a nonregulated electric utility), after an evidentiary hearing, to provide incentives for efficient use of resources (including incentives for economical purchase and use of fuel and electric energy) by such electric utility, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such clause is reviewed not less often than every two years, in the manner described in paragraph (2), by the State regulatory authority having ratemaking authority with respect to such utility (or by the electric utility in the case of a nonregulated electric utility), to insure the maximum economies in those operations and purchases which affect the rates to which such clause applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In making a review under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) with respect to an electric utility, the reviewing authority shall examine and, if appropriate, cause to be audited the practices of such electric utility relating to costs subject to an automatic adjustment clause, and shall require such reports as may be necessary to carry out such review (including a disclosure of any ownership or corporate relationship between such electric utility and the seller to such utility of fuel, electric energy, or other items).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> As used in this subsection and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b">section 2623(b) of this title</ref>, the term “automatic adjustment clause” means a provision of a rate schedule which provides for increases or decreases (or both), without prior hearing, in rates reflecting increases or decreases (or both) in costs incurred by an electric utility. Such term does not include an interim rate which takes effect subject to a later determination of the appropriate amount of the rate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to consumers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For purposes of the standard for information to consumers established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/3">section 2623(b)(3) of this title</ref>, each electric utility shall transmit to each of its electric consumers a clear and concise explanation of the existing rate schedule and any rate schedule applied for (or proposed by a nonregulated electric utility) applicable to such consumer. Such statement shall be transmitted to each such consumer—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not later than sixty days after the date of commencement of service to such consumer or ninety days after the standard established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/3">section 2623(b)(3) of this title</ref> is adopted with respect to such electric utility, whichever last occurs, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than thirty days (sixty days in the case of an electric utility which uses a bimonthly billing system) after such utility’s application for any change in a rate schedule applicable to such consumer (or proposal of such a change in the case of a nonregulated utility).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of the standard for information to consumers established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/3">section 2623(b)(3) of this title</ref>, each electric utility shall transmit to each of its electric consumers not less frequently than once each year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a clear and concise summary of the existing rate schedules applicable to each of the major classes of its electric consumers for which there is a separate rate, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an identification of any classes whose rates are not summarized.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such summary may be transmitted together with such consumer’s billing or in such other manner as the State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility deems appropriate.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f98fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of the standard for information to consumers established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/3">section 2623(b)(3) of this title</ref>, each electric utility, on request of an electric consumer of such utility, shall transmit to such consumer a clear and concise statement of the actual consumption (or degree-day adjusted consumption) of electric energy by such consumer for each billing period during the prior year (unless such consumption data is not reasonably ascertainable by the utility).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f98fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for termination of electric service</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The procedures for termination of service referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/4">section 2623(b)(4) of this title</ref> are procedures prescribed by the State regulatory authority (with respect to electric utilities for which it has ratemaking authority) or by the nonregulated electric utility which provide that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f98ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> no electric service to an electric consumer may be terminated unless reasonable prior notice (including notice of rights and remedies) is given to such consumer and such consumer has a reasonable opportunity to dispute the reasons for such termination, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9900-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> during any period when termination of service to an electric consumer would be especially dangerous to health, as determined by the State regulatory authority (with respect to an electric utility for which it has ratemaking authority) or nonregulated electric utility, and such consumer establishes that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f9901-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> he is unable to pay for such service in accordance with the requirements of the utility’s billing, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f9902-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> he is able to pay for such service but only in installments,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">such service may not be terminated.</continuation>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such procedures shall take into account the need to include reasonable provisions for elderly and handicapped consumers.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9903-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9904-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/5">section 2623(b)(5) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9905-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “advertising” means the commercial use, by an electric utility, of any media, including newspaper, printed matter, radio, and television, in order to transmit a message to a substantial number of members of the public or to such utility’s electric consumers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9906-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “political advertising” means any advertising for the purpose of influencing public opinion with respect to legislative, administrative, or electoral matters, or with respect to any controversial issue of public importance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9907-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The term “promotional advertising” means any advertising for the purpose of encouraging any person to select or use the service or additional service of an electric utility or the selection or installation of any appliance or equipment designed to use such utility’s service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9908-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2623/b/5">section 2623(b)(5) of this title</ref>, the terms “political advertising” and “promotional advertising” do not include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9909-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> advertising which informs electric consumers how they can conserve energy or can reduce peak demand for electric energy,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f990a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> advertising required by law or regulation, including advertising required under part 1 of title II of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8211">42 U.S.C. 8211</ref> et seq.],</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f990b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> advertising regarding service interruptions, safety measures, or emergency conditions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f990c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> advertising concerning employment opportunities with such utility,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f990d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> advertising which promotes the use of energy efficient appliances, equipment or services, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f990e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/h/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any explanation or justification of existing or proposed rate schedules, or notifications of hearings thereon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f990f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2625/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Time-based metering and communications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making a determination with respect to the standard established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/14">section 2621(d)(14) of this title</ref>, the investigation requirement of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/14/F">section 2621(d)(14)(F) of this title</ref> shall be as follows: Each State regulatory authority shall conduct an investigation and issue a decision whether or not it is appropriate for electric utilities to provide and install time-based meters and communications devices for each of their customers which enable such customers to participate in time-based pricing rate schedules and other demand response programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id799f9910-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tI/s115">Pub. L. 95–617, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3125">92 Stat. 3125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII/s1252/b">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII, § 1252(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/965">119 Stat. 965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id799f9911-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id799f9912-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id799f9913-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Energy Conservation Policy Act, referred to in subsec. (h)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3206">92 Stat. 3206</ref>. Part 1 of title II of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act was classified generally to part A (§ 8211 et seq.) of subchapter II of chapter 91 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8229">section 8229 of Title 42</ref> which terminated authority under that part <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8201">section 8201 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id799f9914-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1252/b/1">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1252(b)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “and the standard for time-based metering and communications established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/14">section 2621(d)(14) of this title</ref>” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621/d/3">section 2621(d)(3) of this title</ref>” and substituted “metering and communications costs” for “metering costs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1252/b/3">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1252(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
