<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799f9930-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632"><num value="2632">§ 2632.</num><heading> Consumer representation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9931-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation for costs of participation or intervention</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9932-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If no alternative means for assuring representation of electric consumers is adopted in accordance with subsection (b) and if an electric consumer of an electric utility substantially contributed to the approval, in whole or in part, of a position advocated by such consumer in a proceeding concerning such utility, and relating to any standard set forth in subchapter II, such utility shall be liable to compensate such consumer (pursuant to paragraph (2)) for reasonable attorneys’ fees, expert witness fees, and other reasonable costs incurred in preparation and advocacy of such position in such proceeding (including fees and costs of obtaining judicial review of any determination made in such proceeding with respect to such position).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9933-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A consumer entitled to fees and costs under paragraph (1) may collect such fees and costs from an electric utility by bringing a civil action in any State court of competent jurisdiction, unless the State regulatory authority (in the case of a proceeding concerning a State regulated electric utility) or nonregulated electric utility (in the case of a proceeding concerning such nonregulated electric utility) has adopted a reasonable procedure pursuant to which such authority or nonregulated electric utility—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9934-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> determines the amount of such fees and costs, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9935-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes an award of such fees and costs in its order in the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9936-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The procedure adopted by such State regulatory authority or nonregulated utility under paragraph (2) may include a preliminary proceeding to require that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9937-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as a condition of receiving compensation under such procedure such consumer demonstrate that, but for the ability to receive such award, participation or intervention in such proceeding may be a significant financial hardship for such consumer, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9938-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> persons with the same or similar interests have a common legal representative in the proceeding as a condition to receiving compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9939-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative means</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Compensation shall not be required under subsection (a) if the State, the State regulatory authority (in the case of a proceeding concerning a State regulated electric utility), or the nonregulated electric utility (in the case of a proceeding concerning such nonregulated electric utility) has provided an alternative means for providing adequate compensation to persons—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f993a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> who have, or represent, an interest—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f993b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which would not otherwise be adequately represented in the proceeding, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799f993c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> representation of which is necessary for a fair determination in the proceeding, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f993d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> who are, or represent an interest which is, unable to effectively participate or intervene in the proceeding because such persons cannot afford to pay reasonable attorneys’ fees, expert witness fees, and other reasonable costs of preparing for, and participating or intervening in, such proceeding (including fees and costs of obtaining judicial review of such proceeding).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f993e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Transcripts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility, as the case may be, shall make transcripts of the proceeding available, at cost of reproduction, to parties or intervenors in any ratemaking proceeding, or other regulatory proceeding relating to rates or rate design, before a State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f993f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any claim under this section against any Federal agency shall be subject to the availability of appropriated funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9940-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2632/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights under other authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section affects or restricts any rights of any participant or intervenor in any proceeding under any other applicable law or rule of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id799f9941-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tI/s122">Pub. L. 95–617, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3129">92 Stat. 3129</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
