<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799f9942-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633"><num value="2633">§ 2633.</num><heading> Judicial review and enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9943-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation of Federal jurisdiction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any action arising under any provision of subchapter I or II or of this subchapter except for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9944-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an action over which a court of the United States has jurisdiction under subsection (b) or (c)(2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799f9945-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> review of any action in the Supreme Court of the United States in accordance with sections 1257 and 1258 of title 28.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f9946-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement of intervention right</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9947-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may bring an action in any appropriate court of the United States to enforce his right to intervene and participate under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2631/a">section 2631(a) of this title</ref>, and such court shall have jurisdiction to grant appropriate relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9948-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If any electric utility or electric consumer having a right to intervene under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2631/a">section 2631(a) of this title</ref> is denied such right by any State court, such electric utility or electric consumer may bring an action in the appropriate United States district court to require the State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility to permit such intervention and participation, and such court shall have jurisdiction to grant appropriate relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f9949-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection prohibits any person bringing any action under this subsection in a court of the United States from seeking review and enforcement at any time in any State court of any rights he may have with respect to any motion to intervene or participate in any proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799f994a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id799f994b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any person (including the Secretary) may obtain review of any determination made under subchapter I or II or under this subchapter with respect to any electric utility (other than a utility which is a Federal agency) in the appropriate State court if such person (or the Secretary) intervened or otherwise participated in the original proceeding or if State law otherwise permits such review. Any person (including the Secretary) may bring an action to enforce the requirements of this chapter in the appropriate State court, except that no such action may be brought in a State court with respect to a utility which is a Federal agency. Such review or action in a State court shall be pursuant to any applicable State procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79a2094c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person (including the Secretary) may obtain review in the appropriate court of the United States of any determination made under subchapter I or II or this subchapter by a Federal agency if such person (or the Secretary) intervened or otherwise participated in the original proceeding or if otherwise applicable law permits such review. Such court shall have jurisdiction to grant appropriate relief. Any person (including the Secretary) may bring an action to enforce the requirements of subchapter I or II or this subchapter with respect to any Federal agency in the appropriate court of the United States and such court shall have jurisdiction to grant appropriate relief.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79a2094d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to his authority to obtain review under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary may also participate as an amicus curiae in any review by any court of an action arising under the provisions of subchapter I or II or this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a2094e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Other authority of Secretary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section prohibits the Secretary from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a2094f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> intervening and participating in any proceeding, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a20950-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2633/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> intervening and participating in any review by any court of any action</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6804">section 6804 of title 42</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79a20951-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tI/s123">Pub. L. 95–617, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3130">92 Stat. 3130</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79a20952-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79a20953-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79a20954-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I (§ 101 et seq.) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/617">Pub. L. 95–617</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3120">92 Stat. 3120</ref>, which enacted subchapters I to IV of this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6808">section 6808 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, and amended sections 6802 to 6807 of Title 42. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
