<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7723007d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s271a"><num value="271a">§ 271a.</num><heading> Acquisition of lands; authority of Secretary; exchange of property; cash equalization payments; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; lands subject to reclamation and power withdrawals</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the area which lies within the boundaries of the park, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire lands and interests in lands by such means as he may deem to be in the public interest. The Secretary may accept title to any non-Federal property within the park, including State-owned school sections and riverbed lands, and in exchange therefor he may convey to the grantor of such property any federally owned property under his jurisdiction within the State of Utah, notwithstanding any other provision of law. The properties so exchanged shall be of the same classification, as near as may be, and shall be of approximately equal value, and the Secretary shall take administrative action to complete transfer on any lands in a proper application by the State of Utah on or before the expiration of one hundred twenty days following the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1964-09-12">September 12, 1964</date>] or any amendment thereto: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may accept cash from, or pay cash to, the grantor in such an exchange in order to equalize the values of the properties exchanged. Federal property located within the boundaries of the park may, with the concurrence of the agency having custody thereof, be transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, without consideration, for use by him in carrying out the purposes of this subchapter. Any lands within the boundaries of the park which are subject to Bureau of Reclamation or Federal Power Commission withdrawals are hereby freed and exonerated from any such withdrawal and shall, on <date date="1964-09-12">September 12, 1964</date>, become a part of the Canyonlands National Park subject to no qualifications except those imposed by this subchapter or any amendment thereto.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7723007e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/590/s2">Pub. L. 88–590, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-09-12">Sept. 12, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/937">78 Stat. 937</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/154/s1/b">Pub. L. 92–154, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1971-11-12">Nov. 12, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/421">85 Stat. 421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7723007f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77230080-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77230081-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Date of enactment of this Act or any amendment thereto, referred to in text, means <date date="1964-09-12">Sept. 12, 1964</date>, date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/88/590">Pub. L. 88–590</ref>, originally classified to sections 271 to 271d of this title, and <date date="1971-11-12">Nov. 12, 1971</date>, date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/92/154">Pub. L. 92–154</ref>, amendatory of <ref href="/us/pl/88/590">Pub. L. 88–590</ref> and classified to sections 271 to 271b, 271e to 271g of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77230082-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—<ref href="/us/pl/92/154">Pub. L. 92–154</ref> struck out “described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s271">section 271 of this title</ref>” after “Within the area”, inserted in third sentence “or any amendment thereto” after “the date of enactment of this Act”, and inserted in fifth sentence “or any amendment thereto” after “this subchapter”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77230083-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77230084-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Commission was terminated, and its functions, personnel, property, funds, etc., were transferred to the Secretary of Energy (except for certain functions which were transferred to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission) by sections 7151(b), 7171(a), 7172(a), 7291, and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
