<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id772549e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s273b"><num value="273b">§ 273b.</num><heading> Grazing privileges; right of occupancy or use for fixed term of years; renewal</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where any Federal lands included within the park are legally occupied or utilized on <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>, for grazing purposes, pursuant to a lease, permit, or license for a fixed term of years issued or authorized by any department, establishment, or agency of the United States, the Secretary of the Interior shall permit the persons holding such grazing privileges or their heirs to continue in the exercise thereof during the term of the lease, permit, or license, and one period of renewal thereafter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id772549e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/207/s3">Pub. L. 92–207, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/740">85 Stat. 740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id772549e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id772549ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id772549eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Renewal of Capitol Reef National Park Grazing Authorizations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/446/tI">Pub. L. 100–446, title I</ref>, <date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1779">102 Stat. 1779</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/446/tI">
<inline>“That where any Federal lands included within the boundary of the Park created by the Act of <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date> (<ref href="/us/pl/92/207">Public Law 92–207</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s273">16 U.S.C. 273</ref> et seq.], were legally occupied or utilized on the date of approval of that Act [<date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>] for grazing purposes pursuant to a lease, permit, or license issued or authorized by any department, establishment, or agency of the United States, the person or persons so occupying or utilizing such lands and the heirs of such person or persons shall at that time be entitled to renew said leases, permits, or licenses under such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe, for the lifetime of the permittee or any direct descendants (sons or daughters) born on or before the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/92/207">Public Law 92–207</ref> (<date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date>). Such grazing activities shall be subject to the following conditions:</inline>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Grazing will be based on active preference that exists on the date of this Act [<date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>] and no increase in animal unit months will be allowed on Park lands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> No physical improvements for stock use will be established on National Park Service lands without the written concurrence of the Park Superintendent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall apply to any lease, permit, or license for mining purposes or for public accommodations and services or to any occupancy or utilization of lands for purely temporary purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> Nothing contained in this Act [see Tables for classification] shall be construed as creating any vested right, title interest, or estate in or to any Federal lands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/97/341">Public Law 97–341</ref> [formerly set out as a note below] are hereby repealed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> Grazing will be managed to encourage the protection of the Park’s natural and cultural resources values.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id772549ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Grazing Phaseout at Capitol Reef National Park</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/341">Pub. L. 97–341</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1639">96 Stat. 1639</ref>, provided for retention of Capitol Reef National Park grazing privileges until <date date="1994-12-31">Dec. 31, 1994</date>, and a study of grazing at the Park, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/100/446/tI">Pub. L. 100–446, title I</ref>, <date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1780">102 Stat. 1780</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
