<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79a45401-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907"><num value="2907">§ 2907.</num><heading> Allocation of funds for administration and reimbursement of States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a45402-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The total amount appropriated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2910">section 2910 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year shall be available for administration and for allocation among the States as provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a45403-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation formula</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of the total amount appropriated for any fiscal year pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2910">section 2910 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a45404-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary shall deduct so much, but not to exceed 8 percent thereof, as may be necessary for administering during such fiscal year the provisions of this chapter relating to the purposes for which so appropriated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a45405-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> less the deduction under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall allocate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a45406-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for the District of Columbia and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico each a sum equal to not more than one-half of 1 percent of such amount; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a45407-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands each a sum equal to not more than one-sixth of 1 percent of such amount; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a45408-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> less the deduction under paragraph (1) and the sums allocated under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall allocate for each of the States (other than those provided for in paragraph (2)) a sum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a45409-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> one-third of which is based on the ratio to which the area of such State bears to the total area of all such States, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a4540a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> two-thirds of which is based on the ratio to which the population of such State bears to the total population of all such States,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">except all sums allocated under this paragraph shall be adjusted equitably so that no State shall be allocated a sum which is less than one-half of 1 percent of the amount available for allocation under this paragraph for any fiscal year or more than 5 percent of such amount.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a4540b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of amounts allocated but not used for any fiscal year</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79a4540c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> That portion of any amount deducted by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1) for administrative purposes for any fiscal year and not expended during such fiscal year shall remain available for administrative purposes until the close of the next succeeding fiscal year and if not obligated or expended by the close of such succeeding fiscal year shall be available for disbursement by the Secretary without regard to subsection (b), to the States to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79a4540d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s2907/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> That portion of any amount allocated to any State under subsection (b)(2) or (3) for any fiscal year and not disbursed to the State for such fiscal years under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2905">section 2905 of this title</ref> shall remain available for disbursement to the State under such section for the next succeeding fiscal year and if not disbursed for such succeeding fiscal year shall be available for disbursement by the Secretary, without regard to subsection (b), to the States to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79a4540e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/366/s8">Pub. L. 96–366, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-09-29">Sept. 29, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1328">94 Stat. 1328</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79a6c40f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79a6c410-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79a6c411-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
