<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79a6c450-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102"><num value="3102">§ 3102.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this Act (except that in titles IX and XIV the following terms shall have the same meaning as they have in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], and the Alaska Statehood Act)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c451-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “land” means lands, waters, and interests therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c452-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Federal land” means lands the title to which is in the United States after <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c453-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The term “public lands” means land situated in Alaska which, after <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, are Federal lands, except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a6c454-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> land selections of the State of Alaska which have been tentatively approved or validly selected under the Alaska Statehood Act and lands which have been confirmed to, validly selected by, or granted to the Territory of Alaska or the State under any other provision of Federal law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a6c455-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> land selections of a Native Corporation made under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.] which have not been conveyed to a Native Corporation, unless any such selection is determined to be invalid or is relinquished; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79a6c456-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> lands referred to in section 19(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1618/b">43 U.S.C. 1618(b)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c457-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “conservation system unit” means any unit in Alaska of the National Park System, National Wildlife Refuge System, National Wild and Scenic Rivers Systems, National Trails System, National Wilderness Preservation System, or a National Forest Monument including existing units, units established, designated, or expanded by or under the provisions of this Act, additions to such units, and any such unit established, designated, or expanded hereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c458-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act” means “An Act to provide for the settlement of certain land claims of Alaska Natives, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1971-12-18">December 18, 1971</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c459-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “Native Corporation” means any Regional Corporation, any Village Corporation, any Urban Corporation, and any Native Group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Regional Corporation” has the same meaning as such term has under section 3(g) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/g">43 U.S.C. 1602(g)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “Village Corporation” has the same meaning as such term has under section 3(j) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/j">43 U.S.C. 1602(j)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “Urban Corporation” means those Native entities which have incorporated pursuant to section 14(h)(3) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1613/h/3">43 U.S.C. 1613(h)(3)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “Native Group” has the same meaning as such term has under sections 3(d) and 14(h)(2) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/d">43 U.S.C. 1602(d)</ref> and 1613(h)(2)].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “Native land” means land owned by a Native Corporation or any Native Group and includes land which, as of <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, had been selected under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.] by a Native Corporation or Native Group and had not been conveyed by the Secretary (except to the extent such selection is determined to be invalid or has been relinquished) and land referred to in section 19(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1618/b">43 U.S.C. 1618(b)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c45f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, except that when such term is used with respect to any unit of the National Forest System, such term means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c460-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The terms “wilderness” and “National Wilderness Preservation System” have the same meaning as when used in the Wilderness Act (<ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c461-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “Alaska Statehood Act” means the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the admission of the State of Alaska into the Union”, approved <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>), as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c462-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The term “State” means the state of Alaska.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c463-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> The term “Alaska Native” or “Native” has the same meaning as the term “Native” has in section 3(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/b">43 U.S.C. 1602(b)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c464-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> The term “fish and wildlife” means any member of the animal kingdom, including without limitation any mammal, fish, bird (including any migratory, nonmigratory or endangered bird for which protection is also afforded by treaty or other international agreement), amphibian, reptile, mollusk, crustacean, arthropod or other invertebrate, and includes any part, product, egg, or offspring thereof, or the dead body or part thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79a6c465-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3102/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> The term “take” or “taking” as used with respect to fish or wildlife, means to pursue, hunt, shoot, trap, net capture, collect, kill, harm, or attempt to engage in any such conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id79a6c466-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tI/s102">Pub. L. 96–487, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2375">94 Stat. 2375</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/b/2">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 316(b)(2)</ref>, (d), <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1592">111 Stat. 1592</ref>, 1595.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79a6c467-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79a6c468-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79a6c469-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in provision preceding par. (1) and in par. (4), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. Title IX of this Act enacted sections 1631 to 1638 of Title 43, Public Lands, amended sections 1614 and 1620 of Title 43, and amended provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">section 1611 of Title 43</ref> and preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. Title XIV of this Act enacted sections 1639 to 1641 of Title 43, amended sections 1602, 1606, 1607, 1611, 1613, 1620, and 1621 of Title 43, enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1605, 1613, and 1618 of Title 43, and amended provisions set out as notes under sections 1611 and 1613 of Title 43. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in provision preceding par. (1) and in pars. (3)(B), (C)(5), and (11), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Statehood Act, referred to in provision preceding par. (1) and in pars. (3)(A) and (14), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>, which is set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilderness Act, referred to in par. (13), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/577">Pub. L. 88–577</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">section 1131 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79a6c46a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/s316/b/2">Pub. L. 105–83, § 316(b)(2)</ref>, which directed the amendment of par. (2) generally, to read as follows: “The term ‘Federal land’ means lands the title to which is in the United States after <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>. ‘Federal land’ does not include lands the title to which is in the State, an Alaska Native corporation, or other private ownership.”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/s316/d">Pub. L. 105–83, § 316(d)</ref>. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1997 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79a6c46b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79a6c46c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/d">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 316(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1595">111 Stat. 1595</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/d">“Unless and until laws are adopted in the State of Alaska which provide for the definition, preference, and participation specified in sections 803, 804, and 805 [sections 3113 to 3115 of this title] of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3111">16 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.), the amendments made by subsection (b) of this section [amending this section and sections 3111, 3113 to 3115, 3117, 3124, and 3125 of this title] shall be effective only for the purposes of determining whether the State’s laws provide for such definition, preference, and participation. The Secretary shall certify before <date date="1998-12-01">December 1, 1998</date> if such laws have been adopted in the State of Alaska. Subsection (b) shall be repealed on such date if such laws have not been adopted.”</quotedContent>
 [The State of Alaska did not adopt laws specified above by <date date="1998-12-01">Dec. 1, 1998</date>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id79a6c46d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Clause</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/c">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 316(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1595">111 Stat. 1595</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/c">
<inline>“No provision of this section [amending this section and sections 3111, 3113 to 3115, 3117, 3124, and 3125 of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section], amendment made by this section, or exercise of authority pursuant to this section may be construed to validate, invalidate, or in any way affect—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any assertion that an Alaska Native organization (including a federally recognized tribe, traditional Alaska Native council, or Alaska Native council organized pursuant to the Act of <date date="1934-06-18">June 18, 1934</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s461">25 U.S.C. 461</ref> et seq.) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101">25 U.S.C. 5101</ref> et seq.], as amended) has or does not have governmental authority over lands (including management of, or regulation of the taking of, fish and wildlife) or persons within the boundaries of the State of Alaska;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any assertion that Indian country, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1151">section 1151 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, exists or does not exist within the boundaries of the State of Alaska;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any assertion that the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.) is or is not Indian law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the authority of the Secretary of the Interior under section 1314(c) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3202/c">16 U.S.C. 3202(c)</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79a6c46e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Moratorium on Federal Management of Subsistence Uses in Alaska</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/e/tIII/s339">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 339]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-231">112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–295, provided that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(a) Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/e/tIII/s339/b/2">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 339(b)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-231">112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–295]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) <inline class="small-caps">Subsection</inline> (a) <inline class="small-caps">Repealed.—</inline></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) The Secretary of the Interior shall certify before <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, if a bill or resolution has been passed by the Alaska State Legislature to amend the Constitution of the State of Alaska that, if approved by the electorate, would enable the implementation of state laws of general applicability consistent with, and which provide for the definition, preference, and participation specified in sections 803, 804, and 805 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3113">16 U.S.C. 3113</ref>, 3114, 3115].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Subsection (a) shall be repealed on <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, unless prior to that date the Secretary of the Interior makes such a certification described in paragraph (1). [A certification was not made prior to <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Technical Amendments to the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act</inline>.—[Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3115">section 3115 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(d) <inline class="small-caps">Effect on Tidal and Submerged Land</inline>.—Nothing in this section invalidates, validates, or in any other way affects any claim of the State of Alaska to title to any tidal or submerged land in Alaska.”</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/a">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 316(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1592">111 Stat. 1592</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/a">“None of the funds made available to the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture by this or any other Act hereafter enacted may be used prior to <date date="1998-12-01">December 1, 1998</date> to issue or implement final regulations, rules, or policies pursuant to title VIII of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3111">16 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.] to assert jurisdiction, management, or control over the navigable waters transferred to the State of Alaska pursuant to the Submerged Lands Act of 1953 [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.] or the Alaska Statehood Act of 1959 [<ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
