<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79a935c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3117"><num value="3117">§ 3117.</num><heading> Judicial enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a935c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3117/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Exhaustion of administrative remedies; civil action; parties; preliminary injunctive relief; other relief; costs and attorney’s fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Local residents and other persons and organizations aggrieved by a failure of the State or the Federal Government to provide for the priority for subsistence uses set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3114">section 3114 of this title</ref> (or with respect to the State as set forth in a State law of general applicability if the State has fulfilled the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3115/d">section 3115(d) of this title</ref>) may, upon exhaustion of any State or Federal (as appropriate) administrative remedies which may be available, file a civil action in the United States District Court for the District of Alaska to require such actions to be taken as are necessary to provide for the priority. In a civil action filed against the State, the Secretary may be joined as a party to such action. The court may grant preliminary injunctive relief in any civil action if the granting of such relief is appropriate under the facts upon which the action is based. No order granting preliminary relief shall be issued until after an opportunity for hearing. In a civil action filed against the State, the court shall provide relief, other than preliminary relief, by directing the State to submit regulations which satisfy the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3114">section 3114 of this title</ref>; when approved by the court, such regulations shall be incorporated as part of the final judicial order, and such order shall be valid only for such period of time as normally provided by State law for the regulations at issue. Local residents and other persons and organizations who are prevailing parties in an action filed pursuant to this section shall be awarded their costs and attorney’s fees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a935c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3117/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/22/A">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(22)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3358">98 Stat. 3358</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79a935c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3117/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Section as sole Federal judicial remedy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section is the sole Federal judicial remedy created by this subchapter for local residents and other residents who, and organizations which, are aggrieved by a failure of the State to provide for the priority of subsistence uses set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3114">section 3114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79a935c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tVII/s807">Pub. L. 96–487, title VII, § 807</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2426">94 Stat. 2426</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/22/A">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(22)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3358">98 Stat. 3358</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s316/b/7">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 316(b)(7)</ref>, (d), <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1594">111 Stat. 1594</ref>, 1595.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79a935ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79a935cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79a935cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/s316/b/7">Pub. L. 105–83, § 316(b)(7)</ref>, which directed amendment of section by adding subsec. (b) reading as follows: “State agency actions may be declared invalid by the court only if they are arbitrary, capricious, or an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law. When reviewing any action within the specialized knowledge of a State agency, the court shall give the decision of the State agency the same deference it would give the same decision of a comparable Federal agency.”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/s316/d">Pub. L. 105–83, § 316(d)</ref>. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1997 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> struck out subsec. (b) which had provided that a civil action filed pursuant to this section was to be assigned for hearing at the earliest possible date, was to take precedence over other matters pending on the docket of the United States district court at that time, and was to be expedited in every way by such court and any appellate court.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79a935cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79a935ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Until laws are adopted in Alaska which provide for definition, preference, and participation specified in sections 3113 to 3115 of this title, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/83">Pub. L. 105–83</ref> was effective only for purpose of determining whether State’s laws provide for such definition, preference, and participation, and such amendment was repealed on <date date="1998-12-01">Dec. 1, 1998</date>, because such laws had not been adopted, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/s316/d">section 316(d) of Pub. L. 105–83</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3102">section 3102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79a935cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
