<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79adf0e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166"><num value="3166">§ 3166.</num><heading> Agency, Presidential, and Congressional actions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79adf0e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency action in cases other than those involving section 3165 or wilderness areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of any application for the approval of any transportation or utility system to which <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3165">section 3165 of this title</ref> does not apply or that does not occupy, use, or traverse any area within the National Wilderness Preservation System, if, in compliance with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3164">section 3164 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> each Federal agency concerned decides to approve each authorization within its jurisdiction with respect to that system, then the system shall be deemed to be approved and each such agency shall promptly issue, in accordance with applicable law, such rights-of-way, permits, licenses, leases, certificates, or other authorizations as are necessary with respect to the establishment of the system; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> one or more Federal agencies decide to disapprove any authorization within its jurisdiction with respect, to that system, then the system shall be deemed to be disapproved and the applicant for the system may appeal the disapproval to the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an applicant appeals under paragraph (1)(B), the President, within four months after receiving the appeal, shall decide whether to approve or deny the application. The President shall approve the application if he finds, after consideration of the factors set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3164/g/2">section 3164(g)(2) of this title</ref>, that such approval would be in the public interest and that (1) such system would be compatible with the purposes for which the unit was established; and (2) there is no economically feasible and prudent alternative route for the system. In making a decision, the President shall consider any environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3164/e">section 3164(e) of this title</ref>, comments of the public and Federal agencies received during the preparation of such statement, and the findings and recommendations, if any, of each Federal agency that rendered a decision with respect to the application. The President’s decision to approve or deny the application shall be published in the Federal Register, together with a statement of the reasons for his determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the President approves an application under paragraph (2), each Federal agency concerned shall promptly issue, in accordance with applicable law, such rights-of-way, permits, licenses, leases, certificates, or other authorizations as are necessary with respect to the establishment of the system</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the President denies an application under paragraph (2), the applicant shall be deemed to have exhausted his administrative remedies and may file suit in any appropriate Federal court to challenge such decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79adf0ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency action in cases involving section 3165 or wilderness areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of any application for the approval of a transportation or utility system to which <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3165">section 3165 of this title</ref> applies or that proposes to occupy, use, or traverse any area within the National Wilderness Preservation System, each Federal agency concerned shall promptly submit to the President notification whether the agency tentatively approved or disapproved each authorization within its jurisdiction that applies with respect to the system. Such notification shall be accompanied by a statement of the reasons and findings supporting the agency position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Within four months after receiving all notification referred to in paragraph (1) and after considering such notifications, any environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3164/e">section 3164(e) of this title</ref>, and the comments of the public and Federal agencies received during the preparation of such statement, the President shall decide whether or not the application for the system concerned should be approved. If the President denies an application the applicant shall be deemed to have exhausted his administrative remedies, and may file suit in any appropriate Federal court to challenge such decision. If the President approves the application, he shall submit to Congress his recommendation for approval of the transportation or utility system covered, whereupon the Congress shall consider the application as provided in subsection (c). The President shall include with his recommendation to Congress—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the application which is the subject of his recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a report setting forth in detail the relevant factual background and the reasons for his findings and recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the joint environmental impact statement; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002737">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002737"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “and”.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a statement of the conditions and stipulations which would govern the use of the system if approved by the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79adf0f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional approval</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No application for any transportation or utility system with respect to which the President makes a recommendation for approval under subsection (b) shall be approved unless the Senate and House of Representatives approve a resolution described in paragraph (4) within the first period of one hundred and twenty calendar days of continuous session of the Congress beginning on the date after the date of receipt by the Senate and House of Representatives of such recommendation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> continuity of session of the Congress is broken only by an adjournment sine die; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of the one-hundred-and-twenty-day calendar period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> This subsection is enacted by the Congress—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as an exercise of the rulemaking power of each House of the Congress respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in the House in the case of resolutions described by paragraph (6) of this subsection; and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent therewith; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79adf0fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as those relate to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of such House.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “resolution” means a joint resolution, the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the House of Representatives and Senate approve the application for      under title XI of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act submitted by the President to the Congress on       , 19 .”; the first blank space therein to be filled in with the appropriate transportation or utility system and the second blank therein to be filled with the date on which the President submits the application to the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf0ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719f/d">section 719f(d) of title 15</ref> shall apply to the consideration of the resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79adf100-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3166/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> After an application for a transportation or utility system has been approved under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal agencies shall issue appropriate authorizations in accordance with applicable law. In any case in which an application for a transportation or utility system has been approved pursuant to subsection (b), the appropriate Federal agencies shall issue appropriate authorizations in accordance with title V of the Federal Lands Policy Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1761">43 U.S.C. 1761</ref> et seq.] or other applicable law. After issuance pursuant to this subsection, the appropriate land managing agency shall administer the right-of-way in accordance with relevant management authorities of the land managing agency and title V of the Federal Lands Policy Management Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79adf101-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXI/s1106">Pub. L. 96–487, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2461">94 Stat. 2461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79adf102-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79adf103-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79adf104-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>. Title XI of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act is classified generally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Land Policy and Management Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(6), probably means the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>. Title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 1761 et seq.) of chapter 35 of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">section 1701 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
