<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79adf123-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3171"><num value="3171">§ 3171.</num><heading> Temporary access</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79adf124-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3171/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or other law the Secretary shall authorize and permit temporary access by the State or a private landowner to or across any conservation system unit, national recreation area, national conservation area, the National Petroleum Reserve—Alaska or those public lands designated as wilderness study or managed to maintain the wilderness character or potential thereof, in order to permit the State or private landowner access to its land for purposes of survey, geophysical, exploratory, or other temporary uses thereof whenever he determines such access will not result in permanent harm to the resources of such unit, area, Reserve or lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79adf125-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3171/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Stipulations and conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In providing temporary access pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary may include such stipulations and conditions he deems necessary to insure that the private use of public lands is accomplished in a manner that is not inconsistent with the purposes for which the public lands are reserved and which insures that no permanent harm will result to the resources of the unit, area, Reserve or lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79adf126-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXI/s1111">Pub. L. 96–487, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2465">94 Stat. 2465</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79adf127-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79adf128-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79adf129-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
