<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79adf12f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3173"><num value="3173">§ 3173.</num><heading> Stikine River region; Presidential study and report to Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds that there is a need to study the effect of this Act upon the ability of the Government of Canada to obtain access in the Stikine River region of southeast Alaska. Accordingly, within five years from <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, the President shall consult with the Government of Canada and shall submit a report to the Congress containing his findings and recommendations concerning the need, if any, to provide for such access. Such report shall include, among other things, an analysis of the need for access and the social, environmental and economic impacts which may result from various forms of access including, but not limited to, a road along the Stikine and Iskut Rivers, or other alternative routes, should such access be permitted.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id79adf130-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXI/s1113">Pub. L. 96–487, title XI, § 1113</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2466">94 Stat. 2466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79adf131-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79adf132-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79adf133-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2466">94 Stat. 2466</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
