<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79b061c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193"><num value="3193">§ 3193.</num><heading> Use of cabins and other sites of occupancy on conservation system units</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Improved property on National Park System lands</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> On public lands within the boundaries of any unit of the National Park System created or enlarged by this Act, cabins or other structures existing prior to <date date="1973-12-18">December 18, 1973</date>, may be occupied and used by the claimant to these structures pursuant to a renewable, nontransferable permit. Such use and occupancy shall be for terms of five years each: <i>Provided</i>, That the claimant of the structure by application:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Reasonably demonstrates by affidavit, bill of sale or other documentation, proof of possessory interest or right of occupancy in the cabin or structure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Submits a sketch or photograph of the cabin or structure and a map showing its geographic location;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Agrees to vacate the cabin and to remove all personal property from the cabin or structure upon expiration of the permit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Acknowledges in the permit that the applicant has no interest in the real property on which the cabin or structure is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> On public lands within the boundaries of any unit of the National Park System created or enlarged by this Act, cabins or other structures, the occupancy or use of which commenced between <date date="1973-12-18">December 18, 1973</date>, and <date date="1978-12-01">December 1, 1978</date>, may be used and occupied by the claimant of such structure pursuant to a nontransferable, nonrenewable permit. Such use and occupancy shall be for a maximum term of one year: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the claimant, by application:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Reasonably demonstrates by affidavit, bill of sale, or other documentation proof of possessory interest or right of occupancy in the cabin or structure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Submits a sketch or photograph of the cabin or structure and a map showing its geographic location;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Agrees to vacate the cabin or structure and to remove all personal property from it upon expiration of the permit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Acknowledges in the permit that the applicant has no legal interest in the real property on which the cabin or structure is located.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary may, on a case by case basis, subject to reasonable regulations, extend such permit term beyond one year for such reasons as the Secretary deems equitable and just.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Cabins or other structures not under permit as specified herein shall be used only for official government business: <i>Provided however</i>, That during emergencies involving the safety of human life or where designated for public use by the Secretary, these cabins may be used by the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary may issue a permit under such conditions as he may prescribe for the temporary use, occupancy, construction and maintenance of new cabins or other structures if he determines that the use is necessary to reasonably accommodate subsistence uses or is otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Improved property on other units or areas established or expanded by this Act</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following conditions shall apply regarding the construction, use and occupancy of cabins and related structures on Federal lands within conservation system units or areas not provided for in subsection (a) of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The construction of new cabins is prohibited except as may be authorized pursuant to a nontransferable, five-year special use permit issued by the Secretary. Such special use permit shall only be issued upon a determination that the proposed use, construction, and maintenance of a cabin is compatible with the purposes for which the unit or area was established and that the use of the cabin is either directly related to the administration of the unit or area or is necessary to provide for a continuation of an ongoing activity or use otherwise allowed within the unit or area where the permit applicant has no reasonable alternative site for constructing a cabin. No special use permit shall be issued to authorize the construction of a cabin for private recreational use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Traditional and customary uses of existing cabins and related structures on Federal lands within a unit or area may be allowed to continue in accordance with a nontransferable, renewable five-year special use permit issued by the Secretary. Such special use permit shall be issued only upon a determination that the traditional and customary uses are compatible with the purposes for which the unit or area was established. No special use permits shall be issued to authorize the use of an existing cabin constructed for private recreational use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> No special use permit shall be issued under paragraphs (1) or (2) of this subsection unless the permit applicant:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79b061d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of existing cabins or structures, reasonably demonstrates by affidavit, bill of sale or other documentation, proof of possessory interests or right of occupancy in the cabin or structure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79b061d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Submits a sketch or photograph of the existing or proposed cabin or structure and a map showing its geographic location;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79b061d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Agrees to vacate the cabin or structure and remove, within a reasonable time period established by the Secretary, all personal property from it upon nonrenewal or revocation of the permit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79b061da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Acknowledges in the permit application that the applicant has no interest in the real property on which the cabin or structure is located or will be constructed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The United States shall retain ownership of all new cabins and related structures on Federal lands within a unit or area specified in this subsection, and no proprietary rights or privileges shall be conveyed through the issuance of the special use permit authorized by paragraphs (1) or (2) of this subsection. Cabins or other structures not under permit shall be used only for official Government business: <i>Provided, however</i>, That during emergencies involving the safety of human life or where designated for public use by the unit or area manager, such cabins may be used by the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Permits to be renewed for life of claimant and immediate family</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whenever issuance of a nontransferable renewable five-year special use permit is authorized by subsections (a) or (b) of this section, said permit shall be renewed every five years until the death of the last immediate family member of the claimant residing in the cabin or structure, or unless the Secretary has revoked the special use permit in accordance with the criteria established in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b061de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary, after notice and hearing, may revoke a permit provided for in this section if he determines, on the basis of substantial evidence in the administrative record as a whole, that the use under the permit is causing or may cause significant detriment to the principal purposes for which the unit was established.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061df-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3193/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing cabin leases or permits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall preclude the renewal or continuation of valid leases or permits in effect on <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, for cabins, homesites, or similar structures on Federal lands. Unless the Secretary, or in the case of national forest lands, the Secretary of Agriculture, issues specific findings following notice and an opportunity for the lease-holder or permittee to respond, that renewal or continuation of such valid permit or lease constitutes a direct threat to or a significant impairment to the purposes for which a conservation system unit was established (in the case of a structure located within a conservation system unit) or the public domain or national forest (in case of a structure located outside conservation system units), he shall renew such valid leases or permits upon their expiration in accordance with the provisions of the original lease or permit, subject to such reasonable regulations as he may prescribe. Subject to the provisions of the original lease or permit, nothing in this Act or subsection shall necessarily preclude the appropriate Secretary from transferring such a lease or permit to another person at the election or death of the original permittee or leasee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79b061e0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIII/s1303">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIII, § 1303</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2476">94 Stat. 2476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79b061e1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79b061e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79b061e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (2), (b), and (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
