<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79b061fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197"><num value="3197">§ 3197.</num><heading> Revenue-producing visitor services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation of existing visitor services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as he determines are reasonable, shall permit any persons who, on or before <date date="1979-01-01">January 1, 1979</date>, were engaged in adequately providing any type of visitor service within any area established as or added to a conservation system unit to continue providing such type of service and similar types of visitor services within such area if such service or services are consistent with the purposes for which such unit is established or expanded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b061fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding provisions of law other than those contained in subsection (a), in selecting persons to provide (and in contracting for the provision of) any type of visitor service for any conservation system unit, except sport fishing and hunting guiding activities, the Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b061ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall give preference to the Native Corporations which the Secretary determines are most directly affected by the establishment or expansion of such unit by or under the provisions of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b06200-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall give preference to persons whom he determines, by rule, are local residents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b06201-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> shall, consistent with the provisions of this section, offer to Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, in cooperation with Village Corporations within the Cook Inlet Region when appropriate, the right of first refusal to provide new revenue producing visitor services within the Kenai National Moose Range or that portion of the Lake Clark National Park and Preserve within the boundaries of the Cook Inlet Region that right to remain open for a period of ninety days as agreed to in paragraph VIII of the document referred to in <ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12">section 12 of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b06202-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3197/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Visitor service” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “visitor service” means any service made available for a fee or charge to persons who visit a conservation system unit, including such services as providing food, accommodations, transportation, tours, and guides excepting the guiding of sport hunting and fishing. Nothing in this Act shall limit or affect the authority of the Federal Government or the State of Alaska to license and regulate transportation services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79b06203-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIII/s1307">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIII, § 1307</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2479">94 Stat. 2479</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/333/s10">Pub. L. 105–333, § 10</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3134">112 Stat. 3134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79b06204-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79b06205-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79b06206-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1976-01-02/s12">Section 12 of the Act of January 2, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/204">Public Law 94–204</ref>), referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/204/s12">section 12 of Pub. L. 94–204</ref>, <date date="1976-01-02">Jan. 2, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1150">89 Stat. 1150</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1611">section 1611 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79b06207-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/333">Pub. L. 105–333</ref> substituted “Native Corporations” for “Native Corporation” and “are most directly affected” for “is most directly affected”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
