<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79b2ab46-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3205"><num value="3205">§ 3205.</num><heading> General wilderness review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b2ab47-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3205/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Suitability of lands for preservation; report to President</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within five years from <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>, the Secretary shall, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132/d">section 1132(d) of this title</ref> relating to public notice, public hearings, and review by State and other agencies, review, as to their suitability or nonsuitability for preservation as wilderness, all lands within units of the National Park System and units of the National Wildlife Refuge System in Alaska not designated as wilderness by this Act and report his findings to the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b2ab48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3205/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential recommendations to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct his review, and the President shall advise the United States Senate and House of Representatives of his recommendations, in accordance with the provisions of sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002741">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002741"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 1132(c) and (d) of this title. The President shall advise the Congress of his recommendations with respect to such areas within seven years from <date date="1980-12-02">December 2, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b2ab49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3205/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration of units unaffected pending Congressional action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the administration of any unit of the National Park System or unit of National Wildlife Refuge System in accordance with this Act or other applicable provisions of law unless and until Congress provides otherwise by taking action on any Presidential recommendation made pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79b2ab4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tXIII/s1317">Pub. L. 96–487, title XIII, § 1317</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2485">94 Stat. 2485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79b2ab4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79b2ab4c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79b2ab4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
