<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id772a0508-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s343c–2"><num value="343c–2">§ 343c–2.</num><heading> Addition of lands; Jackson Laboratory</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may, in his discretion, accept title to certain land in the town of Bar Harbor, Hancock County, Maine, held by the Jackson Laboratory, a nonprofit corporation organized and existing under the laws of the State of Maine, said land being more particularly described as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning at a stone bound set in the ground in the southerly side of State Highway Numbered 3 leading from Bar Harbor to Seal Harbor, said stone bound also marking the northeasterly corner of land of the United States of America and the northwesterly corner of land of the Jackson Laboratory;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 72 degrees 58 minutes east and following the southerly side of State Highway Numbered 3, 80 feet to a stone bound set in the ground;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence south 32 degrees 13 minutes east 762.5 feet to an iron pin set in the ledge;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 88 degrees 16 minutes east 270.54 feet to a stone bound set in the ground in the southerly side of the old Morrell Park Racetrack;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 61 degrees 56 minutes east 673.2 feet to an iron pipe driven in the ground, said iron pipe also being in a northwesterly line of land of the United States of America;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence south 24 degrees 30 minutes west and always following a northwesterly line of land of the United States of America, 149 feet to an iron pipe driven in the ground;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence south 64 degrees 05 minutes west and always following a northwesterly line of land of the United States of America, 577 feet to a stone bound set in the ground;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence south 78 degrees 50 minutes west and always following a northerly line of land of the United States of America, 115 feet to an iron pin in a large boulder;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 84 degrees 00 minutes west and always following a northerly line of land of the United States of America, 357 feet to an iron pin in the ledge;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 22 degrees 40 minutes west and always following a northeasterly line of land of the United States of America, 460 feet to an iron pin in the ledge;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">thence north 14 degrees 05 minutes west and always following an easterly line of land of the United States of America, 281.7 feet to the point of beginning, and containing 4.828 acres.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Said land, upon acceptance of title thereto, shall become a part of the Acadia National Park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id772a0509-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/262/s1">Pub. L. 90–262, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-03-04">Mar. 4, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/40">82 Stat. 40</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
