<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c10397-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3636"><num value="3636">§ 3636.</num><heading> Rulemaking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c10398-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3636/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of regulations by Secretary of Commerce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating and the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Council, shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the United States international obligations under the Treaty and this chapter, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3635">section 3635 of this title</ref>, as well as conforming amendatory regulations applicable to the United States Exclusive Economic Zone. Any such regulation may be made applicable, as necessary, to all persons and all vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, wherever located. Such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to carry out obligations of the United States under the Treaty involve a foreign affairs function, and as such shall not be subject to sections 553 through 557 of title 5, or the National Environmental Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c10399-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3636/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additions to fishery regimes and Fraser River Panel regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with the Regional Fishery Management Councils, States, and treaty Indian tribes, may promulgate regulations applicable to nationals or vessels of the United States, or both, which are in addition to, and not in conflict with, fishery regimes and Fraser River Panel regulations adopted under the Treaty. Such regulations shall not discriminate between residents of different States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c1039a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3636/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Regulations promulgated by the Secretary under this chapter shall be subject to judicial review by the district courts of the United States to the extent authorized by, and in accordance with, chapter 7 of title 5; except that section 705 of such title is not applicable, and the appropriate court shall only set aside any such regulation on a ground specified in section 706(2)(A), (B), (C), or (D) of such title. A civil action filed pursuant to this section shall be assigned for hearing at the earliest possible date, shall take precedence over other matters pending on the docket of the United States district court at that time, and shall be expedited in every way by such court and any appellate court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79c1039b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/5/s7">Pub. L. 99–5, § 7</ref>, <date date="1985-03-15">Mar. 15, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/12">99 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/251/tIII/s306/b">Pub. L. 102–251, title III, § 306(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-03-09">Mar. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/66">106 Stat. 66</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79c1039c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id79c1039d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Subsection (a)</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic"><ref href="/us/pl/102/251/tIII">Pub. L. 102–251, title III</ref>, §§ 306(b), 308, <date date="1992-03-09">Mar. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/66">106 Stat. 66</ref>, provided that, effective on the date on which the Agreement between the United States and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Maritime Boundary, signed <date date="1990-06-01">June 1, 1990</date>, enters into force for the United States, with authority to prescribe implementing regulations effective <date date="1992-03-09">Mar. 9, 1992</date>, but with no such regulation to be effective until the date on which the Agreement enters into force for the United States, subsection (a) is amended by inserting “and special areas” after “Exclusive Economic Zone”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79c1039e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79c1039f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act, referred to in subsec. (a), probably means the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79c103a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79c103a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/251">Pub. L. 102–251</ref> effective on date on which Agreement between United States and Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Maritime Boundary, signed <date date="1990-06-01">June 1, 1990</date>, enters into force for United States, with authority to prescribe implementing regulations effective <date date="1992-03-09">Mar. 9, 1992</date>, but with no such regulation to be effective until date on which Agreement enters into force for United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/251/s308">section 308 of Pub. L. 102–251</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s773">section 773 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79c103a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
