<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76f0ccb8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s38"><num value="38">§ 38.</num><heading> Exchange for State or private lands authorized</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized in his discretion to accept, on behalf of the United States, title to any lands held in private or State ownership within the townships described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s37">section 37 of this title</ref>, and in exchange therefor may patent not to exceed an equal value of national forest land in the State of Montana, surveyed and nonmineral in character, or the Secretary of Agriculture may authorize the grantor to cut and remove not to exceed an equal value of timber within the national forests of said State, the values in each case to be determined by the Secretary of Agriculture: <i>Provided</i>, That before any such exchange is effected, notice of the contemplated exchange reciting the lands involved shall be published once each week for four successive weeks in some newspaper of general circulation in the county or counties in which may be situated the lands to be accepted and in some like newspaper published in any county in which may be situated any lands or timber to be given in such exchange. Timber given in exchange shall be cut and removed from national forests under the laws and regulations relating to the national forests and under the direction and supervision and in accordance with the requirements of the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76f33cb9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-05-26/ch399/s2">May 26, 1926, ch. 399, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/655">44 Stat. 655</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/509/s1/f">Pub. L. 86–509, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/205">74 Stat. 205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76f33cba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id76f33cbb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id76f33cbc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Secretary of the Interior under this section, with respect to exchanges of lands held in private or State ownership for national forest lands or timber in Montana, transferred to Secretary of Agriculture, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/509">Pub. L. 86–509</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/205">74 Stat. 205</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
