<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c82eb0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812"><num value="3812">§ 3812.</num><heading> Exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82eb1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons eligible for program benefits in connection with production or reduced production of crops on certain lands; eligibility based upon compliance with conservation plan by <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>; minimization of documentation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c82eb2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> During the period beginning on <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, and ending on the later of <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, or the date that is 2 years after the date land on which a crop of an agricultural commodity is produced was mapped by the Soil Conservation Service for purposes of classifying such land under the land capability classification system in effect on <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, except as provided in paragraph (2), no person shall become ineligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for program loans, payments, and benefits as the result of the production of a crop of an agricultural commodity on any land that was—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82eb3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> cultivated to produce any of the 1981 through 1985 crops of an agricultural commodity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82eb4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> set aside, diverted or otherwise not cultivated under a program administered by the Secretary for any such crops to reduce production of an agricultural commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c82eb5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility based on compliance with conservation plan.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82eb6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If, as of <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, or 2 years after the Soil Conservation Service has completed a soil survey for the farm, whichever is later, a person is actively applying a conservation plan, such person shall have until <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, to comply with the plan without being subject to program ineligibility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82eb7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimization of documentation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary, Soil Conservation Service, and local soil conservation districts shall minimize the quantity of documentation a person must submit to comply with this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82eb8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crop insurance.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82eb9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operations new to compliance</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a">section 3811(a) of this title</ref>, in the case of a person that is subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for the first time solely due to the amendment made by section 2611(a) of the Agricultural Act of 2014, any person who produces an agricultural commodity on the land that is the basis of the payments described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a/1/E">section 3811(a)(1)(E) of this title</ref> shall have 5 reinsurance years after the date on which such payments become subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> to develop and comply with an approved conservation plan so as to maintain eligibility for such payments.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82eba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Existing operations with prior violations</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a">section 3811(a) of this title</ref>, in the case of a person that the Secretary determines would have been in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a">section 3811(a) of this title</ref> if the person had continued participation in the programs requiring compliance at any time after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, and is currently in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a">section 3811(a) of this title</ref>, the person shall have 2 reinsurance years after the date on which the payments described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a/1/E">section 3811(a)(1)(E) of this title</ref> become subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> to develop and comply with an approved conservation plan, as determined by the Secretary, so as to maintain eligibility for such payments.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ebb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicable reinsurance year</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Ineligibility for the payment described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811/a/1/E">section 3811(a)(1)(E) of this title</ref> for a violation under this subparagraph during a crop year shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79c82ebc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> only apply to reinsurance years subsequent to the date of a final determination of a violation, including all administrative appeals; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79c82ebd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/2/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> not apply to the existing reinsurance year or any reinsurance year prior to the date of the final determination.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c82ebe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any person who owns or operates highly erodible land that was the subject of a contract entered into under subpart B of part I of subchapter IV shall only be required to apply a conservation plan established under this subchapter. The person shall not be required to meet a higher conservation standard than the standard applied to other highly erodible cropland located within the same area. If the person’s conservation plan requires structures to be constructed, the person shall have until 2 years after the expiration of such contract to comply with the conservation plan, or a longer period of time if the Secretary determines compliance is otherwise technically or economically not feasible, or such longer period is otherwise appropriate, before such person will be subject to program ineligibility with respect to such land under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c82ebf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> On the expiration of a contract entered into under subpart B of part I of subchapter IV, the provisions of this subchapter shall apply to the acreage that was the subject of such contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ec0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons eligible for program benefits in connection with production of certain planted crops or production of crops on highly erodible land</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall become ineligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for program loans, payments, and benefits as the result of the production of a crop of an agricultural commodity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ec1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> planted before <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ec2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> planted during any crop year beginning before <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ec3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for loans and payments under section 3811</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall become ineligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for program loans, payments, and benefits as the result of the production of a crop of an agricultural commodity or the designation of land to be set aside, diverted, devoted to conservation uses, or otherwise not cultivated under a program administered by the Secretary to reduce production of an agricultural commodity (hereafter in this subsection referred to as “set aside”)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ec4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> on highly erodible land in an area—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ec5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> within a conservation district, under a conservation system that has been approved by a conservation district after the district has determined that the conservation system is in conformity with technical standards set forth in the Soil Conservation Service technical guide for such district; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ec6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not within a conservation district, under a conservation system determined by the Secretary to be adequate for the protection of highly erodible land that has been set aside or for the production of such agricultural commodity on any highly erodible land subject to this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ec7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> on highly erodible land that is planted or set aside in reliance on a determination by the Soil Conservation Service that such land was not highly erodible land, except that this paragraph shall not apply to any agricultural commodity that was planted or set aside on any land after the Soil Conservation Service determines that such land is highly erodible land; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ec8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> on highly erodible land planted to alfalfa during each of the 1981 through 1985 crop years as part of a rotation practice approved by the Secretary, if the person has submitted a conservation plan, in which case, such person shall have until <date date="1988-06-01">June 1, 1988</date>, to comply with the plan without being subject to program ineligibility under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ec9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Program ineligibility inapplicable to pre-<date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, section 3811 loans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">Section 3811 of this title</ref> shall not apply to a loan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> made before <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82eca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on ineligibility for tenants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a tenant is determined to be ineligible for payments and other benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may limit such ineligibility only to the farm which is the basis for such ineligibility determination if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ecb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the tenant has established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ecc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the tenant has made a good faith effort to meet the requirements of this section, including enlisting the assistance of the Secretary to obtain a reasonable conservation plan for such farm; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ecd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the landlord on the farm refuses to comply with such plan on such farm; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ece-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary determines that such lack of compliance is not a part of a scheme or device to avoid such compliance.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall provide an annual report to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate concerning the ineligibility determinations limited during the previous 12-month period under this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ecf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Graduated penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ed0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Ineligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No person shall become ineligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for program loans, payments, and benefits as a result of the failure of the person to actively apply a conservation plan, if the Secretary determines that the person has acted in good faith and without an intent to violate this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ed1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible reviewers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A determination of the Secretary, or a designee of the Secretary, under paragraph (1) shall be reviewed by the applicable—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ed2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> State Executive Director, with the technical concurrence of the State Conservationist; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c82ed3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> district director, with the technical concurrence of the area conservationist.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ed4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Period for implementation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) shall be allowed a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Secretary, but not to exceed 1 year, during which to implement the measures and practices necessary to be considered to be actively applying the conservation plan of the person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ed5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ed6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">This paragraph applies if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79c82ed7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a person has failed to comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> with respect to highly erodible cropland, and has acted in good faith and without an intent to violate <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79c82ed8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the violation—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79c82ed9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is technical and minor in nature; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79c82eda-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has a minimal effect on the erosion control purposes of the conservation plan applicable to the land on which the violation has occurred.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82edb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If this paragraph applies under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall, in lieu of applying the ineligibility provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref>, reduce program benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> that the producer would otherwise be eligible to receive in a crop year by an amount commensurate with the seriousness of the violation, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82edc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent crop years</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person whose benefits are reduced for any crop year under this subsection shall continue to be eligible for all of the benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> for any subsequent crop year if, prior to the beginning of the subsequent crop year, the Secretary determines that the person is actively applying a conservation plan according to the schedule specified in the plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82edd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation or revision of conservation plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in providing assistance to an individual in the preparation or revision of a conservation plan under this section, shall provide such individual with information—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82ede-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> concerning cost effective and applicable erosion control measures that may be available to such individual to meet the requirements of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c82edf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> concerning crop flexibility, base adjustment, and conservation assistance options that may be available to such individual to meet the requirements of this section, including the provisions of titles X, XII, and XIII of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (or the amendments made by such titles).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c82ee0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3812/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Noncommercial production of agricultural commodities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">Section 3811 of this title</ref> shall not apply to the noncommercial production of agricultural commodities on a farm if such production is limited to two acres or less and if the Secretary determines that such production is not intended to circumvent the conservation requirements otherwise applicable to lands under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79c82ee1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXII/s1212">Pub. L. 99–198, title XII, § 1212</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1506">99 Stat. 1506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/28">Pub. L. 100–28</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1987-04-24">Apr. 24, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/291">101 Stat. 291</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIV/s1412">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIV, § 1412</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3569">104 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tII/s204/2">Pub. L. 102–237, title II, § 204(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1854">105 Stat. 1854</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tIII">Pub. L. 104–127, title III</ref>, §§ 301(d), 312–314, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/981-983">110 Stat. 981–983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tII/s2002">Pub. L. 110–234, title II, § 2002</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1027">122 Stat. 1027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title II, § 2002, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1755; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tII/s2611/a/2">Pub. L. 113–79, title II, § 2611(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/762">128 Stat. 762</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79c82ee2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79c82ee3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79c82ee4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2611(a) of the Agricultural Act of 2014, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(C)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s2611/a">section 2611(a) of Pub. L. 113–79</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/762">128 Stat. 762</ref>, which amended this section and sections 3811 and 3812a of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(B), was in the original “this title”, meaning title XII of <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref>, which enacted this chapter and former <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2005a">section 2005a of this title</ref> and amended sections 590g, 2004, 2005, 2006, and 2009 of this title, sections 4207 and 4209 of Title 7, Agriculture, and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1981">section 1981 of Title 7</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (g)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3359">104 Stat. 3359</ref>. Title X of the Act enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1446h">section 1446h of Title 7</ref> and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1425a">section 1425a of Title 7</ref>. Title XII of the Act, known as the Forest Stewardship Act of 1990, is classified principally to amended chapter 41 (§ 2101 et seq.) of this title. Title XIII of the Act enacted sections 138 to 138i and 499b–1 of Title 7, amended sections 499c, 608c, and 608e–1 of Title 7, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 499a and 1622 of Title 7. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1990 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79c82ee5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79c82ee6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> inserted par. (2) heading, designated first sentence as subpar. (A) and inserted heading, designated second sentence as subpar. (B) and inserted heading, and added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s2002">Pub. L. 110–246, § 2002</ref>, added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which related to graduated sanctions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(1)</ref>, in first sentence, struck out “that documents the decisions of the person with respect to location, land use, tillage systems, and conservation treatment measures and schedule and that is based on the local Soil Conservation Service technical guide and approved by the local soil conservation district, in consultation with the local committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of this title</ref> and the Secretary, or by the Secretary” after “applying a conservation plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s312">Pub. L. 104–127, § 312</ref>, substituted “shall only be required to apply a conservation plan established under this subchapter. The person shall not be required to meet a higher conservation standard than the standard applied to other highly erodible cropland located within the same area. If the person’s conservation plan requires structures to be constructed, the person shall” for “shall, if the conservation plan established under this subchapter for such land requires structures to be constructed,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/2">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “, in which case,” for “based on the local Soil Conservation Service technical guide and approved by the local soil conservation district, in consultation with the local committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of this title</ref> and the Secretary,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/3">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “conservation plan” for “conservation compliance plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s313/a">Pub. L. 104–127, § 313(a)</ref>, substituted “No person” for “Except to the extent provided in paragraph (2), no person” and substituted “the person has acted in good faith and without an intent to violate this subchapter. A person who meets the requirements of this paragraph shall be allowed a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Secretary, but not to exceed 1 year, during which to implement the measures and practices necessary to be considered to be actively applying the person’s conservation plan.” for “such person has—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) not violated the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3811">section 3811 of this title</ref> within the previous 5 years on a farm; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) acted in good faith and without the intent to violate the provisions of this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/4/A">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(4)(A)</ref>, struck out “that documents the decisions of such person with respect to location, land use, tillage systems, and conservation treatment measures and schedules prepared under subsection (a) of this section” after “apply a conservation plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s313/b">Pub. L. 104–127, § 313(b)</ref>, substituted “with respect to highly erodible cropland that was not in production prior to <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, and has acted in good faith and without an intent to violate the provisions” for “meets the requirements of paragraph (1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/4/B">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “prepared under subsection (a) of this section” after “a conservation plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s313/c">Pub. L. 104–127, § 313(c)</ref>, struck out concluding sentence which read as follows: “A determination or the granting of a variance by the Secretary under this paragraph shall not be counted as a violation for the purposes of paragraph (1)(A).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s301/d/4/C">Pub. L. 104–127, § 301(d)(4)(C)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “that documents the decisions of such person with respect to location, land use, tillage systems, and conservation treatment measures and schedules prepared under subsection (a) of this section” after “apply a conservation plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s314/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 314(1)</ref>, substituted “problem, including weather, pest, and disease problems” for “problem”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s314/2">Pub. L. 104–127, § 314(2)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (f)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s204/2/A">Pub. L. 102–237, § 204(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “such violation” for “such violations” after “which”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/235/s204/2/B">Pub. L. 102–235, § 204(2)(B)</ref>, struck out comma after “XIII”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/a">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(a)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “or” in par. (1) and substituted a period for a semicolon in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/4">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(4)</ref>, redesignated pars. (3) to (5) as pars. (1) to (3), respectively, of subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/3">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(3)</ref>, (4), added subsec. (c) introductory provisions, and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/4">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(4)</ref>, (5), redesignated par. (3) of subsec. (b) as par. (1) of subsec. (c) and in subpar. (B) inserted “for the protection of highly erodible land that has been set aside or” after “adequate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/4">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(4)</ref>, (6), redesignated par. (4) of subsec. (b) as par. (2) of subsec. (c) and inserted “or set aside” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/4">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(4)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) of subsec. (b) as par. (3) of subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/b/3">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(b)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1412/c">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1412(c)</ref>–(f), added subsecs. (e) to (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/28/s3">Pub. L. 100–28, § 3</ref>, inserted “that documents the decisions of the person with respect to location, land use, tillage systems, and conservation treatment measures and schedule and that is” after “conservation plan”, and inserted at end “In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary, Soil Conservation Service, and local soil conservation districts shall minimize the quantity of documentation a person must submit to comply with this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/28/s2/b">Pub. L. 100–28, § 2(b)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79c82ee7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79c82ee8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
