<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79e4b887-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954"><num value="3954">§ 3954.</num><heading> National coastal wetlands conservation grants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b888-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Matching grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall, with the funds made available in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3955">section 3955 of this title</ref>, make matching grants to any coastal State to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects from funds made available for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b889-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the cost-sharing requirements of this section, the Director may grant or otherwise provide any matching moneys to any coastal State which submits a proposal substantial in character and design to carry out a coastal wetlands conservation project. In awarding such matching grants, the Director shall give priority to coastal wetlands conservation projects that are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e4b88a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consistent with the National Wetlands Priority Conservation Plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3921">section 3921 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e4b88b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in coastal States that have established dedicated funding for programs to acquire coastal wetlands, natural areas and open spaces. In addition, priority consideration shall be given to coastal wetlands conservation projects in maritime forests on coastal barrier islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b88c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may only grant or otherwise provide matching moneys to a coastal State for purposes of carrying out a coastal wetlands conservation project if the grant or provision is subject to terms and conditions that will ensure that any real property interest acquired in whole or in part, or enhanced, managed, or restored with such moneys will be administered for the long-term conservation of such lands and waters and the fish and wildlife dependent thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b88d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b88e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Grants to coastal States of matching moneys by the Director for any fiscal year to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects shall be used for the payment of not to exceed 50 percent of the total costs of such projects: except that such matching moneys may be used for payment of not to exceed 75 percent of the costs of such projects if a coastal State has established and is using one of the following for the purpose of acquiring coastal wetlands, other natural areas or open spaces:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79e4b88f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a trust fund from which the principal is not spent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79e4b890-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a fund derived from a dedicated recurring source of monies including, but not limited to, real estate transfer fees or taxes, cigarette taxes, tax check-offs, or motor vehicle license plate fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b891-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Form of State share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The matching moneys required of a coastal State to carry out a coastal wetlands conservation project shall be derived from a non-Federal source.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b892-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to cash outlays and payments, in-kind contributions of property or personnel services by non-Federal interests for activities under this section may be used for the non-Federal share of the cost of those activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b893-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Partial payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79e4b894-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director may from time to time make matching payments to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects as such projects progress, but such payments, including previous payments, if any, shall not be more than the Federal pro rata share of any such project in conformity with subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79e4b895-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director may enter into agreements to make matching payments on an initial portion of a coastal wetlands conservation project and to agree to make payments on the remaining Federal share of the costs of such project from subsequent moneys if and when they become available. The liability of the United States under such an agreement is contingent upon the continued availability of funds for the purpose of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e4b896-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s3954/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Wetlands assessment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall, with the funds made available in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3955">section 3955 of this title</ref>, direct the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service’s National Wetland Inventory to update and digitize wetlands maps in the State of Texas and to conduct an assessment of the status, condition, and trends of wetlands in that State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79e4b897-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/646/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 101–646, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4785">104 Stat. 4785</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/212/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 102–212, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1660">105 Stat. 1660</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79e4b898-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79e4b899-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79e4b89a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/212">Pub. L. 102–212</ref> substituted “has established and is using one of the following for the purpose of acquiring coastal wetlands, other natural areas or open spaces:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) a trust fund from which the principal is not spent; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) a fund derived from a dedicated recurring source of monies including, but not limited to, real estate transfer fees or taxes, cigarette taxes, tax check-offs, or motor vehicle license plate fees”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for “has established a trust fund, from which the principal is not spent, for the purpose of acquiring coastal wetlands, other natural area or open spaces”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79e4b89b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79e4b89c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/212/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 102–212, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1661">105 Stat. 1661</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/212/tIII/s302/b">“This section [amending this section] shall apply to grants awarded in fiscal year 1992 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
