<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77385cfc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d"><num value="398d">§ 398d.</num><heading> Acquisition of lands, waters, and interests therein</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77385cfd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization; payment requirements; interest rate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the boundaries of Virgin Islands National Park as established and adjusted pursuant to sections 398 and 398a of this title, and as revised by sections 398c to 398f of this title, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire lands, waters, and interests therein by purchase, exchange or donation or with donated funds. In acquiring such lands, up to 6.6 acres, the Secretary may, when agreed upon by the landowner involved, defer payment or schedule payments over a period of ten years and pay interest on the unpaid balance at a rate not exceeding the current prevailing commercial rate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77385cfe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment and training of residents to develop, etc., area</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to the maximum extent feasible to employ and train residents of the Virgin Islands to develop, maintain, and administer the Virgin Islands National Park.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77385cff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment requirements for acquisition of Hassel Island from United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to continued protection and use of Hassel Island for park and recreation purposes, and such other conditions as the Secretary may deem appropriate, the Territory of the Virgin Islands may, within, but not after, five years after <date date="1978-08-18">August 18, 1978</date>, by duly enacted legislation acquire all interests of the United States in Hassel Island by reimbursing the United States in an amount equal to the amount actually expended by the United States for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands and for the costs of construction of permanent improvements, if any.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77385d00-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights of owners of improved property on Hassel Island to use and occupancy of property for noncommercial residential purposes; term; payment requirements; suspension of authority to condemn Royal Mail property; “improved property” defined; termination of rights of owners to use and occupancy</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77385d01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except for property deemed necessary by the Secretary of the Interior for visitor facilities or administration of the park, any owner or owners of improved property on Hassel Island on the date of its acquisition, may retain for themselves a right of use and occupancy of the property for noncommercial residential purposes for twenty-five years or, in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the owner’s spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. The Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the fair market value on such date of the right retained by the owner. The authority of the Secretary to acquire the property commonly known as the Royal Mail (hotel) by condemnation shall be suspended for ten years from <date date="1978-08-18">August 18, 1978</date>, if such owner or owners agree, in writing, within ninety days after <date date="1978-08-18">August 18, 1978</date>, to grant to the United States the right to purchase such property at a purchase price, mutually agreed upon by the Secretary and the landowner, which does not exceed the fixed value of said property on <date date="1978-07-01">July 1, 1978</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77385d02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> As used in subsection (d)(1), “improved property” means a single-family dwelling, the construction of which began before <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>, together with such lands as are in the same ownership and appurtenant buildings located thereon.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77385d03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s398d/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may terminate a right of use and occupancy retained pursuant to subsection (d)(1) upon his determination that such use and occupancy is being, or may be, exercised in a manner inconsistent with the purposes for which they were included within the park and upon tender to the holder of such right of the amount equal to the value of that portion of the right which remains unexpired on the date of termination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77385d04-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/750/s2">Pub. L. 87–750, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/747">76 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/348/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 95–348, § 7(b)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1978-08-18">Aug. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/494">92 Stat. 494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77385d05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77385d06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77385d07-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/348">Pub. L. 95–348</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted provisions respecting acquisitions of up to 6.6 acres, and added subsecs. (b) to (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77385d08-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77385d09-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Caneel Bay Lease Authorization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/261/s1">Pub. L. 111–261, § 1</ref>, <date date="2010-10-08">Oct. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2777">124 Stat. 2777</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/261/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Park</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Park’ means the Virgin Islands National Park.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Resort</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘resort’ means the Caneel Bay resort on the island of St. John in the Park.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retained use estate</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘retained use estate’ means the retained use estate for the Caneel Bay property on the island of St. John entered into between the Jackson Hole Preserve and the United States on <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date> (as amended, assigned, and assumed).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lease Authorization.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines that the long-term benefit to the Park would be greater by entering into a lease with the owner of the retained use estate than by authorizing a concession contract upon the termination of the retained use estate, the Secretary may enter into a lease with the owner of the retained use estate for the operation and management of the resort.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> acquire associated property from the owner of the retained use estate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> on the acquisition of property under subparagraph (A), administer the property as part of the Park.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as otherwise provided by this section, a lease shall be in accordance with subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/pl/91/383/s3">section 3 of Public Law 91–383</ref> ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1a–2/k">16 U.S.C. 1a–2(k)</ref>) [see <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s102102">54 U.S.C. 102102</ref>], notwithstanding paragraph (2) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A lease authorized under this section shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> be for the minimum number of years practicable, taking into consideration the need for the lessee to secure financing for necessary capital improvements to the resort, but in no event shall the term of the lease exceed 40 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> prohibit any transfer, assignment, or sale of the lease or otherwise convey or pledge any interest in the lease without prior written notification to, and approval by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> ensure that the general character of the resort property remains unchanged, including a prohibition against—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> any increase in the overall size of the resort; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> any increase in the number of guest accommodations available at the resort;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> prohibit the sale of partial ownership shares or timeshares in the resort;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> include provisions to ensure the protection of the natural, cultural, and historic features of the resort and associated property, consistent with the laws and policies applicable to property managed by the National Park Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> include any other provisions determined by the Secretary to be necessary to protect the Park and the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rental amounts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining the fair market value rental of the lease required under <ref href="/us/pl/91/383/s3/k/4">section 3(k)(4) of Public Law 91–383</ref> ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1a–2/k/4">16 U.S.C. 1a–2(k)(4)</ref>) [see <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s102102">54 U.S.C. 102102</ref>], the Secretary shall take into consideration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the value of any associated property conveyed to the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the value, if any, of the relinquished term of the retained use estate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of proceeds</inline>.—</heading><content>Rental amounts paid to the United States under a lease shall be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation, for visitor services and resource protection within the Park.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional notification</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall submit a proposed lease under this section to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives at least 60 days before the award of the lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Renewal</inline>.—</heading><content>A lease entered into under this section may not be extended or renewed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon the termination of a lease entered into under this section, if the Secretary determines the continuation of commercial services at the resort to be appropriate, the services shall be provided in accordance with the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998 ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s5951">16 U.S.C. 5951</ref> et seq.) [enacting former sections 5951 to 5966 of this title, which were repealed and restated in sections 101911 et seq. and 101524 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, amending former sections 1a–7 and 3 of this title, repealing section 17b–1 and subchapter IV of chapter 1 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 100101, 101911, and 101912 of Title 54].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retained Use Estate.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>As a condition of the lease, the owner of the retained use estate shall terminate, extinguish, and relinquish to the Secretary all rights under the retained use estate and shall transfer, without consideration, ownership of improvements on the retained use estate to the National Park Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appraisal.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall require an appraisal by an independent, qualified appraiser who is agreed to by the Secretary and the owner of the retained use estate to determine the value, if any, of the relinquished term of the retained use estate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An appraisal under paragraph (1) shall be conducted in accordance with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
