<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id773d3ee3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s404b"><num value="404b">§ 404b.</num><heading> Administration, protection, and development; Federal Power Act inapplicable; minimum area</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The administration, protection, and development of the aforesaid park shall be exercised under the direction of the Secretary of the Interior by the National Park Service, subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date>, entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002082">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002082"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> as amended: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.] shall not apply to this park: <i>And provided further</i>, That the minimum area to be administered and protected by the National Park Service shall be, for the said Mammoth Cave National Park, twenty thousand acres: <i>Provided further</i>, That no general development of said area shall be undertaken until a major portion of the remainder in such area, including all the caves thereof, shall have been accepted by said Secretary, and he shall have established a schedule of fees for admission to such caves.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id773d3ee4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-05-25/ch382/s3">May 25, 1926, ch. 382, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/636">44 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-05-14/ch282/s1">May 14, 1934, ch. 282, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/775">48 Stat. 775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id773d3ee5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id773d3ee6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id773d3ee7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date>, entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,”, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Act, referred to in text, was in the original the “Act approved <date date="1920-06-10">June 10, 1920</date>, known as the Federal Water Power Act,” and was redesignated as the Federal Power Act by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref>. The Federal Power Act is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">act June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>, and is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id773d3ee8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-05-14">May 14, 1934</date>, inserted “and he shall have established a schedule of fees for admission to such caves,” and changed phrase “including all the caves thereof” to its present position instead of following “twenty thousand acres”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id773d3ee9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id773d3eea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
