<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7765ae51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa–22"><num value="410aaa–22">§ 410aaa–22.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the Joshua Tree National Park, (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “park”), as generally depicted on a map entitled “Joshua Tree National Park Boundary—Proposed”, dated May 1991, and four maps entitled “Joshua Tree National Park Boundary and Wilderness”, numbered in the title one through four, and dated October 1991 or prior, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the Superintendent of the park and the Director of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior. The Joshua Tree National Monument is hereby abolished as such, the lands and interests therein are hereby incorporated within and made part of the new Joshua Tree National Park, and any funds available for purposes of the monument shall be available for purposes of the park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7765ae52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/433/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 103–433, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4488">108 Stat. 4488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7765ae53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7765ae54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7765ae55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Boundary Adjustment and Administration, Joshua Tree National Park</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/9/tI/s1433/a">Pub. L. 116–9, title I, § 1433(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/700">133 Stat. 700</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/9/tI/s1433/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Boundary Adjustment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The boundary of the Joshua Tree National Park is adjusted to include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the approximately 2,879 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management that are depicted as ‘BLM Proposed Boundary Addition’ on the map entitled ‘Joshua Tree National Park Proposed Boundary Additions’, numbered 156/149,375, and dated <date date="2018-11-01">November 1, 2018</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the approximately 1,639 acres of land that are depicted as ‘MDLT Proposed Boundary Addition’ on the map entitled ‘Joshua Tree National Park Proposed Boundary Additions’, numbered 156/149,375, and dated <date date="2018-11-01">November 1, 2018</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Maps</inline>.—</heading><content>The map described in subsection (a) and the map depicting the 25 acres described in subsection (c)(2) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall administer any land added to the Joshua Tree National Park under subsection (a) and the additional land described in paragraph (2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> as part of Joshua Tree National Park; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Description of additional land</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The additional land referred to in paragraph (1) is the 25 acres of land—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> depicted on the map entitled ‘Joshua Tree National Park Boundary Adjustment Map’, numbered 156/80,049, and dated <date date="2003-04-01">April 1, 2003</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> added to Joshua Tree National Park by the notice of the Department of the Interior of <date date="2003-08-28">August 28, 2003</date> (68 Fed. Reg. 51799); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> more particularly described as lots 26, 27, 28, 33, and 34 in sec. 34, T. 1 N., R. 8 E., San Bernardino Meridian.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Southern California Edison Company Energy Transport Facilities and Rights-of-way.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section affects any valid right-of-way for the customary operation, maintenance, upgrade, repair, relocation within an existing right-of-way, replacement, or other authorized energy transport facility activities in a right-of-way issued, granted, or permitted to the Southern California Edison Company or the successors or assigns of the Southern California Edison Company that is located on land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), including, at a minimum, the use of mechanized vehicles, helicopters, or other aerial devices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Upgrades and replacements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section prohibits the upgrading or replacement of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Southern California Edison Company energy transport facilities, including the energy transport facilities referred to as the Jellystone, Burnt Mountain, Whitehorn, Allegra, and Utah distribution circuits rights-of-way; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an energy transport facility in rights-of-way issued, granted, or permitted by the Secretary adjacent to Southern California Edison Joshua Tree Utility Facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication of plans</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>] or the issuance of a new energy transport facility right-of-way within the Joshua Tree National Park, whichever is earlier, the Secretary, in consultation with the Southern California Edison Company, shall publish plans for regular and emergency access by the Southern California Edison Company to the rights-of-way of the Southern California Edison Company within Joshua Tree National Park.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “Secretary” as used in section § 1433(a)–(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/116/9">Pub. L. 116–9</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/9/s1401">section 1401 of Pub. L. 116–9</ref>, set out as a Definitions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa–7">section 410aaa–7 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
