<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77681fba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa–52"><num value="410aaa–52">§ 410aaa–52.</num><heading> Preparation of management plan</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within three years after <date date="1994-10-31">October 31, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives a detailed and comprehensive management plan for the preserve. Such plan shall place emphasis on historical and cultural sites and ecological and wilderness values within the boundaries of the preserve. Such plan shall evaluate the feasibility of using the Kelso Depot and existing railroad corridor to provide public access to and a facility for special interpretive, educational, and scientific programs within the preserve. Such plan shall specifically address the needs of individuals with disabilities in the design of services, programs, accommodations and facilities consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">section 794 of title 29</ref>, Public Law 101-336, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.], and other appropriate laws and regulations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77681fbb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/433/tV/s512">Pub. L. 103–433, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4494">108 Stat. 4494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77681fbc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77681fbd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77681fbe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 126 (§ 12101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
