<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77681fdc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa–59"><num value="410aaa–59">§ 410aaa–59.</num><heading> No adverse effect on land until acquired</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless and until acquired by the United States, no lands within the boundaries of wilderness areas or National Park System units designated or enlarged by this Act that are owned by any person or entity other than the United States shall be subject to any of the rules or regulations applicable solely to the Federal lands within such boundaries and may be used to the extent allowed by applicable law. Neither the location of such lands within such boundaries nor the possible acquisition of such lands by the United States shall constitute a bar to the otherwise lawful issuance of any Federal license or permit other than a license or permit related to activities governed by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100903">section 100903 of title 54</ref>. Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the applicability of any provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/b">section 1865(b) of title 18</ref>, subchapter III of chapter 1007 of title 54, the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.), or regulations applicable to oil and gas development as set forth in 36 CFR 9B.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77681fdd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/433/tV/s519">Pub. L. 103–433, title V, § 519</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4495">108 Stat. 4495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77681fde-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77681fdf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77681fe0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is defined in <ref href="/us/pl/103/433/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 103–433</ref>, which is set out as a Definitions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa">section 410aaa of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clean Air Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 85 (§ 7401 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77681fe1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “<ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100903">section 100903 of title 54</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</ref><i>l</i>–22(c)” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/b">section 1865(b) of title 18</ref>, subchapter III of chapter 1007 of title 54” substituted for “the Mining in the Parks Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1901">16 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s6/e">Pub. L. 113–287, § 6(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3272">128 Stat. 3272</ref>, which Act enacted Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
