<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id776cda2a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4"><num value="410bbb–4">§ 410bbb–4.</num><heading> General management plan</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within three years after the date funds are made available therefor and concurrent with the national landmark study referenced in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–1/b/3">section 410bbb–1(b)(3) of this title</ref>, the Secretary, in consultation with the New Orleans Jazz Commission, shall prepare a general management plan for the historical park. The plan shall include, but need not be limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda2b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a visitor use plan indicating programs and facilities associated with park programs that will be made available to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda2c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> preservation and use plans for any structures and sites that are identified through the historic landmark study for inclusion within the historical park;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda2d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the location and associated cost of public facilities that are proposed for inclusion within the historical park, including a visitor center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda2e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identification of programs that the Secretary will implement or be associated with through cooperative agreements with other groups and organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda2f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a transportation plan that addresses visitor use access needs to sites, facilities, and programs central to the purpose of the historical park;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda30-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> plans for the implementation of an archival system for materials, objects, and items of importance relating to the history of jazz; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id776cda31-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410bbb–4/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> guidelines for the application of cooperative agreements that will be used to assist in the management of historical park facilities and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id776cda32-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/433/tXII/s1206">Pub. L. 103–433, title XII, § 1206</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4522">108 Stat. 4522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
