<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id775051b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24"><num value="410cc–24">§ 410cc–24.</num><heading> Withholding of funds; criteria</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may refuse to obligate or expend any money appropriated for the purposes described in section 410cc–13(a)(1) or <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–13/a/2">section 410cc–13(a)(2) of this title</ref> if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> the city of Lowell has failed to establish regulations or laws consistent with the standards and criteria established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–32/e">section 410cc–32(e) of this title</ref> within one year after the date such standards and criteria have been established, except that the Secretary may extend such one-year period for not more than six months if the Secretary determines that the city has made a good faith effort to establish such regulations or laws;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> the city of Lowell has failed to notify the Commission of (1) applications for building permits or zoning variances respecting any property which is included in the index established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–32/d">section 410cc–32(d) of this title</ref>, or (2) any proposals of the city of Lowell to change the regulations or laws described in paragraph (c)(1) of this subsection;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> during the period before the city of Lowell has established regulations or laws consistent with the standards and criteria established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–32/e">section 410cc–32(e) of this title</ref>, the city of Lowell has granted any building permit or zoning variance or has taken any other action respecting any property within the park or preservation district, which either the Secretary or the Commission consider to be inconsistent with such standards and criteria;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> after the city of Lowell has established the regulations or laws described in subparagraph (1) of this paragraph, the city of Lowell has granted any building permit or zoning variance or has taken any other action respecting any property within the park or preservation district, which either the Secretary or the Commission consider to be inconsistent with such regulations or laws; or</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id775051b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–24/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> the Commission has not made good faith efforts to (1) provide for the preservation, restoration, management, development, or maintenance of property within the park and preservation district or (2) carry out the park preservation plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410cc–32">section 410cc–32 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id775051b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/290/tII/s204">Pub. L. 95–290, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1978-06-05">June 5, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/294">92 Stat. 294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
