<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77529bc7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410gg–1"><num value="410gg–1">§ 410gg–1.</num><heading> Acquisition of property</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77529bc8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410gg–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary; manner; State lands: donation, reservations, and restrictions; Federal lands: transfer to administrative jurisdiction of National Park Service and Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the boundary of the park the Secretary is authorized to acquire lands, waters, and interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange, except that property owned by the State of Florida or any political subdivision thereof may be acquired only by donation, and subject to such reservations and restrictions as may be provided by Florida law. Lands, waters, and interests therein within such boundary which are owned by the United States and under the control of the Secretary are hereby transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service to be managed for the purposes of the park. Any federally owned lands within the park which are not under the control of the Secretary shall be transferred to his control for purposes of the park at such time as said lands cease to be needed by the agencies which currently control them.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77529bc9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410gg–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition period; consideration by Secretary of prompt acquisition of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the express intent of the Congress that the Secretary shall substantially complete the land acquisition program authorized herein within three complete fiscal years from the effective date of this subchapter. Any owner of property within the park may notify the Secretary of the desire of such owner that his property be promptly acquired, and the Secretary shall give immediate and careful consideration, subject to the availability of funds, to the prompt acquisition of such property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77529bca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/287/tI/s102">Pub. L. 96–287, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/599">94 Stat. 599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77529bcb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77529bcc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77529bcd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this subchapter, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/96/287">Pub. L. 96–287</ref>, which was approved on <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
