<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77529bc0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410gg"><num value="410gg">§ 410gg.</num><heading> Establishment; description of boundary; minor boundary revisions; publication in Federal Register</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to preserve and protect for the education, inspiration, recreation, and enjoyment of present and future generations a rare combination of terrestrial, marine, and amphibious life in a tropical setting of great natural beauty, there is hereby established the Biscayne National Park (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “park”) in the State of Florida. The boundary of the park shall include the lands, waters, and interests therein as generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Biscayne National Park”, numbered 169–90,003, and dated April 1980, which map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall publish in the Federal Register, not more than one year after <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, a detailed description of the boundary established pursuant to this section. Following reasonable notice in writing to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate of his intention to do so, the Secretary may make minor revisions in the boundary of the park by publication of a revised boundary map or other description in the Federal Register.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77529bc1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/287/tI/s101">Pub. L. 96–287, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/599">94 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s6/d/10">Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(10)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4584">108 Stat. 4584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77529bc2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77529bc3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77529bc4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committee on”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77529bc5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77529bc6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Dante Fascell Biscayne National Park Visitor Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/307">Pub. L. 105–307</ref>, <date date="1998-10-29">Oct. 29, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2931">112 Stat. 2931</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/307">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Dante Fascell Biscayne National Park Visitor Center Designation Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> DESIGNATION OF THE DANTE FASCELL VISITOR CENTER AT BISCAYNE NATIONAL PARK.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Biscayne National Park visitor center, located on the shore of Biscayne Bay on Convoy Point, Florida, is designated as the ‘Dante Fascell Visitor Center’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">References</inline>.—</heading><content>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other document of the United States to the Biscayne National Park visitor center shall be deemed to be a reference to the ‘Dante Fascell Visitor Center’.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
