<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77871926-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410iiii–3"><num value="410iiii–3">§ 410iiii–3.</num><heading> Property acquisition</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to acquire by donation, exchange, or purchase with donated or appropriated funds the real property described in subsections (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410iiii–2">section 410iiii–2 of this title</ref>. Any property owned by the State of Kansas or South Carolina or any political subdivision thereof may be acquired only by donation. The Secretary may also acquire by the same methods personal property associated with, and appropriate for, the interpretation of the historical park. The Secretary may not acquire such personal property without the consent of the owner or by condemnation of any land or interest in land within the boundaries of the historical park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77871927-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/525/tI/s104">Pub. L. 102–525, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1992-10-26">Oct. 26, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3439">106 Stat. 3439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/123">Pub. L. 117–123</ref>, §§ 2(c)(4), 3(f), <date date="2022-05-12">May 12, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1196">136 Stat. 1196</ref>, 1199.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77871928-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77871929-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7787192a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/123">Pub. L. 117–123</ref> substituted “subsections (b) and (c) of section 410iiii–2” for “section 410iiii–2(b)”, “State of Kansas or South Carolina” for “States of Kansas”, and “historical park. The Secretary” for “historic site: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Secretary” and inserted “or by condemnation of any land or interest in land within the boundaries of the historical park” after “without the consent of the owner”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
