<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7746b48b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410j"><num value="410j">§ 410j.</num><heading> Acquisition of land, water, and interests therein; consent of owner; reservations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land and water for Everglades National Park shall on and after <date date="1958-07-02">July 2, 1958</date> be restricted to the area within the boundary described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410i">section 410i of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding the proviso contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410">section 410 of this title</ref>, or any other provision of law, the said Secretary is authorized on and after <date date="1958-07-02">July 2, 1958</date>, within the boundary fixed in sections 410i to 410p of this title and with any funds made available for that purpose, to acquire land, water, and interests therein by purchase or otherwise.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority to acquire land, water, and interests therein within the park boundary fixed in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410i">section 410i of this title</ref> but outside the area designated in sections 410e to 410h of this title, is further subject to the right of retention by the owners thereof, including owners of interests in oil, gas, and mineral rights or royalties, and by their heirs, executors, administrators, successors, and assigns, at their election of the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">(1) The reservation until <date date="1967-10-09">October 9, 1967</date>, of all oil, gas, and mineral rights or interests, including the right to lease, explore for, produce, store, and remove oil, gas, and other minerals from such lands;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">(2) In the event that on or before said date, oil, gas, or other minerals are being produced in commercial quantities anywhere within the boundary fixed in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410i">section 410i of this title</ref> but outside the area designated in sections 410e to 410h of this title, the time of the reservation provided in subsection (1) above shall automatically extend for all owners within said boundary and outside of said area regardless of whether such production is from land in which such owners have an interest, for so long as oil, gas, or other minerals are produced in commercial quantities anywhere within said boundary and outside of said area. To exercise this reservation, the owners, their lessees, agents, employees, and assigns shall have such right of ingress to and egress from such land and water as may be necessary; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">(3) After the termination of the reserved rights of owners as set forth in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, a further reservation of the right to customary royalties, applying at the time of production, in any oil, gas, or other minerals which may be produced from such land and water at any time before <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>, should production ever be authorized by the Federal Government or its assigns.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7746b48c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/482/s2">Pub. L. 85–482, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-07-02">July 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/284">72 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/428/s2">Pub. L. 91–428, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-09-26">Sept. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/885">84 Stat. 885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7746b48d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7746b48e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7746b48f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/428">Pub. L. 91–428</ref> struck out restriction against acquisition of certain described lands in Dade County without the consent of the owner so long as the land is used exclusively for agricultural purposes, including housing directly incident thereto, or is lying fallow or remains in its natural state.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
