<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7759c80d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1"><num value="410mm–1">§ 410mm–1.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c80e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Laws governing; conservation and protection of resources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the park in accordance with this subchapter and with the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,” approved <date date="1916-08-26">August 26, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1–4">16 U.S.C. 1–4</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002117">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002117"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> The Secretary shall protect, manage, and administer the park in such manner as to conserve and protect the scenery, the natural, geologic, historic, and archaeological resources of the park, including fish and wildlife and to provide for the public use and enjoyment of the same in such a manner as to perpetuate these qualities for future generations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c80f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fishing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit fishing on lands and waters under his jurisdiction within the park in accordance with the applicable laws of the United States and the State of Nevada, except that he may designate zones where, and periods when, no fishing may be permitted for reasons of public safety. Except in emergencies, any regulations prescribing such restrictions relating to fishing,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002118">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002118"><num>2</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> shall be put into effect only after consultation with the appropriate State agency having jurisdiction over fishing activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c810-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation of management plan; submission to Congress; amendment of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After notice and opportunity for public hearing, the Secretary shall prepare a management plan for the park. The Secretary shall submit such plan to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States House of Representatives and with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate within three years after <date date="1986-10-27">October 27, 1986</date>. Such plan may be amended from time to time. The plan shall include, but not be limited to, provisions related to grazing within the park to the extent permitted under subsection (e) and provisions providing for the appropriate management of fish and wildlife and fishing within the park in accordance with subsection (b). Such provisions shall be adopted only after consultation with the appropriate State agency having jurisdiction over fish and wildlife.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c811-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of lands from mining and mineral leasing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to valid existing rights, Federal lands and interests therein, within the park, are withdrawn from disposition under the public lands laws and from entry or appropriation under the mining laws of the United States, from the operation of the mineral leasing laws of the United States, and from operation of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1001">30 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c812-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Grazing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to such limitations, conditions, or regulations as he may prescribe, the Secretary may permit grazing on lands within the park to the same extent as was permitted on such lands as of <date date="1985-07-01">July 1, 1985</date>. Grazing within the park shall be administered by the National Park Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c813-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Exchange of park grazing allotment for grazing allotment outside park</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c814-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Exchanges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At the request of the permittee, or at the initiative of the Secretary, negotiations may take place at any time with holders of valid existing grazing permits and grazing leases on land within the park, for an exchange of all or part of their grazing allotments for allotments outside the park. No such exchange shall take place if, in the opinion of the affected Federal land management agency, the exchange would result in overgrazing of Federal lands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c815-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition by donation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c816-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may acquire by donation valid existing permits and grazing leases authorizing grazing on land in the park.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c817-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall terminate a grazing permit or grazing lease acquired under subparagraph (A) so as to end grazing previously authorized by the permit or lease.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c818-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Water-related range improvements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Existing water-related range improvements inside the park may be maintained by the Secretary or the persons benefitting from them, subject to reasonable regulation by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c819-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation to United States of new express or implied water or water-related right not established; exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to establish a new express or implied reservation to the United States of any water or water-related right with respect to the land described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410mm">section 410mm of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That the United States shall be entitled to only that express or implied reserved water right which may have been associated with the initial establishment and withdrawal of Humboldt National Forest and the Lehman Caves National Monument from the public domain with respect to the land described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410mm">section 410mm of this title</ref>. No provision of this subchapter shall be construed as authorizing the appropriation of water, except in accordance with the substantive and procedural law of the State of Nevada.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7759c81a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410mm–1/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements with Federal and other agencies; interpretation of Great Basin physiographic region</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to encourage unified and cost-effective interpretation of the Great Basin physiographic region, the Secretary is authorized and encouraged to enter into cooperative agreements with other Federal, State, and local public departments and agencies providing for the interpretation of the Great Basin physiographic region. Such agreements shall include, but not be limited to, authority for the Secretary to develop and operate interpretive facilities and programs on lands and waters outside of the boundaries of such park, with the concurrence of the owner or administrator thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id775c381b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/565/s3">Pub. L. 99–565, § 3</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3182">100 Stat. 3182</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/c/tIII/s319">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title III, § 319]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-156">110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–203; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id775c381c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id775c381d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id775c381e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,” approved <date date="1916-08-26">August 26, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1–4">16 U.S.C. 1–4</ref>), referred to in subsec. (a), means <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, as amended, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/581">Pub. L. 91–581</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1566">84 Stat. 1566</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1001">section 1001 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id775c381f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/s101/c/tIII/s319/1">Pub. L. 104–134, § 101(c) [title III, § 319(1)]</ref>, substituted “may permit” for “shall permit” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/s101/c/tIII/s319/2">Pub. L. 104–134, § 101(c) [title III, § 319(2)]</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, substituted “grazing permits and grazing leases” for “grazing permits”, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id775c3820-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id775c3821-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
