<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7749265d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410s"><num value="410s">§ 410s.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7749265e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410s/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to preserve for the benefit of the American people certain historic structures and properties of outstanding national significance associated with the opening of the War of the American Revolution, Minute Man National Historical Park is authorized to be established in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts. The purposes of the park shall include the preservation and interpretation of (1) the historic landscape along the road between Lexington and Concord, (2) sites associated with the causes and consequences of the American Revolution, and (3) the Wayside on Lexington Road in Concord, the home of Nathaniel Hawthorne, Bronson Alcott, Louisa May Alcott, and Margaret Sidney, whose works illustrate the nineteenth century American literary renaissance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7749265f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410s/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Boundaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The park shall be comprised of the lands depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map NARO–406–20015C”, dated June 1991.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77492660-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/321/s1">Pub. L. 86–321, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/591">73 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/548/s1">Pub. L. 91–548, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1436">84 Stat. 1436</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/488/s2/s1">Pub. L. 102–488, § 2[(1)]</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3135">106 Stat. 3135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77492661-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77492662-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77492663-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/488">Pub. L. 102–488</ref> substituted “The purposes of the park shall include the preservation and interpretation of (1) the historic landscape along the road between Lexington and Concord, (2) sites associated with the causes and consequences of the American Revolution, and (3) the Wayside on Lexington Road in Concord, the home of Nathaniel Hawthorne, Bronson Alcott, Louisa May Alcott, and Margaret Sidney, whose works illustrate the nineteenth century American literary renaissance.” for “The park shall comprise not more than seven hundred and fifty acres as may be designated by the Secretary of the Interior from within the area beginning at Fiske Hill and thence lying along Massachusetts Avenue, Marrett Road and Marrett Street in the town of Lexington, along Nelson Road, Virginia Road, Old Bedford Road, and North Great Road or State Route 2–A in the town of Lincoln, and along Lexington Road, Monument Street, Liberty Street and Lowell Road in the town of Concord to and including the North Bridge and properties on both sides of the Concord River in the vicinity of the North Bridge.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/488">Pub. L. 102–488</ref> added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Notwithstanding the description set forth in subsection (a) of this section, if the Secretary should determine that the relocation of Highway 2 by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts makes it desirable to establish new boundaries in common with, contiguous or adjacent to the proposed right-of-way for that highway, he is authorized to relocate such boundaries accordingly, and shall give notice thereof by publication of a map or other suitable description in the Federal Register: <i>Provided</i>, That any net acreage increase by reason of the boundary revision and land exchanges with the Commonwealth shall not be included in calculations of acreage in regard to the limitation set forth in subsection (a) of this section, but shall be in addition thereto.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/488">Pub. L. 102–488</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “Any lands added to the Minute Man National Historical Park, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section may be acquired only if such acquisition can be accomplished without cost for land acquisition and, when so acquired, shall be subject to all laws, rules, and regulations applicable thereto.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/548">Pub. L. 91–548</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77492664-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id77492665-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/488/s1">Pub. L. 102–488, § 1</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3135">106 Stat. 3135</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/488/s1">“This Act [enacting sections 410x–1 and 410x–2 of this title and amending this section and sections 410t and 410x of this title] may be cited as the ‘Minute Man National Historical Park Amendments of 1991’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
