<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77492666-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t"><num value="410t">§ 410t.</num><heading> Acquisition and transfer of lands; private owner’s retention of right of use and occupancy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77492667-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of lands; administrative jurisdiction of Federal lands; notice in Federal Register</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire by donation or with donated funds, or with funds authorized to be appropriated, lands and interests in lands within the area designated for the park. Administrative jurisdiction of Federal lands lying within the area designated for the park shall, with the concurrence of the Federal agency involved, be transferred to the Secretary of the Interior for administration as a part of the park.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The park shall be established as Minute Man National Historical Park by notice in the Federal Register when the Secretary of the Interior finds that sufficient lands within the designated area have been acquired to warrant such establishment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77492668-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of lands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall transfer, without reimbursement, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense the two parcels currently administered by the Secretary of the Interior, as depicted on the map dated April 1990 and numbered NARO–406/80805. The Secretary of Defense shall transfer to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, without reimbursement, for inclusion in the Minute Man National Historical Park the 4 parcels now administered by the Secretary of Defense, as depicted on the maps dated April 1990 and numbered NARO–406/80804 and NARO–406/80805.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77492669-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions and limitations to authorization to acquire lands; condemnation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange, lands or interests in lands within the areas included within the boundaries of the park pursuant to amendments made by the Minute Man National Historical Park Amendments of 1991 (hereinafter referred to as “1991 additions”), except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7749266a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> lands, and interests in lands, within the 1991 additions which are owned by the State of Massachusetts or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7749266b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> lands, and interests in lands, within the 1991 additions which are used for noncommercial residential purposes as of <date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>, may be acquired only with the consent of the owner thereof unless the property is being developed, or is proposed to be developed, in a manner which the Secretary determines to be detrimental to the scenic, historical, cultural, and other values of the park.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in paragraph (2) shall be construed to prohibit the use of condemnation as a means of acquiring a clear and marketable title, free of any and all encumbrances for any lands within the 1991 additions. Not later than 6 months after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and after notice and opportunity for public comment, the Secretary of the Interior shall publish specific guidelines for making determinations under paragraph (2). Such guidelines shall provide for (A) written notice to the Secretary prior to commencement of any proposed development on the lands referred to in paragraph (2), (B) written notice by the Secretary to the owner of such lands of any determination proposed to be made under paragraph (2), and (C) a reasonable opportunity for the owner to comment on such proposed determination.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7749266c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Private owner’s retention of right of use and occupancy</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7749266d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any individual who owns private property acquired by the Secretary under subsection (c) may, on the date of such acquisition and as a condition of such acquisition, retain for himself and his successors or assigns, a right of use and occupancy of the property for a definite term of not more than 25 years from the date of acquisition by the Secretary or a term ending at the death of the owner or the owner’s spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7749266e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner reserving a right of use and occupancy under this subsection the fair market value of the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value on that date of the right retained by the owner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7749266f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410t/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of applying this subsection, ownership shall be determined as of <date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77492670-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/321/s2">Pub. L. 86–321, § 2</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/591">73 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/488/s2/3/s2">Pub. L. 102–488, § 2(3)[(2)]</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3135">106 Stat. 3135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77492671-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77492672-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77492673-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Minute Man National Historical Park Amendments of 1991, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/488">Pub. L. 102–488</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3135">106 Stat. 3135</ref>, which enacted sections 410x–1 and 410x–2 of this title, amended this section and sections 410s and 410x of this title, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410s">section 410s of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1992 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410s">section 410s of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77492674-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/488">Pub. L. 102–488</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) to (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77492675-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77492676-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Boundary Adjustment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tVII/s7106">Pub. L. 111–11, title VII, § 7106</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1193">123 Stat. 1193</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/11/tVII/s7106">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Map</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘map’ means the map entitled ‘Minute Man National Historical Park Proposed Boundary’, numbered 406/81001, and dated July 2007.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Park</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Park’ means the Minute Man National Historical Park in the State of Massachusetts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minute Man National Historical Park.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Boundary adjustment.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The boundary of the Park is modified to include the area generally depicted on the map.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of map</inline>.—</heading><content>The map shall be on file and available for inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of land</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may acquire the land or an interest in the land described in paragraph (1)(A) by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> purchase from willing sellers with donated or appropriated funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> donation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> exchange.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration of land</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall administer the land added to the Park under paragraph (1)(A) in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
