<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id777d7bb0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1"><num value="410www–1">§ 410www–1.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as “the Secretary”) shall administer the Martin Luther King, Jr. National Historical Park and Preservation District in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, and the provisions of law generally applicable to national historic sites,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002191">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002191"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “to the National Park System,”.</note> including the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1">16 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 2–4) and the Act of <date date="1935-08-21">August 21, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/666">49 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s461–7">16 U.S.C. 461–7</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within the national historical park the Secretary is authorized to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer, or exchange, lands and interests therein, except that property owned by the State of Georgia or any political subdivision thereof may be acquired only by donation or exchange.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the acquisition authority contained in paragraph (1), any lands or interests therein which are owned wholly or in part, by the widow of Martin Luther King, Junior, or by the Martin Luther King, Junior, Center for Social Change, shall be acquired only with the consent of the owner thereof, except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id777d7bb5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary may acquire such property in accordance with the provisions of this section if he determines that the property is undergoing or is about to undergo a change in use which is inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id777d7bb6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to properties owned by the Center for Social Change, the Secretary shall have the first right of refusal to purchase such property for a purchase price not exceeding the fair market value of such property on the date it is offered for sale.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Property may be acquired pursuant to this section subject to such conditions and reservations as in the judgment of the Secretary are not inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter and the administration of the national historical park, including, in the event that the burial site of Martin Luther King, Junior, is acquired, the condition that his widow may be interred therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any and all legal or equitable title, interests, or encumbrances, if any, held by the Department of Housing and Urban Development in the property designated “Parcel A” on the map referenced in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460bbbb">section 460bbbb of this title</ref> are hereby conveyed to the Secretary to be administered in accordance with the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id777d7bb9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410www–1/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Structural space requirements of the National Park Service to meet its administrative, operational, and interpretive functions for the national historical park and preservation district shall, to the maximum extent feasible without displacing residents, be met within the district through the adaptive use of existing structures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id777d7bba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/428/s2">Pub. L. 96–428, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1839">94 Stat. 1839</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/314/s3">Pub. L. 108–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2004-10-05">Oct. 5, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1199">118 Stat. 1199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/108/s2/2">Pub. L. 115–108, § 2(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2018-01-08">Jan. 8, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2267">131 Stat. 2267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id777d7bbb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id777d7bbc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id777d7bbd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, popularly known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1935-08-21">August 21, 1935</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-21/ch593">act Aug. 21, 1935, ch. 593</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/666">49 Stat. 666</ref>, known as the Historic Sites, Buildings and Antiquities Act and also as the Historic Sites Act of 1935, which enacted sections 461 to 467 of this title. The Act was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1866/a">section 1866(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and sections 102303 and 102304 and chapter 3201 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id777d7bbe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460bbbb–1">section 460bbbb–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id777d7bbf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/108/s2/2">Pub. L. 115–108, § 2(2)</ref>, substituted “Martin Luther King, Jr. National Historical Park” for “Martin Luther King, Junior, National Historic Site”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/108/s2/3">Pub. L. 115–108, § 2(3)</ref>, substituted “national historical park” for “national historic site” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/314">Pub. L. 108–314</ref> inserted “or exchange” before period at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
