<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id777fec6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s410zzz–2"><num value="410zzz–2">§ 410zzz–2.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> When the sites, structures, and other properties authorized for acquisition under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410zzz">section 410zzz of this title</ref> and endowment funds in the amount of $100,000 have been transferred to the United States, the Secretary of the Interior shall establish the Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park by publication of notice thereof in the Federal Register. Following such establishment the Secretary may acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange 279 acres of lands and buildings, or interests therein which he deems necessary for addition to the Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park and which, when acquired, shall become a part of the park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id777fec6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/543/s3">Pub. L. 88–543, § 3</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/749">78 Stat. 749</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 94–578, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2735">90 Stat. 2735</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/491/s1/1">Pub. L. 106–491, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2209">114 Stat. 2209</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/9/tII/s2201/b/1">Pub. L. 116–9, title II, § 2201(b)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/733">133 Stat. 733</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id777fec6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id777fec6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id777fec6f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—<ref href="/us/pl/116/9/s2201/b/3">Pub. L. 116–9, § 2201(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “addition to the Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park” for “addition to the national historical site” and “part of the park” for “part of the site”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/9/s2201/b/1">Pub. L. 116–9, § 2201(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “National Historical Park by publication” for “National Historic Site by publication”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/491">Pub. L. 106–491</ref> substituted “279 acres of lands and buildings, or interests therein” for “not to exceed sixty-four acres of lands and interests therein”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/578">Pub. L. 94–578</ref> inserted at end “Following such establishment the Secretary may acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange not to exceed sixty-four acres of lands and interests therein which he deems necessary for addition to the national historical site and which, when acquired, shall become a part of the site.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
