<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id778bd443-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s426d"><num value="426d">§ 426d.</num><heading> Receipt of report of commission by Secretary of the Interior; acquisition of land for battlefield; other duties of Secretary</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of the report of said commission, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to acquire, by purchase, when purchasable at prices deemed by him reasonable, otherwise by condemnation, such tract or tracts of lands as are recommended by the commission as necessary and desirable for a national battlefield; to establish and substantially mark the boundaries of the said battlefield; to definitely mark all lines of battle and locations of troops within the boundaries of the battlefield and erect substantial historical tablets at such points within the battlefield and in the vicinity of the battlefield and its approaches as are recommended by the commission, together with such other points as the Secretary of the Interior may deem appropriate; to construct the necessary roads and walks, plant trees and shrubs, restore and care for the grounds, including the Hazen Monument: <i>Provided</i>, That the entire cost of acquiring said land, including cost of condemnation proceedings, if any, ascertainment of title, surveys, and compensation for the land, the cost of marking the battlefield, the expenses of the commission, and the establishment of the national military battlefield, shall not exceed the sum of $100,000.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id778bd444-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-03-03/ch374/s5">Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 374, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1400">44 Stat. 1400</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1930-04-15/ch167">Apr. 15, 1930, ch. 167</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/167">46 Stat. 167</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 2, <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>; Ex. Ord. No. 6228, § 1, <date date="1933-07-28">July 28, 1933</date>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/443/s2">Pub. L. 86–443, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-04-22">Apr. 22, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/82">74 Stat. 82</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id778bd445-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id778bd446-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id778bd447-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1930—Act <date date="1930-04-15">Apr. 15, 1930</date>, inserted “military” between “national” and “park”, authorized construction of roads and walks, planting of trees and shrubs, restoration and care of grounds, including the Hazen Monument, and inserted “and the establishment of the national military park” in proviso.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id778bd448-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id778bd449-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“National battlefield” and “battlefield” substituted in text for “national military park” and “park”, respectively, in view of redesignation of Stones River National Military Park as Stones River National Battlefield by <ref href="/us/pl/86/443">Pub. L. 86–443</ref>. See section 426<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id778bd44a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id778bd44b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of administrative functions of park, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s426">section 426 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
