<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id778e44f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s428i"><num value="428i">§ 428i.</num><heading> Protection of monuments, etc.</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any person shall willfully destroy, mutilate, deface, injure, or remove any monument, column, statue, memorial structure, or work of art that shall be erected or placed upon the grounds of the battlefield by lawful authority, or shall willfully destroy or remove any fence, railing, inclosure, or other work for the protection or ornament of said battlefield, or any portion thereof, or shall willfully destroy, cut, hack, bark, break down, or otherwise injure any tree, bush, or shrubbery that may be growing upon said battlefield, or shall cut down or fell or remove any timber, battle relic, tree, or trees growing or being upon such battlefield, except by permission of the Secretary of the Interior, or shall willfully remove or destroy any breastworks, earthworks, walls, or other defenses or shelter, or any part thereof, constructed by the armies formerly engaged in the battle on the lands or approaches to the battlefield, any person so offending shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof before any court of competent jurisdiction shall for each and every such offense be fined not less than $5 nor more than $100.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id778e44f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1928-03-26/ch248/s10">Mar. 26, 1928, ch. 248, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/368">45 Stat. 368</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 2, <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>; Ex. Ord. No. 6228, § 1, <date date="1933-07-28">July 28, 1933</date>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/738">Pub. L. 86–738</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="1960-09-08">Sept. 8, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/876">74 Stat. 876</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id778e44f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id778e44f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id778e44f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Battlefield” substituted for “park” wherever appearing in text in view of redesignation of Fort Donelson National Military Park as Fort Donelson National Battlefield by <ref href="/us/pl/86/738">Pub. L. 86–738</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s428n">section 428n of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id778e44fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id778e44fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of administrative functions of park, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s428">section 428 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
