<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77908f41-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1"><num value="429b–1">§ 429b–1.</num><heading> Acquisition and use of lands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77908f42-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of property or interests in property; scenic preservation of views</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77908f43-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In order to effectuate the purposes of sections 429b to 429b–5 of this title, the Secretary is authorized to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds or exchange, any property or interests therein which are located within the boundaries of the park, except that property owned by the Commonwealth of Virginia or by any political subdivision thereof may be acquired only by donation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77908f44-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall cooperate with the Commonwealth of Virginia, the political subdivisions thereof, and other parties as designated by the Commonwealth or its political subdivisions in order to promote and achieve scenic preservation of views from within the park through zoning and such other means as the parties determine feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77908f45-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of fee simple title with the consent of owner; hearing and review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to areas within the 1954 boundaries of the park, as identified on the map referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s429b">section 429b of this title</ref>, the Secretary may not acquire fee simple title to such areas without the consent of the owner so long as the lands continue to be devoted to a use which is the same as that in effect on <date date="1980-09-01">September 1, 1980</date>. Further, if the Secretary proposes to acquire fee simple title to such property because of a change in use, the owner of such property may seek a review of the proposed acquisition of his or her property and is entitled to a hearing on the record in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77908f46-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary authorized to make land available for Route 234 bypass</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Virginia Department of Highways and Transportation determines that the proposed Route 234 bypass should be properly located between the Virginia Electric Power Company powerline easement and route 705, the Secretary shall make available the land necessary for such bypass, subject to such revisions, terms, and conditions as the Secretary deems are necessary and appropriate to assure that such bypass is located, constructed, operated, and maintained in a manner consistent with the administration of the park.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77908f47-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s429b–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary not to close State roads</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may not close any State roads within the park unless action permitting the closing of such roads has been taken by appropriate officials of the Commonwealth of Virginia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77908f48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-04-17/ch153/s2">Apr. 17, 1954, ch. 153, § 2</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/442/s2">Pub. L. 96–442, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1885">94 Stat. 1885</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tX/s10003">Pub. L. 100–647, title X, § 10003</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3811">102 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77908f49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77908f4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77908f4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
