<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79ee54a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307"><num value="4307">§ 4307.</num><heading> Civil penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ee54a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ee54aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may issue an order assessing a civil penalty against any person who violates any prohibition contained in this chapter, any regulation promulgated pursuant to this chapter, or any permit issued under this chapter. Before issuing such an order, the Secretary shall provide such person written notice and the opportunity to request a hearing on the record within 30 days. Each violation shall be a separate offense, even if such violations occurred at the same time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ee54ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of such civil penalty shall be determined by the Secretary taking into account appropriate factors, including (A) the seriousness of the violation; (B) the economic benefit (if any) resulting from the violation; (C) any history of such violations; and (D) such other matters as the Secretary deems appropriate. The maximum fine permissible under this section is $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ee54ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person aggrieved by an assessment of a civil penalty under this section may file a petition for judicial review of such assessment with the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or for the district in which the violation occurred. Such a petition shall be filed within the 30-day period beginning on the date the order assessing the civil penalty was issued.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ee54ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54ae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> within 30 days after the order was issued under subsection (a), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the order is appealed within such 30-day period, within 10 days after court has entered a final judgment in favor of the Secretary under subsection (b),</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall notify the Attorney General and the Attorney General shall bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court to recover the amount of penalty assessed (plus costs, attorney’s fees, and interest at currently prevailing rates from the date the order was issued or the date of such final judgment, as the case may be). In such an action, the validity, amount, and appropriateness of such penalty shall not be subject to review.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ee54b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4307/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may issue subpoenas in connection with proceedings under this subsection compelling the attendance and testimony of witnesses and subpoenas duces tecum, and may request the Attorney General to bring an action to enforce any subpoena under this section. The district courts shall have jurisdiction to enforce such subpoenas and impose sanctions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79ee54b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/691/s8">Pub. L. 100–691, § 8</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4550">102 Stat. 4550</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
