<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7793002b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s430g"><num value="430g">§ 430g.</num><heading> Gettysburg National Military Park</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The lands heretofore conveyed by the Gettysburg Battlefield Memorial Association to the United States, embracing about 800 acres, more or less, and being a considerable part of the battlefield of Gettysburg, and such other lands on the battlefield as the United States has heretofore acquired or shall hereafter acquire by purchase or condemnation proceedings, shall be designated and known as the “Gettysburg National Park.” Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed and held to prejudice the rights acquired by any State or by any military organization to the ground on which its monuments or markers are placed, nor the right-of-way to the same. It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Interior to establish and enforce proper regulations for the custody, preservation, and care of the monuments erected or which may be hereafter erected within the limits of the said national military park; and such rules shall provide for convenient access by visitors to all such monuments within the park, and the ground included therein, on such days and within such hours as may be designated and authorized by the Secretary of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior may lease the lands of the park at his discretion either to former owners or other persons for agricultural purposes, the proceeds to be applied by the Secretary of the Interior, through the proper disbursing officer, to the maintenance of the park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7793002c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1895-02-11/ch80">Feb. 11, 1895, ch. 80</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/651">28 Stat. 651</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1897-06-04/ch2/s1">June 4, 1897, ch. 2, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/44">30 Stat. 44</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 2, <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>; Ex. Ord. No. 6228, § 1, <date date="1933-07-28">July 28, 1933</date>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/637">80 Stat. 637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7793002d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7793002e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7793002f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref> struck out provisions which required the affairs of park to be subject to supervision and direction of Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77930030-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77930031-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition of Additional Lands for Gettysburg National Military Park; Study and Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/132/s2">Pub. L. 100–132, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-10-16">Oct. 16, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/807">101 Stat. 807</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/132/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Additional Lands</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in section 1 of this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s430g–3">16 U.S.C. 430g–3</ref>], until Congress receives the study under subsection (b), the Secretary of the Interior may not acquire by purchase, donation, exchange, or any other means any additional land for the Gettysburg National Military Park which is not within the boundaries of the 3,874 acre area depicted on the map dated <date date="1974-07-25">July 25, 1974</date>, numbered 305–92,004 and entitled ‘Gettysburg National Military Park’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study by National Park Service</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Interior through the National Park Service shall conduct a boundary study and shall submit a report to Congress within one year of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-10-16">Oct. 16, 1987</date>], with recommendations with respect to the final development of the Gettysburg National Military Park. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consult with the people of the community and their elected representatives at all levels as well as with other interested individuals and groups.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77930032-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77930033-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Administrative functions of Gettysburg National Military Park transferred to Department of the Interior by Ex. Ord. Nos. 6166 and 6228, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s901">section 901 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Park Service substituted for Office of National Parks, Buildings, and Reservations referred to in Ex. Ord. No. 6166, by <ref href="/us/act/1934-03-02/ch38/s1">act Mar. 2, 1934, ch. 38, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/389">48 Stat. 389</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
