<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id779570d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s430k"><num value="430k">§ 430k.</num><heading> Condemnation proceedings; purchase without condemnation; acceptance of donations of land</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to cause condemnation proceedings to be instituted in the name of the United States under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3113">section 3113 of title 40</ref>, to acquire title to the lands, interests therein, or rights pertaining thereto within the said battlefield, and the United States shall be entitled to immediate possession upon the filing of the petition in condemnation in the United States District Court for the District of Maryland: <i>Provided</i>, That when the owner of such lands, interests therein, or rights pertaining thereto shall fix a price for the same, which, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Interior, shall be reasonable, the Secretary may purchase the same without further delay: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to accept, on behalf of the United States, donations of lands, interests therein, or rights pertaining thereto required for the battlefield: <i>And provided further</i>, That title and evidence of title to lands and interests therein acquired for said battlefield shall be satisfactory to the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id779570d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-21/ch694/s2">June 21, 1934, ch. 694, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1199">48 Stat. 1199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/tIII/s319/2">Pub. L. 94–578, title III, § 319(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2738">90 Stat. 2738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id779570d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id779570d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id779570d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3113">Section 3113 of title 40</ref>” substituted in text for “the Act of <date date="1888-08-01">August 1, 1888</date>, entitled ‘An Act to authorize condemnation of lands for sites for public buildings and for other purposes’ (25 Stat.L. 357)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id779570d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/578">Pub. L. 94–578</ref> substituted “battlefield” for “Monocacy National Military Park” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id779570d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id779570d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Battlefield” substituted in text for “park” in view of redesignation of Monocacy National Military Park as Monocacy National Battlefield by <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/s319/1">Pub. L. 94–578, § 319(1)</ref>, set out as <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s430j">section 430j of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
