<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id779570da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s430l"><num value="430l">§ 430l.</num><heading> Leases with preceding owners of acquired lands; conditions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to lease to the immediately preceding owner or owners any lands acquired pursuant to an agreement that such lessee or lessees will occupy such lands in a manner consistent with the purposes of sections 430j to 430m and 430<i>o</i> to 430s of this title and that they will preserve the present breastworks, earthworks, walls, defenses, shelters, buildings, and roads, and the present outlines of the battlefields, and that they will only cut trees or underbrush or disturb or remove the soil, under such regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe, and that they will assist in protecting all tablets, monuments, or such other artificial works as may from time to time be erected by proper authority.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id779570db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-21/ch694/s3">June 21, 1934, ch. 694, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1199">48 Stat. 1199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/tIII/s319/3">Pub. L. 94–578, title III, § 319(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2738">90 Stat. 2738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id779570dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id779570dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id779570de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/578">Pub. L. 94–578</ref> substituted “lease to the immediately preceding owner or owners any lands acquired pursuant to an agreement that such lessee or lessees will occupy such lands in a manner consistent with the purposes of sections 430j to 430m and 430<i>o</i> to 430s of this title and” for “enter into leases with the owners of such of the lands, works, defenses, and buildings thereon within the Monocacy National Military Park, as in his discretion it is unnecessary to forthwith acquire title to, and such leases shall be on such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Interior may prescribe, and may contain options to purchase, subject to later acceptance, if, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Interior, it is as economical to purchase as condemn title to the property: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of the Interior may enter into agreements upon such nominal terms as he may prescribe, permitting the present owners or their tenants to occupy or cultivate their present holdings, upon condition”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
