<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7797ba7b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s430oo"><num value="430oo">§ 430oo.</num><heading> Acquisition of lands for preservation, protection and improvement; limitation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire such lands and interests in land and to enter into such agreements with the owners of land on behalf of themselves, their heirs and assigns with respect to the use thereof as the Secretary finds necessary to preserve, protect and improve the Antietam Battlefield comprising approximately 1,800 acres in the State of Maryland and the property of the United States thereon, to assure the public a full and unimpeded view thereof, and to provide for the maintenance of the site (other than those portions thereof which are occupied by public buildings and monuments and the Antietam National Cemetery) in, or its restoration to, substantially the condition in which it was at the time of the battle of Antietam. Any acquisition authorized by this section may be made without regard to the limitation set forth in the proviso contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s430nn">section 430nn of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7797ba7c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/438">Pub. L. 86–438</ref>, <date date="1960-04-22">Apr. 22, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/79">74 Stat. 79</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/608/s1/11">Pub. L. 93–608, § 1(11)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1969">88 Stat. 1969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/528/s1/a">Pub. L. 100–528, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-25">Oct. 25, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2649">102 Stat. 2649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7797ba7d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7797ba7e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7797ba7f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/528">Pub. L. 100–528</ref> struck out after first sentence “Not more than 600 acres of land, however, shall be acquired in fee by purchase or condemnation, but neither this limitation nor any other provision of law shall preclude such acquisition of the fee title to other lands and its immediate reconveyance to the former owner with such covenants, restrictions, or conditions as will accomplish the purposes of this section: <i>Provided</i>, That the cost to the Government of any such transaction shall not exceed the reasonable value of the covenants, restrictions, or conditions thereby imposed on the property.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/93/608">Pub. L. 93–608</ref> struck out requirement that Secretary report to Congress at least once each year on any acquisition made or agreement entered into under provisions of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7797ba80-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7797ba81-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Scenic Easements; Acquisition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/625/tIII/s319/a">Pub. L. 95–625, title III, § 319(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3488">92 Stat. 3488</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/528/s1/b">Pub. L. 100–528, § 1(b)</ref>, Oct, 25, 1988, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2649">102 Stat. 2649</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/528/s1/b">“In furtherance of the purposes of the Act entitled ‘An Act to provide for the protection and preservation of the Antietam Battlefield in the State of Maryland’, approved <date date="1960-04-22">April 22, 1960</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/74/79">74 Stat. 79</ref>) [this section], and other Acts relative thereto [see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s430nn">section 430nn of this title</ref>], the Secretary is hereby authorized to acquire the additional lands generally depicted on the map entitled ‘Boundary Map, Antietam National Battlefield, Washington County, Maryland,’ numbered 302–80.005–A and dated June 1977.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
