<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id779570f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s430q"><num value="430q">§ 430q.</num><heading> Offenses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any person shall, except by permission of the Secretary of the Interior, destroy, mutilate, deface, injure, or remove any monument, column, statue, memorial structure, or work of art that shall be erected or placed upon the grounds of the park by lawful authority, or shall destroy or remove any fence, railing, enclosure, or other work for the protection or ornament of said park, or any portion thereof, or shall destroy, cut, hack, bark, break down, or otherwise injure any tree, bush, or shrubbery that may be growing upon said park, or shall cut down or fell or remove any timber, battle relic, tree or trees growing or being upon said park, or hunt within the limits of the park, or shall remove or destroy any breastworks, earthworks, walls, or other defenses or shelter or any part thereof constructed by the armies formerly engaged in the battles on the lands or approaches to the park, any person so offending and found guilty thereof, before any United States magistrate judge or court, of the jurisdiction in which the offense may be committed, shall for each and every such offense forfeit and pay a fine, in the discretion of the United States magistrate judge or court, according to the aggravation of the offense.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id779570f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-21/ch694/s8">June 21, 1934, ch. 694, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1200">48 Stat. 1200</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/578/tIV/s402/b/2">Pub. L. 90–578, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1118">82 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/tIII/s319/8">Pub. L. 94–578, title III, § 319(8)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2739">90 Stat. 2739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5117">104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id779570f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id779570f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id779570f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/578">Pub. L. 94–578</ref> struck out provisions which limited fines to not less than $5 nor more than $500.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id779570f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id779570f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States magistrate judge” substituted for “United States magistrate” wherever appearing in text pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/s321">section 321 of Pub. L. 101–650</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s631">section 631 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. Previously, “United States magistrate” substituted for “United States commissioner” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/90/578">Pub. L. 90–578</ref>. See chapter 43 (§ 631 et seq.) of Title 28.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
