<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79ee54ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402"><num value="4402">§ 4402.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Agreement” means the Tripartite Agreement signed in March 1988, by the Director General for Ecological Conservation of Natural Resources of Mexico, the Director of the Canadian Wildlife Service, and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “appropriate Committees” means the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the United States Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “flyway” means the four administrative units used by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the States in the management of waterfowl populations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “Migratory Bird Conservation Commission” means that commission established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s715a">section 715a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “migratory birds” means all wild birds native to North America that are in an unconfined state and that are protected under the Migratory Bird Treaty Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.], including ducks, geese, and swans of the family Anatidae, species listed as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), and species defined as nongame under the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2901–291">16 U.S.C. 2901–291</ref>2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “Plan” means the North American Waterfowl Management Plan signed by the Minister of the Environment for Canada and the Secretary of the Interior for the United States in May 1986, and by the Secretary of Sedesol for Mexico in 1994, and subsequent dates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “State” means the State fish and wildlife agency, which shall be construed to mean any department, or any division of any department of another name, of a State that is empowered under its laws to exercise the functions ordinarily exercised by a State fish and wildlife agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ee54f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> The term “wetlands conservation project” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ee54f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the obtaining of a real property interest in lands or waters, including water rights, of a wetland ecosystem and associated habitat if the obtaining of such interest is subject to terms and conditions that will ensure that the real property will be administered for the long-term conservation of such lands and waters and the migratory birds and other fish and wildlife dependent thereon;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ee54fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the restoration, management, or enhancement of wetland ecosystems and associated habitat for migratory birds and other fish and wildlife species if such restoration, management, or enhancement is conducted on lands and waters that are administered for the long-term conservation of such lands and waters and the migratory birds and other fish and wildlife dependent thereon; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ee54fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4402/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of projects undertaken in Mexico, includes technical training and development of infrastructure necessary for the conservation and management of wetlands and studies on the sustainable use of wetland resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id79ee54fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/233/s3">Pub. L. 101–233, § 3</ref>, <date date="1989-12-13">Dec. 13, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1969">103 Stat. 1969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/308">Pub. L. 107–308</ref>, §§ 4, 8(a)(3)–(5), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2446">116 Stat. 2446</ref>, 2447.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79ee54fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79ee54fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79ee54ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Migratory Bird Treaty Act, referred to in par. (5), is <ref href="/us/act/1918-07-03/ch128">act July 3, 1918, ch. 128</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/755">40 Stat. 755</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 703 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s710">section 710 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Endangered Species Act of 1973, referred to in par. (5), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/205">Pub. L. 93–205</ref>, <date date="1973-12-28">Dec. 28, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/884">87 Stat. 884</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 1531 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Act of 1980, referred to in par. (5), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/366">Pub. L. 96–366</ref>, <date date="1980-09-29">Sept. 29, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1322">94 Stat. 1322</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 49 (§ 2901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2901">section 2901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79ee5500-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/308/s8/a/3">Pub. L. 107–308, § 8(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives” for “Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the United States House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/107/308/s8/a/4">Pub. L. 107–308, § 8(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “of 1973” after “Endangered Species Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/107/308/s8/a/5">Pub. L. 107–308, § 8(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “, and by the Secretary of Sedesol for Mexico in 1994, and subsequent dates” after “1986”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/308/s4/1">Pub. L. 107–308, § 4(1)</ref>, inserted “of a wetland ecosystem and associated habitat” after “including water rights,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/308/s4/2">Pub. L. 107–308, § 4(2)</ref>, substituted “and associated habitat” for “and other habitat”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79ee5501-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id79ee5502-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Resources of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
