<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id779c9cdc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s441o"><num value="441o">§ 441o.</num><heading> Facilities for interpretation of park and history of Sioux Nation; conveyance of reservation lands; submission of terms to Congressional committees</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oglala Sioux Tribe may convey and the Secretary of the Interior may acquire not to exceed forty acres of tribally owned lands on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation for the purpose of erecting thereon permanent facilities to be used to interpret the natural phenomena of the park and the history of the Sioux Nation: <i>Provided</i>, That no such conveyance shall be made until sixty days after the terms thereof have been submitted to the Interior and Insular Affairs Committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id779c9cdd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/468/s6">Pub. L. 90–468, § 6</ref>, <date date="1968-08-08">Aug. 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/666">82 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/tVI/s611">Pub. L. 95–625, title VI, § 611</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3521">92 Stat. 3521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id779c9cde-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id779c9cdf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id779c9ce0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Word “park” substituted in text for “monument” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/s611">Pub. L. 95–625, § 611</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s441e–1">section 441e–1 of this title</ref> and which redesignated Badlands National Monument as Badlands National Park.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the Senate abolished and replaced by Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, effective <date date="1977-02-11">Feb. 11, 1977</date>. See Rule XXV of Standing Rules of the Senate, as amended by Senate Resolution No. 4 (popularly cited as the “Committee System Reorganization Amendments of 1977”), approved <date date="1977-02-04">Feb. 4, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
