<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77a3c863-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s450ii"><num value="450ii">§ 450ii.</num><heading> Joshua Tree National Monument; revision of boundaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Joshua Tree National Monument, in the State of California, established by Proclamation Numbered 2193, of <date date="1936-08-10">August 10, 1936</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/50/1760">50 Stat. 1760</ref>), after <date date="1950-09-25">September 25, 1950</date>, shall comprise the following-described area:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered"><inline class="small-caps">san bernardino meridian</inline></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Township 1 south, range 5 east, sections 22 to 27, inclusive, and sections 34 to 36, inclusive; township 2 south, range 5 east, portion of east half lying north of the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct but excluding therefrom that portion of the Long Canyon Camp and dump area in section 27; township 1 south, range 6 east, sections 19 to 36, inclusive; township 2 south, range 6 east, sections 1 to 30, inclusive, that portion of section 31 lying north of the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct, and sections 32 to 36, inclusive; township 3 south, range 6 east, portion lying north of the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct but excluding therefrom that portion of the Deception Camp and dump area in section 14, that portion of the West Deception Camp and dump area in section 10, and the portions of the East Wide Canyon Camps and dump areas in sections 5 and 6; township 1 south, range 7 east, sections 1 to 4, inclusive, and 9 to 15, inclusive, unsurveyed, section 16, sections 19 to 23, inclusive, section 24, unsurveyed, and sections 25 to 36, inclusive; township 2 south, range 7 east; township 3 south, range 7 east, portion lying north of the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct but excluding therefrom that portion of the Fan Hill Camp and dump area in section 20; township 1 south, range 8 east, partly unsurveyed; townships 2 and 3 south, range 8 east; township 1 south, range 9 east, sections 5 to 9, inclusive, sections 16 to 23, inclusive, and sections 26 to 35, inclusive; township 2 south, range 9 east, sections 2 to 11, inclusive, and sections 14 to 36, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 3 south, range 9 east; township 4 south, range 9 east; sections 1 to 5, inclusive, and sections 11 to 14, inclusive; township 2 south, range 10 east, sections 25 to 36, inclusive, unsurveyed; township 3 south, range 10 east, partly unsurveyed; township 4 south, range 10 east, sections 1 to 18, inclusive, sections 22 to 26, inclusive, and sections 35 and 36; township 5 south, range 10 east, section 1; township 2 south, range 11 east, sections 25 to 36, inclusive, unsurveyed; townships 3 and 4 south, range 11 east, partly unsurveyed; township 5 south, range 11 east, sections 1 to 18, inclusive, sections 22 to 27, inclusive, and sections 34, 35, and 36; township 6 south, range 11 east, portion of sections 1, 2, and 3 lying north of north transmission line right-of-way which is adjacent to the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct but excluding therefrom the Aggregate Deposit in section 3; township 2 south, range 12 east, section 13 and sections 23 to 36, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; townships 3 and 4 south, range 12 east, partly unsurveyed; township 5 south, range 12 east, sections 1 to 24, inclusive, and sections 26 to 34, inclusive, partly unsurveyed, and portions of sections 25 and 35 lying north of north transmission line right-of-way which is adjacent to the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct; township 6 south, range 12 east, portions of sections 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 10, lying north of north transmission line right-of-way which is adjacent to the north right-of-way line of the Colorado River aqueduct but excluding therefrom the Bumpani’s Aggregate Deposit in section 4; township 2 south, range 13 east, sections 1 and 2 and sections 7 to 36, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 3 south, range 13 east, sections 1 to 18, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 5 south, range 13 east, sections 6, 7, 18, and 19, unsurveyed; township 1 south, range 14 east, sections 33 to 36, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 2 south, range 14 east, partly unsurveyed; township 3 south, range 14 east, sections 1 to 18, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 1 south, range 15 east, sections 31 to 35, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 2 south, range 15 east, sections 2 to 36, inclusive, partly unsurveyed; township 3 south, range 15 east, sections 1 to 12, inclusive, partly unsurveyed, and section 18, unsurveyed; township 2 south, range 16 east, sections 18, 19, 30, and 31, unsurveyed; and township 3 south, range 16 east, sections 6 and 7 unsurveyed. Also, all that portion of the south half of the northeast quarter and of the north half of the southeast quarter of section 33, township 1 north, range 9 east, San Bernardino base and meridian, in the county of San Bernardino, State of California, shown on map titled “Record of Survey” by H. F. Cameron, Junior, licensed engineer 6826, dated <date date="1948-12-29">December 29, 1948</date>, and James B. Hommon, licensed engineer 6916, dated <date date="1949-10-05">October 5, 1949</date>, and made for the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and recorded <date date="1949-10-17">October 17, 1949</date>, in volume 7, page 72, of the official records of the county of San Bernardino, said land being described as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Beginning at the United States Government Land Office monument marked as the east quarter corner of said section 33, thence proceeding on a true bearing south 89 degrees 02 minutes 10 seconds west a distance of 50.01 feet to the true point of beginning of the hereinafter described parcel of land;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Thence north 0 degrees 02 minutes 55 seconds west a distance of 250.08 feet to a point of curve; thence along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 20.00 feet a distance of 31.73 feet to a point of tangency; thence south 89 degrees 02 minutes 40 seconds west a distance of 2,559.24 feet; thence south 0 degrees 19 minutes 50 seconds east a distance of 270.76 feet;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Thence south 0 degrees 21 minutes 02 seconds east a distance of 409.32 feet to the beginning of a curve; thence along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 280.98 feet a distance of 275.93 feet to a point of compound curvature; thence along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 800.00 feet a distance of 753.98 feet to a point of tangency; thence north 69 degrees 22 minutes 58 seconds east a distance of 125.31 feet to the beginning of a curve;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Thence along the arc of a curve to the right having a radius of 1,400.00 feet a distance of 1.042.74 feet to a point of tangency; thence south 67 degrees 56 minutes 33 seconds east a distance of 94.55 feet to the beginning of a curve; thence along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 700.00 feet a distance of 366.52 feet to a point of compound curvature;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Thence along the arc of a curve to the left having a radius of 167.60 feet a distance of 240.17 feet to a point of tangency; thence north 0 degrees 02 minutes 55 seconds west a distance of 648.91 feet to the point of beginning containing 57.839 acres, more or less.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77a3c864-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-25/ch1030/s1">Sept. 25, 1950, ch. 1030, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1033">64 Stat. 1033</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/80">Pub. L. 87–80</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/197">75 Stat. 197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77a3c865-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77a3c866-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77a3c867-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/80">Pub. L. 87–80</ref> included within the boundaries of Joshua Tree National Monument certain federally owned lands situate in county of San Bernardino, California.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77a3c868-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77a3c869-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Joshua Tree National Monument</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Joshua Tree National Monument abolished and incorporated in Joshua Tree National Park, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410aaa–22">section 410aaa–22 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
