<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77a3c87a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s450jj"><num value="450jj">§ 450jj.</num><heading> Jefferson National Expansion Memorial; authorization</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be constructed by the Secretary of the Interior upon the Jefferson National Expansion Memorial National Historic Site,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002263">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002263"><num>1</num> See Change of Name note below.</note> Saint Louis, Missouri, an appropriate national memorial to those persons who made possible the territorial expansion of the United States, including President Thomas Jefferson and his aides, Livingston and Monroe, who negotiated the Louisiana Purchase, the great explorers, Lewis and Clark, and the hardy hunters, trappers, frontiersmen, pioneers, and others who contributed to such expansion.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77a3c87b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-05-17/ch204/s1">May 17, 1954, ch. 204, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/98">68 Stat. 98</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77a3c87c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77a3c87d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77a3c87e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Jefferson National Expansion Memorial redesignated Gateway Arch National Park by <ref href="/us/pl/115/128/s2">Pub. L. 115–128, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-02-22">Feb. 22, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/328">132 Stat. 328</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s450jj–10">section 450jj–10 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id77a3c87f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2018 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/128/s1">Pub. L. 115–128, § 1</ref>, <date date="2018-02-22">Feb. 22, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/328">132 Stat. 328</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/128/s1">“This Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s450jj–10">section 450jj–10 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Gateway Arch National Park Designation Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id77a3c880-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/398/tII/s203">Pub. L. 98–398, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1984-08-24">Aug. 24, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1472">98 Stat. 1472</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/398/tII/s203">“This title [enacting sections 450jj–3 to 450jj–9 of this title, enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s450jj–3">section 450jj–3 of this title</ref>, and amending provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Amendments Act of 1984’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77a3c881-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Disposition of Funds Received by National Park Service as Reimbursement for Costs Incurred</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/h/tI/s100">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title I, § 100]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–251, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tI/s100">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title I, § 100]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–251, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tI/s100">“That notwithstanding any other provision of law, hereafter funds received by the National Park Service as reimbursement for the cost of providing security, law enforcement, interpretive, and other services with respect to the operation of facilities at the Jefferson National Expansion Memorial National Historic Site [now Gateway Arch National Park] shall be credited to the appropriation bearing the cost of providing such services.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77a3c882-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization of Appropriations; Federal and Non-Federal Ratio of Expenditures</heading><p>Section 11, formerly section 4, of act <date date="1954-05-17">May 17, 1954</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/85/936">Pub. L. 85–936</ref>, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1794">72 Stat. 1794</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/269">Pub. L. 89–269</ref>, <date date="1965-10-19">Oct. 19, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/991">79 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/578/tII/s201/6">Pub. L. 94–578, title II, § 201(6)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2733">90 Stat. 2733</ref>; and renumbered § 11 and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/398/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 98–398, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-24">Aug. 24, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1471">98 Stat. 1471</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/355/s1/3">Pub. L. 102–355, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/947">106 Stat. 947</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/355/s1/3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $32,750,000 to carry out the purposes of this Act [sections 450jj to 450jj–9 of this title]: <i>Provided</i>, That funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act shall be expended by the United States for construction of the memorial in the ratio of $3 of Federal funds for each $1 of money contributed hereafter by the city of Saint Louis or other non-Federal source for purposes of the memorial, and for such purposes the Secretary is authorized to accept from the said city or other non-Federal sources, and to utilize for purposes of this Act, any money so contributed: <i>Provided further</i>, That the value of any land hereafter contributed by the city of Saint Louis shall be excluded from the computation of the city’s share.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purposes of the East St. Louis portion of the memorial, there are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for land acquisition and, subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3), such sums as may be necessary for development: <i>Provided</i>, That such authorization shall not include any sums for the acquisition, removal, or relocation of the grain elevator and business located within the East St. Louis unit of the Memorial. Such development shall be consistent with the level of development described in phase one of the draft Development and Management Plan and Environmental Assessment, East St. Louis Addition to Jefferson National Expansion Memorial—Illinois/Missouri, dated August 1987.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Federal funds expended under paragraph (1) for development may not exceed 75 percent of the actual cost of such development. The remaining share of such actual costs shall be provided from non-Federal funds, services, or materials, or a combination thereof, fairly valued as determined by the Secretary. Any non-Federal expenditures for the acquisition, removal, or relocation of the grain elevator and business shall be included as part of the non-Federal cost share: <i>Provided</i>, That credit shall not be given for any such expenditures which exceed the cost of acquisition, removal, or relocation of the grain elevator and business located within the East St. Louis unit of the Memorial if such action had been accomplished by the Federal Government as determined by the Secretary under existing law: <i>Provided further</i>, That only those non-Federal funds expended at least sixty days after the transmission of the report referred to in paragraph (3) for the removal of such grain elevator shall be credited towards the non-Federal cost share. For the purposes of this paragraph, the Secretary may accept and utilize for such purposes any non-Federal funds, services, and materials so contributed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Within one year after the date of enactment of this paragraph [<date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>], the Secretary, in direct consultation with the city of East St. Louis, Gateway Arch Park Expansion, and the Southwestern Illinois Development Authority, shall develop and transmit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs [now Committee on Natural Resources] of the United States House of Representatives a study of alternatives to, and costs associated with, the removal of the grain elevator located within the East St. Louis unit of the Memorial. The study shall contain, but need not be limited to, at least one alternative which would incorporate and retain the existing grain elevator into the draft development and management plan and environmental assessment referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Funds appropriated under subsection (b) of this section shall remain available until expended.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
