<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77a883d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459a–1"><num value="459a–1">§ 459a–1.</num><heading> Administration, protection, and development; commercial fishing by residents; hunting</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The administration, protection, and development of the aforesaid national seashore recreational area shall be exercised under the direction of the Secretary of the Interior by the National Park Service, subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>), entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002275">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002275"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> as amended: <i>Provided</i>, That except as hereinafter provided nothing herein shall be construed to divest the jurisdiction of other agencies of the Government exercised on <date date="1937-08-17">August 17, 1937</date>, over Federal-owned lands within the area of the said Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area: <i>Provided further</i>, That the provisions of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.], shall not apply to this national seashore recreational area: <i>And provided further</i>, That the legal residents of villages referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s459">section 459 of this title</ref> shall have the right to earn a livelihood by fishing within the boundaries to be designated by the Secretary of the Interior, subject to such rules and regulations as the said Secretary may deem necessary in order to protect the area for recreational use as provided for in sections 459 to 459a–3 of this title: <i>And provided further</i>, That hunting shall be permitted, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior in conformity with the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of <date date="1918-07-03">July 3, 1918</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/40/755">40 Stat. 755</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.], as follows: (a) Upon the waters of the sounds included within the national seashore recreational area, (b) in the area north of the Currituck County line, (c) on Ocracoke Island, and (d) within not more than two thousand acres of land in the remaining portion of said national seashore recreational area, as shall be designated by the Secretary of the Interior; except on lands and waters included in any existing or future wildlife or migratory bird refuge and adjacent closed waters.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77a883d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-08-17/ch687/s3">Aug. 17, 1937, ch. 687, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/670">50 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-06-29/ch459">June 29, 1940, ch. 459</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/54/702">54 Stat. 702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77a883d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77a883d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77a883da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>), entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Act, referred to in text, was in the original the “Act of <date date="1920-06-10">June 10, 1920</date>, known as the Federal Water Power Act,” and was redesignated as the Federal Power Act by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref>. The Federal Power Act is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">act June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>, and is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Migratory Bird Treaty Act of <date date="1918-07-03">July 3, 1918</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1918-07-03/ch128">act July 3, 1918, ch. 128</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/755">40 Stat. 755</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 703 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s710">section 710 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77a883db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77a883dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “national seashore recreational area” substituted in text for “national seashore” pursuant to act <date date="1940-06-29">June 29, 1940</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77a883dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dB/tXXX/s3057">Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3057</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3813">128 Stat. 3813</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dB/tXXX/s3057">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final rule</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Final Rule’ means the final rule entitled ‘Special Regulations, Areas of the National Park System, Cape Hatteras National Seashore—Off-Road Vehicle Management’ (77 Fed. Reg. 3123 (<date date="2012-01-23">January 23, 2012</date>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National seashore</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘National Seashore’ means the Cape Hatteras National Seashore Recreational Area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ means the State of North Carolina.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review and Adjustment of Wildlife Protection Buffers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>], the Secretary shall review and modify wildlife buffers in the National Seashore in accordance with this subsection and any other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Buffer modifications</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In modifying wildlife buffers under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, using adaptive management practices—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> ensure that the buffers are of the shortest duration and cover the smallest area necessary to protect a species, as determined in accordance with peer-reviewed scientific data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> designate pedestrian and vehicle corridors around areas of the National Seashore closed because of wildlife buffers, to allow access to areas that are open.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination with state</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, after coordinating with the State, shall determine appropriate buffer protections for species that are not listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.), but that are identified for protection under State law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modifications to Final Rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall undertake a public process to consider, consistent with management requirements at the National Seashore, the following changes to the Final Rule:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Opening beaches at the National Seashore that are closed to night driving restrictions, by opening beach segments each morning on a rolling basis as daily management reviews are completed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Extending seasonal off-road vehicle routes for additional periods in the Fall and Spring if off-road vehicle use would not create resource management problems at the National Seashore.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Modifying the size and location of vehicle-free areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction of New Vehicle Access Points</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall construct new vehicle access points and roads at the National Seashore—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> as expeditiously as practicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in accordance with applicable management plans for the National Seashore.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall report to Congress within 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>] on measures taken to implement this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77a883de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77a883df-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
