<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77aacd54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459c–1"><num value="459c–1">§ 459c–1.</num><heading> Description of area</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77aacd55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459c–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Boundary map; availability; publication in Federal Register</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Point Reyes National Seashore shall consist of the lands, waters, and submerged lands generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Point Reyes National Seashore”, numbered 612–80,008–E and dated May 1978, plus those areas depicted on the map entitled “Point Reyes and GGNRA Amendments, dated <date date="1979-10-25">October 25, 1979</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The map referred to in this section shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, Washington, District of Columbia. After advising the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate in writing, the Secretary may make minor revisions of the boundaries of the Point Reyes National Seashore when necessary by publication of a revised drawing or other boundary description in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77aacd56-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459c–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Bear Valley Ranch right-of-way</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The area referred to in subsection (a) shall also include a right-of-way to the aforesaid tract in the general vicinity of the northwesterly portion of the property known as “Bear Valley Ranch”, to be selected by the Secretary, of not more than four hundred feet in width, together with such adjoining lands as would be deprived of access by reason of the acquisition of such right-of-way.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77aacd57-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/657/s2">Pub. L. 87–657, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-09-13">Sept. 13, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/538">76 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/666/s1/a">Pub. L. 89–666, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/919">80 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/550/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–550, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1974-12-26">Dec. 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1744">88 Stat. 1744</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/tIII/s318/a">Pub. L. 95–625, title III, § 318(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3486">92 Stat. 3486</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/199/tI/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 96–199, title I, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-05">Mar. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/67">94 Stat. 67</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s6/d/16">Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(16)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4584">108 Stat. 4584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77aacd58-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77aacd59-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77aacd5a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committee on”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/199">Pub. L. 96–199</ref> inserted “, plus those areas depicted on the map entitled ‘Point Reyes and GGNRA Amendments, dated <date date="1979-10-25">October 25, 1979</date>’ ” after “dated May 1978”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/625">Pub. L. 95–625</ref> substituted as a description of the area the lands generally depicted on Boundary Map numbered 612–80,008–E and dated May 1978 for prior such depiction on Boundary Map numbered 612–80,008–B, and dated August 1974; included submerged lands in the description; made the map specifically available in the Washington, District of Columbia, Office; and authorized minor revisions of boundaries and publication thereof in the Federal Register after advising Congressional committees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/550">Pub. L. 93–550</ref> substituted as a boundary description Boundary Map No. 612–80,008–B, and dated August 1974, on file in the office of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, for a boundary map designated NS–PR–7001, dated <date date="1960-06-01">June 1, 1960</date>, on file with the Director of the National Park Service, Washington, D.C., and all measurements relating thereto.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/666">Pub. L. 89–666</ref> inserted “to the aforesaid tract in the general vicinity of the northwesterly portion of the property known as ‘Bear Valley Ranch’ ” after “right-of-way”, struck out “from the intersection of Sir Francis Drake Boulevard and Haggerty Gulch” after “aforesaid tract” and included such adjoining lands as would be deprived of access by reason of the right-of-way.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
