<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77afaf5d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4"><num value="459g–4">§ 459g–4.</num><heading> Administration; public outdoor recreation and enjoyment; utilization of authorities for conservation and development of natural resources</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf5e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary shall administer the Cape Lookout National Seashore for the general purposes of public outdoor recreation, including conservation of natural features contributing to public enjoyment. In the administration of the seashore and the administrative site, the Secretary may utilize such statutory authorities relating to areas administered and supervised by the Secretary through the National Park Service and such statutory authorities otherwise available to him for the conservation and management of natural resources as he deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of sections 459g to 459g–7 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf5f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf60-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, in accordance with this subsection, shall allow a herd of not less than 110 free roaming horses, with a target population of between 120 and 130 free roaming horses, in Cape Lookout National Seashore (hereinafter referred to as the “Seashore”): <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the Secretary from implementing or enforcing the provisions of paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf61-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Within 180 days after <date date="1998-07-16">July 16, 1998</date>, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the Foundation for Shackleford Horses (a nonprofit corporation established under the laws of the State of North Carolina), or another qualified nonprofit entity, to provide for management of free roaming horses in the seashore. The agreement shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77afaf62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide for cost-effective management of the horses while ensuring that natural resources within the seashore are not adversely impacted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77afaf63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> allow the authorized entity to adopt any of those horses that the Secretary removes from the seashore.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall not remove, assist in, or permit the removal of any free roaming horses from Federal lands within the boundaries of the seashore—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77afaf65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> unless the entity with whom the Secretary has entered into the agreement under paragraph (2), following notice and a 90-day response period, fails to meet the terms and conditions of the agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77afaf66-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> unless removal is carried out as part of a plan to maintain the viability of the herd; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77afaf67-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> except in the case of an emergency, or to protect public health and safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf68-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall annually monitor, assess, and make available to the public findings regarding the population, structure, and health of the free roaming horses in the national seashore.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf69-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Secretary to replace horses or otherwise increase the number of horses within the boundaries of the seashore where the herd numbers fall below 110 as a result of natural causes, including, but not limited to, disease or natural disasters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77afaf6a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459g–4/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as creating liability for the United States for any damages caused by the free roaming horses to property located inside or outside the boundaries of the seashore.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77afaf6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/366/s5">Pub. L. 89–366, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-03-10">Mar. 10, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/35">80 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/202/s2">Pub. L. 105–202, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-07-16">July 16, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/676">112 Stat. 676</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/229/s1">Pub. L. 105–229, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-08-13">Aug. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1517">112 Stat. 1517</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1</ref>, <date date="2005-12-01">Dec. 1, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2526">119 Stat. 2526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77afaf6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77afaf6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77afaf6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “(a)” after “(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1/b/2">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, struck out the subsec. (b) added by <ref href="/us/pl/105/229">Pub. L. 105–229</ref>, which was identical to the subsec. (b) added by <ref href="/us/pl/105/202">Pub. L. 105–202</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “not less than 110 free roaming horses, with a target population of between 120 and 130 free roaming horses,” for “100 free roaming horses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1/a/2">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “unless the number of free roaming horses on Federal lands within Cape Lookout National Seashore exceeds 110; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/117/s1/a/3">Pub. L. 109–117, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “110” for “100”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/229">Pub. L. 105–229</ref> directed an amendment identical to that in <ref href="/us/pl/105/202">Pub. L. 105–202</ref> resulting in the insertion of “(a)” before “(a)” in subsec. (a) and the addition of a second, identical subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/202">Pub. L. 105–202</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
