<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77b1f9b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459h–6"><num value="459h–6">§ 459h–6.</num><heading> Transfer of Horn Island and Petit Bois National Wildlife Refuges from National Wildlife Refuge System; administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77b1f9b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459h–6/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> There are hereby transferred from the National Wildlife Refuge System to the seashore the Horn Island and Petit Bois National Wildlife Refuges to be administered in accordance with the provisions of sections 459h to 459h–10 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77b1f9b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s459h–6/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If any of the Federal land on Santa Rosa or Okaloosa Island, Florida, under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense is ever excess to the needs of the Armed Forces, the Secretary of Defense shall transfer the excess land to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, subject to the terms and conditions acceptable to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Defense. The Secretary of the Interior shall administer the transferred land as part of the seashore in accordance with the provisions of sections 459h to 459h–10 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77b1f9b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/660/s7">Pub. L. 91–660, § 7</ref>, <date date="1971-01-08">Jan. 8, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1969">84 Stat. 1969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dB/tXXVIII/s2872/b">Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2872(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3535">119 Stat. 3535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77b1f9b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77b1f9b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77b1f9b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77b1f9b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77b1f9ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Excess Department of Defense Property on Santa Rosa and Okaloosa Island, Florida, to Gulf Islands National Seashore</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dB/tXXVIII/s2872/a">Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2872(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3534">119 Stat. 3534</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/163/dB/tXXVIII/s2872/a">
<inline>“Congress finds the following:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> <ref href="/us/pl/91/660">Public Law 91–660</ref> of the 91st Congress [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s459h">16 U.S.C. 459h</ref> et seq.] established the Gulf Islands National Seashore in the States of Florida and Mississippi.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The original boundaries of the Gulf Islands National Seashore encompassed certain Federal land used by the Air Force and the Navy, and the use of such land was still required by the Armed Forces when the seashore was established.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Senate Report 91–1514 of the 91th Congress addressed the relationship between these military lands and the Gulf Islands National Seashore as follows: ‘While the military use of these lands is presently required, they remain virtually free of adverse development and they are included in the boundaries of the seashore so that they can be wholly or partially transferred to the Department of the Interior when they become excess to the needs of the Air Force.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Although <ref href="/us/pl/91/660/s2/a">section 2(a) of Public Law 91–660</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s459h–1/a">16 U.S.C. 459h–1(a)</ref>) authorized the eventual transfer of Federal land within the boundaries of the Gulf Islands National Seashore from the Department of Defense to the Secretary of the Interior, an amendment mandating the transfer of excess Department of Defense land on Santa Rosa and Okaloosa Island, Florida, to the Secretary of the Interior is required to ensure that the purposes of the Gulf Islands National Seashore are fulfilled.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
