<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77f25dcc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bbb–7"><num value="460bbb–7">§ 460bbb–7.</num><heading> Management planning</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall revise the document entitled “Smith River National Recreation Area Management Plan” dated February 1990 to conform to the provisions of this subchapter, and such revised plan shall guide management of the recreation area and shall be incorporated in its entirety into the forest plan for the Six Rivers National Forest. This incorporation shall not be deemed a revision or amendment to the forest plan for purposes of the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002359">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002359"><num>1</num> So in original. Word “the” probably should not appear.</note> <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">section 1604 of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall make such further revisions to the management plan as are necessary in order to include more specific development and use plans for the recreation areas. Such revisions shall be made no later than 5 years after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>. Such revisions and any other modifications of the management plan shall be made only through the processes of revision or amendment of the forest plan pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">section 1604 of this title</ref>, including appropriate consultation with State and local government officials and provision for full public participation considering the views of all interested parties, organizations, and individuals.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77f25dcd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/612/s9">Pub. L. 101–612, § 9</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3214">104 Stat. 3214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77f25dce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77f25dcf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77f25dd0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/101/612">Pub. L. 101–612</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3209">104 Stat. 3209</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460bbb">section 460bbb of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77f25dd1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77f25dd2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Management</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/612/s10/c">Pub. L. 101–612, § 10(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3219">104 Stat. 3219</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/612/s10/c">“The management plan prepared under section 9 of this Act [this section] shall be deemed to satisfy the requirement for a comprehensive management plan required under section 3(d)(1) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1274/d/1">section 1274(d)(1) of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
