<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d81f24-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3"><num value="460bb–3">§ 460bb–3.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f25-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Provisions applicable; utilization of authorities for conservation and management of wildlife and natural resources; provisions applicable to Muir Woods National Monument and Fort Point National Historic Site</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the lands, waters and interests therein acquired for the recreation area in accordance with the provisions of the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1">16 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 2–4),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002319">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002319"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> as amended and supplemented, and the Secretary may utilize such statutory authority available to him for the conservation and management of wildlife and natural resources as he deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. Notwithstanding their inclusion within the boundaries of the recreation area, the Muir Woods National Monument and Fort Point National Historic Site shall continue to be administered as distinct and identifiable units of the national park system in accordance with the laws applicable to such monument and historic site.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f26-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal-State cooperative agreements for police and fire protection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with any Federal agency, the State of California, or any political subdivision thereof, for the rendering, on a reimbursable basis, of rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement and fire preventive assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f27-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Water resource developments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority of the Army to undertake or contribute to water resource developments, including shore erosion control, beach protection, and navigation improvements on land and/or waters within the recreation area shall be exercised in accordance with plans which are mutually acceptable to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army and which are consistent with both the purpose of this subchapter and the purpose of existing statutes dealing with water and related resource development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f28-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transportation system; study for coordinated public and private system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in cooperation with the State of California and affected political subdivisions thereof, local and regional transit agencies, and the Secretaries of Transportation and of the Army, shall make a study for a coordinated public and private transportation system to and within the recreation area and other units of the national park system in Marin and San Francisco Counties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f29-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees or admission charges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No fees or admission charges shall be levied for admission of the general public to the recreation area except to portions under lease or permit for a particular and limited purpose authorized by the Secretary. The Secretary may authorize reasonable charges for public transportation and for admission to the sailing vessel Balclutha and other historic vessels of the National Maritime Museum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d81f2a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain rental proceeds; crediting; management contract</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, in the administration of those parcels of property known as Haslett Warehouse, Cliff House Properties and Louis’ Restaurant, the Secretary shall credit any proceeds from the rental of space in the aforementioned properties to the appropriation, if any, bearing the cost of their administration, maintenance, repair and related expenses and also for the maintenance, repair and related expenses of the vessels and the adjacent piers comprising the San Francisco Maritime National Historical Park, and for major renovation and park rehabilitation of those buildings included in the Fort Mason Foundation Cooperative Agreement: <i>Provided</i>, That surplus funds, if any, will be deposited into the Treasury of the United States: <i>Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the administration of said parcels and of the AFDL–38 Drydock or other vessels or heavy marine equipment, the Secretary may, if he deems appropriate, enter into a contract for the management (including rental or lease) of said properties with such terms and conditions as will protect the Government’s interest, with excess funds being used as set forth above.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d81f2b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/589/s4">Pub. L. 92–589, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1302">86 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/tIII/s317/f">Pub. L. 95–625, title III, § 317(f)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3486">92 Stat. 3486</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/395">Pub. L. 99–395</ref>, §§ 1, 2(a), <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/836">100 Stat. 836</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/348/s6">Pub. L. 100–348, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-06-27">June 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/657">102 Stat. 657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77d81f2c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77d81f2d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77d81f2e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1">16 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 2–4), referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77d81f2f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/348">Pub. L. 100–348</ref> substituted “San Francisco Maritime National Historical Park” for “National Maritime Museum”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/395/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–395, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted “and for admission to the sailing vessel Balclutha and other historic vessels of the National Maritime Museum” for “and, for a period not exceeding five years from <date date="1978-11-10">November 10, 1978</date>, for admission to the sailing vessel Balclutha”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/395/s1">Pub. L. 99–395, § 1</ref>, struck out provision which had included a coordinated public and private access system to and within the recreation area and other units of the national park system in Marin and San Francisco Counties among the allowable uses to which rental proceeds from Haslett Warehouse, Cliff House Properties and Louis’ Restaurant were to be put, inserted in second proviso a reference to the administration of the AFDL–38 Drydock and other vessels or heavy marine equipment, and inserted parenthetical in second proviso to include rental or lease of properties under management contracts into which the Secretary may enter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/625">Pub. L. 95–625</ref> added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77d81f30-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77d81f31-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fort Baker Agreements and Leases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dF/tI/s114">Pub. L. 108–7, div. F, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/239">117 Stat. 239</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/54/tI/s131">Pub. L. 109–54, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/525">119 Stat. 525</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/54/tI/s131">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior hereafter has ongoing authority to negotiate and enter into agreements and leases, without regard to section 321 of chapter 314 of the Act of <date date="1932-06-30">June 30, 1932</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s303b">40 U.S.C. 303b</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s1302">40 U.S.C. 1302</ref>], with any person, firm, association, organization, corporation, or governmental entity, for all or part of the property within Fort Baker administered by the Secretary as part of the Golden Gate National Recreation Area. In furtherance of a lease entered into under the first sentence, the Secretary of the Interior or a lessee may impose fees on overnight lodgers for the purpose of covering the cost of providing utilities and transportation services at Fort Baker properties at a rate not to exceed the annual cost of providing these services. The proceeds of the agreements or leases or any statutorily authorized fees, hereafter shall be retained by the Secretary and such proceeds shall remain available until expended, without further appropriation, for the preservation, restoration, operation, maintenance, interpretation, public programs, and related expenses of the National Park Service and nonprofit park partners incurred with respect to Fort Baker properties, including utility expenses of the National Park Service or lessees of the National Park Service.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/291/tI/s115">Pub. L. 106–291, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2000-10-11">Oct. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/943">114 Stat. 943</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tI/s121">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I, § 121]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–159.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77d81f32-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fort Baker Golden Gate National Recreation Area; Tax and Special Assessment Exemption</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tI/s120">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I, § 120]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–159, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/88/dA/tI/s123">Pub. L. 111–88, div. A, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="2009-10-30">Oct. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2932">123 Stat. 2932</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/88/dA/tI/s123">“All properties administered by the National Park Service at Fort Baker, Golden Gate National Recreation Area, and leases, concessions, permits and other agreements associated with those properties, hereafter shall be exempt from all taxes and special assessments, except sales tax, by the State of California and its political subdivisions, including the County of Marin and the City of Sausalito.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/e/tI/s150">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title I, § 150]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-231">112 Stat. 2681–231</ref>, 2681–268.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77d81f33-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fees or Admission Charges; Moneys Collected Since <date date="1983-11-10">November 10, 1983</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/395/s2/b">Pub. L. 99–395, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/836">100 Stat. 836</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/395/s2/b">“Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, moneys collected pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1972-10-27/s4/e">section 4(e) of the Act of October 27, 1972</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460bb–3">16 U.S.C. 460bb–3</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/92/3486">92 Stat. 3486</ref>), since <date date="1983-11-10">November 10, 1983</date>, shall be deemed to have been collected in accordance with such section as amended by this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
