<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d81f8a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460dd"><num value="460dd">§ 460dd.</num><heading> Establishment; boundaries; publication in Federal Register</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77d81f8b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460dd/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In order to provide for public outdoor recreation use and enjoyment of Lake Powell and lands adjacent thereto in the States of Arizona and Utah and to preserve scenic, scientific, and historic features contributing to public enjoyment of the area, there is established the Glen Canyon National Recreation Area (hereafter referred to as the “recreation area”) to comprise the area generally depicted on the drawing entitled “Boundary Map Glen Canyon National Recreation Area,” numbered GLC–91,006 and dated August 1972, which is on file and available for public inspection in the office of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may revise the boundaries of the recreation area from time to time by publication in the Federal Register of a revised drawing or other boundary description, but the total acreage of the national recreation area may not exceed 1,256,000 acres.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77da8f8c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460dd/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In addition to the boundary change authority under subsection (a), the Secretary may acquire approximately 152 acres of private land in exchange for approximately 370 acres of land within the boundary of Glen Canyon National Recreation Area, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Page One Land Exchange Proposal”, number 608/60573a–2002, and dated <date date="2002-05-16">May 16, 2002</date>. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service. Upon conclusion of the exchange, the boundary of the recreation area shall be revised to reflect the exchange.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77da8f8d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/593/s1">Pub. L. 92–593, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1311">86 Stat. 1311</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/43/s2">Pub. L. 108–43, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-07-01">July 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/841">117 Stat. 841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77da8f8e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77da8f8f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77da8f90-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/43">Pub. L. 108–43</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), substituted “1,256,000 acres” for “one million two hundred and thirty-six thousand eight hundred and eighty acres”, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77da8f91-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id77da8f92-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/43/s1">Pub. L. 108–43, § 1</ref>, <date date="2003-07-01">July 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/841">117 Stat. 841</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/43/s1">“This Act [amending this section] may be cited as the ‘Glen Canyon National Recreation Area Boundary Revision Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
