<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77f4cec9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1"><num value="460fff–1">§ 460fff–1.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f4ceca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the recreation area in accordance with applicable provisions of this Act and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1">16 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 2–4),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002365">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002365"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and the Act of <date date="1946-08-07">August 7, 1946</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/60/885">60 Stat. 885</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002365">1</ref> In the administration of such recreation area, the Secretary may utilize such statutory authority as may be available to him for the protection of natural and cultural resources as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to amend or alter the responsibilities of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, under any applicable treaty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f4cecb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance with treaties and other commitments or agreements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The administration of the recreation area by the Secretary shall be subject to and in accordance with all applicable treaties, including the treaty between the United States and Mexico relating to the utilization of waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and the Rio Grande, entered into force <date date="1945-11-08">November 8, 1945</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/59/1219">59 Stat. 1219</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002366">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002366"><num>2</num> So in original. Closing parenthesis probably should follow “1219”.</note> and in accordance with sections 277d–13 to 277d–16 of title 22, and any commitment or agreement entered into pursuant to such treaty or sections, including (but not limited to) commitments or agreements relating to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cecc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the demarcation and maintenance of boundaries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cecd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the use, storage, and furnishing of water;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cece-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> control of floods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cecf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> investigations relative to the operation of the Amistad Dam; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4ced0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the production of hydroelectric energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f4ced1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Survey of cultural resources; report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a survey of the cultural resources in the immediate vicinity of the recreation area. The Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with public or private entities, including landowners, for the purpose of conducting the survey required by this subsection. Not later than two years after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate on the results of the survey required by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f4ced2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Hunting and fishing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f4ced3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall permit hunting and fishing on lands and waters under the Secretary’s jurisdiction within the recreation area in accordance with applicable Federal and State law. The Secretary may designate zones where, and establish periods when, hunting or fishing will not be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, fish and wildlife management, or public use and enjoyment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f4ced4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except in emergencies any regulations issued by the Secretary under this subsection shall be put into effect only after consultation with the appropriate State agencies responsible for hunting and fishing activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f4ced5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of administering the recreation area, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with any Federal agency, the State of Texas, or any political subdivision thereof, for the rendering, on a reimbursable basis, of rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement and fire preventive assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77f4ced6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/628/tV/s506">Pub. L. 101–628, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4494">104 Stat. 4494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77f4ced7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77f4ced8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77f4ced9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/628">Pub. L. 101–628</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4469">104 Stat. 4469</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, subchapters CXV (§ 460ddd) and CXVI (§ 460eee et seq.) of this chapter, chapter 65 (§ 4601 et seq.) of this title, and former sections 1a–9 to 1a–13 of this title, amended section 410ee, former section 463, and sections 1274 and 1276 of this title, enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1132 and 1271 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1522">section 1522 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands, and formerly set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1a–5">section 1a–5 of this title</ref>, and enacted provisions listed in a table of Wilderness Areas set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132">section 1132 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1">16 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 2–4), referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1946-08-07">August 7, 1946</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/60/885">60 Stat. 885</ref>), referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-07/ch788">act Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 788</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/885">60 Stat. 885</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s17j–2">section 17j–2 of this title</ref>. Subsecs. (b) to (g), (i), and (j) of the Act were repealed and restated in <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s103102">section 103102 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs, by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3272.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77f4ceda-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77f4cedb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
