<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77f4cec0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff"><num value="460fff">§ 460fff.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f4cec1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> In order to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cec2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide for public outdoor recreation use and enjoyment of the lands and waters associated with the United States portion of the reservoir known as Lake Amistad, located on the boundary between the State of Texas and Mexico, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f4cec3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> protect the scenic, scientific, cultural, and other value contributing to the public enjoyment of such lands and waters,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">there is hereby established the Amistad National Recreation Area (hereafter in this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460fff–1">section 460fff–1 of this title</ref> referred to as the “recreation area”).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f4cec4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460fff/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The recreation area shall consist of the Federal lands, waters, and interests therein within the area generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Proposed Amistad National Recreation Area”, numbered 621/20,013–B, and dated July 1969. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior (hereafter in this Act referred to as the “Secretary”) may from time to time make minor revisions in the boundary of the recreation area, but the total acreage of the recreation area may not exceed 58,500 acres. Within the boundary of the recreation area, the Secretary may acquire lands and interests in lands by purchase with donated or appropriated funds, exchange, or transfer without reimbursement from any Federal agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77f4cec5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/628/tV/s505">Pub. L. 101–628, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4494">104 Stat. 4494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77f4cec6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77f4cec7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77f4cec8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/628">Pub. L. 101–628</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4469">104 Stat. 4469</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, subchapters CXV (§ 460ddd) and CXVI (§ 460eee et seq.) of this chapter, chapter 65 (§ 4601 et seq.) of this title, and former sections 1a–9 to 1a–13 of this title, amended section 410ee, former section 463, and sections 1274 and 1276 of this title, enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1132 and 1271 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1522">section 1522 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands, and formerly set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1a–5">section 1a–5 of this title</ref>, and enacted provisions listed in a table of Wilderness Areas set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132">section 1132 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
