<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77dd016c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7"><num value="460gg–7">§ 460gg–7.</num><heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate, and may amend, such rules and regulations as he deems necessary to accomplish the purposes of this subchapter. Such rules and regulations shall include, but are not limited to—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77dd016d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> standards for the use and development of privately owned property within the recreation area, which rules or regulations the Secretary may, to the extent he deems advisable, implement with the authorities delegated to him in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–6">section 460gg–6 of this title</ref>, and which may differ among the various parcels of land within the recreation area;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77dd016e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> standards and guidelines to insure the full protection and preservation of the historic, archeological, and paleontological resources in the recreation area;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77dd016f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> provision for the control of the use of motorized and mechanical equipment for transportation over, or alteration of, the surface of any Federal land within the recreation area;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77dd0170-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> provision for the control of the use and number of motorized and nonmotorized river craft: <i>Provided</i>, That the use of such craft is hereby recognized as a valid use of the Snake River within the recreation area; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77dd0171-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460gg–7/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> standards for such management, utilization, and disposal of natural resources on federally owned lands, including but not limited to, timber harvesting by selective cutting, mining, and grazing and the continuation of such existing uses and developments as are compatible with the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77dd0172-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/199/s10">Pub. L. 94–199, § 10</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1121">89 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
