<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77df4ac2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4"><num value="460ii–4">§ 460ii–4.</num><heading> Funding sources and general management plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of appropriated funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">From the appropriations authorized for fiscal year 1978 and succeeding fiscal years pursuant to the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act (<ref href="/us/stat/78/897">78 Stat. 897</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002332">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002332"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> as amended, not more than $115,000,000 may be expended for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands authorized to be acquired pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter. For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200306/a/4">section 200306(a)(4) of title 54</ref>, the statutory ceiling on appropriations under this subsection shall be deemed to be a statutory ceiling contained in a provision of law enacted prior to the convening of the Ninety-sixth Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Donations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may accept a donation of funds or land or an interest in land to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to other funding sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds made available under paragraph (1) are in addition to funding and the donation of land and interests in land by the State of Georgia, local government authorities, private foundations, corporate entities, and individuals for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for development of essential public services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective on <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>, there are authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $500,000 for the development of essential public facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> General management plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ac9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within seven years from <date date="1978-08-15">August 15, 1978</date>, the Secretary shall, after consulting with the Governor of the State of Georgia, develop and transmit to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate a general management plan for the use and development of the recreation area consistent with the findings and purposes of this subchapter and chapter 43 of this title, indicating:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77df4aca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> lands and interests in lands adjacent or related to the recreation area which are deemed necessary or desirable for the purposes of resource protection, scenic integrity, or management and administration of the area in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, the estimated cost of acquisition, and the recommended public acquisition agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77df4acb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number of visitors and types of public use within the recreation area that can be accommodated in accordance with the full protection of its resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77df4acc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the facilities deemed necessary to accommodate and provide access for such visitors and uses, including their location and estimated cost.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4acd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Revised plan</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ace-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 3 years after the date funds are made available, the Secretary shall submit to the committees specified in paragraph (1) a revised general management plan to provide for the protection, enhancement, enjoyment, development, and use of the recreation area.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4acf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In preparing the revised plan, the Secretary shall encourage the participation of the State of Georgia and affected political subdivisions of the State, private landowners, interested citizens, public officials, groups, agencies, educational institutions, and other entities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77df4ad0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal actions affecting corridor area; procedural requirements: notification of Secretary, Secretary’s recommendations or notification of Congressional committees, copies of decisions and recommendations to Congressional committees; concurrence condition; exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Whenever any Federal department, agency, or instrumentality proposes to undertake any action, or provide Federal assistance for any action, or issue any license or permit for an action within the corridor referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460ii">section 460ii of this title</ref> which may have a direct and adverse effect on the natural or cultural resources of the recreation area, the head of such department, agency, or instrumentality shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4ad2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> promptly notify the Secretary of the action at the time it is planning the action, preparing an environmental assessment regarding the action, or preparing an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.] for the action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4ad3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide the Secretary a reasonable opportunity to comment and make recommendations regarding the effect of the Federal action on the natural and cultural resources of the recreation area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4ad4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notify the Secretary of the specific decisions made in respect to the comments and recommendations of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The requirements of this subsection shall be carried out in accordance with procedures established by the Federal agency responsible for undertaking or approving the Federal action. These procedures may utilize the procedures developed by such Agency pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.].</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Following receipt of notification pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary, after consultation with the Governor of Georgia, shall make such comments and recommendations as the Secretary deems appropriate pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) as promptly as practicable in accordance with the notifying agency’s procedures established pursuant to paragraph (1)(A). In any instance in which the Secretary does not provide comments and recommendations under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall notify in writing, the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Following receipt of the notifying agency’s decisions pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, including the authorizing committees with primary jurisdiction for the program under which the proposed action is being taken, a copy of the notifying agency’s specific decisions made pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), along with a copy of the comments and recommendations made pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any instance in which the Secretary has not been notified of a Federal agency’s proposed action within the corridor, and on his or her own determination finds that such action may have a significant adverse effect on the natural or cultural resources of the recreation area, the Secretary shall notify the head of such Federal agency in writing. Upon such notification by the Secretary, such agency shall promptly comply with the provisions of subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Each agency or instrumentality of the United States conducting Federal action upon federally owned lands or waters which are administered by the Secretary and which are located within the authorized boundary of the recreation area shall not commence such action until such time as the Secretary has concurred in such action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77df4ad9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The following Federal actions which constitute a major and necessary component of an emergency action shall be exempt from the provisions of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4ada-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> those necessary for safeguarding of life and property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4adb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> those necessary to respond to a declared state of disaster;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4adc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> those necessary to respond to an imminent threat to national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77df4add-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ii–4/d/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> those that the Secretary has determined to be not inconsistent with the general management plan for the recreation area.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Actions which are part of a project recommended in the study entitled “Metropolitan Atlanta Water Resources Management Study, Georgia: Report of Chief of Engineers”, dated <date date="1982-06-01">June 1, 1982</date>, and any Federal action which pertains to the control of air space, which is regulated under the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.], or which is required for maintenance or rehabilitation of existing structures or facilities shall also be exempt from the provisions of this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77df4ade-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/344/tI/s105">Pub. L. 95–344, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1978-08-15">Aug. 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/476">92 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/568/s1/e">Pub. L. 98–568, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2929">98 Stat. 2929</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/154/s2/d">Pub. L. 106–154, § 2(d)</ref>, (e)(4), <date date="1999-12-09">Dec. 9, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1738">113 Stat. 1738</ref>, 1739.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77df4adf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77df4ae0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77df4ae1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Land and Water Conservation Fund Act (<ref href="/us/stat/78/897">78 Stat. 897</ref>), referred to in subsec. (a)(1), probably means the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, <ref href="/us/pl/88/578">Pub. L. 88–578</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/897">78 Stat. 897</ref>, which was classified principally to part B (§ 460<i>l</i>–4 et seq.) of subchapter LXIX of this chapter. Sections 2, 3, 4(i)(1)(C), (j) to (n), 5 to 10, and 201 of the Act were repealed and restated as sections 100506(c) and 100904 and chapter 2003 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The convening of the Ninety-sixth Congress, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), took place on <date date="1979-01-15">Jan. 15, 1979</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clean Air Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(6), is <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 85 (§ 7401 et seq.) of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77df4ae2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(1), “<ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200306/a/4">section 200306(a)(4) of title 54</ref>” substituted for “section 7(a)(3) of the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</ref><i>l</i>–9(a)(3))” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s6/e">Pub. L. 113–287, § 6(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3272">128 Stat. 3272</ref>, which Act enacted Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77e1bbe3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/154/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 106–154, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, inserted section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/154/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 106–154, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, substituted “$115,000,000” for “$79,400,000” and “this subchapter” for “this subchapter and chapter 43 of this title”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/154/s2/d/3">Pub. L. 106–154, § 2(d)(3)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. (1) heading, redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, substituted “transmit to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives” for “transmit to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States House of Representatives”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/154/s2/e/4">Pub. L. 106–154, § 2(e)(4)</ref>, substituted “of this subchapter” for “of this subchapter and chapter 43 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/568/s1/e/1">Pub. L. 98–568, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “$79,400,000” for “$72,900,000” and inserted provision respecting applicable statutory ceiling on appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/568/s1/e/2">Pub. L. 98–568, § 1(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “seven years” for “three years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/568/s1/e/3">Pub. L. 98–568, § 1(e)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77e1bbe4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77e1bbe5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Resources of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
