<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77f71978-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2"><num value="460iii–2">§ 460iii–2.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f71979-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f7197a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is hereby established the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f7197b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The purposes for which the conservation area is established, and shall be managed, are to provide for the conservation, protection, and enhancement of raptor populations and habitats and the natural and environmental resources and values associated therewith, and of the scientific, cultural, and educational resources and values of the public lands in the conservation area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77f7197c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–3">section 460iii–3 of this title</ref>, uses of the public lands in the conservation area existing on <date date="1993-08-04">August 4, 1993</date>, shall be allowed to continue.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f7197d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Area included</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The conservation area shall consist of approximately 482,457 acres of federally owned lands and interests therein managed by the Bureau of Land Management as generally depicted on the map entitled “Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area”, dated November 1991.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f7197e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Map and legal description</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as is practicable after <date date="1993-08-04">August 4, 1993</date>, the map referred to in subsection (b) and a legal description of the conservation area shall be filed by the Secretary with the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate. Each such map shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter; except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in such map and legal description. Each such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Director and the Idaho State Director of the Bureau of Land Management of the Department of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f7197f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460iii–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal lands within the conservation area are hereby withdrawn from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; and from entry, application, and selection under the Act of <date date="1877-03-03">March 3, 1877</date> (Ch. 107, <ref href="/us/stat/19/377">19 Stat. 377</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s321">43 U.S.C. 321</ref> et seq.; commonly referred to as the “Desert Lands Act”), <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s641">section 641 of title 43</ref>, the Act of <date date="1890-07-03">July 3, 1890</date> (Ch. 656, <ref href="/us/stat/26/215">26 Stat. 215</ref>; commonly referred to as the “State of Idaho Admissions Act”), <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s851">section 851 of title 43</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s852">section 852 of title 43</ref>. The Secretary shall return to the applicants any such applications pending on <date date="1993-08-04">August 4, 1993</date>, without further action. Subject to valid existing rights, as of <date date="1993-08-04">August 4, 1993</date>, lands within the Birds of Prey Conservation Area are withdrawn from location under the general mining laws, the operation of the mineral and geothermal leasing laws, and the mineral material disposal laws, except that mineral materials subject to disposal may be made available from existing sites to the extent compatible with the purposes for which the conservation area is established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77f71980-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/64/s3">Pub. L. 103–64, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-08-04">Aug. 4, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/304">107 Stat. 304</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tII/s2301/a/2">Pub. L. 111–11, title II, § 2301(a)(2)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1101">123 Stat. 1101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77f71981-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77f71982-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77f71983-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1877-03-03">March 3, 1877</date>, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1877-03-03/ch107">act Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 107</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/19/377">19 Stat. 377</ref>, which is classified generally to sections 321 to 323, 325, and 327 to 329 of Title 43. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-07-03">July 3, 1890</date>, referred to in subsec. (d), is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77f71984-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref> inserted “Morley Nelson” before “Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area” and struck out “(hereafter referred to as the ‘conservation area’)” before period at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
