<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77c2c32e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460m–4"><num value="460m–4">§ 460m–4.</num><heading> Cooperative land development programs; hunting and fishing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c2c32f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460m–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of comprehensive plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized to cooperate with the State of Missouri, its political subdivisions, and other Federal agencies and organizations in formulating comprehensive plans for the Ozark National Scenic Riverways and for the related watershed of the Current and Jacks Fork Rivers in Missouri, and to enter into agreements for the implementation of such plans. Such plans may provide for land use and development programs, for preservation and enhancement of the natural beauty of the landscape, and for conservation of outdoor resources in the watersheds of the Current and Jacks Fork Rivers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c2c330-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460m–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of hunting and fishing zones and periods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit hunting and fishing on lands and waters under his jurisdiction within the Ozark National Scenic Riverways area in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws. The Secretary may designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting shall be permitted, for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment and shall issue regulations after consultation with the Conservation Commission of the State of Missouri.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77c2c331-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/492/s5">Pub. L. 88–492, § 5</ref>, <date date="1964-08-27">Aug. 27, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/609">78 Stat. 609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
