<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77e405a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460mm–2"><num value="460mm–2">§ 460mm–2.</num><heading> Establishment of recreation area</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the White Mountains National Recreation Area containing approximately one million acres of public lands, as generally depicted on the map entitled “White Mountains National Recreation Area—proposed”, and dated October 1978. Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall administer the area in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460mm–4">section 460mm–4 of this title</ref> and other applicable provisions of this Act, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], and other applicable law. In planning for the recreational use and management of this area, the Secretary shall work closely with the State of Alaska.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77e405aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 96–487, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2397">94 Stat. 2397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77e405ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77e405ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77e405ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">section 1701 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
