<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7803269f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–103"><num value="460nnn–103">§ 460nnn–103.</num><heading> Land Exchange, Tom J. Davis Livestock, Incorporated</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id780326a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–103/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Exchange authorized</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of protecting and consolidating Federal lands within the Wilderness Area, the Secretary may carry out a land exchange with Tom J. Davis Livestock, Incorporated, to convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to certain parcels of land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management in the vicinity of Steens Mountain, Oregon, as depicted on the map referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–105/a">section 460nnn–105(a) of this title</ref>, consisting of a total of approximately 5,340 acres in exchange for the private lands described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id780326a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–103/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Receipt of non-Federal lands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As consideration for the conveyance of the Federal lands referred to in subsection (a) and the disbursement referred to in subsection (c), Tom J. Davis Livestock, Incorporated, shall convey to the Secretary a parcel of land consisting of approximately 5,103 acres, as depicted on the map referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–105/a">section 460nnn–105(a) of this title</ref>, for inclusion in the Wilderness Area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id780326a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–103/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Disbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon completion of the land exchange authorized by this section, the Secretary is authorized to make a disbursement to Tom J. Davis Livestock, Incorporated, in the amount of $800,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id780326a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460nnn–103/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Completion of conveyance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall complete the conveyance of the Federal lands under subsection (a) within 70 days after the Secretary accepts the lands described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id780326a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/399/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 106–399, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1672">114 Stat. 1672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
