<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77e40604-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460pp"><num value="460pp">§ 460pp.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e40605-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460pp/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assure the conservation and protection of certain natural, scenic, historic, pastoral, and fish and wildlife values and to provide for the enhancement of the recreational values associated therewith, the Mount Baker National Recreation Area located in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, Washington, is hereby established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e40606-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460pp/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Acreage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Mount Baker National Recreation Area (hereafter referred to as the “recreation area”) shall comprise approximately eight thousand six hundred acres as generally depicted on the map entitled “Mount Baker National Recreation Area—Proposed”, dated March 1984, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief, Forest Service, Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e67707-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460pp/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Map and legal description</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall, as soon as practicable after <date date="1984-07-03">July 3, 1984</date>, file a map and a legal description of the recreation area with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, United States Senate, and the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, House of Representatives, and each such map and legal description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, That correction of clerical and typographical errors in such legal description and map may be made. The map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief of the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e67708-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460pp/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall administer the recreation area in accordance with the laws, rules and regulations applicable to the national forests in such manner as will best provide for (1) public outdoor recreation (including but not limited to snowmobile use); (2) conservation of scenic, natural, historic, and other values contributing to public enjoyment; and (3) such management, utilization, and disposal of natural resources on federally owned lands within the recreation area which are compatible with and which do not significantly impair the purposes for which the recreation area is established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77e67709-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/339/s7">Pub. L. 98–339, § 7</ref>, <date date="1984-07-03">July 3, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/304">98 Stat. 304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77e6770a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77e6770b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77e6770c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/98/339">Pub. L. 98–339</ref>, <date date="1984-07-03">July 3, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/299">98 Stat. 299</ref>, known as the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984, which enacted this subchapter and provisions listed in a table of Wilderness Areas set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132">section 1132 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77e6770d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77e6770e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
