<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77c77cea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460q–2"><num value="460q–2">§ 460q–2.</num><heading> Establishment of units; publication in Federal Register; boundary descriptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c77ceb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460q–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Shasta; Clair Engle-Lewiston</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the Secretary of Agriculture determines that sufficient lands, waters, or interest therein are owned or have been acquired by the United States within the boundaries of the Shasta unit or within the boundaries of the Clair Engle-Lewiston unit to permit efficient initial development and administration for the purposes of this subchapter, he shall publish in the Federal Register a notice to that effect and a detailed description of the boundaries of such unit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c77cec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460q–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Whiskeytown</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the Secretary of the Interior determines that sufficient lands, waters, or interest therein are owned or have been acquired by the United States within the boundaries of the Whiskeytown unit to permit efficient initial development and administration for the purposes of this subchapter, he shall publish in the Federal Register a notice to that effect and a detailed description of the boundaries of the unit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c77ced-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460q–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Following the publication of any such notice, the respective Secretaries may continue to acquire the remaining property within the recreation area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77c77cee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/336/s3">Pub. L. 89–336, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1297">79 Stat. 1297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
