<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77c9ee85-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460t–3"><num value="460t–3">§ 460t–3.</num><heading> Hunting and fishing</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit hunting and fishing on lands and waters under his jurisdiction within the recreation area in accordance with the appropriate laws of the United States and of the States of Montana or Wyoming to the extent applicable, except that the Secretary may designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting or fishing shall be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, fish or wildlife management, or public use and enjoyment, and except that nothing in this section shall impair the rights under other law of the Crow Tribe and its members to hunt and fish on lands of the Crow Tribe that are included in the recreation area, or the rights of the members of the Crow Tribe to hunt and fish under <ref href="/us/act/1958-07-15/s2/d">section 2(d) of the Act of July 15, 1958</ref>. Except in emergencies, any regulations of the Secretary pursuant to this section shall be put into effect only after consultation with the Montana Fish and Game Department or the Wyoming Game and Fish Commission.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77c9ee86-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/664/s4">Pub. L. 89–664, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/914">80 Stat. 914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77c9ee87-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77c9ee88-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77c9ee89-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1958-07-15/s2/d">Section 2(d) of the Act of July 15, 1958</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/363">72 Stat. 363</ref>, referred to in text, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1958-07-15/s2/d">“The members of the Crow Tribe of Indians of Montana shall be permitted to hunt and fish in and on the Yellowtail Reservoir and taking area without a license.”</quotedContent>
, and was not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
