<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77cc3824-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–19"><num value="460u–19">§ 460u–19.</num><heading> Acquisition of land outside present boundaries; notice to Congressional committees; publication in Federal Register</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After notifying the Committees on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States Congress, in writing, of his intentions to do so and of the reasons therefor, the Secretary may, if he finds that such lands would make a significant contribution to the purposes for which the Park was established, accept title to any lands, or interests in lands, located outside the present boundaries of the Park but contiguous thereto or to lands acquired under this section, such lands the State of Indiana or its political subdivisions may acquire and offer to donate to the United States or which any private person, organization, or public or private corporation may offer to donate to the United States and he shall administer such lands as a part of the Park after publishing notice to that effect in the Federal Register.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77cc3825-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s19">Pub. L. 89–761, § 19</ref>, formerly § 20, as added and renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/94/549/s1/8">Pub. L. 94–549, § 1(8)</ref>, (9), <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2532">90 Stat. 2532</ref>, 2533; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dE/tI/s115/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–6, div. E, title I, § 115(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/232">133 Stat. 232</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77cea926-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77cea927-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77cea928-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—<ref href="/us/pl/116/6">Pub. L. 116–6</ref> substituted “Park” for “lakeshore” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77cea929-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77cea92a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the Senate abolished and replaced by Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, effective <date date="1977-02-11">Feb. 11, 1977</date>. See Rule XXV of Standing Rules of the Senate, as amended by Senate Resolution No. 4 (popularly cited as the “Committee System Reorganization Amendments of 1977”), approved <date date="1977-02-04">Feb. 4, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
