<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77cc37d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–9"><num value="460u–9">§ 460u–9.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations; general management plan; submittal to Congressional committees; feasibility study</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may expend such sums as may be necessary from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for acquisition of lands and interests in lands, and not to exceed $27,500,000 for development: <i>Provided</i>, That not more than $500,000 of said amount may be appropriated for the development of the Paul H. Douglas Environmental Education Center authorized pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460u–20">section 460u–20 of this title</ref>. By <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, the Secretary shall develop and transmit to the Committees on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States Congress a general management plan detailing the development of the National Park consistent with the preservation objectives of this subchapter, indicating:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cc37d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–9/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the facilities needed to accommodate the health, safety, and recreation needs of the visiting public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cc37da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–9/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the location and estimated costs of all facilities, together with a review of the consistency of the master plan with State, areawide, and local governmental development plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cc37db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–9/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the projected need for any additional facilities within the National Park; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cc37dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–9/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> specific opportunities for citizen participation in the planning and development of proposed facilities and in the implementation of the general management plan generally.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a feasibility study of establishing United States Highway 12 as the “Indiana Dunes Parkway” under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service. The Secretary shall submit the results of such study to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate within two years after <date date="1986-10-29">October 29, 1986</date>. Effective <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the purposes of conducting the feasibility study.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id77cc37dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s9">Pub. L. 89–761, § 9</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1966-11-05">Nov. 5, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1312">80 Stat. 1312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/477/tI/s101/6">Pub. L. 93–477, title I, § 101(6)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-26">Oct. 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1445">88 Stat. 1445</ref>; renumbered § 9 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/549/s1/7">Pub. L. 94–549, § 1(7)</ref>, (9), <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2530">90 Stat. 2530</ref>, 2533; <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/tI/s101/16">Pub. L. 95–625, title I, § 101(16)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3472">92 Stat. 3472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/612/s1/10">Pub. L. 96–612, § 1(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-28">Dec. 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3576">94 Stat. 3576</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/583/s1/d">Pub. L. 99–583, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-29">Oct. 29, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3319">100 Stat. 3319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/430/s9">Pub. L. 102–430, § 9</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2210">106 Stat. 2210</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dE/tI/s115/a/1/A">Pub. L. 116–6, div. E, title I, § 115(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/232">133 Stat. 232</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77cc37de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77cc37df-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77cc37e0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/625/s101/16">section 101(16) of Pub. L. 95–625</ref> was, in the original, to <ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 89–761</ref> but has been executed to <ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s9">section 9 of Pub. L. 89–761</ref>, as the probable intent of Congress, in view of the prior re­designation of former <ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 89–761</ref> as section 9 by <ref href="/us/pl/94/549/s9">Pub. L. 94–549, § 9</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2533">90 Stat. 2533</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id77cc37e1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s9">section 9 of Pub. L. 89–761</ref> was renumbered section 8 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460u–8">section 460u–8 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77cc37e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—<ref href="/us/pl/116/6">Pub. L. 116–6</ref> substituted “National Park” for “national lakeshore” in introductory provisions and in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/430">Pub. L. 102–430</ref> substituted “The Secretary may expend such sums as may be necessary from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for acquisition of lands and interests in lands, and not to exceed $27,500,000 for development:” for “The Secretary may not expend more than $60,812,100 from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands nor more than $20,000,000 for development:”; struck out second par. which read as follows: “In addition to any sums heretofore authorized for the acquisitions of lands and interests in lands pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, there are further authorized to be appropriated an additional $3,120,000.”; and struck out first sentence of last par. which read as follows: “In addition to any other sums authorized for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter there are authorized to be appropriated an additional $3,500,000 to be used for such purposes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/583">Pub. L. 99–583</ref> substituted “$20,000,000” for “$11,000,000” and inserted provisions authorizing an additional $3,500,000 for acquisition of property and directing the Secretary to conduct a feasibility study of establishing Indiana Dunes Parkway.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/612">Pub. L. 96–612</ref> increased the amount the Secretary could expend for land development from $9,440,000 to $11,000,000, inserted proviso that not more than $500,000 of said amount could be appropriated for the development of the education center, and authorized appropriations of $3,120,000 in addition to sums already authorized for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/625">Pub. L. 95–625</ref> increased development appropriations authorization to $9,440,000 from $8,500,000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/549/s1/7">Pub. L. 94–549, § 1(7)</ref>, substituted provision authorizing the Secretary to expend not more than $60,812,100 from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for the acquisition of lands and interest in lands and not more than $8,500,000 for development and requiring the Secretary to develop and submit a general management plan to the Committees on the Interior and Insular Affairs by <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date> for provision which authorized not more than $35,526,000 for acquisition in land and interest in land.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/477">Pub. L. 93–477</ref> substituted “$35,526,000” for “$27,900,000”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77cc37e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77cc37e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the Senate abolished and replaced by Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, effective <date date="1977-02-11">Feb. 11, 1977</date>. See Rule XXV of Standing Rules of the Senate, as amended by Senate Resolution No. 4 (popularly cited as the “Committee System Reorganization Amendments of 1977”), approved <date date="1977-02-04">Feb. 4, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
