<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77cea95c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–26"><num value="460u–26">§ 460u–26.</num><heading> Units VII–D and I–M</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cea95d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–26/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Before acquiring lands or interests in lands in Unit VII–D (as designated on the map described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460u">section 460u of this title</ref>) the Secretary shall consult with the Commissioner of the Indiana Department of Transportation to determine what lands or interests in lands are required by the State of Indiana for improvements to 15th Avenue (including the extension known as Old Hobart Road) and reconstruction and relocation of the intersection of 15th Avenue and State Road 51 so that the acquisition by the Secretary of lands or interests in lands in Unit VII–D will not interfere with planned improvements to the interchange and 15th Avenue in the area.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cea95e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460u–26/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Before acquiring lands or interests in lands in Unit I–M (as designated on the map referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460u">section 460u of this title</ref>) the Secretary shall consult with the Commissioner of the Indiana Department of Transportation to determine what lands or interests in lands are required by the State of Indiana for improvements to State Road 49 and reconstruction and relocation of the interchange with State Road 49 and U.S. 20 so that the acquisition by the Secretary of lands or interests in lands in Unit I–M will not interfere with planned improvements to such interchange and State Road 49 in the area.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77cea95f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/761/s26">Pub. L. 89–761, § 26</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/430/s7">Pub. L. 102–430, § 7</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2209">106 Stat. 2209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
