<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77e8e88f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47"><num value="460uu–47">§ 460uu–47.</num><heading> Access</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e8e890-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonexclusive access by Indians for cultural and religious purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In recognition of the past use of portions of the monument and the conservation area by Indian people for traditional cultural and religious purposes, the Secretary shall assure nonexclusive access to the monument and the conservation area by Indian people for traditional cultural and religious purposes, including the harvesting of pine nuts. Such access shall be consistent with the purpose and intent of the American Indian Religious Freedom Act of <date date="1978-08-11">August 11, 1978</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</ref> [, 1996a]), and (with respect to areas designated as wilderness) the Wilderness Act (<ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e8e891-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations from Indian leaders regarding access and protection of cultural and religious sites</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In preparing the plans for the monument and the conservation area pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–41">section 460uu–41 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall request that the Governor of the Pueblo of Acoma and the chief executive officers of other appropriate Indian tribes make recommendations on methods of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77e8e892-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assuring access pursuant to subsection (a) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77e8e893-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enhancing the privacy of traditional cultural and religious activities in the monument and the conservation area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77e8e894-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> protecting traditional cultural and religious sites in the monument and the conservation area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e8e895-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary closure to public of lands for protection of religious activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to implement this section and in furtherance of the American Indian Religious Freedom Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</ref>, 1996a], the Secretary, upon the request of an appropriate Indian tribe, may from time to time temporarily close to general public use one or more specific portions of the monument or the conservation area in order to protect the privacy of religious activities in such areas by Indian people. Any such closure shall be made so as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period necessary for such purposes. Not later than seven days after the initiation of any such closure, the Secretary shall provide written notification of such action to the Energy and Natural Resources Committee of the United States Senate and the Natural Resources Committee of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e8e896-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460uu–47/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory committee; membership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish an advisory committee to advise the Secretary concerning the implementation of this section. Any such advisory committee shall include representatives of the Pueblo of Acoma, the Pueblo of Zuni, other appropriate Indian tribes and other persons or groups interested in the implementation of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77e8e897-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/225/tV/s507">Pub. L. 100–225, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1548">101 Stat. 1548</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s6/d/19">Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(19)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4584">108 Stat. 4584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77e8e898-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77e8e899-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77e8e89a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The American Indian Religious Freedom Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/341">Pub. L. 95–341</ref>, <date date="1978-08-11">Aug. 11, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/469">92 Stat. 469</ref>, which is classified to sections 1996 and 1996a of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1996">section 1996 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wilderness Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/577">Pub. L. 88–577</ref>, <date date="1964-09-03">Sept. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/890">78 Stat. 890</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1131">section 1131 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77e8e89b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” before “Committee of the House”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77e8e89c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77e8e89d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
