<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eb3198-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv"><num value="460vv">§ 460vv.</num><heading> Findings and purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3199-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> select areas of undeveloped National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma possess outstanding natural characteristics which give them high values as wilderness and will, if properly preserved, contribute as an enduring resource of wilderness for the benefit of the American people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Department of Agriculture’s second roadless area review and evaluation (RARE II) and other studies of National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma and the related congressional review of such lands have identified areas which, on the basis of their landform, ecosystem, associated wildlife, and location, will help to fulfill the National Forest System’s share of a quality National Wilderness Preservation System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Department of Agriculture’s second roadless area review and evaluation, of National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma and the related congressional review of such lands have also identified areas which do not possess outstanding wilderness attributes or which possess outstanding energy, mineral, timber, grazing, dispersed recreation and other values, and which should not be designated as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System but should be available for nonwilderness multiple uses under the land management planning process and other applicable laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> many areas of the Ouachita National Forest possess qualities that can only be expressed and utilized in such a manner that designation of such areas as a national recreation area is appropriate for the maximum potential and enjoyment of the area by the American people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> select areas possess unique plant and tree species and plant communities that are significant in their occurrence, variety and location and warrant designation as botanical areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb319f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> select areas possess unique scenic and wildlife qualities that designation of such areas as a national scenic area and a national scenic and wildlife area is appropriate for the preservation of the natural beauty and wildlife habitat for the enjoyment of the American people.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb31a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> designate certain National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, in order to promote, perpetuate, and preserve the wilderness character of the lands, protect watersheds and wildlife habitat, preserve scenic and historic resources, and promote scientific research, primitive recreation, solitude, physical and mental challenge, and inspiration for the benefit of all the American people, to a greater extent than is possible in the absence of wilderness designation; and to ensure that certain other National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma be available for nonwilderness multiple uses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> designate certain National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma as a national recreation area, 2 botanical areas, a national scenic area, and a national scenic and wildlife area in order to enhance and further certain natural resources characteristics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eb31a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/499/s2">Pub. L. 100–499, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-10-18">Oct. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2491">102 Stat. 2491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eb31a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77eb31a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id77eb31a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/499/s1">Pub. L. 100–499, § 1</ref>, <date date="1988-10-18">Oct. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2491">102 Stat. 2491</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/499/s1">“This Act [enacting this subchapter] may be referred to as the ‘Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
