<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eb31b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4"><num value="460vv–4">§ 460vv–4.</num><heading> Wilderness review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb31b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Department of Agriculture has completed the second roadless area review and evaluation program (RARE II); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Congress has made its own review and examination of National Forest System roadless areas in Oklahoma and of the environmental impacts associated with alternative allocations of such areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb31bc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional determination and direction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On the basis of such review, the Congress hereby determines and directs that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31bd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> without passing on the questions of the legal and factual sufficiency of the RARE II Final Environmental Impact Statement (dated January 1979) with respect to National Forest System lands in States other than Oklahoma, such statement shall not be subject to judicial review with respect to National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31be-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to the National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma which were reviewed by the Department of Agriculture in the second roadless area review and evaluation (RARE II) and those lands referred to in subsection (d), that review and evaluation or reference shall be deemed for the purposes of the initial land management plans required for such lands by the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, to be an adequate consideration of the suitability of such lands for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System and the Department of Agriculture shall not be required to review the wilderness option prior to the revision of the plans, but shall review the wilderness option when the plans are revised, which revisions will ordinarily occur on a ten-year cycle, or at least every fifteen years, unless, prior to such time the Secretary of Agriculture finds that conditions in a unit have significantly changed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31bf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> areas in the State of Oklahoma reviewed in such final environmental statement or referenced in subsection (d) and not designated wilderness upon enactment of this subchapter shall be managed for multiple use in accordance with land management plans pursuant to section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</ref>], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, except that such areas need not be managed for the purpose of protecting their suitability for wilderness designation prior to or during revision of the initial land management plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31c0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the event that revised land management plans in the State of Oklahoma are implemented pursuant to section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</ref>], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, and other applicable law, areas not recommended for wilderness designation need not be managed for the purpose of protecting their suitability for wilderness designation prior to or during revision of such plans, and areas recommended for wilderness designation shall be managed for the purpose of protecting their suitability for wilderness designation as may be required by the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, and other applicable law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> unless expressly authorized by Congress, the Department of Agriculture shall not conduct any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of the National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma for the purpose of determining their suitability for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb31c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of term</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, and as provided in section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</ref>], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, the term “revision” shall not include an “amendment” to a plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb31c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall also apply to:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> those National Forest System roadless lands in the State of Oklahoma in the Ouachita National Forest which were evaluated in the Rich Mountain and Beech Creek unit plans; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb31c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–4/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> National Forest System roadless lands in the State of Oklahoma which are less than five thousand acres in size.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eb31c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/499/s6">Pub. L. 100–499, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-10-18">Oct. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2493">102 Stat. 2493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eb31c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77eb31c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77eb31c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), (4), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/378">Pub. L. 93–378</ref>, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/476">88 Stat. 476</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1600 et seq.) of chapter 36 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">section 1600 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Forest Management Act of 1976, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2)–(4) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2949">90 Stat. 2949</ref>, which enacted sections 472a, 521b, 1600, and 1611 to 1614 of this title, amended sections 500, 515, 516, 518, 576b, and 1601 to 1610 of this title, repealed sections 476, 513, and 514 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 476, 513, 528, 594–2, and 1600 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1976 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">section 1600 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
