<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eb3212-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–18"><num value="460vv–18">§ 460vv–18.</num><heading> Land acquisition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3213-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–18/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange, any lands or interests therein, which the Secretary determines are needed to establish and manage the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3214-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–18/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Offers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In exercising the authority conferred by this section to acquire lands, the Secretary of Agriculture shall give prompt and careful consideration to any offer made by an individual owning any land, or interest in land, within the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area. In considering any such offer, the Secretary shall take into consideration any hardship to the owner which might result from any undue delay in acquiring the property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3215-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–18/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may acquire sites at locations outside such boundaries of the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area, as he determines necessary, for visitor orientation and the establishment of a lodge and additional facilities to enhance the quality of the area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3216-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460vv–18/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional lands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the limitations contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200306/a/2">section 200306(a)(2) of title 54</ref>, the Secretary of Agriculture may acquire by purchase, exchange, donation or otherwise any right, title, and interest in lands in Le Flore County, Oklahoma, which are outside the boundaries of the Ouachita National Forest. No such right, title or interest may be acquired without the consent of the owner thereof. All lands and interests therein acquired under this subsection shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in accordance with the Act of <date date="1911-03-01">March 1, 1911</date>, commonly referred to as the Weeks Act (<ref href="/us/stat/36/961">36 Stat. 961</ref>) and in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations generally applicable to units of the national forest system. The Secretary of Agriculture shall extend the boundaries of the Ouachita National Forest to include such lands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eb3217-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/499/s20">Pub. L. 100–499, § 20</ref>, <date date="1988-10-18">Oct. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2499">102 Stat. 2499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eb3218-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77eb3219-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77eb321a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1911-03-01">March 1, 1911</date>, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1911-03-01/ch186">act Mar. 1, 1911, ch. 186</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/961">36 Stat. 961</ref>, popularly known as the Weeks Law, which enacted former sections 513 and 514 and sections 515 to 519, 521, 552, and 563 of this title and amended sections 480 and 500 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s552">section 552 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77eb321b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “<ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200306/a/2">section 200306(a)(2) of title 54</ref>” substituted for “section 7(a)(1) of the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s6/e">Pub. L. 113–287, § 6(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3272">128 Stat. 3272</ref>, which Act enacted Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
