<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eb3228-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1"><num value="460ww–1">§ 460ww–1.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3229-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The recreation area shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and with the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1–4">16 U.S.C. 1–4</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002349">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002349"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Hunting and fishing; fish stocking</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall permit hunting, trapping and fishing on lands and waters within the recreation area in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws. The Secretary may, after consultation with the State of West Virginia Department of Natural Resources, designate zones where, and establish periods when, such activities will not be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, fish and wildlife habitat or public use and enjoyment subject to such terms and conditions as he deems necessary in the furtherance of this Act. The Secretary shall permit the State of West Virginia to undertake or continue fish stocking activities carried out by the State in consultation with the Secretary on waters within the boundaries of the recreation area. Nothing in this Act shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of West Virginia with respect to fish and wildlife <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002350">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002350"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements with State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In administering the recreation area the Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with the State of West Virginia, or any political subdivision thereof, for the rendering, on a reimbursable basis, of rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement services and cooperative assistance by nearby law enforcement and fire preventive agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of other provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278/a">section 1278(a) of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002351">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002351"><num>3</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> shall apply to the recreation area in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to river segments referred to in such provisions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Recreational access</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing public roads</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the State of West Virginia under which the Secretary shall be authorized to maintain and improve existing public roads and public rights-of-way within the boundaries of the national recreation area to the extent necessary to facilitate and improve reasonable access to the recreation area at existing access points where such actions would not unreasonably diminish the scenic and natural values of the area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb322f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Facilities adjacent to dam</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to accommodate visitation to the recreation area, the Secretary shall construct such facilities as necessary to enhance and improve access, vehicle parking and related facilities, and provide river access for whitewater recreation and for other recreational activities, immediately downstream of the Summersville Dam, to the extent that such facilities are not provided pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–4">section 460ww–4 of this title</ref> and such facilities are within the boundaries of the recreation area. Such construction shall be subject to the memorandum of understanding referred to in subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3230-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Other locations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition, in order to provide reasonable public access and vehicle parking for public use and enjoyment of the recreation area, consistent with the preservation and enhancement of the natural and scenic values of the recreation area, the Secretary may, with the consent of the owner thereof, acquire such lands and interests in lands to construct such parking and related facilities at other appropriate locations outside the boundaries of, but within one mile of the recreation area as may be necessary and appropriate. Any such lands shall be managed in accordance with the management provisions for the recreation area as defined in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3231-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to river</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb3232-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In order to facilitate public safety, use, and enjoyment of the recreation area, and to protect, to the maximum extent feasible, the scenic and natural resources of the area, the Secretary is authorized and directed to acquire such lands or interests in lands and to take such actions as are necessary to provide access by noncommercial entities on the north side of the Gauley River at the area known as Woods Ferry utilizing existing roads and rights-of-way. Such actions by the Secretary shall include the construction of parking and related facilities in the vicinity of Woods Ferry for noncommercial use on lands acquired pursuant to paragraph (3) or on lands acquired with the consent of the owner thereof within the boundaries of the recreation area.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb3233-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If necessary, in the discretion of the Secretary, in order to minimize environmental impacts, including visual impacts, within portions of the recreation area immediately adjacent to the river, the Secretary may, by contract or otherwise, provide transportation services for noncommercial visitors, at reasonable cost, between such parking facilities and the river.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eb3234-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall affect the rights of any person to continue to utilize, pursuant to a lease in effect on <date date="1993-04-01">April 1, 1993</date>, any right of way acquired pursuant to such lease which authorizes such person to use an existing road referred to in subparagraph (A). Except as provided under paragraph (2) relating to access immediately downstream of the Summersville project, until there is compliance with this paragraph the Secretary is prohibited from acquiring or developing any other river access points within the recreation area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eb3235-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460ww–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Properties and facilities of Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consultation with any other Federal agency managing lands and waters within or contiguous to the recreation area, the Secretary shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with such other Federal agency to identify those areas within the recreation area which are (1) under the administrative jurisdiction of such other agency; (2) directly related to the operation of the Summersville project; and (3) essential to the operation of such project. The memorandum of understanding shall also include provisions regarding the management of all such lands and waters in a manner consistent with the operation of such project and the management of the recreation area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eda336-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/534/tII/s202">Pub. L. 100–534, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1988-10-26">Oct. 26, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2702">102 Stat. 2702</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/333/dI/tIV/s406/c/2">Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title IV, § 406(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-11-12">Nov. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4150">110 Stat. 4150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eda337-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77eda338-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77eda339-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/100/534">Pub. L. 100–534</ref>, <date date="1988-10-26">Oct. 26, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2699">102 Stat. 2699</ref>, known as the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987, which enacted this subchapter and sections 410eeee–12 to 410eeee–15 of this title, amended sections 410eeee–1 and 1274 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 410eeee–1 and 1274 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s410eeee–1">section 410eeee–1 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1–4">16 U.S.C. 1–4</ref>), referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77eda33a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/333">Pub. L. 104–333</ref> added par. (4).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
