<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77cea989-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460w–2"><num value="460w–2">§ 460w–2.</num><heading> Acquisition of property; authority of Secretary; State and Federal lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may acquire within the boundaries of the lakeshore lands and interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange, but lands and interests in lands owned by the State of Wisconsin may be acquired only by donation. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any Federal property located within the boundaries of the lakeshore is hereby transferred without transfer of funds to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purposes of the lakeshore: <i>Provided</i>, That the United States Coast Guard may retain a right to utilize a portion of such land and facilities for use as navigational aids so long as may be required.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77cea98a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/424/s3">Pub. L. 91–424, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-09-26">Sept. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/880">84 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/497/s1/2">Pub. L. 99–497, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1267">100 Stat. 1267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77cea98b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77cea98c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77cea98d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/497">Pub. L. 99–497</ref> substituted “is hereby” for “may, with the concurrence of the agency having custody thereof, be” and inserted proviso permitting the United States Coast Guard to utilize a portion of the lands and facilities for use as navigational aids as long as required.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77cea98e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77cea98f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
