<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eda39a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1"><num value="460yy–1">§ 460yy–1.</num><heading> Plan and management</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda39b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To achieve the purpose of this subchapter, the Secretary, acting through the National Park Service, in cooperation with appropriate State and Federal agencies, local units of government and local residents shall formulate a comprehensive plan for the protection, preservation, and interpretation of the reserve. The plan shall identify those areas or zones within the reserve which would most appropriately be devoted to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda39c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> public use and development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda39d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> historic and natural preservation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda39e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> private use subject to appropriate local ordinances designed to protect the historic rural setting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda39f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal of plan to Congress and State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within eighteen months following <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall transmit the plan to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and to the Governor of the State of Idaho.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of management and administration to State or local units of government</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At such time as the State or appropriate units of local government having jurisdiction over land use within the reserve have enacted ordinances or established regulations which in the judgment of the Secretary will protect and preserve the historic and natural features of the area in accordance with the comprehensive plan, the Secretary shall, pursuant to cooperative agreement—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda3a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> transfer management and administration over all or any part of the property acquired under subsection (d) of this section to the State or appropriate units of local government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda3a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide technical assistance to such State or units of local government in the management, protection, and interpretation of the reserve; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77eda3a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make periodic grants, which shall be supplemental to any other funds to which the grantee may be entitled under any other provision of law, to such State or local unit of government to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of land</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77eda3a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to acquire such lands and interests as he determines are necessary to accomplish the purposes of this subchapter by donation, purchase with donated funds, or appropriated funds, or exchange, except that the Secretary may not acquire the fee simple title to any land without the consent of the owner. The Secretary shall, in addition, give prompt and careful consideration to any offer made by an individual owning property within the reserve to sell such property, if such individual notifies the Secretary that the continued ownership of such property is causing, or would result in, undue hardship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77eda3a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Lands and waters, and interests therein, within the boundaries of the reserve which were administered by the Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture or the Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior prior to <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, are hereby transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary to be administered by the National Park Service in accordance with this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77eda3a7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Lands and interest therein so acquired shall, so long as responsibility for management and administration remains with the United States, be administered by the Secretary subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002353">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002353"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> as amended and supplemented, and in a manner consistent with the purpose of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of management and administration from State or local units of government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, after the transfer of management and administration of any lands pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary determines that the reserve is not being managed in a manner consistent with the purposes of this subchapter, he shall so notify the appropriate officers of the State or local unit of government to which such transfer was made and provide for a one hundred and eighty-day period in which the transferee may make such modifications in applicable laws, ordinances, rules, and procedures as will be consistent with such purposes. If, upon the expiration of such one hundred and eighty-day period, the Secretary determines that such modifications have not been made or are inadequate, he shall withdraw the management and administration from the transferee and he shall manage such lands in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Water rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds that there are unique circumstances with respect to the water and water related resources within the Reserve <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002354">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002354"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> designated by this subchapter. The Congress recognizes that the management of this area may be transferred to the State of Idaho, that the State has committed to providing the water necessary to fulfill the purposes of this subchapter, and that there is little or no water or water-related resources that require the protection of a Federal reserved water right. Nothing in this subchapter, nor any action taken pursuant thereto, shall constitute either an express or implied reservation of water or water right for any purpose: <i>Provided</i>, That the United States shall retain that reserved water right which is associated with the initial establishment and withdrawal of the national forest lands which will be transferred to the Reserve <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002354">2</ref> under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of lands from disposition under other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to valid existing rights, Federal lands and interests therein, within the reserve, are hereby withdrawn from disposition under the public land laws and from entry or appropriation under the mining laws of the United States, from the operation of the mineral leasing laws of the United States, and from operation of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1001">30 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda3ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy–1/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $2,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eda3ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/696/tII/s202">Pub. L. 100–696, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4574">102 Stat. 4574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eda3ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77eda3ae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77eda3af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>), referred to in subsec. (d)(3), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of former sections of this title, see Disposition Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100101">section 100101 of Title 54</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (g), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/581">Pub. L. 91–581</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1566">84 Stat. 1566</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1001">section 1001 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77eda3b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77eda3b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Permission To Hunt on Reserve; Restrictions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/512/tI">Pub. L. 101–512, title I</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1923">104 Stat. 1923</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/512/tI">“with respect to lands and waters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior within the City of Rocks National Reserve established by title II of <ref href="/us/pl/100/696">Public Law 100–696</ref> [enacting sections 460yy and 460yy–1 of this title], the Secretary shall hereafter permit hunting in accordance with the otherwise applicable laws of the United States and the State of Idaho, except that he may designate zones where and periods when no hunting may be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, floral and faunal protection and management, or public use and enjoyment: <i>Provided further</i>, That except in emergencies, any regulation prescribing such restrictions shall be put into effect only after consultation with the appropriate State agency having jurisdiction over hunting activities”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
