<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77eda392-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy"><num value="460yy">§ 460yy.</num><heading> Establishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda393-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the City of Rocks National Reserve (hereinafter referred to as the “reserve”), in order to preserve and protect the significant historical and cultural resources; to manage recreational use; to protect and maintain scenic quality; and to interpret the nationally significant values of the reserve.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda394-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Area included</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The reserve shall include approximately fourteen thousand three hundred and twenty acres as depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, City of Rocks National Reserve, Idaho” numbered P30–80,005 and dated October 1987. The map shall be on file in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior and the Offices of the Governor, State of Idaho.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77eda395-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460yy/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Legal description</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within six months after <date date="1988-11-18">November 18, 1988</date>, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall file a legal description of the reserve designated under this section with the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States House of Representatives and with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate. Such legal description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in such legal description and in the map referred to in subsection (b). The legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior and the offices of the Governor of the State of Idaho.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77eda396-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/696/tII/s201">Pub. L. 100–696, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4573">102 Stat. 4573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77eda397-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77eda398-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77eda399-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives on <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>, by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
