<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d3649a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460z–9"><num value="460z–9">§ 460z–9.</num><heading> Water utilization; transportation of wastes; easements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d3649b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460z–9/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Water utilization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed, subject to applicable water quality standards now or hereafter established, to permit, subject to reasonable rules and regulations, the investigation for, appropriation, storage, and withdrawal of ground water, surface water, and lake, stream, and river water from the recreation area and the conveyance thereof outside the boundaries of the recreation area for beneficial use in accordance with applicable laws of the United States and of the State of Oregon if permission therefor has been obtained from the State of Oregon before <date date="1972-03-23">March 23, 1972</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein shall prohibit or authorize the prohibition of the use of water from Tahkenitch or Siltcoo Lakes in accordance with permission granted by the State of Oregon prior to <date date="1972-03-23">March 23, 1972</date>, in connection with certain industrial plants developed or being developed at or near Gardiner, Oregon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d3649c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460z–9/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transportation and storage of wastes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed, subject to applicable water quality standards now or hereafter established, to permit, subject to reasonable rules and regulations, transportation and storage in pipelines within and through the recreation area of domestic and industrial wastes in accordance with applicable laws of the United States and of the State of Oregon if permission therefor has been obtained from the State of Oregon before <date date="1972-03-23">March 23, 1972</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d3649d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s460z–9/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Easements and rights for the disposal of wastes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is further authorized, subject to applicable water quality standards now or hereafter established, to grant such additional easements and rights, in terms up to perpetuity, as in his judgment would be appropriate and desirable for the effective use of the rights to water and the disposal of waste provided for herein and for other utility and private purposes if permission therefor has been obtained from the State of Oregon, subject to such reasonable terms and conditions as he deems necessary for the protection of the scenic, scientific, historic, and recreational features of the recreation area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d3649e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/260/s11">Pub. L. 92–260, § 11</ref>, <date date="1972-03-23">Mar. 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/101">86 Stat. 101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
