<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7813c874-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e"><num value="469e">§ 469e.</num><heading> Plan for continental glaciation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7813c875-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To implement the purpose of sections 469d to 469i of this title, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter called the “Secretary”), in cooperation with State and local governmental authorities of Wisconsin, may formulate within two years after <date date="1964-10-13">October 13, 1964</date>, a comprehensive plan for the protection, preservation, and interpretation of outstanding examples of continental glaciation in Wisconsin; but he shall not spend more than $50,000 of Federal funds thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7813c876-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Copies to Congress; establishment; boundaries</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the comprehensive plan is completed and the Secretary is satisfied that State legislation exists for the preservation of the nationally significant features of the reserve, open to the people of the entire Nation, he shall transmit copies thereof to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and may, ninety days thereafter and after consulting with the Governor of the State of Wisconsin, publish notice in the Federal Register of the establishment of the Ice Age National Scientific Reserve and of the boundaries thereof, which boundaries shall comprise lands owned or to be acquired by the State and local governments of Wisconsin in the following areas:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7813c877-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Eastern area (portions of the northern unit of the Kettle Moraine State Forest and Campbellsport drumlin area);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7813c878-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Central area (portions of Devil’s Lake State Park);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7813c879-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Northwestern area (portions of Chippewa County);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7813c87a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Related areas (other areas in the State of Wisconsin which the Secretary and the Governor of Wisconsin agree upon as significant examples of continental glaciation).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7813c87b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s469e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion and exclusion of other areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any area outside of the national forests that the Secretary and the Governor of Wisconsin agree has significant examples of continental glaciation but is not described in the original notice may be included in the reserve by the Secretary after notice to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and publication in the Federal Register, as hereinbefore provided, and any area that they consider to be no longer desirable as a part of the reserve may be excluded from it by the Secretary in the same manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7813c87c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/655/s2">Pub. L. 88–655, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1087">78 Stat. 1087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
