<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79f58177-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724"><num value="4724">§ 4724.</num><heading> State aquatic nuisance species management plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58178-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> State or interstate invasive species management plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58179-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After providing notice and opportunity for public comment, the Governor of each State may prepare and submit, or the Governors of the States and the governments of the Indian tribes involved in an interstate organization, may jointly prepare and submit—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f5817a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a comprehensive management plan to the Task Force for approval which identifies those areas or activities within the State or within the interstate region involved, other than those related to public facilities, for which technical, enforcement, or financial assistance (or any combination thereof) is needed to eliminate or reduce the environmental, public health, and safety risks associated with aquatic nuisance species, particularly the zebra mussel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f5817b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a public facility management plan to the Assistant Secretary for approval which is limited solely to identifying those public facilities within the State or within the interstate region involved for which technical and financial assistance is needed to reduce infestations of zebra mussels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f5817c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Content</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each plan shall, to the extent possible, identify the management practices and measures that will be undertaken to reduce infestations of aquatic nuisance species. Each plan shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f5817d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify and describe State and local programs for environmentally sound prevention and control of the target aquatic nuisance species;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f5817e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identify Federal activities that may be needed for environmentally sound prevention and control of aquatic nuisance species and a description of the manner in which those activities should be coordinated with State and local government activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f5817f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identify any authority that the State (or any State or Indian tribe involved in the interstate organization) does not have at the time of the development of the plan that may be necessary for the State (or any State or Indian tribe involved in the interstate organization) to protect public health, property, and the environment from harm by aquatic nuisance species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79f58180-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a schedule of implementing the plan, including a schedule of annual objectives, and enabling legislation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58181-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f58182-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In developing and implementing a management plan, the State or interstate organization should, to the maximum extent practicable, involve local governments and regional entities, Indian tribes, and public and private organizations that have expertise in the control of aquatic nuisance species.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f58183-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Upon the request of a State or the appropriate official of an interstate organization, the Task Force or the Assistant Secretary, as appropriate under paragraph (1), may provide technical assistance in developing and implementing a management plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58184-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 90 days after the submission of a management plan, the Task Force or the Assistant Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, as appropriate under paragraph (1), shall review the proposed plan and approve it if it meets the requirements of this subsection or return the plan to the Governor or the interstate organization with recommended modifications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58185-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58186-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> State grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director may, at the recommendation of the Task Force, make grants to States with management plans approved under subsection (a) for the implementation of those plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58187-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An application for a grant under this subsection shall include an identification and description of the best management practices and measures which the State proposes to utilize in implementing an approved management plan with any Federal assistance to be provided under the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f58188-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f58189-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Federal share of the cost of each comprehensive management plan implemented with Federal assistance under this section in any fiscal year shall not exceed 75 percent of the cost incurred by the State in implementing such management program and the non-Federal share of such costs shall be provided from non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f5818a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Federal share of the cost of each public facility management plan implemented with Federal assistance under this section in any fiscal year shall not exceed 50 percent of the cost incurred by the State in implementing such management program and the non-Federal share of such costs shall be provided from non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f5818b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, administrative costs for activities and programs carried out with a grant in any fiscal year shall not exceed 5 percent of the amount of the grant in that year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79f5818c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to cash outlays and payments, in-kind contributions of property or personnel services by non-Federal interests for activities under this section may be used for the non-Federal share of the cost of those activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f5818d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s4724/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of a State or Indian tribe, the Director or the Under Secretary, to the extent allowable by law and in a manner consistent with section 141 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002798">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002798"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 14, may provide assistance to a State or Indian tribe in enforcing an approved State or interstate invasive species management plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79f5818e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/646/tI/s1204">Pub. L. 101–646, title I, § 1204</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4770">104 Stat. 4770</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)</ref>, (h)(1), <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4089">110 Stat. 4089</ref>, 4091; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXIII/s11327/e/4">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIII, § 11327(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4098">136 Stat. 4098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79f5818f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79f58190-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79f58191-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t14/s141">Section 141 of title 14</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s701">section 701 of title 14</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s106/b">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 106(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4203">132 Stat. 4203</ref>, and references to <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s141">section 141 of title 14</ref> deemed to refer to such redesignated section, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/1">section 123(b)(1) of Pub. L. 115–282</ref>, set out as a References to Sections of Title 14 as Redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s101">section 101 of Title 14</ref>, Coast Guard.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79f58192-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “Administrative” for “Adminisrative” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/h/1">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(h)(1)</ref>, made technical amendment to <ref href="/us/pl/101/646/s1204">Pub. L. 101–646, § 1204</ref>, which enacted this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/i">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “State or interstate invasive species management plans” for “State plan” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/ii/I">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “After providing notice and opportunity for public comment, the Governor of each State may prepare and submit, or the Governors of the States and the governments of the Indian tribes involved in an interstate organization, may jointly prepare and submit” for “The Governor of each State may, after notice and opportunity for public comment, prepare and submit” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/ii/II">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(ii)(II)</ref>, (III), inserted “or within the interstate region involved” after “within the State” and substituted “technical, enforcement, or financial assistance (or any combination thereof)” for “technical and financial assistance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/ii/III">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(ii)(III)</ref>, inserted “or within the interstate region involved” after “within the State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/iii/I">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(iii)(I)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/iii/III">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(iii)(III)</ref>, added subpar. (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/iii/II">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(iii)(II)</ref>, (IV), redesignated subpar. (C) as (D) and inserted “, and enabling legislation” before period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/iv/I">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(iv)(I)</ref>, inserted “or interstate organization” after “the State” and “Indian tribes,” after “local governments and regional entities,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/iv/II">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(iv)(II)</ref>, inserted “or the appropriate official of an interstate organization” after “a State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/A/v">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(A)(v)</ref>, inserted “or the interstate organization” after “the Governor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/B">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(B)</ref>, struck out “or the Assistant Secretary, as appropriate under subsection (a),” after “The Director” and substituted “management plans approved under subsection (a)” for “approved management plans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/332/s2/e/6/C">Pub. L. 104–332, § 2(e)(6)(C)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
