<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id781d3f01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s473"><num value="473">§ 473.</num><heading> Revocation, modification, or vacation of orders or proclamations establishing national forests</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States is authorized and empowered to revoke, modify, or suspend any and all Executive orders and proclamations or any part thereof issued under section 471 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002404">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002404"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, from time to time as he shall deem best for the public interests. By such modification he may reduce the area or change the boundary lines or may vacate altogether any order creating a national forest.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id781d3f02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1897-06-04/ch2/s1">June 4, 1897, ch. 2, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/34">30 Stat. 34</ref>, 36.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id781d3f03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id781d3f04-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id781d3f05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s471">Section 471 of this title</ref>, referred to in text, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/94/579/tVII/s704/a">Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 704(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2792">90 Stat. 2792</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id781d3f06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The two sentences of this section are from provisions in section 1 of the Sundry Civil Appropriation Act for the fiscal year 1898, act <date date="1897-06-04">June 4, 1897</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first sentence is a portion of the third paragraph and was prefaced by the words “To remove any doubt which may exist pertaining to the authority of the President thereunto.” Other provisions of the same paragraph have been omitted as temporary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The second sentence is a portion of the seventh paragraph the whole of which reads as follows: “The President is hereby authorized at any time to modify any Executive order that has been or may hereafter be made establishing any forest reserve, and by such modification may reduce the area or change the boundary lines of such reserve, or may vacate altogether any order creating such reserve.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id781faf07-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id781faf08-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Certain provisions of <ref href="/us/act/1897-06-04/ch2">act June 4, 1897, ch. 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/34">30 Stat. 34</ref>, under the headings “<inline class="small-caps">under the department of the interior</inline>.” and “<inline class="small-caps">surveying the public lands</inline>.”, which enacted sections 473 to 478, 479 to 482, and 551 of this title, are popularly known as the Organic Administration Act.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
