<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id782220c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s487"><num value="487">§ 487.</num><heading> Cutting timber on land added to Siskiyou National Forest</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, in his discretion, to sell the merchantable timber on the land added to the Siskiyou National Forest by section 1 hereof, in accordance with the regulations governing the sale of public timber in the national forests, and the entire proceeds of any sale of the timber on such land shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States in a special fund designated as “The Oregon and California land-grant fund”, referred to in the Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date>, chapter 137, section 10, Thirty-ninth Statutes, page 222, and be disposed of in the manner therein designated, the land added forming part of the area which revested in the United States under the provisions of the said Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id782220c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-22/ch407/s2">Sept. 22, 1922, ch. 407, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1019">42 Stat. 1019</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id782220c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id782220c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id782220c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1 hereof, referred to in text, means section 1 of <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-22/ch407">act Sept. 22, 1922, ch. 407</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1019">42 Stat. 1019</ref>, which related to exchanges of lands in or adjacent to Siskiyou National Forest and was not classified to the Code. See Codification note set out under sections 486a to 486w of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date>, referred to in text, was not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
