<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id782220c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s487a"><num value="487a">§ 487a.</num><heading> Cutting timber on lands added to Rogue River National Forest</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the Secretary of Agriculture finds that merchantable timber may be cut without detriment to the purity or depletion of the water supply from lands added to the Rogue River National Forest by Act of <date date="1936-06-04">June 4, 1936</date>, chapter 494, section 1, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1460">49 Stat. 1460</ref>, title to which has been revested in the United States under the Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/218">39 Stat. 218</ref>), said Secretary is authorized to dispose of such merchantable timber on such lands in accordance with the rules and regulations of the Secretary of Agriculture for the national forests and the entire proceeds of any such sale shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States in a special fund designated “The Oregon and California Land Grant Fund”, referred to in section 10 of the said Act of <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date>, and be disposed of in the manner therein designated.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id782220c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-04/ch494/s2">June 4, 1936, ch. 494, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1461">49 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id782220ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id782220cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id782220cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1936-06-04">June 4, 1936</date>, chapter 494, section 1, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1460">49 Stat. 1460</ref>, referred to in text, related to exchanges of lands in or adjacent to Rogue River National Forest and was not classified to the Code. See Codification note set out under sections 486a to 486w of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date>, referred to in text, was not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
