<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76f7f86d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s49"><num value="49">§ 49.</num><heading> Rights of claimants and owners of lands included; laws and regulations applicable within park</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">None of the lands patented and in private ownership in the area included under sections 46 and 47 of this title in the Sierra National Forest shall have the privileges of the lieu-land scrip provisions of the land laws, but otherwise to be in all respects under the laws and regulations affecting the national forests. All laws, rules, and regulations affecting national forests, including the right to change the boundaries thereof by Executive proclamation, shall take effect and be in force within the limits of the territory excluded by sections 46 and 47 of this title from the Yosemite National Park, except as otherwise provided.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76f7f86e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1905-02-07/ch547/s2">Feb. 7, 1905, ch. 547, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/33/703">33 Stat. 703</ref>; <date date="1906-06-11">June 11, 1906</date>, No. 27, § 2, <ref href="/us/stat/34/832">34 Stat. 832</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/1269">34 Stat. 1269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76f7f86f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76f7f870-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76f7f871-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Sierra National Forest” and “national forests” substituted in text for “Sierra Forest Reserve” and for “forest reserves” and “forest reservations”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">act Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/1269">34 Stat. 1269</ref>, which provided that forest reserves shall hereafter be known as national forests.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
