<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id782469f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s497"><num value="497">§ 497.</num><heading> Use and occupation of lands for hotels, resorts, summer homes, stores, and facilities for industrial, commercial, educational or public uses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, under such regulations as he may make and upon such terms and conditions as he may deem proper, (a) to permit the use and occupancy of suitable areas of land within the national forests, not exceeding eighty acres and for periods not exceeding thirty years, for the purpose of constructing or maintaining hotels, resorts, and any other structures or facilities necessary or desirable for recreation, public convenience, or safety; (b) to permit the use and occupancy of suitable areas of land within the national forests, not exceeding five acres and for periods not exceeding thirty years, for the purpose of constructing or maintaining summer homes and stores; (c) to permit the use and occupancy of suitable areas of land within the national forest, not exceeding eighty acres and for periods not exceeding thirty years, for the purpose of constructing or maintaining buildings, structures, and facilities for industrial or commercial purposes whenever such use is related to or consistent with other uses on the national forests; (d) to permit any State or political subdivision thereof, or any public or nonprofit agency, to use and occupy suitable areas of land within the national forests not exceeding eighty acres and for periods not exceeding thirty years, for the purpose of constructing or maintaining any buildings, structures, or facilities necessary or desirable for education or for any public use or in connection with any public activity. The authority provided by this section shall be exercised in such manner as not to preclude the general public from full enjoyment of the natural, scenic, recreational, and other aspects of the national forests.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id782469f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1915-03-04/ch144">Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 144</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/1101">38 Stat. 1101</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-28/ch771">July 28, 1956, ch. 771</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/708">70 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id782469f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id782469f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id782469f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Act <date date="1956-07-28">July 28, 1956</date>, increased maximum area of land for each purpose for which permits may be granted from not more than 5 acres to not more than 80 acres, and authorized permits for facilities for public safety, for buildings, structures, and facilities for industrial or commercial purposes whenever such purposes are related to or consistent with other use of the national forests, and for facilities to be used by public or nonprofit agencies for education or public use or in connection with any public activity.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id782469f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id782469f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Forest Service Administration of Rights-of-Way and Land Uses</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tIII/s331">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 331]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–196, as amended, formerly set out as a note under this section, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s497e">section 497e of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
