<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7826db82-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s502"><num value="502">§ 502.</num><heading> Rental of property for Forest Service; forage, care, and housing of animals; storage of vehicles and other equipment; pack stock; loss, damage, or destruction of horses, vehicles, and other equipment</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, under such regulations as he may prescribe:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7826db83-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s502/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> To hire or rent property from employees of the Forest Service for the use of that Service whenever the public interest will be promoted thereby.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7826db84-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s502/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> To provide forage, care, and housing for animals, and storage for vehicles and other equipment obtained by the Forest Service for the use of that service from employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7826db85-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s502/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> To contract with public and private agencies, corporations, firms, associations, or individuals to train, provide forage, care, and housing for, and to work pack stock owned and held in reserve by the Forest Service for fire emergency purposes and as all or part of the consideration therefor to permit such contractors to use the stock for their own purposes during the periods of nonuse by the Forest Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7826db86-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s502/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> To reimburse owners for loss, damage, or destruction of horses, vehicles, and other equipment obtained by the Forest Service for the use of that service from employees or other private owners: <i>Provided</i>, That payments or reimbursements herein authorized may be made from the applicable appropriations for the Forest Service: <i>And provided further</i>, That except for fire fighting emergencies no reimbursement herein authorized shall be made in an amount in excess of $50 to persons who were employees of the Forest Service prior to the time the equipment was obtained or $2,500 in any other case, unless the equipment was made available under a written agreement, contract, or lease.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7826db87-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch145/s1">Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 145, § 1</ref> (part), <ref href="/us/stat/37/843">37 Stat. 843</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1931-01-31/ch76">Jan. 31, 1931, ch. 76</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1052">46 Stat. 1052</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/464/s1">Pub. L. 85–464, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-06-20">June 20, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/216">72 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/270">Pub. L. 89–270</ref>, <date date="1965-10-19">Oct. 19, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/991">79 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/375/tI/s103/b">Pub. L. 97–375, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1819">96 Stat. 1819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7826db88-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7826db89-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7826db8a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/375">Pub. L. 97–375</ref> struck out provision that the Secretary transmit to Congress a statement of rentals under the authority of this paragraph as soon as practicable after the end of each fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/270">Pub. L. 89–270</ref> required the transmittal of statement of rentals during the fiscal year to congressional committees and omitted restriction against use of hired or rented property by the employee from whom hired or rented and $3,000 limitation on aggregate amount of payment in any one year to permanent employees, exclusive of fire emergency obligations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/464">Pub. L. 85–464</ref> added subsec. (c), redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d) and authorized reimbursement in an amount not in excess of $2,500 in any case where the person is not an employee of the Forest Service at the time the equipment is obtained.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1931—Act <date date="1931-01-31">Jan. 31, 1931</date>, substituted “The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, under such regulations as he may prescribe” for prior provision which authorized Secretary to reimburse owners of private property lost or damaged while being used for necessary official business.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a) to (c). Act <date date="1931-01-31">Jan. 31, 1931</date>, added subsecs. (a) to (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
