<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7826dba1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s505a"><num value="505a">§ 505a.</num><heading> Interchange of lands between Department of Agriculture and military departments of Department of Defense; report to Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest System lands and the Secretary of a military department with respect to lands under the control of the military department which lie within or adjacent to the exterior boundaries of a unit of the National Forest System are authorized, subject to any applicable provisions of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, to interchange such lands, or any part thereof, without reimbursement or transfer of funds whenever they shall determine that such interchange will facilitate land management and will provide maximum use thereof for authorized purposes: <i>Provided</i>, That no such interchange of lands shall become effective until forty-five days (counting only days occurring during any regular or special session of the Congress) after the submission to the Congress by the respective Secretaries of notice of intention to make the interchange.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7826dba2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-07-26/ch736/s1">July 26, 1956, ch. 736, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/656">70 Stat. 656</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/409/s7/a">Pub. L. 100–409, § 7(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-08-20">Aug. 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1091">102 Stat. 1091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7826dba3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7826dba4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7826dba5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41” substituted for “the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, which Act enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7826dba6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/409">Pub. L. 100–409</ref> substituted “National Forest System lands” for “national forest lands” and “a unit of the National Forest System” for “a national forest”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
