<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7826dc05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s521"><num value="521">§ 521.</num><heading> Lands acquired to be reserved, held, and administered as national forest lands; designation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s519">section 519 of this title</ref> the lands acquired under this Act shall be permanently reserved, held, and administered as national forest lands under the provisions of section 471 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002407">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002407"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title and acts supplemental to and amendatory thereof. And the Secretary of Agriculture may from time to time divide the lands acquired under this Act into such specific national forests and so designate the same as he may deem best for administrative purposes.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7826dc06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-01/ch186/s11">Mar. 1, 1911, ch. 186, § 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/963">36 Stat. 963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7826dc07-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7826dc08-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7826dc09-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/act/1911-03-01/ch186">act Mar. 1, 1911, ch. 186</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/961">36 Stat. 961</ref>, popularly known as the Weeks Law, which enacted this section, former sections 513 and 514 of this title, and sections 515 to 519, 552, and 563 of this title and amended sections 480 and 500 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s552">section 552 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s471">Section 471 of this title</ref>, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to section 24 of <ref href="/us/act/1891-03-03/ch561">act Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/1103">26 Stat. 1103</ref>, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/94/579/tVII/s704/a">Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 704(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2792">90 Stat. 2792</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
