<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78294c90-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s535"><num value="535">§ 535.</num><heading> Forest development roads; acquisition, construction, and maintenance; maximum economy; methods of financing; cost arrangements for construction standards; transfer of unused effective purchaser credit for road construction</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to provide for the acquisition, construction, and maintenance of forest development roads within and near the national forests and other lands administered by the Forest Service in locations and according to specifications which will permit maximum economy in harvesting timber from such lands tributary to such roads and at the same time meet the requirements for protection, development, and management thereof, and for utilization of the other resources thereof. Financing of such roads may be accomplished (1) by the Secretary utilizing appropriated funds, (2) by requirements on purchasers of national forest timber and other products, including provisions for amortization of road costs in contracts, (3) by cooperative financing with other public agencies and with private agencies or persons, or (4) by a combination of these methods: <i>Provided</i>, That where roads of a higher standard than that needed in the harvesting and removal of the timber and other products covered by the particular sale are to be constructed, the purchaser of the national forest timber and other products shall not be required to bear that part of the costs necessary to meet such higher standard, and the Secretary is authorized to make such arrangements to this end as may be appropriate. The Secretary is authorized, under such rules and regulations as he shall prescribe, to permit the transfer of unused effective purchaser credit for road construction earned after <date date="1975-12-16">December 16, 1975</date>, from one timber sale to a purchaser to another timber sale to the same purchaser within the same National Forest.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78294c91-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/657/s4">Pub. L. 88–657, § 4</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1089">78 Stat. 1089</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/154">Pub. L. 94–154</ref>, <date date="1975-12-16">Dec. 16, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/823">89 Stat. 823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78294c92-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78294c93-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78294c94-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/94/154">Pub. L. 94–154</ref> authorized the Secretary to permit the transfer of unused effective purchaser credit for road construction earned after <date date="1975-12-16">Dec. 16, 1975</date>, from one timber sale to a purchaser to another timber sale to the same purchaser within the same National Forest.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78294c95-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78294c96-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Financing of Forest Development Roads</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Financing of forest development roads authorized by cl. (2) of this section deemed “budget authority” and “budget outlays” as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621/a">section 621(a) of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and effective for purpose specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s651/a">section 651(a) of Title 2</ref>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1608">section 1608 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78294c97-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78294c98-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture under sections 532 to 538 of this title to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s533">section 533 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
