<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id782b95e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s539"><num value="539">§ 539.</num><heading> Additions to existing national forests; administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id782b95e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s539/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The following units of the National Forest System are hereby expanded:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id782b95e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s539/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Chugach National Forest by the addition of four areas, Nellie Juan, College Fjord, Copper/Rude River, and Controller Bay, containing approximately one million nine hundred thousand acres of public land, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Chugach National Forest additions—proposed”, and dated October 1978; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id782b95e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s539/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Tongass National Forest by the addition of three areas, Kates Needle, Juneau Icefield, and Brabazon Range, containing approximately one million four hundred and fifty thousand acres of public lands, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Tongass National Forest additions—proposed”, and dated October 1978.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id782b95e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s539/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Subject to valid existing rights, lands added to the Tongass and Chugach National Forests by this section shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with the applicable provisions of this Act and the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the national forest system: <i>Provided</i>, That the conservation of fish and wildlife and their habitat shall be the primary purpose for the management of the Copper/Rude River addition and the Copper River-Bering River portion of the existing Chugach National Forest, as generally depicted on the map appropriately referenced and dated October 1978: <i>Provided</i>, That the taking of fish and wildlife shall be permitted within zones established by this subsection pursuant to the provisions of this Act and other applicable State and Federal law. Multiple use activities shall be permitted in a manner consistent with the conservation of fish and wildlife and their habitat as set forth in special regulations which shall be promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id782b95ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/487/tV/s501">Pub. L. 96–487, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2398">94 Stat. 2398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id782b95eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id782b95ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id782b95ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/487">Pub. L. 96–487</ref>, <date date="1980-12-02">Dec. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2371">94 Stat. 2371</ref>, known as the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id782b95ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id782b95ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Chugach National Forest Boundary Change</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/415/s6">Pub. L. 102–415, § 6</ref>, <date date="1992-10-14">Oct. 14, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2113">106 Stat. 2113</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5/d/12">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(12)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3265">128 Stat. 3265</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/287/s5/d/12">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Boundary Adjustment</inline>.—</heading><content>The boundary of the Chugach National Forest, Alaska, is modified to include the approximately 9,300 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled ‘Official Map, Boundary Modification, Chugach National Forest’ and dated September 1988. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Chief of the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands brought within the boundary of the Chugach National Forest by subsection (a) are added to and shall be administered as part of the Chugach National Forest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this Act [see Short Title of 1992 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands] shall be construed to affect the validity of, or the terms and conditions of, any right-of-way, easement, lease, license, or permit on lands transferred by this section that is in existence on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-14">Oct. 14, 1992</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior shall delegate, as necessary, to the Secretary of Agriculture the authority to renew or reissue the authorizations described in paragraph (1). The change of administrative jurisdiction over these lands resulting from subsection (a) shall not constitute a ground for the denial of renewal or re­issuance of the authorizations described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Land and Water Conservation Fund Act</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100506">section 100506 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, the boundary of the Chugach National Forest, as modified by this section, shall be treated as if it were the boundary of the Chugach National Forest as of <date date="1965-01-01">January 1, 1965</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
