<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7839ee62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d"><num value="542d">§ 542d.</num><heading> Comprehensive management plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Boundaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The research site shall consist of approximately thirty-one thousand acres, including a principle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002422">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002422"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “principal”.</note> research facility of approximately one thousand acres. The boundaries are depicted on a map entitled “Langmuir Research Site”, dated August 1980, which is on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief, Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable, after <date date="1980-12-19">December 19, 1980</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall develop a comprehensive management plan for the research site consistent with requirements of the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (<ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Public Law 94–588</ref>) (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</ref>), which shall be incorporated into the initial Cibola National Forest land and resource management plan as provided for under that Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment in boundaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Following timely notice in writing to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate of his intention to do so, the Secretary may make minor adjustments in the boundaries of the research site to provide for more effective management or to encourage further research activity. For the purposes of this subsection, minor boundary adjustments shall not increase or decrease the amount of land within the research site by more than seven thousand acres.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee66-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with other public interest groups</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the plan, the Secretary shall consult with the National Science Foundation, the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology, the New Mexico Academy of Science and appropriate conservation, wilderness, wildlife, industry, and other public interest groups.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee67-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Objectives of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The plan shall prescribe specific research and management objectives necessary for the protection, management, and regulation of the research site as outlined in subsection (f) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7839ee68-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Management of site in accordance with the objectives</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The research site shall be managed in accordance with the following objectives:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7839ee69-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The principal research facility shall be managed primarily for scientific research purposes. Dispersed recreation, grazing, and other uses which the Secretary determines to be compatible with scientific research may be permitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7839ee6a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The research site shall be managed to enhance scientific research objectives. Scientific research activities and associated research equipment and structures shall be permitted within the research site in accordance with the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7839ee6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Roads shall be limited to those necessary for scientific research activities and other reasonable activities as determined by the Secretary. Motor vehicle use shall be restricted to roads designated in the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7839ee6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s542d/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The landing of small instrumented research rockets shall be permitted to continue in portions of the research site designated for such purposes in the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7839ee6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/550/tII/s205">Pub. L. 96–550, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3225">94 Stat. 3225</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s6/d/32">Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(32)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4584">108 Stat. 4584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7839ee6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7839ee6f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7839ee70-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Forest Management Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2949">90 Stat. 2949</ref>, which enacted sections 472a, 521b, 1600, and 1611 to 1614 of this title, amended sections 500, 515, 516, 518, 576b, and 1601 to 1610 of this title, repealed sections 476, 513, and 514 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 476, 513, 528, 594–2, and 1600 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1976 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">section 1600 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7839ee71-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committee on”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
