<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id783c5f37-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d"><num value="544d">§ 544d.</num><heading> Scenic area management plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f38-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Studies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after the date the Commission is established, it shall, in cooperation with the Secretary, complete the following studies for use in preparing the management plan:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f39-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Resource inventory</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall complete a resource inventory. The resource inventory shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f3a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> document all existing land uses, natural features and limitations, scenic, natural, cultural, archaeological and recreation and economic resources and activities: <i>Provided</i>, That the location of any Indian burial grounds, village sites, and other areas of archaeological or religious significance shall not be made public information and such information shall be used for administrative purposes only; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f3b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> incorporate without change the resource inventory developed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref> for the special management areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f3c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Economic opportunity study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall complete a study to identify opportunities to enhance the economies of communities in the scenic area in a manner consistent with the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f3d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Recreation assessment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall complete an assessment of recreation resources and opportunities for enhancement of these resources. The recreation assessment shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f3e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> designate the location and specify the construction of an interpretive center or other appropriate facility, to be located in the State of Oregon, and of a conference center or other appropriate facility, to be located in the State of Washington;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f3f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identify areas within the scenic area that are suitable for other public use facilities, including but not limited to educational and interpretive facilities, campsites, picnic areas, boat launch facilities and river access areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f40-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> subject to the treaty and other rights of Indian tribes, designate areas to provide increased access for recreation purposes to the Columbia River and its tributaries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f41-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> incorporate without change the recreation assessment developed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref> for the special management areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f42-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Land use designations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within two years after the Commission is established, it shall develop land use designations for the use of non-Federal lands within the scenic area. The land use designations shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f43-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be based on the results of the resource inventory developed pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section, and consistent with the standards established in subsection (d) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f44-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> designate those lands used or suitable for the production of crops, fruits or other agricultural products or the sustenance of livestock as agricultural lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f45-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> designate lands used or suitable for the production of forest products as forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f46-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> designate lands suitable for the protection and enhancement of open spaces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f47-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> designate areas in the scenic area outside special management areas used or suitable for commercial development: <i>Provided</i>, That such designation shall encourage, but not require, commercial development to take place in urban areas and shall take into account the physical characteristics of the areas in question and their geographic proximity to transportation, commercial, and industrial facilities and other amenities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> designate areas used or suitable for residential development, taking into account the physical characteristics of the areas in question and their geographic proximity to transportation and commercial facilities and other amenities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> incorporate without change the designation of urban areas established in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544b/e">section 544b(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Adoption of management plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within three years after the date the Commission is established, it shall adopt a management plan for the scenic area. The Commission shall adopt the management plan by a majority vote of the members appointed, including at least three members from each State. The management plan shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be based on the results of the resource inventory developed pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f4c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include land use designations developed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> be consistent with the standards established in subsection (d) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f4e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> incorporate without change the management direction for the use of Federal lands within and the land use designations for the special management areas adopted by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f4f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> include guidelines for the adoption of land use ordinances for lands within the scenic area. The guidelines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f50-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall incorporate without change the guidelines for the development of special management area land use ordinances developed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall not apply to urban areas designated in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544b/e">section 544b(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards for management plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The management plan and all land use ordinances and interim guidelines adopted pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title shall include provisions to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> protect and enhance agricultural lands for agricultural uses and to allow, but not require, conversion of agricultural lands to open space, recreation development or forest lands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> protect and enhance forest lands for forest uses and to allow, but not require, conversion of forest lands to agricultural lands, recreation development or open spaces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> protect and enhance open spaces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f56-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> protect and enhance public and private recreation resources and educational and interpretive facilities and opportunities, in accordance with the recreation assessment adopted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f57-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> prohibit major development actions in special management areas, except for partitions or short plats which the Secretary determines are desirable to facilitate land acquisitions pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f58-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> prohibit industrial development in the scenic area outside urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f59-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> require that commercial development outside urban areas take place without adversely affecting the scenic, cultural, recreation, or natural resources of the scenic area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f5a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> require that residential development outside urban areas take place without adversely affecting the scenic, cultural, recreation, and natural resources of the scenic area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783c5f5b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> require that the exploration, development and production of mineral resources, and the reclamation of lands thereafter, take place without adversely affecting the scenic, cultural, recreation and natural resources of the scenic area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f5c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency consultation and public involvement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the Commission shall exercise their responsibilities pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title in consultation with Federal, State, and local governments having jurisdiction within the scenic area or expertise pertaining to its administration and with Indian tribes. The Secretary and the Commission shall conduct public hearings and solicit public comment prior to final adoption of the management plan and the Commission shall conduct public hearings and solicit public comment prior to final adoption of land use ordinances. The Commission and the appropriate county shall promptly notify the Secretary, the States, local governments and Indian tribes of all proposed major development actions and residential development in the scenic area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f5d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Concurrence of management plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f5e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon adoption of the management plan, the Commission shall promptly submit the plan to the Secretary for review. If the Secretary agrees with the Commission that the management plan is consistent with the standards established in this section and the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title, the Secretary shall concur to that effect. Should the Secretary fail to act on the proposed plan within ninety days, the Secretary shall be deemed to have concurred on the management plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f5f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial of concurrence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If concurrence is denied, the Secretary shall state the reasons for finding the plan is inconsistent with the standards established in this section or the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title, and shall submit to the Commission suggested modifications to the management plan to make it consistent with such standards and the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f60-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission reconsideration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within one hundred and twenty days after receipt of notification of non-concurrence, the Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f61-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> revise and resubmit the plan to the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783c5f62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> by a vote of two-thirds of its membership, including a majority of the members appointed from each State, reject the suggested modifications of the Secretary and adopt a management plan consistent with the provisions of this section and the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Revision of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No sooner than five years after adoption of the management plan, but at least every ten years, the Commission shall review the management plan to determine whether it should be revised. The Commission shall submit any revised management plan to the Secretary for review and concurrence, in accordance with the provisions of this section for adoption of the management plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783c5f64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544d/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Amendment of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Commission determines at any time that conditions within the scenic area have significantly changed, it may amend the management plan. The Commission shall submit amendments to the management plan to the Secretary for review, in accordance with the provisions of this section for adoption of the management plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id783c5f65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/663/s6">Pub. L. 99–663, § 6</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4279">100 Stat. 4279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
