<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id783ea8e1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k"><num value="544k">§ 544k.</num><heading> Tributary rivers and streams</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea8e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Water resources projects</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following rivers and streams shall be subject to the same restrictions on the licensing, permitting, and exempting from licensing and the construction of water resource projects as provided for components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System pursuant to section 7(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1278/a">16 U.S.C. 1278(a)</ref>):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any tributary river or stream to the Columbia River not designated in subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002430">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002430"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (c) or (d) of this section or otherwise specified in this subsection which flows in whole or in part through a special management area, unless the construction of a water resources project would not have a direct and adverse effect on the scenic, cultural, recreation, and natural resources of the scenic area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any river or river segment which flows in whole or in part through the scenic area and which is established pursuant to State law as a wild, scenic, or recreation river or which is under study pursuant to State law for the potential inclusion in any such State protected river system, unless such project or projects meet terms and conditions set by State agencies exercising administration over such river or river segment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the Wind River, Washington, for a period not less than three years following the later of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea8e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> final approval of the Gifford Pinchot National Forest Plan, adopted pursuant to the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (Act of <date date="1976-10-22">October 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Public Law 94–588</ref>, as amended) (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">16 U.S.C. 1600</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea8e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> submittal by the Secretary of a report to the President on the suitability or nonsuitability for addition to the national wild and scenic rivers system and a report by the President to the Congress of recommendations and proposals with respect to the designation of such river under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1271">16 U.S.C. 1271</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Hood River, Oregon, if such facility impounds or diverts water other than by means of a dam or diversion existing as of <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the segment of the Little White Salmon, Washington, from the Willard National Fish Hatchery to its confluence with the Columbia River if such facility impounds or diverts water other than by means of a dam or diversion existing as of <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea8ea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544k/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to those portions of tributary rivers or streams to the Columbia River which flow through or border on Indian reservations. Nothing in this section shall apply to or affect any segment of any river designated as a wild and scenic river under section 3 of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1274">16 U.S.C. 1274</ref>) or any river designated for study under section 5 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1276">16 U.S.C. 1276</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id783ea8eb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/663/s13/a">Pub. L. 99–663, § 13(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4293">100 Stat. 4293</ref>, 4294; <ref href="/us/pl/111/11/tI/s1203/b">Pub. L. 111–11, title I, § 1203(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1012">123 Stat. 1012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id783ea8ec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id783ea8ed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id783ea8ee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c) or (d) of this section, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is subsec. (c) or (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/663/s13">section 13 of Pub. L. 99–663</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4294">100 Stat. 4294</ref>, which amended sections 1274(a) and 1276(a), respectively, of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Forest Management Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/588">Pub. L. 94–588</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2949">90 Stat. 2949</ref>, which enacted sections 472a, 521b, 1600, and 1611 to 1614 of this title, amended sections 500, 515, 516, 518, 576b, and 1601 to 1610 of this title, repealed sections 476, 513, and 514 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 476, 513, 528, 594–2, and 1600 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1976 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1600">section 1600 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/542">Pub. L. 90–542</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/906">82 Stat. 906</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 28 (§ 1271 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1271">section 1271 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id783ea8ef-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/663/s13">Section 13 of Pub. L. 99–663</ref>, which enacted this section, consisted of subsecs. (a) to (d). Subsecs. (a) and (b) of section 13 were classified to this section, and subsecs. (c) and (d) of section 13 amended sections 1274 and 1276 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id783ea8f0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/11">Pub. L. 111–11</ref> struck out “for a period not to exceed twenty years from <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>,” before “if such facility”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
