<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id783ea8f1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l"><num value="544l">§ 544l.</num><heading> Implementation measures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea8f2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance to counties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis to counties for the development of land use ordinances prescribed by sections 544e and 544f of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event a county fails to obtain approval by the Commission for a land use ordinance within three years after the date technical assistance is first provided under this subsection for the development of a land use ordinance, the Secretary shall terminate all technical assistance for any participation in the development of such ordinance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea8f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of timber receipts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea8f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s500">section 500 of this title</ref>, that portion of which is paid under such provisions to the State of Oregon with respect to the special management areas within the Mount Hood National Forest, the Gates of the Columbia Gorge Special Management Area, Mount Hood National Forest, and to the State of Washington with respect to the special management areas within the Gifford Pinchot National Forest—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not less than 50 per centum shall be expended for the benefit of the public schools of the county which has adopted implementation measures pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the remainder shall be expended for the benefit of public roads or any public purposes of any county which has adopted implementation measures pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea8f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to any amount paid by the Secretary of the Treasury under the provisions of law referred to in subsection (b)(1) at the end of any fiscal year ending before <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for a particular county, if the county does not have in effect a land use ordinance which has been found consistent by the Commission and concurred on by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea8fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments to local governments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea8fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544n/b">section 544n(b) of this title</ref>, in the case of any land or interest therein acquired by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544g">section 544g of this title</ref>, which was subject to local real property taxes within the five years preceding such acquisition and which is located in a county which has in effect a land use ordinance which has been found consistent by the Commission and concurred on by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544f">section 544f of this title</ref>, the Secretary is authorized and directed to make annual payments to the county in which such lands are located in an amount equal to 1 per centum of the fair market value of such land or interest therein on the date of acquisition by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea8fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, any payment made for any fiscal year to a county pursuant to this subsection shall not exceed the amount of real property taxes assessed and levied on such property during the last full fiscal year before the fiscal year in which such land or interest therein was acquired by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea8fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no payment shall be made under this subsection with respect to any land or interest therein after the eighth full fiscal year beginning after the first fiscal year in which such a payment was made with respect to such land or interest therein.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea8ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of certain payments</inline>.—</heading><content>For any land or interest in land for which the Secretary is making a payment in fiscal year 2000, such payment shall be continued for a total of eight fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea900-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal consistency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e) or in section 544<i>o</i> of this title, Federal agencies having responsibilities within the scenic area shall exercise such responsibilities consistent with the provisions of sections 544 to 544p of this title as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea901-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on Federal expenditures affecting the scenic area</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea902-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), if the Commission has not been established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544c">section 544c of this title</ref> within fifteen months after <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>, or is otherwise disestablished for any reason, no new expenditures or new financial assistance may be made available, and no new license or new permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement, shall be issued, under authority of any Federal law for any activity within the scenic area, excluding urban areas, which the Secretary,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002431">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002431"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> determines is inconsistent with any implementation measure pursuant to, the standards established in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b">section 544d(b) of this title</ref>, or the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea903-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea904-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea905-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> An expenditure or financial assistance made available under authority of Federal law shall be treated, for purposes of this subsection, as a new expenditure or new financial assistance if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea906-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in any case with respect to which specific appropriations are required, no money for construction or purchase was appropriated before <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea907-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> no legally binding commitment for the expenditure or financial assistance was made before <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea908-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Payments made to the State pursuant to the following Acts shall not be treated as an expenditure or financial assistance for purposes of this subsection: <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s500">section 500 of this title</ref>; the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s181">30 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.]; chapter 69 of title 31 (relating to payments in lieu of taxes for entitlement land); the Act of <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/218">39 Stat. 218</ref>), and the Act of <date date="1919-02-26">Feb. 26, 1919</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/40/1179">40 Stat. 1179</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea909-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A license or permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement, shall be treated, for purposes of this subsection, as a new license or new permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement, if such license or permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement, was issued on or after <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>. A renewal under similar terms and conditions of a license or permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement, issued before <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>, shall not be treated as a new license or new permit, or exemption from a license or permit requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea90a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the appropriate Federal officer, after consultation with the Secretary, may make Federal expenditures or financial assistance available within the area for any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea90b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The maintenance of existing channel improvements and related structures, and including the disposal of dredge materials related to such improvements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea90c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The maintenance, replacement, reconstruction, or repair, but not the expansion, of publicly owned or publicly operated roads, structures, or facilities that are essential links in a larger network or system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea90d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Military activities essential to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id783ea90e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Any of the following actions or projects, but only if the making available of expenditures or assistance therefor is consistent with the standards in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s544d/b">section 544d(b) of this title</ref> and the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea90f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Projects for the study, management, protection and enhancement of fish and wildlife resources and habitats, including, but not limited to, acquisition of fish and wildlife habitats and related lands, stabilization projects for fish and wildlife habitats, and recreational projects.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea910-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The establishment, operation, and maintenance of air and water navigation aids and devices, and for access thereto.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea911-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Projects under chapter 2003 of title 54 and the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea912-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Scientific research, including but not limited to aeronautical, atmospheric, space, geologic, marine, fish and wildlife, and other research, development, and applications.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea913-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Assistance for emergency actions essential to the saving of lives and the protection of property and the public health and safety, if such actions are performed pursuant to sections 305 and 306 of the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5145">42 U.S.C. 5145</ref> and 5146) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002432">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002432"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and section 1362 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4103">42 U.S.C. 4103</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002432">2</ref> and are limited to actions that are necessary to alleviate the emergency.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea914-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The maintenance, replacement, reconstruction, or repair, but not the expansion, of publicly owned or publicly operated roads, structures, or facilities. This clause shall not apply to roads, structures, or facilities referred to in paragraph (3)(B).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id783ea915-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/3/D/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> Nonstructural projects for shoreline stabilization that are designed to mimic, enhance, or restore natural stabilization systems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea916-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall, on behalf of each Federal agency concerned, make written certification that each such agency has complied with the provisions of this subsection during each fiscal year beginning after <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>. Such certification shall be submitted on an annual basis to the House of Representatives and the Senate pursuant to the schedule required under the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id783ea917-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed as indicating an intent on the part of the Congress to change the existing relationship of other Federal laws to the law of a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or to relieve any person or any obligation imposed by any law of any State, or political subdivision of a State. No provision of this subsection shall be construed to invalidate any provision of State or local law unless there is a direct conflict between such provision and the law of the State, or political subdivision of the State, so that the two cannot be reconciled or consistently stand together. This subsection shall in no way be interpreted to interfere with a State’s right to protect, rehabilitate, preserve, and restore lands within its established boundary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id783ea918-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s544l/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of public lands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to valid existing rights, all public lands within the scenic area administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Land Management are hereby transferred without consideration to the jurisdiction of the Secretary to be managed as National Forest lands in accordance with the provisions of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id783ea919-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/663/s14">Pub. L. 99–663, § 14</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4294">100 Stat. 4294</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/291/tIII/s346/e">Pub. L. 106–291, title III, § 346(e)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-11">Oct. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1000">114 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5/d/16">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(16)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3265">128 Stat. 3265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id783ea91a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id783ea91b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id783ea91c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(ii), is <ref href="/us/act/1920-02-25/ch85">act Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/437">41 Stat. 437</ref>, known as the Mineral Leasing Act, which is classified generally to chapter 3A (§ 181 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s181">section 181 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1916-06-09">June 9, 1916</date>, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(ii), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-06-09/ch137">act June 9, 1916, ch. 137</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/218">39 Stat. 218</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1919-02-26">Feb. 26, 1919</date>, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(ii), is <ref href="/us/act/1919-02-26/ch47">act Feb. 26, 1919, ch. 47</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1179">40 Stat. 1179</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, referred to in subsec. (e)(3)(D)(iii), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref> as added by <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1280">86 Stat. 1280</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1451 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Disaster Relief Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (e)(3)(D)(v), was renamed The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and was substantially revised by <ref href="/us/pl/100/707">Pub. L. 100–707</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4689">102 Stat. 4689</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s102/b">Section 102(b) of Pub. L. 100–707</ref> provided that a reference in any other law to a provision of the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 shall be deemed to be a reference to such provision of The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act was renamed the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act by <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 106–390, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1572">114 Stat. 1572</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s105/d">Section 105(d) of Pub. L. 100–707</ref> repealed sections 305 and 306 of the Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5145">42 U.S.C. 5145</ref> and 5146) and redesignated sections 308 and 309 of the Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5148">42 U.S.C. 5148</ref> and 5149), and any references thereto, as sections 305 and 306, respectively. For corresponding provisions to former sections 305 and 306 of the Act, see sections 5170a, 5170b, and 5192 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1362 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4103">42 U.S.C. 4103</ref>), referred to in subsec. (e)(3)(D)(v), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tV/s551/a">Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 551(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2269">108 Stat. 2269</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (e)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/344">Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/297">88 Stat. 297</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id783ea91d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (e)(3)(D)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (e)(3)(D)(iii) by substituting “chapter 2003 of title 54” for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</ref><i>l</i>–4 through 11)”, was executed by making the substitution for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s4601–4">16 U.S.C. 4601–4</ref> through 11)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/291">Pub. L. 106–291</ref> inserted par. heading, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted subpar. heading, substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no payment” for “No payment”, substituted “eighth full fiscal year” for “fifth full fiscal year”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
