<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7845d60b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s568"><num value="568">§ 568.</num><heading> Cooperation by Secretary of Agriculture with States in establishing, etc., wood lots, shelter belts, windbreaks, etc.; limitation on expenditure; authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed, in cooperation with the land grant colleges and universities of the various States or, in his discretion, with other suitable State agencies, to aid farmers through advice, education, demonstrations, and other similar means in establishing, renewing, protecting, and managing wood lots, shelter belts, windbreaks, and other valuable forest growth, and in harvesting, utilizing, and marketing the products thereof. Except for preliminary investigations, the amount expended by the Federal Government under this section in cooperation with any State or other cooperating agency during any fiscal year shall not exceed the amount expended by the State or other cooperating agency for the same purpose during the same fiscal year, and the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make expenditures on the certificate of the appropriate State official that the State expenditures, as provided for in this section, have been made. There is authorized to be appropriated annually out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, not more than $500,000 to enable the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7845d60c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1924-06-07/ch348/s5">June 7, 1924, ch. 348, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/654">43 Stat. 654</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-26/ch735/s3">Oct. 26, 1949, ch. 735, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/910">63 Stat. 910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7845d60d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7845d60e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7845d60f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Act <date date="1949-10-26">Oct. 26, 1949</date>, enlarged and clarified the Federal-State educational program with small forest-land owners, and increased the annual appropriations from $100,000 to $500,000.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7845d610-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7845d611-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fiscal Year Transition Period of <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, Through <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, Deemed Fiscal Year for Purposes of Matching Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Fiscal year transition period of <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, through <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, deemed fiscal year for purposes of this section relating to matching requirements, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/274/s202/2">section 202(2) of Pub. L. 94–274</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/392">90 Stat. 392</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2652">section 2652 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7845d612-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Contributions by States, etc.</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412/tII/s208">Act Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412, title II, § 208</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/736">58 Stat. 736</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412/tII/s208">“No part of any appropriation which is available for carrying out the Cooperative Farm Forestry Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s568b">16 U.S.C. 568b</ref>) [repealed] and sections 4 and 5 of the Clarke-McNary Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s567">16 U.S.C. 567</ref> [repealed], 568) shall be expended in any State or Territory unless the State or Territory, or local subdivision thereof, or individuals, or associations contribute a sum equal to that to be allotted therefrom by the Government or make contributions other than money deemed by the Secretary to be the value equivalent thereof.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78484613-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations Available for 3 Years</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412/tII/s209">Act Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412, title II, § 209</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/737">58 Stat. 737</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412/tII/s209">“Appropriations for carrying out the Cooperative Farm Forestry Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s568b">16 U.S.C. 568b</ref>) [repealed] and sections 4 and 5 of the Clarke-McNary Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s567">16 U.S.C. 567</ref> [repealed], 568) and Acts supplementary thereto allocated for the production or procurement of nursery stock by any Federal agency, or funds appropriated to any Federal agency for allocation to cooperating States for the production or procurement of nursery stock, shall remain available for expenditure for not more than three fiscal years.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
