<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7848467d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s577a"><num value="577a">§ 577a.</num><heading> Conserving shore line beauty for recreational use of public lands in northern Minnesota; regulation of logging</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The principle of conserving the natural beauty of shore lines for recreational use shall apply to all Federal lands which border upon any boundary lake or stream contiguous to this area, or any other lake or stream within this area which is now or eventually to be in general use for boat or canoe travel, and that for the purpose of carrying out this principle logging of all such shores to a depth of four hundred feet from the natural water line is forbidden except as the Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture may see fit in particular instances to vary the distance for practical reasons: <i>Provided</i>, That in no case shall logging of any timber other than diseased, insect infested, dying, or dead be permitted closer to the natural shore line than two hundred feet, except where necessary to open areas for banking grounds, landings, and other uses connected with logging operations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7848467e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-07-10/ch881/s2">July 10, 1930, ch. 881, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1021">46 Stat. 1021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7848467f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78484680-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78484681-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
