<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id784a8fc2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e"><num value="579e">§ 579e.</num><heading> Forest service budget restructure</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish the ‘Forest Service Operations’ account not later than <date date="2020-10-01">October 1, 2020</date>, for the necessary expenses of the Forest Service: (1) for the base salary and expenses of employees in the Chief’s Office, the Work Environment and Performance Office, the Business Operations Deputy Area, and the Chief Financial Officer’s Office to carry out administrative and general management support functions; (2) for the costs of facility maintenance, repairs, and leases for buildings and sites; (3) for the costs of utility and communication expenses, business services, and information technology, including cybersecurity requirements; and (4) for such other administrative support function expenses necessary for the operation of the Forest Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Subsequent to the establishment of the account under subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture may execute appropriations of the Department for fiscal year 2021 as provided pursuant to such subsection, including any continuing appropriations made available for fiscal year 2021 before enactment of a regular appropriations Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture may transfer any unobligated balances made available to the Forest Service by this or prior appropriations Acts to the account established under subsection (a) to carry out such subsection, and shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives within 5 days of such transfer: <i>Provided</i>, That no amounts may be transferred from amounts that were made available for wildfire suppression operations pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s901/b/2/F">section 901(b)(2)(F) of title 2</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2020-11-01">November 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish the preliminary baseline for application of transfer authorities and submit the report specified in paragraph (2) to the Committees on Appropriations for the Senate and the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id784a8fc8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The report required in this subsection shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id784a8fc9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a delineation of the amount and account of each transfer made pursuant to subsection (b) or (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id784a8fca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a table for each appropriation with a separate column to display the fiscal year 2020 enacted levels, adjustments made by Congress, adjustments due to enacted rescissions, if appropriate, and adjustments made pursuant to the transfer authority in subsection (b) or (c), and the resulting fiscal year level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id784a8fcb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a delineation in the table for each appropriation, adjusted as described in paragraph (2), both by budget activity and program, project, and activity as detailed in the Budget Appendix; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id784a8fcc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579e/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an identification of funds directed for a specific activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id784a8fcd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dD/tIV/s435">Pub. L. 116–94, div. D, title IV, § 435</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2750">133 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
