<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id784a8fce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s579f"><num value="579f">§ 579f.</num><heading> Forest Service Nonrecurring Expenses Fund</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Forest Service Nonrecurring Expenses Fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds, and discretionary no-year funds at least four years old and deemed by the Chief of the Forest Service no longer needed for their intended purpose, appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year from the general fund of the Treasury to the Forest Service by this or any other Act may be transferred into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, and in addition to such other funds as may be available, for information technology; administrative expenses such as, but not limited to, utility and lease payments; facilities infrastructure maintenance, improvements, and construction; and roads infrastructure maintenance, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may not be obligated without written notification to and the prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate in conformance with the reprogramming guidelines described in this Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id784a8fcf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dE/tIV/s444">Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title IV, § 444</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/297">138 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id784a8fd0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id784a8fd1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id784a8fd2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act”, referred to in text, means div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/118/42">Pub. L. 118–42</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/220">138 Stat. 220</ref>, see Definitions note set out below. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id784a8fd3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id784a8fd4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “this Act” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/42/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 118–42</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s1">section 1 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
