<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78569dc8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590m"><num value="590m">§ 590m.</num><heading> Execution of powers of Secretary by Production and Marketing Administration</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized and directed to provide for the execution by the Production and Marketing Administration of such powers conferred upon him under sections 590g, 590h, 590i, and 590j to 590n of this title as he deems may be appropriately exercised by such Administration, and for such purposes the provisions of law applicable to the appointment and compensation of persons employed by the Production and Marketing Administration shall apply.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78569dc9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-04-27/ch85/s13">Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 13</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1936-02-29/ch104/s1">Feb. 29, 1936, ch. 104, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1151">49 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 501, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7877, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78569dca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78569dcb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78569dcc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Production and Marketing Administration functions transferred to other units of Department of Agriculture under Secretary’s memorandum 1320, supp. 4, of <date date="1953-11-02">Nov. 2, 1953</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Agriculture Adjustment Administration consolidated into Production and Marketing Administration by Secretary of Agriculture’s Memorandum No. 1118, <date date="1945-08-18">Aug. 18, 1945</date>, which consolidation was ratified by 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Crop Insurance Corporation consolidated with other agencies into Agricultural Conservation and Adjustment Administration for duration of World War II, see Ex. Ord. No. 9069, <date date="1942-02-23">Feb. 23, 1942</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions respecting lands under jurisdiction of Department of the Interior, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590a">section 590a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
