<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78569dec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590q–1"><num value="590q–1">§ 590q–1.</num><heading> Sale and distribution of supplies, materials, and equipment to other Government agencies; reimbursement</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Soil Conservation Service subject to applicable regulations under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3306(f), 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4104, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 may sell and distribute supplies, materials, and equipment to other Government activities, the cost of such supplies and materials or the value of such equipment (including the cost of transportation and handling) to be reimbursed to appropriations current at the time additional supplies, materials, or equipment are procured from the appropriations chargeable with the cost or value of such supplies, materials, or equipment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78569ded-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412">Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title III, § 302(b), <ref href="/us/stat/58/738">58 Stat. 738</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-31/ch654/s2/12">Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 2(12)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/707">65 Stat. 707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78569dee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78569def-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78569df0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Agriculture Organic Act of 1944, and not as part of the Soil Conservation and Domestic Allotment Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3306(f), 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4104, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41” substituted for “the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended,” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, which Act enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78569df1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-10-31">Oct. 31, 1951</date>, inserted reference to applicable regulations of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
