<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7858e85d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7"><num value="590z–7">§ 590z–7.</num><heading> Provisions for furnishing surplus power and municipal or miscellaneous water supplies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e85e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In connection with any project undertaken pursuant to this subchapter, provisions, including contracts of sale, may be made for furnishing municipal or miscellaneous water supplies, or for developing and furnishing power in addition to the power requirements of irrigation: <i>Provided</i>, That expenditures from appropriations made directly pursuant to the authority contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590z–10/1">section 590z–10(1) of this title</ref> to meet costs allocated to municipal or miscellaneous water supplies or surplus power shall not exceed $500,000 for any one project: <i>Provided further</i>, That no contract relating to a water supply for municipal or miscellaneous purposes or to electric power shall be made unless, in the judgment of the Secretary, it will not impair the efficiency of the project for irrigation purposes. On any project where such provisions are made, the Secretary shall allocate to municipal or miscellaneous water purposes or to surplus power the part of the estimated construction costs of the project which he deems properly so allocable; and such allocations shall not be included in the reimbursable construction costs covered by the repayment contract or contracts required under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590z–2">section 590z–2 of this title</ref>. All right, title, and interest in the facilities provided for such municipal or miscellaneous water supplies or surplus power and the revenues derived therefrom shall be and remain in the United States. Contracts for such municipal or miscellaneous water supplies or for such surplus power shall be at such rates as, in the Secretary’s judgment, will produce revenues at least sufficient to cover the appropriate share of the annual operation and maintenance cost of the project and such fixed charges, including interest, as the Secretary deems proper. Contracts for the sale of surplus power shall be for periods not to exceed forty years and contracts for water supply for municipal or miscellaneous purposes shall be for such periods as the Secretary may determine and may include such renewal options as the Secretary deems desirable: <i>And provided further</i>, That in sales or leases of such power, preference shall be given to municipalities and other public corporations or agencies; and also to cooperatives and other nonprofit organizations financed in whole or in part by loans made pursuant to the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.] and any amendments thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e85f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain leases authorized</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e860-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7858e861-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may enter into leases of power privileges for electric power generation in connection with any project constructed pursuant to this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7858e862-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall have authority over any project constructed pursuant to this subchapter in addition to and alternative to any existing authority relating to a particular project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e863-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In entering into a lease of power privileges under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall use the processes, terms, and conditions applicable to a lease under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s485h/c">section 485h(c) of title 43</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e864-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings not required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No findings under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590z–1">section 590z–1 of this title</ref> shall be required for a lease under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e865-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights retained by lessee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided under paragraph (5), all right, title, and interest in and to installed power facilities constructed by non-Federal entities pursuant to a lease under paragraph (1), and any direct revenues derived from that lease, shall remain with the lessee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e866-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Lease charges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590z–6">section 590z–6 of this title</ref>, lease charges shall be credited to the project from which the power is derived.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7858e867-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s590z–7/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section alters or affects any agreement in effect on <date date="2014-12-19">December 19, 2014</date>, for the development of hydropower projects or disposition of revenues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7858e868-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1939-08-11/ch717/s9">Aug. 11, 1939, ch. 717, § 9</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1940-10-14/ch861">Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 861</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1124">54 Stat. 1124</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dB/tXXX/s3087">Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3087</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3857">128 Stat. 3857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7858e869-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7858e86a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7858e86b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rural Electrification Act of 1936, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-05-20/ch432">act May 20, 1936, ch. 432</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1363">49 Stat. 1363</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 31 (§ 901 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">section 901 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7858e86c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
