<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id785da292-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c"><num value="620c">§ 620c.</num><heading> Restriction on exports of unprocessed timber from State and other public lands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da293-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Order to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (g), the Secretary of Commerce shall issue orders to prohibit the export from the United States of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, as provided in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da294-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule for determination to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da295-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> States with annual sales of 400,000,000 board feet or less</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to States with annual sales volumes of 400,000,000 board feet or less, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da296-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> States with annual sales of greater than 400,000,000 board feet</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to any State with an annual sales volume greater than 400,000,000 board feet, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective as of <date date="1997-11-14">November 14, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da297-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on substitution</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da298-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), each order of the Secretary of Commerce under paragraph (1) or (2) shall also prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person from purchasing, directly or indirectly, unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da299-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such unprocessed timber would be used in substitution for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da29a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such person has, during the preceding 24-month period, exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da29b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The prohibitions referred to in subparagraph (A) shall not apply in a State on or after the date on which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da29c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Governor of that State provides the Secretary of Commerce with notification of a prior program under subparagraph (C) of subsection (d)(2),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da29d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Secretary of Commerce approves a program of that State under subparagraph (A) of subsection (d)(2), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da29e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> regulations of the Secretary of Commerce issued under subsection (c) to carry out this section take effect,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">whichever occurs first.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da29f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1995-06-01">June 1, 1995</date>, the Secretary of Commerce, in conjunction with the Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior, shall issue a report to the Congress on the effects of the reallocation, as a result of the enactment of sections 620 to 620j of this title, of public lands timber resources to the domestic timber processing sector, the ability of the domestic timber processing sector to meet domestic demand for forest products, the volume of transshipment of timber originating from public lands across State borders, the effectiveness of rules issued and administered by the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title and the effectiveness of State programs authorized under subsection (d), and trends in growth and productivity in the domestic timber processing sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration by the Secretary of Commerce</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Commerce shall, as soon as possible after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da2a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> determine the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber to be prohibited from export in each State that is subject to an order issued under subsection (a);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da2a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> administer the prohibitions consistent with sections 620 to 620j of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da2a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> ensure that the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber prohibited from export within each State is representative of the species, grades, and geographic origin of timber comprising the total timber sales program of the State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785da2a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The actions and regulations of the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a State that is administering and enforcing a program under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to enter into agreements with Federal and State agencies with appropriate jurisdiction to assist the Secretary in carrying out sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorized State programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of new State programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (c), the Governor of any State may submit a program to the Secretary of Commerce for approval that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785da2ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> implements, with respect to unprocessed timber originating from public lands in that State, the prohibition on exports set forth in the Secretary’s order under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785da2ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensures that the species, grades, and geographic origin of unprocessed timber prohibited from export within the State is representative of the species, grades, and geographic origin of timber comprising the total timber sales program of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval of State programs</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2ae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Program approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the submission of a program under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Commerce shall approve the program unless the Secretary finds that the program will result in the export of unprocessed timber from public lands in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title and publishes that finding in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> State program in lieu of Federal program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary of Commerce approves a program submitted under paragraph (1), the Governor of the State for which the program was submitted, or such other official of that State as the Governor may designate, may administer and enforce the program, which shall apply in that State in lieu of the regulations issued under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Prior State programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, the Governor of any State that had, before <date date="1993-05-04">May 4, 1993</date>, issued regulations under this subsection as in effect before <date date="1993-05-04">May 4, 1993</date>, may provide the Secretary of Commerce with written notification that the State has a program that was in effect on <date date="1993-05-03">May 3, 1993</date>, and that meets the requirements of paragraph (1). Upon such notification, that State may administer and enforce that program in that State until the end of the 9-month period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Commerce issues regulations under subsection (c), and that program shall, during the period in which it is so administered and enforced, apply in that State in lieu of the regulations issued under subsection (c). Such Governor may submit, with such notification, the program for approval by the Secretary under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prior contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall apply to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id785da2b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> any contract for the purchase of unprocessed timber originating from public lands that was entered into before—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785da2b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1990-09-10">September 10, 1990</date>, with respect to States with annual sales volumes of 400,000,000 board feet or less; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785da2b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, with respect to States with annual sales volumes greater than 400,000,000 board feet; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id785da2b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any contract under which exports of unprocessed timber were permitted pursuant to an order of the Secretary of Commerce in effect under this section before <date date="1992-10-23">October 23, 1992</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Western red cedar</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede section 4606(i) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002463">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002463"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 50.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized, after suitable notice and a public comment period of not less than 120 days, to suspend the provisions of this section if a panel of experts has reported to the Dispute Settlement Body of the World Trade Organization (as the term “World Trade Organization” is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501/8">section 3501(8) of title 19</ref>), or a ruling issued under the formal dispute settlement proceeding provided under any other trade agreement finds, that the provisions of this section are in violation of, or inconsistent with, United States obligations under that trade agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal or modifications of State restrictions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Based upon a determination that it is in the national economic interest, the President may remove or modify any prohibition on exports from public lands in a State if that State petitions the President to remove or modify such prohibition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of prior Federal law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision of Federal law which imposes requirements with respect to the generation of revenue from State timberlands and was enacted before <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>, shall be construed to invalidate, supersede, or otherwise affect any action of a State or political subdivision of a State pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Surplus timber</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The prohibitions on exports contained in orders of the Secretary of Commerce issued under subsection (a) shall not apply to specific quantities of grades and species of unprocessed timber originating from public lands which the Secretary concerned determines by rule to be surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States. Any such determination may, by rule, be withdrawn by the Secretary concerned if the Secretary determines that the affected timber is no longer surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of prohibitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, beginning on <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>, and annually thereafter, if the President finds, upon review of the purposes and implementation of sections 620 to 620j of this title, that the prohibitions on exports required by subsection (a) no longer promote the purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title, then the President may suspend such prohibitions, except that such suspension shall not take effect until 90 days after the President notifies the Congress of such finding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785da2bc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s620c/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing authority not affected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in sections 620 to 620j of this title shall be construed to limit the authority of the President or the United States Trade Representative to take action authorized by law to respond appropriately to any measures taken by a foreign government in connection with sections 620 to 620j of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id785da2bd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/382/tIV/s491">Pub. L. 101–382, title IV, § 491</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/719">104 Stat. 719</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2</ref>, <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/223">107 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tVI/s602/b">Pub. L. 105–83, title VI, § 602(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1620">111 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/36/tI/s1002/a/2">Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/133">113 Stat. 133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id785da2be-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id785da2bf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id785da2c0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4606/i">Section 4606(i) of title 50</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXVII/s1766/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVII, § 1766(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2232">132 Stat. 2232</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id785da2c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/106/36">Pub. L. 106–36</ref> substituted “Dispute Settlement Body of the World Trade Organization (as the term ‘World Trade Organization’ is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501/8">section 3501(8) of title 19</ref>)” for “Contracting Parties to the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/83">Pub. L. 105–83</ref> struck out “the following shall apply:” in introductory provisions, substituted “the Secretary” for “(A) The Secretary” and “as of <date date="1997-11-14">November 14, 1997</date>” for “during the period beginning on <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>, and ending on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>”, and struck out subpar. (B) which read as follows: “For all periods on or after <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) of this section not later than <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>. Such order shall prohibit the export of the lesser of 400,000,000 board feet or the annual sales volume in that State of unprocessed timber originating from public lands.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2/1">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2(1)</ref>, substituted “(g)” for “(e)” and “as provided” for “in the amounts specified”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2/2/A">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “, notwithstanding any other provision of law,” after “prohibit” and substituted “, effective <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>” for “not later than 21 days after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2/2/B">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A), redesignated subpar. (D) as (B) and substituted “annual sales volume in that State of unprocessed timber originating from public lands” for “total annual sales volume” at end, and struck out former subpars. (B) and (C). Prior to amendment, former subpars. (A) to (C) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) The Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) of this section not later than 21 days after <date date="1990-08-20">August 20, 1990</date>. Such order shall cover a period beginning 120 days after the issuance of such an order, or <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, whichever is earlier, and shall extend to <date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>. Such order shall prohibit the export of 75 percent of the annual sales volume in such State of unprocessed timber from public lands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) For the period beginning on <date date="1992-01-01">January 1, 1992</date>, and ending on <date date="1993-12-31">December 31, 1993</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, issue an order referred to in subsection (a) of this section not later than <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>. Such order shall prohibit the export of at least 75 percent of such State’s annual sales volume for this 2-year period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) For the period beginning on <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, and ending on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, the Secretary of Commerce shall, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, issue an order referred to in subsection (a) of this section not later than <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>. Such order shall prohibit the export of at least 75 percent of such State’s annual sales volume for this 2-year period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2/2/C">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2(2)(C)</ref>, (D), added par. (3), redesignated former par. (3) as (4), and substituted “the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title and the effectiveness of State programs authorized under subsection (d)” for “States pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s2/3">Pub. L. 103–45, § 2(3)</ref>, (4), added subsecs. (c) to (f), struck out former subsecs. (c) and (d) which related to basis for increase in volume prohibited from export and administrative provisions, respectively, and redesignated former subsecs. (e) to (j) as (g) to (<i>l</i>), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id785da2c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="id785da2c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Severability of Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/45/s4">Pub. L. 103–45, § 4</ref>, <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/228">107 Stat. 228</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/45/s4">“If any provision of this Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s620d">section 620d of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s620">section 620 of this title</ref>], or the amendments made by this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this Act and such amendments and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected by such invalidation.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id785da2c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension and Issuance of Order Under Subsection (b)(2)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/d/tIII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(d) [title III]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-181">110 Stat. 3009–181</ref>, 3009–223, which in part directed Secretary of Commerce to extend until <date date="1997-09-30">Sept. 30, 1997</date>, the order issued under subsec. (b)(2)(A) of this section and to issue an order under subsec. (b)(2)(B) of this section effective <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, was from the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997, and was not repeated in subsequent appropriations acts. Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/c/tIII/s333">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title III, § 333]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-156">110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–210; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/99/tI/s130">Pub. L. 104–99, title I, § 130</ref>, <date date="1996-01-26">Jan. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/34">110 Stat. 34</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
