<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76f7f89a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s63"><num value="63">§ 63.</num><heading> Transportation of birds, animals, or fish; violations of statute or rules or regulations for management, care, and preservation of parks; damage or spoliation; punishment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person or persons, or stage or express company, or railway company, who knows or has reason to believe that they were taken or killed contrary to the provisions of sections 57, 58, and 60 to 65 of this title, and who receives for transportation any of said animals, birds, or fish so killed, caught, or taken, or who shall violate any of the other provisions of said sections, or any rule or regulation that may be promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior, with reference to the management and care of the said parks, or either of them, or for the protection of the property therein for the preservation from injury or spoliation of timber, mineral deposits, other than those legally located prior to the passage of the respective Acts creating and establishing said parks, natural curiosities, or wonderful objects within said parks, or either of them, or for the protection of the animals, birds, or fish in the said parks, or either of them, or who shall within said parks commit any damage, injury, spoliation to or upon any building, fence, hedge, gate, guidepost, tree, wood, underwood, timber, garden, crops, vegetables, plants, land, springs, mineral deposits other than those legally located prior to the passage of the respective Acts creating and establishing said parks, natural curiosities, or other matter or thing growing or being thereon, or situated therein, shall be subject to the penalty provided for the violation of rules and regulations of the Secretary of the Interior authorized by section 3 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (Thirty-ninth Statutes, page 535), entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002008"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76f7f89b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1920-06-02/ch218/s5">June 2, 1920, ch. 218, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/732">41 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76f7f89c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76f7f89d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id76f7f89e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 3 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1916-08-25">August 25, 1916</date> (Thirty-ninth Statutes, page 535), entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, referred to in text, is section 3 of <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-25/ch408">act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/535">39 Stat. 535</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3">section 3 of this title</ref>. Section 3 of the Act was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1865/a">section 1865(a) of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, by <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref>, §§ 3, 4(a)(1), 7, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3094">128 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3260, 3272.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
