<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id786013ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s661"><num value="661">§ 661.</num><heading> Short title; authorization</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786013cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s661/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This Act may be cited as the “Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786013d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s661/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of recognizing the vital contribution of our wildlife resources to the Nation, the increasing public interest and significance thereof due to expansion of our national economy and other factors, and to provide that wildlife conservation shall receive equal consideration and be coordinated with other features of water-resource development programs through the effectual and harmonious planning, development, maintenance, and coordination of wildlife conservation and rehabilitation for the purposes of this Act in the United States, its Territories and possessions, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized (1) to provide assistance to, and cooperate with, Federal, State, and public or private agencies and organizations in the development, protection, rearing, and stocking of all species of wildlife, resources thereof, and their habitat, in controlling losses of the same from disease or other causes, in minimizing damages from overabundant species, in providing public shooting and fishing areas, including easements across public lands for access thereto, and in carrying out other measures necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act; (2) to make surveys and investigations of the wildlife of the public domain, including lands and waters or interests therein acquired or controlled by any agency of the United States; and (3) to accept donations of land and contributions of funds in furtherance of the purposes of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id786013d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-03-10/ch55/s1">Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/401">48 Stat. 401</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), (f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-14/ch965">Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 965</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1080">60 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/624/s2">Pub. L. 85–624, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/563">72 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/9/tVII/s7001/b/2/A">Pub. L. 116–9, title VII, § 7001(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/779">133 Stat. 779</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id786013d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id786013d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id786013d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1934-03-10/ch55">act Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/401">48 Stat. 401</ref>, known as the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act, which is classified generally to sections 661 to 666c–1 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id786013d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—<ref href="/us/pl/116/9">Pub. L. 116–9</ref> inserted section catchline, designated existing provisions as subsec. (b), inserted heading, and added subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/624">Pub. L. 85–624</ref> inserted provisions which relate to recognition of the vital contribution of wildlife resources to the Nation, the increasing public interest and significance thereof, and to equal consideration and coordination of wildlife conservation with other water-resources development programs, and which authorize the Secretary to provide public fishing areas, and to accept donations of lands and contributions of funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-08-14">Aug. 14, 1946</date>, amended section generally in order to promote more effectual planning and cooperation between Federal, State, public, and private agencies for the conservation and rehabilitation of wildlife.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id786013d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id786013d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2022 Amendment</heading><p>Section 1 of H.R. 5608, One Hundred Seventeenth Congress, as engrossed in the House of Representatives on <date date="2021-12-08">Dec. 8, 2021</date>, which was enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dHH/tV/s603">Pub. L. 117–328, div. HH, title V, § 603</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5996">136 Stat. 5996</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dHH/tV/s603">“This Act [probably means H.R. 5608 as enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/117/328">Pub. L. 117–328</ref>, enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s667i">section 667i of this title</ref>, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8302">section 8302 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s667i">section 667i of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Chronic Wasting Disease Research and Management Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id786013d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/624/s1">Pub. L. 85–624, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/563">72 Stat. 563</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/624/s1">“That the Act of <date date="1934-03-10">March 10, 1934</date>, as amended [sections 661 to 666c–1 of this title], and as further amended by this Act may be cited as the ‘Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id786013d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions, appropriations, records, and property of Secretary of the Interior and Fish and Wildlife Service of Department of the Interior which affect or relate to breeding, raising, producing, marketing, or any other phase of production or distribution of domestically raised fur-bearing animals, or the products thereof transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by section 2 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-04-30/ch242">act Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s399">section 399 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id786013da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/624/s4">Pub. L. 85–624, § 4</ref>, <date date="1958-08-12">Aug. 12, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/568">72 Stat. 568</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/624/s4">“There is authorized to be appropriated and expended such funds as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act [amending this section and sections 662 to 664 of this title and enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1008">section 1008 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id786013db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Soft- and Hard-Shell Clams</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1948-05-26/ch348">Act May 26, 1948, ch. 348</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/274">62 Stat. 274</ref>, directed the Fish and Wildlife Service to undertake, in cooperation with appropriate State and interstate agencies in accordance with the provisions of the Act of <date date="1946-08-14">August 14, 1946</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/60/1080">60 Stat. 1080</ref>), comprehensive studies of the soft-shell clam, Mya arenaria, and the hard-shell clam, Venus mercenaria, with particular respect to the biology, propagation, and methods of cultivation of such clams, required the Service to recommend appropriate measures for (1) arresting depletion in existing productive beds; (2) restoring to production beds formerly productive but now barren or unusable; (3) developing new areas which may be found suitable; (4) improving methods and techniques of digging, transplanting, and handling; and (5) otherwise increasing production and improving the quality of such clams for the benefit of both producers and consumers, and authorized for the five-year period beginning <date date="1948-07-01">July 1, 1948</date>, the sum of $250,000 to carry out the studies of the soft-shell clam and the sum of $250,000 to carry out the studies of the hard-shell clam.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id786013dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id786013dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of the Interior related to compliance with wildlife consultation in act <date date="1934-03-10">Mar. 10, 1934</date> (see Short Title note above), and such functions of Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture, insofar as they involve lands and programs under jurisdiction of that Department, related to compliance with act <date date="1934-03-10">Mar. 10, 1934</date>, with respect to pre-construction, construction, and initial operation of transportation system for Canadian and Alaskan natural gas transferred to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, until first anniversary of date of initial operation of Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, see Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1979, §§ 102(e), (f), 203(a), 44 F.R. 33663, 33666, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1373">93 Stat. 1373</ref>, 1376, effective <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System abolished and functions and authority vested in Inspector transferred to Secretary of Energy by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s3012/b">section 3012(b) of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, set out as an Abolition of Office of Federal Inspector note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719e">section 719e of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade. Functions and authority vested in Secretary of Energy subsequently transferred to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s720d/f">section 720d(f) of Title 15</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. III of 1940, § 3, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1232">54 Stat. 1232</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, consolidated Bureau of Fisheries and Bureau of Biological Survey with their respective functions into one agency in Department of the Interior to be known as the Fish and Wildlife Service, and abolished the office of Commissioner and Deputy Commissioner of Fisheries and transferred their functions to the consolidated agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, transferred Bureau of Fisheries in Department of Commerce, and its functions, to Department of the Interior; transferred functions of Secretary of Commerce relating to protection of fur seals and other fur-bearing animals to Secretary of the Interior; and transferred functions of Secretary of Agriculture relating to conservation of wildlife, game, and migratory birds to Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id786013de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13443. Facilitation of Hunting Heritage and Wildlife Conservation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13443, <date date="2007-08-16">Aug. 16, 2007</date>, 72 F.R. 46537, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. The purpose of this order is to direct Federal agencies that have programs and activities that have a measurable effect on public land management, outdoor recreation, and wildlife management, including the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture, to facilitate the expansion and enhancement of hunting opportunities and the management of game species and their habitat.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Federal Activities</i>. Federal agencies shall, consistent with agency missions:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Evaluate the effect of agency actions on trends in hunting participation and, where appropriate to address declining trends, implement actions that expand and enhance hunting opportunities for the public;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Consider the economic and recreational values of hunting in agency actions, as appropriate;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Manage wildlife and wildlife habitats on public lands in a manner that expands and enhances hunting opportunities, including through the use of hunting in wildlife management planning;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Work collaboratively with State governments to manage and conserve game species and their habitats in a manner that respects private property rights and State management authority over wildlife resources;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Establish short and long term goals, in cooperation with State and tribal governments, and consistent with agency missions, to foster healthy and productive populations of game species and appropriate opportunities for the public to hunt those species;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Ensure that agency plans and actions consider programs and recommendations of comprehensive planning efforts such as State Wildlife Action Plans, the North American Waterfowl Management Plan, and other range-wide management plans for big game and upland game birds;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Seek the advice of State and tribal fish and wildlife agencies, and, as appropriate, consult with the Sporting Conservation Council and other organizations, with respect to the foregoing Federal activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>North American Wildlife Policy Conference</i>. The Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality (Chairman) shall, in coordination with the appropriate Federal agencies and in consultation with the Sporting Conservation Council and in cooperation with State and tribal fish and wildlife agencies and the public, convene not later than 1 year after the date of this order, and periodically thereafter at such times as the Chairman deems appropriate, a White House Conference on North American Wildlife Policy (Conference) to facilitate the exchange of information and advice relating to the means for achieving the goals of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Recreational Hunting and Wildlife Resource Conservation Plan</i>. The Chairman shall prepare, consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations, in coordination with the appropriate Federal agencies and in consultation with the Sporting Conservation Council, and in cooperation with State and tribal fish and wildlife agencies, not later than 1 year following the conclusion of the Conference, a comprehensive Recreational Hunting and Wildlife Conservation Plan that incorporates existing and ongoing activities and sets forth a 10-year agenda for fulfilling the actions identified in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right, benefit, trust responsibility, or privilege, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, instrumentalities, or entities, its officers or employees, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
