<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7869b030-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee"><num value="668ee">§ 668ee.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b031-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “compatible use” means a wildlife-dependent recreational use or any other use of a refuge that, in the sound professional judgment of the Director, will not materially interfere with or detract from the fulfillment of the mission of the System or the purposes of the refuge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b032-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The terms “wildlife-dependent recreation” and “wildlife-dependent recreational use” mean a use of a refuge involving hunting, fishing, wildlife observation and photography, or environmental education and interpretation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b033-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “sound professional judgment” means a finding, determination, or decision that is consistent with principles of sound fish and wildlife management and administration, available science and resources, and adherence to the requirements of this Act and other applicable laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b034-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The terms “conserving”, “conservation”, “manage”, “managing”, and “management”, mean to sustain and, where appropriate, restore and enhance, healthy populations of fish, wildlife, and plants utilizing, in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws, methods and procedures associated with modern scientific resource programs. Such methods and procedures include, consistent with the provisions of this Act, protection, research, census, law enforcement, habitat management, propagation, live trapping and transplantation, and regulated taking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b035-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “Coordination Area” means a wildlife management area that is made available to a State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7869b036-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by cooperative agreement between the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and a State agency having control over wildlife resources pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s664">section 664 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7869b037-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> by long-term leases or agreements pursuant to title III of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act (<ref href="/us/stat/50/525">50 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1010">7 U.S.C. 1010</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b038-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “Director” means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or a designee of that Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b039-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The terms “fish”, “wildlife”, and “fish and wildlife” mean any wild member of the animal kingdom whether alive or dead, and regardless of whether the member was bred, hatched, or born in captivity, including a part, product, egg, or offspring of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “plant” means any member of the plant kingdom in a wild, unconfined state, including any plant community, seed, root, or other part of a plant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The terms “purposes of the refuge” and “purposes of each refuge” mean the purposes specified in or derived from the law, proclamation, executive order, agreement, public land order, donation document, or administrative memorandum establishing, authorizing, or expanding a refuge, refuge unit, or refuge subunit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “refuge” means a designated area of land, water, or an interest in land or water within the System, but does not include Coordination Areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b03f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The terms “State” and “United States” mean the several States of the United States, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b040-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “System” means the National Wildlife Refuge System designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s668dd/a/1">section 668dd(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7869b041-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s668ee/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The terms “take”, “taking”, and “taken” mean to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, or kill, or to attempt to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, or kill.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7869b042-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/669/s5">Pub. L. 89–669, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/929">80 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/57/s3/a">Pub. L. 105–57, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-09">Oct. 9, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1253">111 Stat. 1253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7869b043-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7869b044-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7869b045-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/pl/89/669">Pub. L. 89–669</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/927">80 Stat. 927</ref>, which enacted sections 668aa to 668ee, amended sections 460k, 696, 696b, 715c, 715i to 715k, 718d, and repealed sections 715d–1, 715d–2, 715<i>l</i>, 715m of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, referred to in par. (5)(B), is <ref href="/us/act/1937-07-22/ch517">act July 22, 1937, ch. 517</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/522">50 Stat. 522</ref>. Title III of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1010 et seq.) of chapter 33 of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1000">section 1000 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7869b046-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/57">Pub. L. 105–57</ref> inserted section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) The term ‘person’ as used in this Act means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) The terms ‘take’ or ‘taking’ or ‘taken’ as used in this Act mean to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, kill, or attempt to pursue, hunt, shoot, capture, collect, or kill.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) The terms ‘State’ and the ‘United States’ as used in this Act mean the several States of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and Guam.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
