<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id786bfa92-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c"><num value="669c">§ 669c.</num><heading> Allocation and apportionment of available amounts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfa93-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Set-aside for expenses for administration of this chapter</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfa94-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfa95-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Set-aside</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For fiscal year 2001 and each fiscal year thereafter, of the revenues (excluding interest accruing under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669b/b">section 669b(b) of this title</ref>) covered into the fund for the fiscal year, the Secretary of the Interior may use not more than the available amount specified in subparagraph (B) for the fiscal year for expenses for administration incurred in implementation of this chapter, in accordance with this subsection and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669h">section 669h of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfa96-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Available amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The available amount referred to in subparagraph (A) is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id786bfa97-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> for the fiscal year that includes <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id786bfa98-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> $12,786,434; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id786bfa99-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the change, relative to the preceding fiscal year, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id786bfa9a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> for each fiscal year thereafter, the sum obtained by adding—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id786bfa9b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the available amount specified in this subparagraph for the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id786bfa9c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id786bfa9d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the available amount specified in this subparagraph for the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id786bfa9e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/1/B/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the change, relative to the preceding fiscal year, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfa9f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of availability; apportionment of unobligated amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For each fiscal year, the available amount under paragraph (1) shall remain available for obligation for use under that paragraph until the end of the subsequent fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment of unobligated amounts</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/2/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 60 days after the end of a fiscal year, the Secretary of the Interior shall apportion among the States any of the available amount under paragraph (1) that remained available for obligation pursuant to subparagraph (A) during that fiscal year and remains unobligated at the end of that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The available amount apportioned under clause (i) shall be apportioned on the same basis and in the same manner as other amounts made available under this chapter were apportioned among the States for the fiscal year in which the amount was originally made available.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment to States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, after deducting the available amount under subsection (a), the amount apportioned under subsection (c), any amount apportioned under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669g–1">section 669g–1 of this title</ref>, and amounts provided as grants under sections 669h–1 and 669h–2 of this title, shall apportion the remainder of the revenue in said fund for each fiscal year among the several States in the following manner: One-half in the ratio which the area of each State bears to the total area of all the States, and one-half in the ratio which the number of paid hunting-license holders of each State in the second fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which such apportionment is made, as certified to said Secretary by the State fish and game departments, bears to the total number of paid hunting-license holders of all the States. Such apportionments shall be adjusted equitably so that no State shall receive less than one-half of 1 per centum nor more than 5 per centum of the total amount apportioned. The term fiscal year as used in this chapter shall be a period of twelve consecutive months from October 1 through the succeeding September 30, except that the period for enumeration of paid hunting-license holders shall be a State’s fiscal or license year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment of revenues from pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), ½ of the revenues accruing to the fund under this chapter each fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year 1975) from any tax imposed on pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows shall be apportioned among the States in proportion to the ratio that the population of each State bears to the population of all the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Condition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount apportioned to each State under paragraph (1) shall be not greater than 3 percent and not less than 1 percent of the revenues described in such paragraph and Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Puerto Rico, and the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be apportioned one-sixth of 1 per centum of such revenues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Population determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of this subsection, population shall be determined on the basis of the latest decennial census for which figures are available, as certified by the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaa9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to other uses authorized under this chapter, amounts apportioned under this subsection may be used for hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfaaa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment of Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfaab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior shall make the following apportionment from the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfaac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to the District of Columbia and to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, each a sum equal to not more than one-half of 1 percent thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfaad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, each a sum equal to not more than one-fourth of 1 percent thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfaae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfaaf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior, after making the apportionment under paragraph (1), shall apportion the remaining amount in the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account for each fiscal year among the States in the following manner:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfab0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> one-third of which is based on the ratio to which the land area of such State bears to the total land area of all such States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfab1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> two-thirds of which is based on the ratio to which the population of such State bears to the total population of all such States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfab2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amounts apportioned under this paragraph shall be adjusted equitably so that no such State shall be apportioned a sum which is less than one percent of the amount available for apportionment under this paragraph for any fiscal year or more than five percent of such amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfab3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Of the amounts transferred to the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account, not to exceed 3 percent shall be available for any Federal expenses incurred in the administration and execution of programs carried out with such amounts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id786bfab4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Wildlife conservation and restoration programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfab5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any State, through its fish and wildlife department, may apply to the Secretary of the Interior for approval of a wildlife conservation and restoration program, or for funds from the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account, to develop a program. To apply, a State shall submit a comprehensive plan that includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfab6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provisions vesting in the fish and wildlife department of the State overall responsibility and accountability for the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfab7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> provisions for the development and implementation of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfab8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> wildlife conservation projects that expand and support existing wildlife programs, giving appropriate consideration to all wildlife;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfab9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> wildlife-associated recreation projects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfaba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> wildlife conservation education projects pursuant to programs under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669g/a">section 669g(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfabb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provisions to ensure public participation in the development, revision, and implementation of projects and programs required under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id786bfabc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Wildlife conservation strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Within five years of the date of the initial apportionment, develop and begin implementation of a wildlife conservation strategy based upon the best available and appropriate scientific information and data that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfabd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> uses such information on the distribution and abundance of species of wildlife, including low population and declining species as the State fish and wildlife department deems appropriate, that are indicative of the diversity and health of wildlife of the State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfabe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> identifies the extent and condition of wildlife habitats and community types essential to conservation of species identified under paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfabf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> identifies the problems which may adversely affect the species identified under paragraph (1) or their habitats, and provides for priority research and surveys to identify factors which may assist in restoration and more effective conservation of such species and their habitats;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfac0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> determines those actions which should be taken to conserve the species identified under paragraph (1) and their habitats and establishes priorities for implementing such conservation actions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfac1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> provides for periodic monitoring of species identified under paragraph (1) and their habitats and the effectiveness of the conservation actions determined under paragraph (4), and for adapting conservation actions as appropriate to respond to new information or changing conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfac2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> provides for the review of the State wildlife conservation strategy and, if appropriate, revision at intervals of not more than ten years;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id786bfac3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/1/D/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> provides for coordination to the extent feasible the State fish and wildlife department, during the development, implementation, review, and revision of the wildlife conservation strategy, with Federal, State, and local agencies and Indian tribes that manage significant areas of land or water within the State, or administer programs that significantly affect the conservation of species identified under paragraph (1) or their habitats.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A State shall provide an opportunity for public participation in the development of the comprehensive plan required under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the Secretary finds that the comprehensive plan submitted by a State complies with paragraph (1), the Secretary shall approve the wildlife conservation and restoration program of the State and set aside from the apportionment to the State made pursuant to subsection (d), as redesignated <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002473">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002473"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> an amount that shall not exceed 75 percent of the estimated cost of developing and implementing the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), after the Secretary approves a State’s wildlife conservation and restoration program, the Secretary may make payments on a project that is a segment of the State’s wildlife conservation and restoration program as the project progresses. Such payments, including previous payments on the project, if any, shall not be more than the United States pro rata share of such project. The Secretary, under such regulations as he may prescribe, may advance funds representing the United States pro rata share of a project that is a segment of a wildlife conservation and restoration program, including funds to develop such program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Not more than 10 percent of the amounts apportioned to each State under this section for a State’s wildlife conservation and restoration program may be used for wildlife-associated recreation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id786bfac9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669c/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “State” shall include the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id786bfaca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-09-02/ch899/s4">Sept. 2, 1937, ch. 899, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/918">50 Stat. 918</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-24/ch605/s1">July 24, 1946, ch. 605, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/656">60 Stat. 656</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/503/tI/s102">Pub. L. 91–503, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1970-10-23">Oct. 23, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1098">84 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/558/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 92–558, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1172">86 Stat. 1172</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/273/s4/1">Pub. L. 94–273, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/377">90 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/396/s8/b">Pub. L. 99–396, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/839">100 Stat. 839</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/233/s7/a/2">Pub. L. 101–233, § 7(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-13">Dec. 13, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1975">103 Stat. 1975</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/408/tI/s111/a">Pub. L. 106–408, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1763">114 Stat. 1763</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/553/s1/a/2/tIX/s902/e">Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title IX, § 902(e)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2762">114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–121; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tV/s501/d">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title V, § 501(d)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3192">133 Stat. 3192</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dB/tVIII/s28001/b/1">Pub. L. 117–58, div. B, title VIII, § 28001(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/887">135 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXIII/s11324/b/1">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIII, § 11324(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4095">136 Stat. 4095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id786bfacb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id786bfacc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id786bfacd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (d), as redesignated, referred to in subsec. (e)(3), probably refers to the redesignation of a second subsec. (c) of this section as (d) by <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dP/tV/s501/d/2/A">Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title V, § 501(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3192">133 Stat. 3192</ref>. See 2019 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id786bface-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> amended cl. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (i) read as follows: “for the fiscal year that includes <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>, the sum obtained by adding—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) the available amount specified in this subparagraph for the preceding fiscal year; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) $979,500; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s28001/b/1/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 28001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which provided amounts available for fiscal years 2001 and thereafter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s28001/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 117–58, § 28001(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “subsequent” before “fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s28001/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 28001(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which related to apportionment of unobligated amounts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/1/A">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/1/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), designated the portion of the first sentence of existing provisions preceding the proviso as par. (1), inserted heading, and substituted “Subject to paragraph (2), ½” for “One-half” and a period for “: <i>Provided</i>, That”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/1/D">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(1)(D)</ref>, designated the portion of the first sentence of existing provisions that had followed “<i>Provided</i>, That” as par. (2), inserted heading, and substituted “The amount apportioned to each State under paragraph (1) shall be not greater than 3 percent and not less than 1 percent of the revenues described in such paragraph” for “each State shall be apportioned not more than 3 per centum and not less than 1 per centum of such revenues”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/1/E">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(1)(E)</ref>, designated second sentence of existing provisions as par. (3) and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/1/F">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(1)(F)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/2/A">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(2)(A)</ref>, redesignated second subsec. (c), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref>, and subsec. (d) as (d) as (e), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s501/d/2/B">Pub. L. 116–94, § 501(d)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d), as redesignated” for “subsection (c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/408">Pub. L. 106–408</ref> inserted section catchline, substituted subsec. (a) for “(a) So much, not to exceed 8 per centum, of the revenues (excluding interest accruing under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669b/b">section 669b(b) of this title</ref>) covered into said fund in each fiscal year as the Secretary of the Interior may estimate to be necessary for his expenses in the administration and execution of this chapter and the Migratory Bird Conservation Act shall be deducted for that purpose, and such sum is authorized to be made available therefor until the expiration of the next succeeding fiscal year, and within sixty days after the close of such fiscal year the Secretary of the Interior shall apportion such part thereof as remains unexpended by him, if any, and make certificate thereof to the Secretary of the Treasury and to the State fish and game departments on the same basis and in the same manner as is provided as to other amounts authorized by this chapter to be apportioned among the States for such current fiscal year.”, inserted subsec. (b) designation and heading, substituted “after deducting the available amount under subsection (a), the amount apportioned under subsection (c), any amount apportioned under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669g–1">section 669g–1 of this title</ref>, and amounts provided as grants under sections 669h–1 and 669h–2 of this title, shall apportion” for “after making the aforesaid deduction, shall apportion, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section,”, redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c), and inserted “Puerto Rico,” after “American Samoa,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> added subsec. (c) relating to apportionment of Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/233">Pub. L. 101–233</ref> inserted “(excluding interest accruing under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669b/b">section 669b(b) of this title</ref>)” after “revenues” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/396">Pub. L. 99–396</ref> inserted “and Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be apportioned one-sixth of 1 per centum of such revenues”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/273">Pub. L. 94–273</ref> substituted “September” for “June”, and “October” for “July”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/558">Pub. L. 92–558</ref> substituted “(beginning with the fiscal year 1975)” for “(beginning with the fiscal year 1971)” and “pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows” for “pistols and revolvers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/503">Pub. L. 91–503</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), substituted “second fiscal year preceding” for “preceding fiscal year” in provision dealing with the apportionment by the Secretary of the Interior, defined “fiscal year”, and struck out provisions dealing with the maximum and minimum apportionments “to all the States”, and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-07-24">July 24, 1946</date>, substituted proviso making apportionment upon a percentage basis for provisos providing for certain definite sums to be apportioned to each State.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id786bfacf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id786bfad0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/233">Pub. L. 101–233</ref> effective <date date="1989-10-01">Oct. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/233/s7/a/3">section 7(a)(3) of Pub. L. 101–233</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669b">section 669b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id786bfad1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/558">Pub. L. 92–558</ref> effective <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/558/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 92–558</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669b">section 669b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id786bfad2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Suspension of Expense Limitation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Interior Department Appropriation Act, 1945, <ref href="/us/act/1944-06-28/ch298/s1">act June 28, 1944, ch. 298, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/504">58 Stat. 504</ref>, provided that the limitations in this chapter were waived to the extent necessary to provide overtime under the provisions of the War Overtime Pay Act, 1943, former sections 1401 to 1415 of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, which act expired <date date="1945-06-30">June 30, 1945</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id786bfad3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id786bfad4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, transferred functions of Secretary of Agriculture relating to conservation of wildlife, game, and migratory birds to Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
