<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id786bfad5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669d"><num value="669d">§ 669d.</num><heading> Apportionment; certification to States and Secretary of the Treasury; acceptance by States; disposition of funds not accepted</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Interior shall certify, at the time at which a deduction or apportionment is made, to the Secretary of the Treasury and to each State fish and game department the sum which he has estimated to be deducted for administering this chapter and the Migratory Bird Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s715">16 U.S.C. 715</ref> et seq.] and the sum which he has apportioned to each State. Any State desiring to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter shall notify the Secretary of the Interior to this effect within sixty days after it has received the certification referred to in this section. The sum apportioned to any State which fails to notify the Secretary of the Interior as herein provided is authorized to be made available for expenditure by the Secretary of the Interior in carrying out the provisions of the Migratory Bird Conservation Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id786bfad6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-09-02/ch899/s5">Sept. 2, 1937, ch. 899, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/918">50 Stat. 918</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/503/tI/s102">Pub. L. 91–503, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1970-10-23">Oct. 23, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1098">84 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/408/tI/s114">Pub. L. 106–408, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1769">114 Stat. 1769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id786bfad7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id786bfad8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id786bfad9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Migratory Bird Conservation Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1929-02-18/ch257">act Feb. 18, 1929, ch. 257</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1222">45 Stat. 1222</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 715 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s715">section 715 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id786bfada-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/408">Pub. L. 106–408</ref> in first sentence inserted “, at the time at which a deduction or apportionment is made,” after “certify” and struck out “and executing” after “for administering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/503">Pub. L. 91–503</ref> struck out requirement that apportionments be made by February 20 of each year preceding commencement of fiscal year in which funds would be used.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id786bfadb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id786bfadc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, transferred functions of Secretary of Agriculture relating to conservation of wildlife, game, and migratory birds to Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
