<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id786e6c00-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s669g–1"><num value="669g–1">§ 669g–1.</num><heading> Payment of funds to and cooperation with Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and Virgin Islands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to cooperate with the Secretary of Agriculture of Puerto Rico, the Governor of Guam, the Governor of American Samoa, the Governor of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Governor of the Virgin Islands, in the conduct of wildlife-restoration projects, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669a">section 669a of this title</ref>, and hunter safety programs as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669g/b">section 669g(b) of this title</ref>, upon such terms and conditions as he shall deem fair, just, and equitable, and is authorized to apportion to Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands, out of the money available for apportionment under this chapter, such sums as he shall determine, not exceeding for Puerto Rico one-half of 1 per centum, for Guam one-sixth of 1 per centum, for American Samoa one-sixth of one per centum, for the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands one-sixth of 1 per centum, and for the Virgin Islands one-sixth of 1 per centum of the total amount apportioned, in any one year, but the Secretary shall in no event require any of said cooperating agencies to pay an amount which will exceed 25 per centum of the cost of any project. Any unexpended or unobligated balance of any apportionment made pursuant to this section shall be available for expenditure in Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, as the case may be, in the succeeding year, on any approved project, and if unexpended or unobligated at the end of such year is authorized to be made available for expenditure by the Secretary of the Interior in carrying out the provisions of the Migratory Bird Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s715">16 U.S.C. 715</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id786e6c01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-09-02/ch899/s8A">Sept. 2, 1937, ch. 899, § 8A</ref>, formerly § 8(a), as added <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/ch367">Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 367</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/632">55 Stat. 632</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-03/ch523">Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 523</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/399">64 Stat. 399</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-02/ch489/s2">July 2, 1956, ch. 489, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/473">70 Stat. 473</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch852/s7">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 852, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/908">70 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/70/s15">Pub. L. 86–70, § 15</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/143">73 Stat. 143</ref>; renumbered § 8A and amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/503/tI/s102">Pub. L. 91–503, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1970-10-23">Oct. 23, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1101">84 Stat. 1101</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/597/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 96–597, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3478">94 Stat. 3478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/347/s2/a">Pub. L. 98–347, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-09">July 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/321">98 Stat. 321</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/396/s8/a">Pub. L. 99–396, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/839">100 Stat. 839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id786e6c02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id786e6c03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id786e6c04-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Migratory Bird Conservation Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1929-02-18/ch257">act Feb. 18, 1929, ch. 257</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1222">45 Stat. 1222</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 715 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s715">section 715 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id786e6c05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/396">Pub. L. 99–396</ref> inserted reference to hunter safety programs as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669g/b">section 669g(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/347">Pub. L. 98–347</ref> inserted “the Governor of American Samoa,” after “the Governor of Guam,”, “American Samoa,” after “Puerto Rico, Guam,” in two places, and “for American Samoa one-sixth of one per centum,” after “for Guam one-sixth of 1 per centum,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/597">Pub. L. 96–597</ref> inserted references to Governor and Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/503">Pub. L. 91–503</ref> substituted “Secretary of Agriculture of Puerto Rico” for “Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce of Puerto Rico” and substituted maximum limits of apportionment of one half of one percent to Puerto Rico, one sixth of one percent each to the Virgin Islands and Guam, for maximum limit of apportionment of $10,000 for the three governments together.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/70">Pub. L. 86–70</ref> struck out provisions which authorized cooperation with the Alaska Game Commission and permitted apportionment of not more than $75,000 in any one year to the Territory of Alaska.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, inserted “the Governor of Guam” after “Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce of Puerto Rico,” and “Guam” after “Puerto Rico” where they appeared in the three remaining places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1956-07-02">July 2, 1956</date>, struck out provisions which authorized the Secretary to cooperate with the Division of Game and Fish of the Board of Commissioners of Agriculture and Forestry of Hawaii, removed the limitation of $25,000 on the amount of funds which could be apportioned to Hawaii in any one year, and substituted “Territory of Alaska” for “Territories” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-08-03">Aug. 3, 1950</date>, increased funds allocated annually to Alaska and Hawaii from $25,000 to $10,000, respectively, to $75,000 and $25,000.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id786e6c06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id786e6c07-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/347/s2/b">Pub. L. 98–347, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-09">July 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/322">98 Stat. 322</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/347/s2/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id786e6c08-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1956 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1956-07-02">July 2, 1956</date>, applicable only with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1956-07-02">July 2, 1956</date>, see section 5 of such act <date date="1956-07-02">July 2, 1956</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s669a">section 669a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id786e6c09-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Increase of Annual Apportionments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-05-19/ch313">Act May 19, 1956, ch. 313</ref>, ch. VI, § 601, <ref href="/us/stat/70/169">70 Stat. 169</ref>, authorized increases of not more than 20 percent in the annual appropriations for the former territories of Alaska and Hawaii, and Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
