<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7873266c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j"><num value="670j">§ 670j.</num><heading> Enforcement provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7873266d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations and penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7873266e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any person who hunts, traps, or fishes on any public land which is subject to a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter without having on his person a valid public land management area stamp, if the possession of such a stamp is required, shall be fined not more than $1,000, or imprisoned for not more than six months, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7873266f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s670h/c/5">section 670h(c)(5) of this title</ref> shall be fined not more than $500, or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78732670-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement powers and proceedings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78732671-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purpose of enforcing subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may designate any employee of their respective departments, and any State officer or employee authorized under a cooperative agreement to enforce such subsection (a), to (i) carry firearms; (ii) execute and serve any warrant or other process issued by a court or officer of competent jurisdiction; (iii) make arrests without warrant or process for a misdemeanor he has reasonable grounds to believe is being committed in his presence or view; (iv) search without warrant or process any person, place, or conveyance as provided by law; and (v) seize without warrant or process any evidentiary item as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78732672-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon the sworn information by a competent person, any United States magistrate judge or court of competent jurisdiction may issue process for the arrest of any person charged with committing any offense under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78732673-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any person charged with committing any offense under subsection (a) of this section may be tried and sentenced by any United States magistrate judge designated for that purpose by the court by which he was appointed, in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3401">section 3401 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78732674-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Seizure and forfeiture</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All guns, traps, nets, and other equipment, vessels, vehicles, and other means of transportation used by any person when engaged in committing an offense under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States and may be seized and held pending the prosecution of any person arrested for committing such offense. Upon conviction for such offense, such forfeiture may be adjudicated as a penalty in addition to any other provided for committing such offense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78732675-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s670j/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of customs laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All provisions of law relating to the seizure, forfeiture, and condemnation of a vessel for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of such vessel or the proceeds from the sale thereof, and the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, shall apply to the seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this section, insofar as such provisions of law are applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this section; except that all powers, rights, and duties conferred or imposed by the customs laws upon any officer or employee of the Department of the Treasury shall, for the purposes of this section, be exercised or performed by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, or by such persons as he may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78732676-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/797/tII/s204">Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/452/s2">Pub. L. 93–452, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1372">88 Stat. 1372</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tIII/s312/b/10">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(10)</ref>, (c), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1354">125 Stat. 1354</ref>, 1355.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78732677-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78732678-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78732679-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s312/b/10">Pub. L. 112–81, § 312(b)(10)</ref>, inserted section catchline and headings for subsecs. (a) to (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s312/c">Pub. L. 112–81, § 312(c)</ref>, substituted “magistrate judge” for “magistrate”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
