<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78759834-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s683"><num value="683">§ 683.</num><heading> Areas set aside for protection of game and fish; unlawfully taking game or fish</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States is authorized to designate such areas on any lands which have been, or which may hereafter be, purchased by the United States under the provisions of the Act of March first, nineteen hundred and eleven, and Acts supplementary thereto and amendatory thereof, as should, in his opinion, be set aside for the protection of game animals, birds, or fish; and, except under such rules and regulations as the Secretary of Agriculture may from time to time prescribe, it shall be unlawful for any person to hunt, catch, trap, willfully disturb or kill any kind of game animal, game or nongame bird, or fish, or take the eggs of any such bird on any lands so set aside, or in or on the waters thereof.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78759835-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1916-08-11/ch313">Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/476">39 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645/s10">June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/860">62 Stat. 860</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78759836-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78759837-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78759838-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of March first, nineteen hundred and eleven, referred to in text, was in the original “Act of March first, nineteen hundred and eleven (Thirty-six Statutes at Large, page nine hundred and sixty-one), entitled ‘An Act to enable any State to cooperate with any other State or States, or with the United States, for the protection of watersheds of navigable streams, and to appoint a commission for the acquisition of lands for the purpose of conserving the navigability of navigable streams’ ”, which is popularly known as the Weeks Law, and which enacted former sections 513 and 514 and sections 515 to 519, 521, 552, and 563 of this title and amended sections 480 and 500 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s552">section 552 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78759839-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, struck out penal provisions (see <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s41">section 41 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure), and inserted provision relating to the unlawfulness in hunting, catching, etc. game animals, etc. under rules and regulations of Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7875983a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7875983b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1948 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 20 of act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, provided that the amendment made by that act is effective <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7875983c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7875983d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Designation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The following areas have been designated by the President:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">Big Levels Game Refuge. Proclamation of <date date="1935-07-06">July 6, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/3448">49 Stat. 3448</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">Cherokee National Game Refuges. Proclamation of <date date="1924-08-05">Aug. 5, 1924</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/43/1964">43 Stat. 1964</ref>), and <date date="1934-10-22">Oct. 22, 1934</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/3423">49 Stat. 3423</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">National Catahoula Wildlife Management Preserve. Proclamation of <date date="1941-09-27">Sept. 27, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/55/1689">55 Stat. 1689</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">National Red Dirt Wildlife Management Preserve. Proclamation of <date date="1941-09-27">Sept. 27, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/55/1688">55 Stat. 1688</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">Noontootly National Game Refuge. Proclamation of <date date="1938-07-06">July 6, 1938</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/1549">52 Stat. 1549</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I30" class="indent3 firstIndent-1">Pisgah National Game Preserve. Proclamation of <date date="1916-10-17">Oct. 17, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/1811">39 Stat. 1811</ref>).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
