<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a206193-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902"><num value="6902">§ 6902.</num><heading> Appointment of United States Commissioners</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206194-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States shall be represented on the Commission by 5 United States Commissioners. The President shall appoint individuals to serve on the Commission at the pleasure of the President. In making the appointments, the President shall select Commissioners from among individuals who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning highly migratory fish stocks and commercial fishing in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean, one of whom shall be an officer or employee of the Department of Commerce, and one of whom shall be the chairman or a member of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council, and one of whom shall be the chairman or a member of the Pacific Fishery Management Council. The Commissioners shall be entitled to adopt such rules of procedures as they find necessary and to select a chairman from among members who are officers or employees of the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206195-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternate Commissioners</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, may designate from time to time and for periods of time deemed appropriate Alternate United States Commissioners to the Commission. Any Alternate United States Commissioner may exercise at any meeting of the Commission, Council, any Panel, or the advisory committee established pursuant to subsection (d), all powers and duties of a United States Commissioner in the absence of any Commissioner appointed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section for whatever reason. The number of such Alternate United States Commissioners that may be designated for any such meeting shall be limited to the number of United States Commissioners appointed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section who will not be present at such meeting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206196-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative matters</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206197-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Individuals serving as such Commissioners, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall not be considered Federal employees except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206198-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The United States Commissioners or Alternate Commissioners, although officers of the United States while so serving, shall receive no compensation for their services as such Commissioners or Alternate Commissioners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a206199-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a20619a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall pay the necessary travel expenses of United States Commissioners and Alternate United States Commissioners in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a20619b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may reimburse the Secretary of State for amounts expended by the Secretary of State under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a20619c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a20619d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of permanent advisory committee</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a20619e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There is established an advisory committee which shall be composed of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a20619f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> not less than 15 nor more than 20 individuals appointed by the Secretary of Commerce in consultation with the United States Commissioners, who shall select such individuals from the various groups concerned with the fisheries covered by the WCPFC Convention, providing, to the maximum extent practicable, an equitable balance among such groups;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a2061a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the chair of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Committee or the chair’s designee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a2061a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> officials of the fisheries management authorities of American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands (or their designees).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and privileges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each member of the advisory committee appointed under subparagraph (A) shall serve for a term of 2 years and shall be eligible for reappointment. The advisory committee shall be invited to attend all non-executive meetings of the United States Commissioners and at such meetings shall be given opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigation, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The advisory committee established by subparagraph (A) shall determine its organization, and prescribe its practices and procedures for carrying out its functions under this chapter,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002838">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002838"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), and the WCPFC Convention. The advisory committee shall publish and make available to the public a statement of its organization, practices, and procedures. A majority of the members of the advisory committee shall constitute a quorum. Meetings of the advisory committee, except when in executive session, shall be open to the public, and prior notice of meetings shall be made public in a timely fashion.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002839">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002839"><num>2</num> So in original. The period probably should be a comma.</note> and the advisory committee shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary and the Secretary of State shall furnish the advisory committee with relevant information concerning fisheries and international fishery agreements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Agenda recommendations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No later than 30 days before each annual meeting of the Commission, the Advisory Committee shall transmit to the United States Commissioners recommendations relating to the agenda of the annual meeting. The recommendations must be agreed to by a majority of the Advisory Committee members. The United States Commissioners shall consider such recommendations, along with additional views transmitted by Advisory Committee members, in the formulation of the United States position for the Commission meeting and during the negotiations at that meeting.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative matters</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Support services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall provide to advisory committees in a timely manner such administrative and technical support services as are necessary for their effective functioning.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061a8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation; status; expenses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Individuals appointed to serve as a member of an advisory committee—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a2061a9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall serve without pay, but while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the advisory committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a2061aa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall not be considered Federal employees except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061ab-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002840">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002840"><num>3</num> So in original. No subsec. (e) has been enacted.</note> Memorandum of understanding</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For highly migratory species in the Pacific, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall develop a memorandum of understanding with the Western Pacific, Pacific, and North Pacific Fishery Management Councils, that clarifies the role of the relevant Council or Councils with respect to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061ac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> participation in United States delegations to international fishery organizations in the Pacific Ocean, including government-to-government consultations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061ad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing formal recommendations to the Secretary and the Secretary of State regarding necessary measures for both domestic and foreign vessels fishing for these species;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061ae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> coordinating positions with the United States delegation for presentation to the appropriate international fishery organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061af-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6902/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> recommending those domestic fishing regulations that are consistent with the actions of the international fishery organization, for approval and implementation under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.)</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a2061b0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/479/tV/s503">Pub. L. 109–479, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3636">120 Stat. 3636</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/348/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 111–348, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3672">124 Stat. 3672</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/327/tIII/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 114–327, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1993">130 Stat. 1993</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/133">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(133)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4320">136 Stat. 4320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a2061b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a2061b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a2061b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(C), probably should have been “this title” in the original, meaning title V of <ref href="/us/pl/109/479">Pub. L. 109–479</ref> which enacted this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, referred to in subsecs. (d)(1)(C) and (f)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/265">Pub. L. 94–265</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/331">90 Stat. 331</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 38 (§ 1801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a2061b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (d)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/327/s301/a/1/A">Pub. L. 114–327, § 301(a)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “and commercial fishing” after “fish stocks”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/114/327/s301/a/1/B">Pub. L. 114–327, § 301(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/348/s301/1">Pub. L. 111–348, § 301(1)</ref>, substituted “Management Council, and one of whom shall be the chairman or a member of” for “Management Council and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/348/s301/2">Pub. L. 111–348, § 301(2)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Individuals serving as such Commissioners, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, only for purposes of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) injury compensation under chapter 81 of title 5;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) requirements concerning ethics, conflicts of interest, and corruption as provided under title 18; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) any other criminal or civil statute or regulation governing the conduct of Federal employees.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/348/s301/3">Pub. L. 111–348, § 301(3)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out former cl. (ii) which read as follows: “shall be considered Federal employees while performing service as members of an advisory committee only for purposes of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) injury compensation under chapter 81 of title 5;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) requirements concerning ethics, conflicts-of-interest, and corruption, as provided by title 18; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(III) any other criminal or civil statute or regulation governing the conduct of Federal employees in their capacity as Federal employees.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
