<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a2061c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905"><num value="6905">§ 6905.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> administer and enforce this chapter and any regulations issued under this chapter, except to the extent otherwise provided for in this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> request and utilize on a reimbursed or non-reimbursed basis the assistance, services, personnel, equipment, and facilities of other Federal departments and agencies in—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the administration and enforcement of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the conduct of scientific, research, and other programs under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> conduct fishing operations and biological experiments for purposes of scientific investigation or other purposes necessary to implement the WCPFC Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> collect, utilize, and disclose such information as may be necessary to implement the WCPFC Convention, subject to sections 552 and 552a of title 5 and section 402(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1881a/b">16 U.S.C. 1881a(b)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> if recommended by the United States Commissioners or proposed by a Council with authority over the relevant fishery, assess and collect fees, not to exceed three percent of the ex-vessel value of fish harvested by vessels of the United States in fisheries managed pursuant to this chapter, to recover the actual costs to the United States of management and enforcement under this chapter, which shall be deposited as an offsetting collection in, and credited to, the account providing appropriations to carry out the functions of the Secretary under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2061ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> issue permits to owners and operators of United States vessels to fish in the convention area seaward of the United States Exclusive Economic Zone, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, and shall remain valid for a period to be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consistency with other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure the consistency, to the extent practicable, of fishery management programs administered under this Act, the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), the Tuna Conventions Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s951">16 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.), the South Pacific Tuna Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s973">16 U.S.C. 973</ref> et seq.), <ref href="/us/pl/108/219/s401">section 401 of Public Law 108–219</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1821">16 U.S.C. 1821</ref> note) (relating to Pacific albacore tuna), and the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971">16 U.S.C. 971</ref> [et seq.]).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional prohibitions and enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For additional prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1826g">section 1826g of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any information submitted to the Secretary in compliance with any requirement under this Act shall be confidential and shall not be disclosed, except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to Federal employees who are responsible for administering, implementing, and enforcing this Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the Commission, in accordance with requirements in the Convention and decisions of the Commission, and, insofar as possible, in accordance with an agreement with the Commission that prevents public disclosure of the identity or business of any person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to State or Marine Fisheries Commission employees pursuant to an agreement with the Secretary that prevents public disclosure of the identity or business or any person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> when required by court order; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2061d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> when the Secretary has obtained written authorization from the person submitting such information to release such information to persons for reasons not otherwise provided for in this subsection, and such release does not violate other requirements of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2061d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s6905/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall, by regulation, prescribe such procedures as may be necessary to preserve the confidentiality of information submitted in compliance with any requirement or regulation under this Act, except that the Secretary may release or make public any such information in any aggregate or summary form that does not directly or indirectly disclose the identity or business of any person. Nothing in this subsection shall be interpreted or construed to prevent the use for conservation and management purposes by the Secretary of any information submitted in compliance with any requirement or regulation under this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a2061d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/479/tV/s506">Pub. L. 109–479, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3640">120 Stat. 3640</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/tI/s105/1">Pub. L. 114–81, title I, § 105(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/657">129 Stat. 657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a2061d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a2061d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a2061d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (b), and (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/479">Pub. L. 109–479</ref>, <date date="2007-01-12">Jan. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3575">120 Stat. 3575</ref>, known as the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Reauthorization Act of 2006. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2007 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/265">Pub. L. 94–265</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/331">90 Stat. 331</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 38 (§ 1801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tuna Conventions Act, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950, <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-07/ch907">act Sept. 7, 1950, ch. 907</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/777">64 Stat. 777</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 951 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s951">section 951 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The South Pacific Tuna Act, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the South Pacific Tuna Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/330">Pub. L. 100–330</ref>, <date date="1988-06-07">June 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/591">102 Stat. 591</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16C (§ 973 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s973">section 973 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atlantic Tunas Convention Act, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975, <ref href="/us/pl/94/70">Pub. L. 94–70</ref>, <date date="1975-08-05">Aug. 5, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/385">89 Stat. 385</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16A (§ 971 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s971">section 971 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a2061d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—<ref href="/us/pl/114/81">Pub. L. 114–81</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary shall prevent any person from violating this chapter in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1857">16 U.S.C. 1857</ref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter. Any person that violates any provision of this chapter is subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, power, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of that Act were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
