<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78759875-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s690b"><num value="690b">§ 690b.</num><heading> Consent of Utah to acquisition of lands for Bear River Refuge; approval of title to lands acquired</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No such area shall be acquired by the Secretary of the Interior unless or until the Legislature of the State of Utah has consented to the acquisition of lands by the United States for use as a refuge for migratory wild fowl, and shall have provided for the use as a refuge for migratory wild fowl by the United States of any lands owned or controlled by the State in Bear River Bay, Utah, and vicinity, which the Secretary of the Interior may deem necessary for such purpose, and which the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to accept on behalf of the United States; and, except in the case of a lease, no payments shall be made by the United States for any such area until title thereto is satisfactory to the Attorney General.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78759876-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1928-04-23/ch413/s3">Apr. 23, 1928, ch. 413, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/449">45 Stat. 449</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78759877-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78759878-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78759879-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, transferred functions of Secretary of Agriculture relating to conservation of wildlife, game, and migratory birds to Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
