<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id787a5275-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h"><num value="698h">§ 698h.</num><heading> Right of use and occupancy of improved property on Big Cypress Preserve and Addition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787a5276-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Election of right of use and occupancy; payment of fair market value; termination of right</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The owner of an improved property on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary may, as a condition of such acquisition, retain for himself and his heirs and assigns a right of use of and occupancy of the improved property for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years or, in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the death of his spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. Unless this property is wholly or partially donated to the United States, the Secretary shall pay the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of acquisition less the fair market value, on that date, of the right retained by the owner. A right retained pursuant to this section shall be subject to termination by the Secretary upon his determination that it is being exercised in a manner inconsistent with the purposes of sections 698f to 698m–4 of this title, which shall include the exercise of such right in violation of any applicable State or local laws and ordinances, and it shall terminate by operation of law upon the Secretary’s notifying the holder of the right of such determination and tendering to him an amount equal to the fair market value of that portion of the right which remains unexpired.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787a5277-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> “Improved property” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in sections 698f to 698m–4 of this title, the term “improved property” means:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a5278-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h/b/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a detached one family dwelling, construction of which was begun before <date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>, with respect to the preserve and <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, with respect to the Addition which is used for noncommercial residential purposes, together with not to exceed three acres of land on which the dwelling is situated and such additional lands as the Secretary deems reasonably necessary for access thereto, such land being in the same ownership as the dwelling, and together with any structures accessory to the dwelling which are situated on such lands and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a5279-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h/b/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any other building, construction of which was begun before <date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>, with respect to the preserve and <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, with respect to the Addition which was constructed and is used in accordance with all applicable State and local laws and ordinances, together with as much of the land on which the building is situated, such land being in the same ownership as the building, as the Secretary shall designate to be reasonably necessary for the continued enjoyment and use of the building in the same manner and to the same extent as existed in <date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>, or <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, as the case may be, together with any structures accessory to the building which are situated on the lands so designated. In making such designation the Secretary shall take into account the manner of use in which the building, accessory structures, and lands were customarily enjoyed prior to <date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date> or <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, as the case may be.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002483">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002483"><num>1</num> See 1988 Amendment note below.</note></content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787a527a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698h/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of right to relocation assistance by election of right of use and occupancy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever an owner of property elects to retain a right of use and occupancy as provided in this section, such owner shall be deemed to have waived any benefits or rights accruing under sections 4623, 4624, 4625, and 4626 of title 42, and for the purposes of such sections such owner shall not be considered a displaced person as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601/6">section 4601(6) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id787a527b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/440/s3">Pub. L. 93–440, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1259">88 Stat. 1259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/301/s4/f">Pub. L. 100–301, § 4(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-29">Apr. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/445">102 Stat. 445</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id787a527c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id787a527d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id787a527e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/301/s4/f/1">Pub. L. 100–301, § 4(f)(1)</ref>, inserted “with respect to the preserve and <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, with respect to the Addition” after “<date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/301/s4/f/2/A">Pub. L. 100–301, § 4(f)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “with respect to the preserve and <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, with respect to the Addition” after “<date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/301/s4/f/2/B">Pub. L. 100–301, § 4(f)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, as the case may be,” after “<date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>,” the second and third places it appears, was executed by making the insertion after “<date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>,” the second place it appears and after “<date date="1971-11-23">November 23, 1971</date>” preceding the period as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
