<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id787a52b1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3"><num value="698m–3">§ 698m–3.</num><heading> Status of Big Cypress National Preserve and Addition; report to Congress; plan</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than two years after <date date="1988-04-29">April 29, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a detailed report on, and further plan for, the preserve and Addition including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a52b2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the status of the existing preserve, the effectiveness of past regulation and management of the preserve, and recommendations for future management of the preserve and the Addition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a52b3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a summary of the public’s use of the preserve and the status of the access points developed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s698m–2">section 698m–2 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a52b4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the need for involvement of other State and Federal agencies in the management and expansion of the preserve and Addition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a52b5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the status of land acquisition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787a52b6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s698m–3/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a determination, made in conjunction with the State of Florida, of the adequacy of the number, location, and design of the recreational access points on I–75/Alligator Alley for access to the Big Cypress National Preserve, including the Addition.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The determination required by paragraph (5) shall incorporate the results of any related studies of the State of Florida Department of Transportation and other Florida State agencies. Any recommendation for significant changes in the approved recreational access points, including any proposed additions, shall be accompanied by an assessment of the environmental impact of such changes.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id787a52b7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/440/s11">Pub. L. 93–440, § 11</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/301/s6">Pub. L. 100–301, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-04-29">Apr. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/446">102 Stat. 446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
