<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78817e61-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704"><num value="704">§ 704.</num><heading> Determination as to when and how migratory birds may be taken, killed, or possessed</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78817e62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Subject to the provisions and in order to carry out the purposes of the conventions, referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">section 703 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed, from time to time, having due regard to the zones of temperature and to the distribution, abundance, economic value, breeding habits, and times and lines of migratory flight of such birds, to determine when, to what extent, if at all, and by what means, it is compatible with the terms of the conventions to allow hunting, taking, capture, killing, possession, sale, purchase, shipment, transportation, carriage, or export of any such bird, or any part, nest, or egg thereof, and to adopt suitable regulations permitting and governing the same, in accordance with such determinations, which regulations shall become effective when approved by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78817e63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> It shall be unlawful for any person to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78817e64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> take any migratory game bird by the aid of baiting, or on or over any baited area, if the person knows or reasonably should know that the area is a baited area; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78817e65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> place or direct the placement of bait on or adjacent to an area for the purpose of causing, inducing, or allowing any person to take or attempt to take any migratory game bird by the aid of baiting on or over the baited area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78817e66-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Framework Closing Date for Hunting of Ducks, Mergansers, and Coots.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78817e67-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations relating to framework closing date.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78817e68-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In promulgating regulations under subsection (a) relating to the Federal framework for the closing date up to which the States may select seasons for migratory bird hunting, except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall, with respect to the hunting season for ducks, mergansers, and coots—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78817e69-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subject to subparagraph (B), adopt the recommendation of each respective flyway council (as defined in section 20.152 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations) for the Federal framework if the Secretary determines that the recommendation is consistent with science-based and sustainable harvest management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78817e6a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> allow the States to establish the closing date for the hunting season in accordance with the Federal framework.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78817e6b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The framework closing date promulgated by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall not be later than January 31 of each year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78817e6c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special hunting days for youths, veterans, and active military personnel.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78817e6d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the Federal framework closing date under paragraph (1) and subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Secretary shall allow States to select 2 days for youths and 2 days for veterans (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of title 38</ref>) and members of the Armed Forces on active duty, including members of the National Guard and Reserves on active duty (other than for training), to hunt eligible ducks, geese, swans, mergansers, coots, moorhens, and gallinules, if the Secretary determines that the addition of those days is consistent with science-based and sustainable harvest management. Such days shall be treated as separate from, and in addition to, the annual Federal framework hunting season lengths.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78817e6e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In selecting days under subparagraph (A), a State shall ensure that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78817e6f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the days selected—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id78817e70-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> may only include the hunting of duck, geese, swan, merganser, coot, moorhen, and gallinule species that are eligible for hunting under the applicable annual Federal framework;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id78817e71-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> are not more than 14 days before or after the Federal framework hunting season for ducks, mergansers, and coots; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id78817e72-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> are otherwise consistent with the Federal framework; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78817e73-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the total number of days in a hunting season for any migratory bird species, including any days selected under subparagraph (A), is not more than 107 days.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78817e74-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>A State may combine the 2 days allowed for youths with the 2 days allowed for veterans and members of the Armed Forces on active duty under subparagraph (A), but in no circumstance may a State have more than a total of 4 additional days added to its regular hunting season for any purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78817e75-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s704/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations in accordance with this subsection for the Federal framework for migratory bird hunting for the 2019–2020 hunting season and each hunting season thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78817e76-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1918-07-03/ch128/s3">July 3, 1918, ch. 128, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/755">40 Stat. 755</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-20/ch634/s2">June 20, 1936, ch. 634, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1556">49 Stat. 1556</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/312/tI/s102">Pub. L. 105–312, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2956">112 Stat. 2956</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/9/tIV/s4301">Pub. L. 116–9, title IV, § 4301</ref>, <date date="2019-03-12">Mar. 12, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/764">133 Stat. 764</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78817e77-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78817e78-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78817e79-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/9">Pub. L. 116–9</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/312">Pub. L. 105–312</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1936—Act <date date="1936-06-20">June 20, 1936</date>, substituted “conventions” for “convention” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78817e7a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78817e7b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1936 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1936-06-20/ch634/s2">Act June 20, 1936, ch. 634, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1556">49 Stat. 1556</ref>, provided in part that the amendment by section 2 is effective as of the day aforesaid (<date date="1937-06-30">June 30, 1937</date>). See note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">section 703 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78817e7c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Baiting of Migratory Game Birds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12601">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12601</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5003">132 Stat. 5003</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12601">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Normal agricultural operation</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘normal agricultural operation’ has the meaning given the term in section 20.11 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Post-disaster flooding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘post-disaster flooding’ means the destruction of a crop through flooding in accordance with practices required by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation for agricultural producers to obtain crop insurance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501">7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) on land on which a crop was not harvestable due to a natural disaster (including any hurricane, storm, tornado, flood, high water, wind-driven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, drought, fire, snowstorm, or other catastrophe that is declared a major disaster by the President in accordance with section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref>)) in the crop year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in which the natural disaster occurred; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> immediately preceding the crop year in which the natural disaster occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rice ratooning</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘rice ratooning’ means the agricultural practice of harvesting rice by cutting the majority of the aboveground portion of the rice plant but leaving the roots and growing shoot apices intact to allow the plant to recover and produce a second crop yield.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations to Exclude Rice Ratooning and Post-disaster Flooding</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall revise part 20 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, to clarify that rice ratooning and post-disaster flooding, when carried out as part of a normal agricultural operation, do not constitute baiting.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not less frequently than once each year—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Secretary of the Interior a report that describes any changes to normal agricultural operations across the range of crops grown by agricultural producers in each region of the United States in which the official recommendations described in section 20.11(h) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), are provided to agricultural producers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and after seeking input from the heads of State departments of fish and wildlife or the Regional Migratory Bird Flyway Councils of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall publicly post a report on the impact that rice ratooning and post-disaster flooding have on the behavior of migratory game birds that are hunted in the area in which rice ratooning and post-disaster flooding, respectively, have occurred.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78817e7d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Effects of 1998 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/312/tI/s104">Pub. L. 105–312, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2956">112 Stat. 2956</ref>, directed that no later than 5 years after <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, the Secretary of the Interior submit to the appropriate Senate and House committees a report analyzing the effect of certain amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/105/312">Pub. L. 105–312</ref>, and the general practice of baiting, on migratory bird conservation and law enforcement efforts under the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78817e7e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78817e7f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions of Secretary of Agriculture to Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan, No. II of 1939, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s701">section 701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id78817e80-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation to Secretary of the Interior of authority vested in President, see Ex. Ord. No. 10752, <date date="1958-02-12">Feb. 12, 1958</date>, 23 F.R. 973, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s715j">section 715j of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary of the Interior empowered to promulgate regulations under this section without approval, ratification, or other action of President, see section 2(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 10250, <date date="1951-06-05">June 5, 1951</date>, 16 F.R. 5385, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
