<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7888aabf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s724"><num value="724">§ 724.</num><heading> Consent of States to acquisition; existing rights-of-way, easements, etc.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7888aac0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s724/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> No such area shall be acquired by the Secretary of the Interior until the legislature of each State in which is situated any part of the areas to be acquired under this chapter has consented to the acquisition of such part by the United States for the purposes of this chapter, and, except in the case of a lease, no payment shall be made by the United States for any such area until title thereto is satisfactory to the Attorney General and is vested in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7888aac1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s724/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The existence of a right of way, easement, or other reservation or exception in respect of such area shall not be a bar to its acquisition (1) if the Secretary of the Interior determines that any such reservation or exception will in no manner interfere with the use of the area for the purposes of this chapter, or (2) if in the deed or other conveyance it is stipulated that any reservation or exception in respect of such area, in favor of the person from whom the United States receives title, shall be subject to regulations prescribed under authority of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7888aac2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1924-06-07/ch346/s4">June 7, 1924, ch. 346, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/650">43 Stat. 650</ref>; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. <date date="1939-07-01">July 1, 1939</date>, 4 F.R. 2731, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1433">53 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7888aac3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7888aac4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7888aac5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions of Secretary of Agriculture to Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s723">section 723 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
