<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78921fe8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s758e–1"><num value="758e–1">§ 758e–1.</num><heading> Consultation and cooperation between certain Federal officers, affected States, etc., in carrying out program</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the purposes of sections 758e to 758e–5 of this title, the Secretary shall consult, and may otherwise cooperate, with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of State, the State of Hawaii and other affected States, the governments of American Samoa and Guam, the Office of the High Commissioner of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, educational institutions, the commercial fishing industry, and all appropriate member nations of a South Pacific regional fishery agency (hereinafter referred to in sections 758e to 758e–5 of this title as the “agency”), if such an agency is formed.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78921fe9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/444/s3">Pub. L. 92–444, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-09-29">Sept. 29, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/745">86 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/295/s1/2">Pub. L. 95–295, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-06-16">June 16, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/319">92 Stat. 319</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78921fea-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78921feb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78921fec-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/295">Pub. L. 95–295</ref> inserted provisions requiring consultation and cooperation with the Secretary of State, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and all appropriate member nations of a South Pacific regional fishery agency, if such an agency is formed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78921fed-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78921fee-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
