<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78922035-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s760d"><num value="760d">§ 760d.</num><heading> Grants for education and training of personnel in the field of commercial fishing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78922036-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s760d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Public and private nonprofit universities and colleges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to make grants, out of funds appropriated for the purposes of this section, to public and nonprofit private universities and colleges in the several States and Territories of the United States for such purposes as may be necessary to promote the education and training of professionally trained personnel (including scientists, technicians, and teachers) needed in the field of commercial fishing. Any amount appropriated for the purposes of this section shall be apportioned on an equitable basis, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce, among the several States and Territories for the purpose of making grants within each such State and Territory. In making such apportionment the Secretary of Commerce shall take into account the extent of the fishing industry within each State and Territory as compared with the total fishing industry of the United States (including Territories), and such other factors as may be relevant in view of the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78922037-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s760d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated not in excess of $550,000 for the fiscal year beginning on <date date="1955-07-01">July 1, 1955</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter for the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78922038-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s760d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce may establish such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78922039-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-08/ch1039/s1">Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1039, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/1126">70 Stat. 1126</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7892203a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7892203b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7892203c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions to Secretary of Commerce from Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s755">section 755 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
