<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a29ff4f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631"><num value="7631">§ 7631.</num><heading> Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a29ff50-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to the functions required by Executive Order 13648 (78 Fed. Reg. 40621), the Task Force shall be informed by the Secretary of State’s annual report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s7621">section 7621 of this title</ref> and considering all available information, ensure that relevant United States Government agencies—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff51-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> collaborate, to the greatest extent practicable, with the national wildlife services, or other relevant bodies of each focus country to prepare, not later than 90 days after the date of submission of the report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s7621/a">section 7621(a) of this title</ref>, a United States mission assessment of the threats to wildlife in that focus country and an assessment of the capacity of that country to address wildlife trafficking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff52-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collaborate, to the greatest extent practicable, with relevant ministries, national wildlife services, or other relevant bodies of each focus country to prepare, not later than 180 days after preparation of the assessment referred to in paragraph (1), a United States mission strategic plan that includes recommendations for addressing wildlife trafficking, taking into account any regional or national strategies for addressing wildlife trafficking in a focus country developed before the preparation of such assessment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff53-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> coordinate efforts among United States Federal agencies and non-Federal partners, including missions, domestic and international organizations, the private sector, and other global partners, to implement the strategic plans required by paragraph (2) in each focus country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff54-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> not less frequently than annually, consult and coordinate with stakeholders qualified to provide advice, assistance, and information regarding effective support for anti-poaching activities, coordination of regional law enforcement efforts, development of and support for effective legal enforcement mechanisms, and development of strategies to reduce illicit trade and reduce consumer demand for illegally traded wildlife and wildlife products, and other relevant topics under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff55-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> pursue programs and develop a strategy—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a29ff56-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to expand the role of technology for anti-poaching and anti-trafficking efforts, in partnership with the private sector, foreign governments, academia, and nongovernmental organizations (including technology companies and the transportation and logistics sectors); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a29ff57-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to enable local governments to develop and use such technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff58-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> consider programs and initiatives that address the expansion of the illegal wildlife trade to digital platforms, including the use of digital currency and payment platforms for transactions by collaborating with the private sector, academia, and nongovernmental organizations, including social media, e-commerce, and search engine companies, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff59-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff5a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> implement interventions to address the drivers of poaching, trafficking, and demand for illegal wildlife and wildlife products in focus countries and countries of concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff5b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> set benchmarks for measuring the effectiveness of such interventions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff5c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> consider alignment and coordination with indicators developed by the Task Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff5d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> consider additional opportunities to increase coordination between law enforcement and financial institutions to identify trafficking activity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff5e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> coordinate or carry out other functions as are necessary to implement this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a29ff5f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duplication and efficiency</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Task Force shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff60-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> ensure that the activities of the Federal agencies involved in carrying out efforts under this chapter are coordinated and not duplicated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff61-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> encourage efficiencies and coordination among the efforts of Federal agencies and interagency initiatives ongoing as of <date date="2016-10-07">October 7, 2016</date>, to address trafficking activities, including trafficking of wildlife, humans, weapons, and narcotics, illegal trade, transnational organized crime, or other illegal activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a29ff62-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consistency with agency responsibilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Task Force shall carry out its responsibilities under this chapter in a manner consistent with the authorities and responsibilities of agencies represented on the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a29ff63-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Task Force strategic review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">One year after <date date="2016-10-07">October 7, 2016</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Task Force shall submit a strategic assessment of its work and provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees that shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a29ff64-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> a review and assessment of the Task Force’s implementation of this chapter, identifying successes, failures, and gaps in its work, or that of agencies represented on the Task Force, including detailed descriptions of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a29ff65-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> what approaches, initiatives, or programs have succeeded best in increasing the willingness and capacity of focus countries to suppress and prevent illegal wildlife trafficking, and what approaches, initiatives, or programs have not succeeded as well as hoped; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a2c4856-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which foreign governments subject to subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s7621">section 7621 of this title</ref> have proven to be the most successful partners in suppressing and preventing illegal wildlife trafficking, which focus countries have not proven to be so, and what factors contributed to these results in each country discussed;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2c4857-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of each Task Force member agency’s priorities and objectives for combating wildlife trafficking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2c4858-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an account of total United States funding each year since fiscal year 2014 for all government agencies and programs involved in countering poaching and wildlife trafficking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2c4859-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an account of total United States funding since fiscal year 2014 to support the activities of the Task Force, including administrative overhead costs and congressional reporting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2c485a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> recommendations for how to improve United States and international efforts to suppress and prevent illegal wildlife trafficking in the future, based upon the Task Force’s experience as of the time of the review; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a2c485b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> an analysis of the indicators developed by the Task Force, and recommended by the Government Accountability Office, to track and measure inputs, outputs, law enforcement outcomes, and the market for wildlife products for each focus country listed in the report, including baseline measures, as appropriate, for each indicator in each focus country to determine the effectiveness and appropriateness of such indicators to assess progress and whether additional or separate indicators, or adjustments to indicators, may be necessary for focus countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a2c485c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s7631/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of Task Force</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The statutory authorization for the Task Force provided by this chapter shall terminate on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002861">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002861"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a2c485d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/231/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 114–231, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/952">130 Stat. 952</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLIX/s5943/c/2">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5943(c)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3471">136 Stat. 3471</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a2c485e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a2c485f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a2c4860-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 13648, referred to in subsec. (a), is Ex. Ord. No. 13648, <date date="2013-07-01">July 1, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 40621, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">section 1531 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/114/231">Pub. L. 114–231</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/949">130 Stat. 949</ref>, known as the Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act of 2016, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s7601">section 7601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a2c4861-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(5) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5943/c/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5943(c)(2)</ref>, added pars. (5) to (8) and redesignated former par. (5) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5943/c/3/A/i">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5943(c)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “biennially” for “annually” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5943/c/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5943(c)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>–(iv), added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5943/c/3/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5943(c)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>” for “5 years after <date date="2016-10-07">October 7, 2016</date>, or such earlier date that the President terminates the Task Force by rescinding, superseding, or otherwise modifying relevant portions of Executive Order 13648.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
