<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78994bac-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e"><num value="777e">§ 777e.</num><heading> Submission and approval of plans and projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78994bad-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State desiring to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter shall, by its State fish and game department, submit programs or projects for fish restoration in either of the following two ways:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78994bae-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The State shall prepare and submit to the Secretary of the Interior a comprehensive fish and wildlife resource management plan which shall insure the perpetuation of these resources for the economic, scientific, and recreational enrichment of the people. Such plan shall be for a period of not less than five years and be based on projections of desires and needs of the people for a period of not less than fifteen years. It shall include provisions for updating at intervals of not more than three years and be provided in a format as may be required by the Secretary of the Interior. If the Secretary of the Interior finds that such plans conform to standards established by him and approves such plans, he may finance up to 75 per centum of the cost of implementing segments of those plans meeting the purposes of this chapter from funds apportioned under this chapter upon his approval of an annual agreement submitted to him.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78994baf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A State may elect to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter by its State fish and game department submitting to the Secretary of the Interior full and detailed statements of any fish restoration and management project proposed for that State. If the Secretary of the Interior finds that such project meets with the standards set by him and approves said project, the State fish and game department shall furnish to him such surveys, plans, specifications, and estimates therefor as he may require. If the Secretary of the Interior approves the plans, specifications, and estimates for the project, he shall notify the State fish and game department and immediately set aside so much of said appropriation as represents the share of the United States payable under this chapter on account of such project, which sum so set aside shall not exceed 75 per centum of the total estimated cost thereof.<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall approve only such comprehensive plans or projects as may be substantial in character and design and the expenditure of funds hereby authorized shall be applied only to such approved comprehensive fishery plan or projects and if otherwise applied they shall be replaced by the State before it may participate in any further apportionment under this chapter. No payment of any money apportioned under this chapter shall be made on any comprehensive fishery plan or project until an agreement to participate therein shall have been submitted to and approved by the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78994bb0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> “Project” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the State elects to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter by preparing a comprehensive fish and wildlife plan under option (1) of subsection (a) of this section, then the term “project” may be defined for the purpose of this chapter as a fishery program, all other definitions notwithstanding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78994bb1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Administrative costs in the form of overhead or indirect costs for services provided by State central service activities outside of the State fish and game department charged against programs or projects supported by funds made available under this chapter shall not exceed in any one fiscal year 3 per centum of the annual apportionment to the State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78994bb2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s777e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements to finance initial costs of acquisition of lands and construction of structures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may enter into agreements to finance up to 75 per centum of the initial costs of the acquisition of lands or interests therein and the construction of structures or facilities from appropriations currently available for the purposes of this chapter; and to agree to finance up to 75 per centum of the remaining costs over such a period of time as the Secretary may consider necessary. The liability of the United States in any such agreement is contingent upon the continued availability of funds for the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78994bb3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-08-09/ch658/s6">Aug. 9, 1950, ch. 658, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/432">64 Stat. 432</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/503/tII/s202">Pub. L. 91–503, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1970-10-23">Oct. 23, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1102">84 Stat. 1102</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tX/s1014/a/5">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title X, § 1014(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1016">98 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tX/s10001/c">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title X, § 10001(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1621">129 Stat. 1621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78994bb4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78994bb5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78994bb6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> substituted “from appropriations” for “for appropriations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/503">Pub. L. 91–503</ref> added an alternative method of application for funds by submission of a comprehensive fish and wildlife resource management plan for a period of five years based on projections for fifteen years, to be updated every three years, laid down a maximum limit of assistance of 75 percent of the estimated cost of the implementation of plan, and in existing method of application struck out reference to Secretary of the Treasury and requirement that State pay 10 percent of costs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/503">Pub. L. 91–503</ref> added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78994bb7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78994bb8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78994bb9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-10-01">Oct. 1, 1984</date>, and applicable with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">Sept. 30, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s1014/b">section 1014(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s777">section 777 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78994bba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78994bbb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions to Secretary of Commerce from Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s777">section 777 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
