<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76fa68c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b"><num value="79b">§ 79b.</num><heading> Park area</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id76fa68c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Boundaries; maps; maximum acreage</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id76fa68c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Redwood National Park consists of the land generally depicted on the map entitled “Redwood National Park, Revised Boundary”, numbered 167/60502, and dated February, 2003.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id76fa68ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The map referred to in paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id76fa68cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id76fa68cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provided by the Secretary of the Interior to the appropriate officers of Del Norte and Humboldt Counties, California.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id76fa68cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002011"><num>1</num> So in original. The semicolon probably should not appear.</note> of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may from time to time, with a view to carrying out the purpose of this subchapter and with particular attention to minimizing siltation of the streams, damage to the timber, and assuring the preservation of the scenery within the boundaries of the national park as depicted on said maps, modify said boundaries, giving notice of any changes involved therein by publication of a revised drawing or boundary description in the Federal Register and by filing said revision with the officers with whom the original maps were filed, but the acreage within said park shall at no time exceed 133,000 acres, exclusive of submerged lands and publicly owned highways and roads.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id76fa68ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Highways and roads</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to acquire all or part of existing publicly owned highways and roads within the boundaries of the park as he may deem necessary for park purposes. Until such highways and roads have been acquired, the Secretary may cooperate with appropriate State and local officials in patroling <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002012"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “patrolling”.</note> and maintaining such roads and highways.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id76fa68cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Park protection zone</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the area outside the boundaries of Redwood National Park indicated as the “Park Protection Zone” on the map entitled “Proposed Additions, Redwood National Park, California”, numbered 167–80005–D and dated March 1978, the Secretary is authorized to acquire lands and interests in land: <i>Provided</i>, That lands may be acquired from a willing seller or upon a finding by the Secretary that failure to acquire all or a portion of such lands could result in physical damage to park resources and following notice to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives. Any lands so acquired shall be managed in a manner which will maximize the protection of the resources of Redwood National Park, and in accordance with the Act of <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.]. Acquisition of a parcel of land under the authority of this subsection shall not as a result of such acquisition diminish the right of owners of adjacent lands to the peaceful use and enjoyment of their land and shall not confer authority upon the Secretary to acquire additional lands except as provided in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id76fa68d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/545/s2">Pub. L. 90–545, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/931">82 Stat. 931</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/tI/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 95–250, title I, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/163">92 Stat. 163</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s6/d/7">Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4583">108 Stat. 4583</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/131/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 109–131, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2005-12-20">Dec. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2569">119 Stat. 2569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76fa68d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76fa68d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id76fa68d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>), referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2743">90 Stat. 2743</ref>, known as the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, which is classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">section 1701 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id76fa68d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/131">Pub. L. 109–131</ref> designated existing provisions of first sentence as par. (1), in par. (1) substituted “The Redwood National Park consists of the land generally depicted on the map entitled ‘Redwood National Park, Revised Boundary’, numbered 167/60502, and dated February, 2003.” for “The area to be included within the Redwood National Park is that generally depicted on the maps entitled ‘Redwood National Park,’ numbered NPS–RED–7114–A and NPS–RED–7114–B, and dated September 1968, and the area indicated as ‘Proposed Additions’ on the map entitled ‘Additional Lands, Redwood National Park, California,’ numbered 167–80005–D and dated March 1978, copies of which maps shall be kept available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and shall be filed with appropriate officers of Del Norte and Humboldt Counties.”, added par. (2), designated existing provisions of second sentence as par. (3), and in par. (3) substituted “The Secretary;” for “The Secretary” and “133,000 acres” for “one hundred and six thousand acres”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committee on”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 95–250, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “and the area indicated as ‘Proposed Additions’ on the map entitled ‘Additional Lands, Redwood National Park, California’, numbered 167–80005–D and dated March 1978,” after “and dated September 1968,” and substituted “one hundred and six thousand acres, exclusive of submerged lands and publicly owned highways and roads” for “fifty-eight thousand acres, exclusive of submerged lands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 95–250, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “by donation only” after “The Secretary is authorized to acquire”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 95–250, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
