<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76fa68e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79c–1"><num value="79c–1">§ 79c–1.</num><heading> Vesting in United States of all right, title, etc., in real property and down tree personal property in additional lands; effective date; authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of the Act of <date date="1968-10-02">October 2, 1968</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79a">16 U.S.C. 79a</ref> et seq.], the vesting in the United States of all right, title, and interest in, and the right to immediate possession of, all real property and all down tree personal property within the area indicated as “Proposed Additions” on the map entitled “Additional Lands, Redwood National Park, California,” numbered 167–80005–D and dated March 1978, as established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c/b/1">section 79c(b)(1) of this title</ref>, shall be effective on <date date="1978-03-27">March 27, 1978</date>. The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c/b/3">section 79c(b)(3) of this title</ref> shall also relate to the effective date of this section. From the appropriations authorized for fiscal year 1978 and succeeding fiscal years such sums as may be necessary may be expended for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands, and down tree personal property, authorized to be acquired, or acquired, pursuant to the provisions of this Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76fa68e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/250/tI/s101/c">Pub. L. 95–250, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/166">92 Stat. 166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76fa68e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76fa68e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id76fa68e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1968-10-02">October 2, 1968</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/90/545">Pub. L. 90–545</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/931">82 Stat. 931</ref>, which is classified generally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c/b/1">Section 79c(b)(1) of this title</ref>, referred to in text, was in the original “subsection (a)(4) of the first section of this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/s101/a/4">section 101(a)(4) of Pub. L. 95–250</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c/b/1">section 79c(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/pl/95/250">Pub. L. 95–250</ref>, <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/163">92 Stat. 163</ref>, which, insofar as classified to the Code, enacted sections 79c–1 and 79k to 79q of this title, amended former section 1a–1 and sections 79b and 79c of this title, and enacted provisions set out and formerly set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79k">section 79k of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this section, referred to in text, probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/250/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 95–250</ref>, which was approved <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76fa68e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/pl/90/545">Pub. L. 90–545</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/931">82 Stat. 931</ref>, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
