<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76fa68f3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79g"><num value="79g">§ 79g.</num><heading> Contract authorization within prescribed cost limits; installments: duration, interest; provisions for payment of judgments and compromise settlements applicable to judgments against United States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id76fa68f4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79g/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall have the same authority with respect to contracts for the acquisition of land and interests in land for the purposes of this subchapter as was given the Secretary of the Treasury for other land acquisitions by <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3171">section 3171 of title 40</ref>, and the Secretary and the owner of land to be acquired under this subchapter may agree that the purchase price will be paid in periodic installments over a period that does not exceed ten years, with interest on the unpaid balance thereof at a rate which is not in excess of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities on the installments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id76fcd9f5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s79g/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Judgments against the United States, including final partial judgments and compromise settlements of claims referred to the Attorney General for defense of suits against the United States, for amounts in excess of the deposit in court in actions under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c">section 79c of this title</ref> shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1304">section 1304 of title 31</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2414">section 2414 of title 28</ref>. Final partial judgments and compromise settlements are payable only after certification by the Attorney General to the Comptroller General that it is in the interest of the United States to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id76fcd9f6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/545/s7">Pub. L. 90–545, § 7</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/934">82 Stat. 934</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/151/tII/s203">Pub. L. 99–151, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1985-11-13">Nov. 13, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/807">99 Stat. 807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76fcd9f7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76fcd9f8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76fcd9f9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3171">Section 3171 of title 40</ref>” substituted in subsec. (a) for “<ref href="/us/act/1908-05-30/s34">section 34 of the Act of May 30, 1908</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/35/545">35 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s261">40 U.S.C. 261</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id76fcd9fa-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/151">Pub. L. 99–151</ref>, in amending subsec. (b) generally, inserted provisions relating to final partial judgments and compromise settlements, substituted reference to actions under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s79c">section 79c of this title</ref> for reference to condemnation actions, and deleted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2517">section 2517 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
