<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a31039e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8012"><num value="8012">§ 8012.</num><heading> Engagement of diplomatic missions of the United States</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, each chief of mission (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3902">section 3902 of title 22</ref>) to a relevant country in a priority region or to a priority flag state may, if the Secretary of State determines such action is appropriate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31039f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8012/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> convene a working group, led by Department of State officials, to examine IUU fishing, which may include stakeholders such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a3103a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8012/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> United States officials from relevant agencies participating in the interagency Working Group identified in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s8031">section 8031 of this title</ref>, foreign officials, nongovernmental organizations, the private sector, and representatives of local fishermen in the region; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a3103a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8012/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> experts on IUU fishing, law enforcement, criminal justice, transnational organized illegal activity, defense, intelligence, vessel movement monitoring, and international development operating in or with knowledge of the region; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3103a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8012/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> designate a counter-IUU Fishing Coordinator from among existing personnel at the mission if the chief of mission determines such action is appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7a3103a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dC/tXXXV/s3542">Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3542</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2001">133 Stat. 2001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
