<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76ff245f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s80a–3"><num value="80a–3">§ 80a–3.</num><heading> Lands excluded from Sierra National Forest and Sequoia National Forest and added to Kings Canyon National Park</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All lands in Tehipite Valley within the Sierra National Forest lying north of a line described as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">Beginning at a point on the existing west boundary of the Kings Canyon National Park on the hydrographic divide on the southwest side of the Gorge of Despair in section 13, township 12 south, range 29 east, Mount Diablo base and meridian, being the crest of a ridge designated as Silver Spur;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">thence following the crest of Silver Spur westerly to the intersection with the west line of section 14, township 12 south, range 29 east; thence northwesterly in a straight line across the middle fork of the Kings River to the point of intersection of the right bank of a stream or intermittent stream and the 4,400-foot contour north of Tombstone Ridge, in section 15, township 12 south, range 29 east, being a point on the existing west boundary of the park;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and all lands in the Cedar Grove area of the Sequoia National Forest lying east of the west section lines of sections 11 and 14, township 13 south, range 30 east, Mount Diablo base and meridian, are hereby excluded from the said national forests and made a part of the Kings Canyon National Park, subject to all the laws and regulations applicable to such park.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76ff2460-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/111">Pub. L. 89–111</ref>, <date date="1965-08-06">Aug. 6, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/446">79 Stat. 446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76ff2461-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76ff2462-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76ff2463-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/act/1940-03-04/ch40">act Mar. 4, 1940, ch. 40</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/41">54 Stat. 41</ref>, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
