<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78a2e921-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s812"><num value="812">§ 812.</num><heading> Public-service licensee; regulations by State or by commission as to service, rates, charges, etc.</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a condition of the license, every licensee under this chapter which is a public-service corporation, or a person, association, or corporation owning or operating any project and developing, transmitting, or distributing power for sale or use in public service, shall abide by such reasonable regulation of the services to be rendered to customers or consumers of power, and of rates and charges of payment therefor, as may from time to time be prescribed by any duly constituted agency of the State in which the service is rendered or the rate charged. That in case of the development, transmission, or distribution, or use in public service of power by any licensee under this chapter or by its customer engaged in public service within a State which has not authorized and empowered a commission or other agency or agencies within said State to regulate and control the services to be rendered by such licensee or by its customer engaged in public service, or the rates and charges of payment therefor, or the amount or character of securities to be issued by any of said parties, it is agreed as a condition of such license that jurisdiction is conferred upon the commission, upon complaint of any person aggrieved or upon its own initiative, to exercise such regulation and control until such time as the State shall have provided a commission or other authority for such regulation and control: <i>Provided</i>, That the jurisdiction of the commission shall cease and determine as to each specific matter of regulation and control prescribed in this section as soon as the State shall have provided a commission or other authority for the regulation and control of that specific matter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78a2e922-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, pt. I, § 19, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1073">41 Stat. 1073</ref>; renumbered pt. I, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-26/ch687">Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 687</ref>, title II, § 212, <ref href="/us/stat/49/847">49 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
