<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76ff2494-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s81b"><num value="81b">§ 81b.</num><heading> Revision of boundaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to all the laws and regulations applicable to the Colonial National Historical Park, the boundaries of said historical park as established by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s81a">section 81a of this title</ref> and as defined by Presidential Proclamation Numbered 2055, dated <date date="1933-08-22">August 22, 1933</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/1706">48 Stat. 1706</ref>), are revised by the elimination of the parkway area described in said proclamation as running north and west of the city of Williamsburg to Jamestown Island, and the substitution therefor of a parkway area running southerly through or around the city of Williamsburg, thence continuing south of said city to the James River and thence along said river and connecting waters to Jamestown Island, the exact location of which shall be determined by the Secretary of the Interior: <i>Provided</i>, That said parkway area shall not exceed an average of five hundred feet in width outside the city of Williamsburg: <i>And provided further</i>, That condemnation proceedings shall not be had, exercised, or resorted to as to any lands in the city of Williamsburg except such lands as may be required for a right-of-way not exceeding two hundred feet in width through said city to connect with highways or parkways leading from Williamsburg to Jamestown and Yorktown.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76ff2495-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-28/ch775/s1">June 28, 1938, ch. 775, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1208">52 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76ff2496-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76ff2497-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76ff2498-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/act/1930-07-03/ch837">act July 3, 1930, ch. 837</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/855">46 Stat. 855</ref>, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id76ff2499-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id76ff249a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1936-06-05">June 5, 1936</date>, changed “Colonial National Monument” to “Colonial National Historical Park”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
