<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id76ff249b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s81c"><num value="81c">§ 81c.</num><heading> Addition of lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion, to acquire by purchase and/or accept by donation, in behalf of the United States, such lands, easements, and buildings comprising the former Governor Berkeley’s mansion and homestead in James City County and Carter’s Grove mansion and homestead in the same county, and the Rosewell mansion and homestead in Gloucester County as are desirable for the proper rounding out of the boundaries and for the administrative control of the Colonial National Historical Park, and such lands as are necessary for parkways, not to exceed five hundred feet wide, to connect said mansions to the said Colonial National Historical Park, the title and evidence of title to lands acquired to be satisfactory to the Secretary of the Interior: <i>Provided</i>, That the said acquisition of lands and/or improvements shall be made only from such funds as may be appropriated pursuant to the authorization of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s81f">section 81f of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id76ff249c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-05/ch525">June 5, 1936, ch. 525</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1483">49 Stat. 1483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id76ff249d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id76ff249e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id76ff249f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/act/1930-07-03/ch837">act July 3, 1930, ch. 837</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/855">46 Stat. 855</ref>, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s443a–1">section 443a–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id76ff24a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id76ff24a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/act/1936-06-05/ch525/s2">Act June 5, 1936, ch. 525, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1483">49 Stat. 1483</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1936-06-05/ch525/s2">“That the area now within the Colonial National Monument, together with such additions as may hereafter be made thereto, pursuant to section 1 hereof, shall be known as the ‘Colonial National Historical Park’, under which name the aforesaid national park shall be entitled to receive and to use all moneys heretofore or hereafter appropriated for the Colonial National Monument.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
