<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78a7a41b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824"><num value="824">§ 824.</num><heading> Declaration of policy; application of subchapter</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a41c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal regulation of transmission and sale of electric energy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is declared that the business of transmitting and selling electric energy for ultimate distribution to the public is affected with a public interest, and that Federal regulation of matters relating to generation to the extent provided in this subchapter and subchapter III of this chapter and of that part of such business which consists of the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce and the sale of such energy at wholesale in interstate commerce is necessary in the public interest, such Federal regulation, however, to extend only to those matters which are not subject to regulation by the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a41d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use or sale of electric energy in interstate commerce</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a41e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The provisions of this subchapter shall apply to the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce and to the sale of electric energy at wholesale in interstate commerce, but except as provided in paragraph (2) shall not apply to any other sale of electric energy or deprive a State or State commission of its lawful authority now exercised over the exportation of hydroelectric energy which is transmitted across a State line. The Commission shall have jurisdiction over all facilities for such transmission or sale of electric energy, but shall not have jurisdiction, except as specifically provided in this subchapter and subchapter III of this chapter, over facilities used for the generation of electric energy or over facilities used in local distribution or only for the transmission of electric energy in intrastate commerce, or over facilities for the transmission of electric energy consumed wholly by the transmitter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a41f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (f), the provisions of sections 824b(a)(2), 824e(e), 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824<i>o</i>–1, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, and 824v of this title shall apply to the entities described in such provisions, and such entities shall be subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission for purposes of carrying out such provisions and for purposes of applying the enforcement authorities of this chapter with respect to such provisions. Compliance with any order or rule of the Commission under the provisions of section 824b(a)(2), 824e(e), 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824<i>o</i>–1, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, or 824v of this title, shall not make an electric utility or other entity subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission for any purposes other than the purposes specified in the preceding sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a420-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Electric energy in interstate commerce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter, electric energy shall be held to be transmitted in interstate commerce if transmitted from a State and consumed at any point outside thereof; but only insofar as such transmission takes place within the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a421-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “Sale of electric energy at wholesale” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “sale of electric energy at wholesale” when used in this subchapter, means a sale of electric energy to any person for resale.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a422-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “Public utility” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “public utility” when used in this subchapter and subchapter III of this chapter means any person who owns or operates facilities subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under this subchapter (other than facilities subject to such jurisdiction solely by reason of section 824e(e), 824e(f),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002528">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002528"><num>1</num> So in original. <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s824e">Section 824e of this title</ref> does not contain a subsec. (f).</note> 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824<i>o</i>–1, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, or 824v of this title).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a423-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> United States, State, political subdivision of a State, or agency or instrumentality thereof exempt</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision in this subchapter shall apply to, or be deemed to include, the United States, a State or any political subdivision of a State, an electric cooperative that receives financing under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) or that sells less than 4,000,000 megawatt hours of electricity per year, or any agency, authority, or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing, or any corporation which is wholly owned, directly or indirectly, by any one or more of the foregoing, or any officer, agent, or employee of any of the foregoing acting as such in the course of his official duty, unless such provision makes specific reference thereto.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a424-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Books and records</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a425-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon written order of a State commission, a State commission may examine the books, accounts, memoranda, contracts, and records of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a426-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an electric utility company subject to its regulatory authority under State law,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a427-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any exempt wholesale generator selling energy at wholesale to such electric utility, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a428-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any electric utility company, or holding company thereof, which is an associate company or affiliate of an exempt wholesale generator which sells electric energy to an electric utility company referred to in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">wherever located, if such examination is required for the effective discharge of the State commission’s regulatory responsibilities affecting the provision of electric service.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a429-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Where a State commission issues an order pursuant to paragraph (1), the State commission shall not publicly disclose trade secrets or sensitive commercial information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a42a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any United States district court located in the State in which the State commission referred to in paragraph (1) is located shall have jurisdiction to enforce compliance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a42b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Nothing in this section shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a42c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> preempt applicable State law concerning the provision of records and other information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a42d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in any way limit rights to obtain records and other information under Federal law, contracts, or otherwise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a42e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> As used in this subsection the terms “affiliate”, “associate company”, “electric utility company”, “holding company”, “subsidiary company”, and “exempt wholesale generator” shall have the same meaning as when used in the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 2005 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16451">42 U.S.C. 16451</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78a7a42f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, pt. II, § 201, as added <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-26/ch687">Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 687</ref>, title II, § 213, <ref href="/us/stat/49/847">49 Stat. 847</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tII/s204/b">Pub. L. 95–617, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3140">92 Stat. 3140</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tVII/s714">Pub. L. 102–486, title VII, § 714</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2911">106 Stat. 2911</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII</ref>, §§ 1277(b)(1), 1291(c), 1295(a), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/978">119 Stat. 978</ref>, 985; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dF/s61003/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. F, § 61003(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1778">129 Stat. 1778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78a7a430-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78a7a431-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78a7a432-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rural Electrification Act of 1936, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-05-20/ch432">act May 20, 1936, ch. 432</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1363">49 Stat. 1363</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 31 (§ 901 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">section 901 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Utility Holding Company Act of 2005, referred to in subsec. (g)(5), is subtitle F of title XII of <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/972">119 Stat. 972</ref>, which is classified principally to part D (§ 16451 et seq.) of subchapter XII of chapter 149 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15801">section 15801 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78a7a433-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s61003/b/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 61003(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “824<i>o</i>–1,” after “824<i>o</i>,” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s61003/b/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 61003(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “824<i>o</i>–1,” after “824<i>o</i>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1295/a/1">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1295(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Notwithstanding subsection (f), the provisions of sections 824b(a)(2), 824e(e), 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, and 824v of this title” for “The provisions of sections 824i, 824j, and 824k of this title” and “Compliance with any order or rule of the Commission under the provisions of section 824b(a)(2), 824e(e), 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, or 824v of this title” for “Compliance with any order of the Commission under the provisions of section 824i or 824j of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1295/a/2">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1295(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 824e(e), 824e(f), 824i, 824j, 824j–1, 824k, 824<i>o</i>, 824p, 824q, 824r, 824s, 824t, 824u, or 824v of this title” for “section 824i, 824j, or 824k of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1291/c">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1291(c)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (f) by substituting “political subdivision of a State, an electric cooperative that receives financing under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s901">7 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) or that sells less than 4,000,000 megawatt hours of electricity per year,” for “political subdivision of a state,”, was executed by making the substitution for “political subdivision of a State,” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1277/b/1">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1277(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “2005” for “1935”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/617/s204/b/1">Pub. L. 95–617, § 204(b)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “except as provided in paragraph (2)” after “in interstate commerce, but”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/617/s204/b/2">Pub. L. 95–617, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “(other than facilities subject to such jurisdiction solely by reason of section 824i, 824j, or 824k of this title)” after “under this subchapter”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78a7a434-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78a7a435-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1277/b/1">section 1277(b)(1) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref> effective 6 months after <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, with provisions relating to effect of compliance with certain regulations approved and made effective prior to such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1274">section 1274 of Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16451">section 16451 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78a7a436-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">State Authorities; Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> to be construed as affecting or intending to affect, or in any way to interfere with, authority of any State or local government relating to environmental protection or siting of facilities, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s731">section 731 of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s796">section 796 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78a7a437-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Actions; Effect On Other Authorities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tII/s214">Pub. L. 95–617, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3149">92 Stat. 3149</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/617/tII/s214">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prior Actions</inline>.—</heading><content>No provision of this title [enacting sections 823a, 824i to 824k, 824a–1 to 824a–3 and 825q–1 of this title, amending sections 796, 824, 824a, 824d, and 825d of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 824a, 824d, and 825d of this title] or of any amendment made by this title shall apply to, or affect, any action taken by the Commission [Federal Energy Regulatory Commission] before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Authorities.—</inline></heading><content>No provision of this title [enacting sections 823a, 824i to 824k, 824a–1 to 824a–3 and 825q–1 of this title, amending sections 796, 824, 824a, 824d, and 825d of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 824a, 824d, and 825d of this title] or of any amendment made by this title shall limit, impair or otherwise affect any authority of the Commission or any other agency or instrumentality of the United States under any other provision of law except as specifically provided in this title.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
