<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78a7a468-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2"><num value="824a–2">§ 824a–2.</num><heading> Reliability</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a469-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a46a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall conduct a study with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a46b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the level of reliability appropriate to adequately serve the needs of electric consumers, taking into account cost effectiveness and the need for energy conservation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a46c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the various methods which could be used in order to achieve such level of reliability and the cost effectiveness of such methods, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a46d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the various procedures that might be used in case of an emergency outage to minimize the public disruption and economic loss that might be caused by such an outage and the cost effectiveness of such procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such study shall be completed and submitted to the President and the Congress not later than 18 months after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>. Before such submittal the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment on the results of such study.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78a7a46e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The study under paragraph (1) shall include consideration of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a46f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the cost effectiveness of investments in each of the components involved in providing adequate and reliable electric service, including generation, transmission, and distribution facilities, and devices available to the electric consumer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a470-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the environmental and other effects of the investments considered under subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a471-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> various types of electric utility systems in terms of generation, transmission, distribution and customer mix, the extent to which differences in reliability levels may be desirable, and the cost-effectiveness of the various methods which could be used to decrease the number and severity of any outages among the various types of systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a472-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> alternatives to adding new generation facilities to achieve such desired levels of reliability (including conservation);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a473-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the cost-effectiveness of adding a number of small, decentralized conventional and nonconventional generating units rather than a small number of large generating units with a similar total megawatt capacity for achieving the desired level of reliability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a474-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any standards for electric utility reliability used by, or suggested for use by, the electric utility industry in terms of cost-effectiveness in achieving the desired level of reliability, including equipment standards, standards for operating procedures and training of personnel, and standards relating the number and severity of outages to periods of time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a475-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Examination of reliability issues by reliability councils</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, may, from time to time, request the reliability councils established under section 202(a) of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s824a/a">16 U.S.C. 824a(a)</ref> of this title] or other appropriate persons (including Federal agencies) to examine and report to him concerning any electric utility reliability issue. The Secretary shall report to the Congress (in its annual report or in the report required under subsection (a) if appropriate) the results of any examination under the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78a7a476-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of Energy recommendations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, and after opportunity for public comment, may recommend industry standards for reliability to the electric utility industry, including standards with respect to equipment, operating procedures and training of personnel, and standards relating to the level or levels of reliability appropriate to adequately and reliably serve the needs of electric consumers. The Secretary shall include in his annual report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a477-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any recommendations made under this subsection or any recommendations respecting electric utility reliability problems under any other provision of law, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a7a478-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s824a–2/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of actions taken by electric utilities with respect to such recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78a7a479-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tII/s209">Pub. L. 95–617, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3143">92 Stat. 3143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78a7a47a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78a7a47b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78a7a47c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, and not as part of the Federal Power Act which generally comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78a7a47d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id78a7a47e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2602">section 2602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
