<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78b38b95-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m"><num value="825m">§ 825m.</num><heading> Enforcement provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78b38b96-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Enjoining and restraining violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever it shall appear to the Commission that any person is engaged or about to engage in any acts or practices which constitute or will constitute a violation of the provisions of this chapter, or of any rule, regulation, or order thereunder, it may in its discretion bring an action in the proper District Court of the United States or the United States courts of any Territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, to enjoin such acts or practices and to enforce compliance with this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order thereunder, and upon a proper showing a permanent or temporary injunction or decree or restraining order shall be granted without bond. The Commission may transmit such evidence as may be available concerning such acts or practices to the Attorney General, who, in his discretion, may institute the necessary criminal proceedings under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78b38b97-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Writs of mandamus</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon application of the Commission the district courts of the United States and the United States courts of any Territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States shall have jurisdiction to issue writs of mandamus commanding any person to comply with the provisions of this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order of the Commission thereunder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78b38b98-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of attorneys</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may employ such attorneys as it finds necessary for proper legal aid and service of the Commission or its members in the conduct of their work, or for proper representation of the public interests in investigations made by it or cases or proceedings pending before it, whether at the Commission’s own instance or upon complaint, or to appear for or represent the Commission in any case in court; and the expenses of such employment shall be paid out of the appropriation for the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78b38b99-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on violators</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any proceedings under subsection (a), the court may prohibit, conditionally or unconditionally, and permanently or for such period of time as the court determines, any individual who is engaged or has engaged in practices constituting a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s824u">section 824u of this title</ref> (and related rules and regulations) from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78b38b9a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> acting as an officer or director of an electric utility; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78b38b9b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> engaging in the business of purchasing or selling—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78b38b9c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> electric energy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78b38b9d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825m/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> transmission services subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78b38b9e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, pt. III, § 314, as added <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-26/ch687">Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 687</ref>, title II, § 213, <ref href="/us/stat/49/861">49 Stat. 861</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-25/ch804">June 25, 1936, ch. 804</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1921">49 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s32/b">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/991">62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/107">63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII/s1288">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII, § 1288</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/982">119 Stat. 982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78b38b9f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78b38ba0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78b38ba1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">As originally enacted subsecs. (a) and (b) contained references to the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia. Act <date date="1936-06-25">June 25, 1936</date>, substituted “the district court of the United States for the District of Columbia” for “the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia”, and act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, as amended by act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, substituted “United States District Court for the District of Columbia” for “district court of the United States for the District of Columbia”. However, the words “United States District Court for the District of Columbia” have been deleted entirely as superfluous in view of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s132/a">section 132(a) of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, which states that “There shall be in each judicial district a district court which shall be a court of record known as the United States District Court for the district”, and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s88">section 88 of Title 28</ref> which states that “the District of Columbia constitutes one judicial district”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78b38ba2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
