<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78b5fc01-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s825s–4"><num value="825s–4">§ 825s–4.</num><heading> Southwestern Power Administration; deposit and availability of advance payments</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref>, beginning in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter, such funds as are received by the Southwestern Power Administration from any State, municipality, corporation, association, firm, district, or individual as advance payment for work that is associated with Southwestern’s transmission facilities, consistent with that authorized in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s825s">section 825s of this title</ref>, shall be credited to this account and be available until expended.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78b5fc02-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 108–447, div. C, title III</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2956">118 Stat. 2956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78b5fc03-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78b5fc04-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78b5fc05-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2005, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005, and not as part of the Federal Power Act which generally comprises this chapter. Section is based on the proviso in the paragraph under the headings “POWER MARKETING ADMINISTRATIONS” and “<inline class="small-caps">Operation and Maintenance, Southwestern Power Administration</inline>” in title III of div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id78b5fc06-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in the following prior appropriation act:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/137/tIII">Pub. L. 108–137, title III</ref>, <date date="2003-12-01">Dec. 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1858">117 Stat. 1858</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
