<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78bd2807-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s831ee"><num value="831ee">§ 831ee.</num><heading> Essential stewardship activities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For essential stewardship activities for which appropriations were provided to the Tennessee Valley Authority in <ref href="/us/pl/104/206">Public Law 104–206</ref>, such sums as are necessary in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, to be derived only from one or more of the following sources: nonpower fund balances and collections; investment returns of the nonpower program; applied programmatic savings in the power and nonpower programs; savings from the suspension of bonuses and awards; savings from reductions in memberships and contributions; increases in collections resulting from nonpower activities, including user fees; or increases in charges to private and public utilities both investor and cooperatively owned, as well as to direct load customers: <i>Provided</i>, That such funds are available to fund the stewardship activities under this section, notwithstanding sections 11, 14, 15, 29 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s831j">16 U.S.C. 831j</ref>, 831m, 831n, 831bb], or other provisions of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s831">16 U.S.C. 831</ref> et seq.], as amended, or provisions of the TVA power bond covenants: <i>Provided further</i>, That the savings from, and revenue adjustments to, the TVA budget in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter shall be sufficient to fund the aforementioned stewardship activities such that the net spending authority and resulting outlays for these activities shall not exceed $0 in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78bd2808-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/62/tIV">Pub. L. 105–62, title IV</ref>, <date date="1997-10-13">Oct. 13, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1338">111 Stat. 1338</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78bd2809-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78bd280a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78bd280b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/206">Public Law 104–206</ref>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/104/206">Pub. L. 104–206</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2984">110 Stat. 2984</ref>, known as the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1997. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tennessee Valley Authority Act, referred to in text, probably means the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-18/ch32">act May 18, 1933, ch. 32</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/58">48 Stat. 58</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s831">section 831 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78bd280c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1998, and not as part of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
