<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78c69d7b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s835k"><num value="835k">§ 835k.</num><heading> Return of construction costs from marketing revenues in event of inability of irrigation water users to repay within repayment period and lack of other sources of revenue</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of section 835<i>l</i> of this title, that portion of the construction cost of any project hereafter authorized to be constructed, operated, and maintained by the Secretary of the Interior under the Federal reclamation laws (Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto) within the Pacific Northwest which, though allocated to irrigation, is beyond the ability of the irrigation water users to repay within the repayment period prescribed by law for that project and cannot be returned within the same period from other project sources of revenue shall be charged to and returned within that period from net revenues derived from the marketing of commercial power and energy through the Federal Columbia River power system, unless otherwise provided by law. As used in this section, the term “Pacific Northwest” has the meaning ascribed to it in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s837">section 837 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78c69d7c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/448/s2/a">Pub. L. 89–448, § 2(a)</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1966-06-14">June 14, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/200">80 Stat. 200</ref>, renumbered and amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/561/s6/1">Pub. L. 89–561, § 6(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/714">80 Stat. 714</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78c69d7d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78c69d7e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78c69d7f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1902-06-17">June 17, 1902</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1902-06-17/ch1093">act June 17, 1902, ch. 1093</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/388">32 Stat. 388</ref>, popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 371 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s371">section 371 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78c69d80-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of second par. of <ref href="/us/pl/89/448/s2/a">section 2(a) of Pub. L. 89–448</ref>, as so designated by <ref href="/us/pl/89/561">Pub. L. 89–561</ref>. First sentence of first par. of such section 2(a) is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s835j">section 835j of this title</ref>; second sentence of such first par. repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s832h/c">section 832h(c) of this title</ref>; subsecs. (b) and (c) of section 2 are classified to sections 835<i>l</i> and 835m of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78c69d81-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/561/s6/2">Pub. L. 89–561, § 6(2)</ref>, substituted “Subject to the provisions of section 835<i>l</i> of this title, that” for “That”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78c69d82-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78c69d83-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Power marketing functions of Bureau of Reclamation, including construction, operation, and maintenance of transmission lines and attendant facilities, transferred to Secretary of Energy by section 7152(a)(1)(E), (3) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and are to be exercised by Secretary through a separate Administration within Department of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
