<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78c90f16-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i"><num value="838i">§ 838i.</num><heading> Bonneville Power Administration fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78c90f17-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition; availability of transferred funds for expenditures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a Bonneville Power Administration fund (hereinafter referred to as the “fund”). The fund shall consist of (1) all receipts, collections, and recoveries of the Administrator in cash from all sources, including trust funds, (2) all proceeds derived from the sale of bonds by the Administrator, (3) any appropriations made by the Congress for the fund, and (4) the following funds which are hereby transferred to the Administrator: (i) all moneys in the special account in the Treasury established pursuant to Executive Order Numbered 8526 dated <date date="1940-08-26">August 26, 1940</date>, (ii) the unexpended balances in the continuing fund established by the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s832j">section 832j of this title</ref>, and (iii) the unexpended balances of funds appropriated or otherwise made available for the Bonneville Power Administration. All funds transferred hereunder shall be available for expenditure by the Secretary of Energy, acting by and through the Administrator, as authorized in this chapter and any other Act relating to the Federal Columbia River transmission system, subject to such limitations as may be prescribed by any applicable appropriation act effective during such period as may elapse between their transfer and the approval by the Congress of the first subsequent annual budget program of the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78c90f18-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorized purposes of expenditures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may make expenditures from the fund, which shall have been included in his annual budget submitted to Congress, without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation, but within such specific directives or limitations as may be included in appropriation acts, for any purpose necessary or appropriate to carry out the duties imposed upon the Administrator pursuant to law, including but not limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f19-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> construction, acquisition, and replacement of (i) the transmission system, including facilities and structures appurtenant thereto, and (ii) additions, improvements, and betterments thereto (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as “transmission system”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> operation, maintenance, repair, and relocation, to the extent such relocation is not provided for under subsection (1) above, of the transmission system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> electrical research, development, experimentation, test, and investigation related to construction, operation, and maintenance of transmission systems and facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> marketing of electric power;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> transmission over facilities of others and rental, lease, or lease-purchase of facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> purchase of electric power (including the entitlement of electric plant capability) (i) on a short-term basis to meet temporary deficiencies in electric power which the Administrator is obligated by contract to supply, or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002551">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002551"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “or” probably should not appear.</note> (ii) if such purchase has been heretofore authorized or is made with funds expressly appropriated for such purchase by the Congress, (iii) if to be paid for with funds provided by other entities for such purpose under a trust or agency arrangement, or (iv) on a short term basis to meet the Administrator’s obligations under section 4(h) of the Pacific Northwest Electric Power Planning and Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s839b/h">16 U.S.C. 839b(h)</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f1f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> defraying emergency expenses or insuring continuous operation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f20-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> paying the interest on, premiums, discounts, and expenses, if any, in connection with the issuance of, and principal of all bonds issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s838k/a">section 838k(a) of this title</ref>, including provision for and maintenance of reserve and other funds established in connection therewith;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f21-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> making such payments to the credit of the reclamation fund or other funds as are required by or pursuant to law to be made into such funds in connection with reclamation projects in the Pacific Northwest: <i>Provided</i>, That this clause shall not be construed as permitting the use of revenues for repayment of costs allocated to irrigation at any project except as otherwise expressly authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f22-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> making payments to the credit of miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury for all unpaid costs required by or pursuant to law to be charged to and returned to the general fund of the Treasury for the repayment of the Federal investment in the Federal Columbia River Power System from electric power marketed by the Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f23-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> acquiring such goods and services, and paying dues and membership fees in such professional, utility, industry, and other societies, associations, and institutes, together with expenses related to such memberships, including but not limited to the acquisitions and payments set forth in the general provisions of the annual appropriations Act for the Department of Energy, as the Administrator determines to be necessary or appropriate in carrying out the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c90f24-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> making such payments, as shall be required to carry out the purposes and provisions of the Pacific Northwest Electric Power Planning and Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s839">16 U.S.C. 839</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78c90f25-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on use of expenditures to authorized purposes; expenditures of moneys received in trust; applicability of provisions relating to control of Government corporations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Moneys heretofore or hereafter appropriated shall be used only for the purposes for which appropriated, and moneys received by the Administrator in trust shall be used only for carrying out such trust. The provisions of chapter 91 of title 31 shall be applicable to the Administrator in the same manner as they are applied to the wholly owned Government corporations named in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101">section 9101 of title 31</ref>, but nothing in section 9105(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002552">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002552"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 31 shall be construed as affecting the powers granted in subsection (b)(11) of this section and in sections 832a(f), 832i(b), and 832k(a) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78c90f26-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s838i/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit of financial transactions by Comptroller General; report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 9105 and 9106 of title 31, the financial transactions of the Administrator shall be audited by the Comptroller General at such times and to such extent as the Comptroller General deems necessary, and reports of the results of each such audit shall be made to the Congress within 6½ months following the end of the fiscal year covered by the audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78c90f27-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/454/s11">Pub. L. 93–454, § 11</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1378">88 Stat. 1378</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s302/a/1/D">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 302(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/578">91 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/501/s8/a">Pub. L. 96–501, § 8(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2728">94 Stat. 2728</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78c90f28-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78c90f29-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78c90f2a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order Numbered 8526 dated <date date="1940-08-26">August 26, 1940</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Pacific Northwest Electric Power Planning and Conservation Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(12), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/501">Pub. L. 96–501</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2697">94 Stat. 2697</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 12H (§ 839 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s839">section 839 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9105">Section 9105 of title 31</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/576/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 101–576, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2853">104 Stat. 2853</ref>, and, as so amended, does not contain a subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78c90f2b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c), “chapter 91 of title 31”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101">section 9101 of title 31</ref>”, and “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9105/d">section 9105(d) of title 31</ref>” substituted for “the Government Corporation Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s841">31 U.S.C. 841</ref> et seq.)”, “section 101 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s846">31 U.S.C. 846</ref>)”, and “the proviso in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s850">section 850 of title 31</ref>, United States Code,”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “sections 9105 and 9106 of title 31” substituted for “sections 105 and 106 of the Government Corporation Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s850">31 U.S.C. 850</ref>, 851]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78c90f2c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b)(6)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/96/501/s8/a">Pub. L. 96–501, § 8(a)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/96/501/s8/b">Pub. L. 96–501, § 8(b)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78c90f2d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78c90f2e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/501">Pub. L. 96–501</ref> effective <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/501/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 96–501</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s839">section 839 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78c90f2f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted for “Secretary of the Interior” in subsec. (a) and “Department of Energy” substituted for “Department of Interior” in subsec. (b)(11) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/s302/a/1/D">Pub. L. 95–91, § 302(a)(1)(D)</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/D">section 7152(a)(1)(D) of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Secretary of the Interior with respect to Bonneville Power Administration transferred to Secretary of Energy by section 7152(a)(1)(D), (2) of Title 42, with Bonneville Power Administration to be preserved as a distinct organizational entity within Department of Energy and headed by an Administrator.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78c90f30-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Bonneville Power Administration Fund: State clean energy programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 116–94, div. C, title III</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2675">133 Stat. 2675</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dC/tIII">“Expenditures from the Bonneville Power Administration Fund, established pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/93/454">Public Law 93–454</ref> are authorized and approved, without fiscal year limitation, for the cost of current and future year purchases or payments of emissions expenses associated with Bonneville Power Administration power and transmission operations in states with clean energy programs: <i>Provided further</i>, This expenditure authorization is limited solely to Bonneville Power Administration’s voluntary purchase or payments made in conjunction with state clean energy programs and is not a broader waiver of Bonneville Power Administration’s sovereign immunity.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78c90f31-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Incur Obligations in Excess of Borrowing Authority and Cash in Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/371/tIII">Pub. L. 100–371, title III</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/869">102 Stat. 869</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/371/tIII">“Without fiscal year limitation, the Bonneville Power Administration continues to be authorized to incur obligations for authorized purposes and may do so in excess of borrowing authority and cash in the Bonneville Power Administration Fund.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
