<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78cb58c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a"><num value="839a">§ 839a.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “Acquire” and “acquisition” shall not be construed as authorizing the Administrator to construct, or have ownership of, under this chapter or any other law, any electric generating facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “Conservation” means any reduction in electric power consumption as a result of increases in the efficiency of energy use, production, or distribution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58c8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> “Cost-effective”, when applied to any measure or resource referred to in this chapter, means that such measure or resource must be forecast—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58c9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to be reliable and available within the time it is needed, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58ca-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to meet or reduce the electric power demand, as determined by the Council or the Administrator, as appropriate, of the consumers of the customers at an estimated incremental system cost no greater than that of the least-cost similarly reliable and available alternative measure or resource, or any combination thereof.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58cb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “system cost” means an estimate of all direct costs of a measure or resource over its effective life, including, if applicable, the cost of distribution and transmission to the consumer and, among other factors, waste disposal costs, end-of-cycle costs, and fuel costs (including projected increases), and such quantifiable environmental costs and benefits as the Administrator determines, on the basis of a methodology developed by the Council as part of the plan, or in the absence of the plan by the Administrator, are directly attributable to such measure or resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58cc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In determining the amount of power that a conservation measure or other resource may be expected to save or to produce, the Council or the Administrator, as the case may be, shall take into account projected realization factors and plant factors, including appropriate historical experience with similar measures or resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58cd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the “estimated incremental system cost” of any conservation measure or resource shall not be treated as greater than that of any nonconservation measure or resource unless the incremental system cost of such conservation measure or resource is in excess of 110 per centum of the incremental system cost of the nonconservation measure or resource.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58ce-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “Consumer” means any end user of electric power.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58cf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> “Council” means, unless otherwise specifically provided, the members appointed to the Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s839b">section 839b of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> “Customer” means anyone who contracts for the purchase of power from the Administrator pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> “Direct service industrial customer” means an industrial customer that contracts for the purchase of power from the Administrator for direct consumption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “Electric power” means electric peaking capacity, or electric energy, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> “Federal base system resources” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58d4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Federal Columbia River Power System hydroelectric projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58d5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> resources acquired by the Administrator under long-term contracts in force on <date date="1980-12-05">December 5, 1980</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58d6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> resources acquired by the Administrator in an amount necessary to replace reductions in capability of the resources referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe or band which is located in whole or in part in the region and which has a governing body which is recognized by the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58d8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> “Major resource” means any resource that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58d9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has a planned capability greater than fifty average megawatts, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58da-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if acquired by the Administrator, is acquired for a period of more than five years.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such term does not include any resource acquired pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s838i/b/6">section 838i(b)(6) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58db-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><chapeau> “New large single load” means any load associated with a new facility, an existing facility, or an expansion of an existing facility—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58dc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which is not contracted for, or committed to, as determined by the Administrator, by a public body, cooperative, investor-owned utility, or Federal agency customer prior to <date date="1979-09-01">September 1, 1979</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58dd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which will result in an increase in power requirements of such customer of ten average megawatts or more in any consecutive twelve-month period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58de-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><chapeau> “Pacific Northwest”, “region”, or “regional” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58df-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/14/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the area consisting of the States of Oregon, Washington, and Idaho, the portion of the State of Montana west of the Continental Divide, and such portions of the States of Nevada, Utah, and Wyoming as are within the Columbia River drainage basin; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58e0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/14/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any contiguous areas, not in excess of seventy-five air miles from the area referred to in subparagraph (A), which are a part of the service area of a rural electric cooperative customer served by the Administrator on <date date="1980-12-05">December 5, 1980</date>, which has a distribution system from which it serves both within and without such region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> “Plan” means the Regional Electric Power and Conservation plan (including any amendments thereto) adopted pursuant to this chapter and such plan shall apply to actions of the Administrator as specified in this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> “Renewable resource” means a resource which utilizes solar, wind, hydro, geothermal, biomass, or similar sources of energy and which either is used for electric power generation or will reduce the electric power requirements of a consumer, including by direct application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> “Reserves” means the electric power needed to avert particular planning or operating shortages for the benefit of firm power customers of the Administrator and available to the Administrator (A) from resources or (B) from rights to interrupt, curtail, or otherwise withdraw, as provided by specific contract provisions, portions of the electric power supplied to customers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> “Residential use” or “residential load” means all usual residential, apartment, seasonal dwelling and farm electrical loads or uses, but only the first four hundred horsepower during any monthly billing period of farm irrigation and pumping for any farm.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><chapeau> “Resource” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58e6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/19/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> electric power, including the actual or planned electric power capability of generating facilities, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78cb58e7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/19/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> actual or planned load reduction resulting from direct application of a renewable energy resource by a consumer, or from a conservation measure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78cb58e8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s839a/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id78cb58e9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/501/s3">Pub. L. 96–501, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2698">94 Stat. 2698</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
