<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a35e608-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401"><num value="8401">§ 8401.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e609-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal land management agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Federal land management agency” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e60a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal recreational lands and waters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Federal recreational lands and waters” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e60b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Gateway community</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “gateway community” means a community that serves as an entry point, or is adjacent, to a recreation destination on Federal recreational lands and waters or non-Federal land at which there is consistently high, in the determination of the Secretaries, seasonal or year-round visitation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e60c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e60d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Land use plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “land use plan” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e60e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a land use plan prepared by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1712">section 1712 of title 43</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e60f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a land management plan prepared by the Forest Service for a unit of the National Forest Service pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1604">section 1604 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e610-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretaries</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretaries” means each of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e611-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e612-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e613-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e614-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary concerned</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e615-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a35e616-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land managed by the Forest Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a35e617-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s8401/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7a35e618-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/118/234/s2">Pub. L. 118–234, § 2</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2837">138 Stat. 2837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a35e619-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a35e61a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a35e61b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in introductory provisions, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/118/234">Pub. L. 118–234</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2836">138 Stat. 2836</ref>, known as the Expanding Public Lands Outdoor Recreation Experiences Act and also known as the EXPLORE Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a35e61c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id7a35e61d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/234/s1/a">Pub. L. 118–234, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2836">138 Stat. 2836</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/234/s1/a">“This Act [enacting this chapter, sections 460<i>l</i>–6d, 558a to 558g, and 6804a of this title, and sections 100905 and 308106 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, amending sections 2113a, 6801 to 6804, 6807, 6809, 6852, 6854, and 6855 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1761a">section 1761a of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands, and sections 101703, 104909, 200102 to 200104, 308101 to 308103, and 308105 of Title 54, repealing section 460<i>l</i>–6d of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1703">section 1703 of Title 43</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s100905">section 100905 of Title 54</ref>, omitting sections 558a to 558d of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s558a">section 558a of this title</ref>, and amending provisions set out as notes under sections 580d and 6804 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Expanding Public Lands Outdoor Recreation Experiences Act’ or the ‘EXPLORE Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7a35e61e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7a35e61f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14313. Establishing the President’s Make America Beautiful Again Commission</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14313, <date date="2025-07-03">July 3, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 30197, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. The United States is blessed with vast beautiful landscapes, abundant natural resources, and a rich heritage of discovery by travelers and outdoorsmen. America’s national parks, forests, waterways, and public lands have inspired generations and kindled our Nation’s spirit of exploration. To ensure that the next generation of Americans inherits this same sense of duty and adventure, my Administration will prioritize conserving our great American national parks and outdoor recreation areas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Years of mismanagement, regulatory overreach, and neglect of routine maintenance require action. Land-use restrictions have stripped hunters, fishers, hikers, and outdoorsmen of access to public lands that belong to them. These bureaucratic restrictions have undermined outdoor traditions and threatened conservation funding. The National Park Service and the United States Forest Service face more than $23 billion and $10.8 billion in deferred maintenance, respectively, leaving roads, trails, and historic landmarks in disrepair. Despite these challenges, our Nation has proven that conservation and economic growth go hand in hand. Since the signing of the Great American Outdoors Act (<ref href="/us/pl/116/152">Public Law 116–152</ref>) [see Tables for classification], the outdoor recreation economy has grown to $1.2 trillion in economic output, and, in 2023, comprised 3.1 percent of employees in the United States and supported 5 million jobs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Through both innovation and commonsense policies, America can preserve its natural beauty and expand outdoor recreation opportunities for future generations. It is the policy of my Administration to prioritize responsible conservation, restore our lands and waters, and protect our Nation’s outdoor heritage for the enjoyment of the American people.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>General Policies</i>. All Federal land management agencies, as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s6801/3">16 U.S.C. 6801(3)</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s802/3">section 802(3) of Pub. L. 108–447</ref>], shall, to the extent practicable, ensure that their policies:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) promote responsible stewardship of natural resources while driving economic growth;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) expand access to public lands and waters for recreation, hunting, and fishing;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) encourage responsible, voluntary conservation efforts;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) cut bureaucratic delays that hinder effective environmental management; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) recover America’s fish and wildlife populations through proactive, voluntary, on-the-ground collaborative conservation efforts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Establishment and Composition of the President’s Make America Beautiful Again Commission</i>. (a) There is hereby established the President’s Make America Beautiful Again Commission (Commission), which shall be chaired by the Secretary of the Interior (Chair), with the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy serving as Executive Director (Executive Director).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In addition to the Chair and the Executive Director, the Commission shall include the following officials or their designees:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the Secretary of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the Secretary of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) the Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) the Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vii) the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(viii) the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ix) other members of my Administration invited to participate, at the discretion of the Chair and the Executive Director.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Conserving Our National Treasures</i>. The Commission shall advise and assist the President regarding how best to responsibly conserve America’s national treasures and natural resources, including by:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) monitoring the implementation of this order and facilitating interagency coordination on conservation efforts;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) providing to the President actionable recommendations for improving conservation efforts;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) developing policies to recover fish and wildlife populations through collaboration rather than regulation, including policies involving coordination with State wildlife agencies;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) recommending to the President solutions to expand access to clean drinking water and restore aquatic ecosystems to improve water quality and availability; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) developing policies to expand access to public lands, national parks, national forests, and wildlife refuges while promoting a wide range of outdoor recreation opportunities like hunting, fishing, hiking, biking, skiing, climbing, boating, off-roading, and wildlife viewing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The costs for publication of this order shall be borne by the Department of the Interior.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
