<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id770194fb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s90"><num value="90">§ 90.</num><heading> Establishment; statement of purposes; description of area</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to preserve for the benefit, use, and inspiration of present and future generations certain majestic mountain scenery, snow fields, glaciers, alpine meadows, and other unique natural features in the North Cascade Mountains of the State of Washington, there is hereby established, subject to valid existing rights, the North Cascades National Park (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “park”). The park shall consist of the lands, waters, and interests therein within the area designated “national park” on the map entitled “Proposed Management Units, North Cascades, Washington,” numbered NP–CAS–7002, and dated October 1967. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Director, National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and in the office of the Chief, Forest Service, Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id770194fc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/544/tI/s101">Pub. L. 90–544, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/926">82 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id770194fd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id770194fe-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id770194ff-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/668/s1">Pub. L. 100–668, § 1</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3961">102 Stat. 3961</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/668/s1">“That this Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s110c">section 110c of this title</ref>, amending sections 90b, 90c–1, 90d–4, 251n, 256b, 256c, and 1274 of this title, and enacting provisions listed in a table of Wilderness Areas set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1132">section 1132 of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s251n">section 251n of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Washington Park Wilderness Act of 1988’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77019500-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Dedication of Park to Senator Henry M. Jackson</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/85">Pub. L. 100–85</ref>, <date date="1987-08-10">Aug. 10, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/551">101 Stat. 551</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/85">
<inline>“That the North Cascades National Park, Washington, is hereby dedicated to Senator Henry M. Jackson in recognition of his leadership in establishing the North Cascades National Park, his outstanding contributions to the National Park System, the National Wilderness Preservation System, and to the protection and preservation of our great natural resources for the benefit of the people of the United States for all time.</inline>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><content> In order to carry out the provisions of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to provide such identification by signs, including, but not limited to changes in existing signs, materials, maps, markers, interpretive programs, or other means as will adequately inform the public of the contributions of Henry M. Jackson.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="3">“Sec. 3.</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior is further authorized and directed to cause to be erected and maintained, within the boundaries of the North Cascades National Park, an appropriate memorial to Henry M. Jackson. Such memorial shall include but not be limited to an appropriate permanent marker describing the contributions of Henry M. Jackson to the Nation.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="4">“Sec. 4.</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.”</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
