<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77019508-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s90b"><num value="90b">§ 90b.</num><heading> Land acquisition; authority of Secretary; manner and place; donation of State lands; transfer to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; elimination of lands from national forests</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77019509-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s90b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002020">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002020"><num>1</num> Subsec. (a) designation editorially supplied.</note> Within the boundaries of the park and recreation areas, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) may acquire lands, waters, and interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange, except that he may not acquire any such interests within the recreation areas without the consent of the owner, so long as the lands are devoted to uses compatible with the purposes of this subchapter. Lands owned by the State of Washington or any political subdivision thereof may be acquired only by donation. Federal property within the boundaries of the park and recreation areas is hereby transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for administration by him as part of the park and recreation areas. The national forest land within such boundaries is hereby eliminated from the national forests within which it was heretofore located.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7701950a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s90b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary is hereby authorized to acquire, with the consent of the owner, lands outside of the authorized boundaries of North Cascades National Park Service Complex for the purpose of construction and operation of a backcountry information center not to exceed five acres. The Secretary of the Interior is further authorized to acquire with the consent of the owner, lands for the construction of a headquarters and administrative site or sites, for the North Cascades National Park, Ross Lake National Recreation Area, and Lake Chelan National Recreation Area not to exceed ten acres. The lands so acquired shall be managed as part of the park.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7701950b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/544/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 90–544, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/927">82 Stat. 927</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/668/tII/s203">Pub. L. 100–668, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3963">102 Stat. 3963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7701950c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7701950d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7701950e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/668">Pub. L. 100–668</ref> added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7701950f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77019510-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Boundary Adjustments for Road</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/668/tII/s207">Pub. L. 100–668, title II, § 207</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dB/tXXX/s3040">Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3040</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3788">128 Stat. 3788</ref>, authorized Secretary to adjust boundaries of North Cascades National Park and Stephen Mather Wilderness in order to provide a 100-foot-wide corridor along which the Stehekin Valley Road could be rebuilt and directed that such adjustment be made so that equal acreage amounts would be exchanged, resulting in no net loss of acreage to either the Park or the Wilderness.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
