<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7703df1f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s90d–4"><num value="90d–4">§ 90d–4.</num><heading> Federal Power Act administrative jurisdiction unaffected</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to supersede, repeal, modify, or impair the jurisdiction of the Federal Power Commission under the Federal Power Act (<ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.], in the lands and waters within the Skagit River Hydroelectric Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 553, including the proposed Copper Creek, High Ross, and Thunder Creek elements of the Project; and the Newhalem Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 2705, within the Ross Lake National Recreation Area; the lands and waters within the Lake Chelan Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 637; the Company Creek small hydroelectric project at Stehekin within the Lake Chelan National Recreation Area; and existing hydrologic monitoring stations necessary for the proper operation of the hydroelectric projects listed herein.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7703df20-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/544/tV/s505">Pub. L. 90–544, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1968-10-02">Oct. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/930">82 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/668/tII/s202">Pub. L. 100–668, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3963">102 Stat. 3963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7703df21-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7703df22-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7703df23-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-20/ch285">act June 20, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7703df24-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/668">Pub. L. 100–668</ref> substituted “in the lands and waters within the Skagit River Hydroelectric Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 553, including the proposed Copper Creek, High Ross, and Thunder Creek elements of the Project; and the Newhalem Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 2705, within the Ross Lake National Recreation Area; the lands and waters within the Lake Chelan Project, Federal Energy and Regulatory Commission Project 637; the Company Creek small hydroelectric project at Stehekin within the Lake Chelan National Recreation Area; and existing hydrologic monitoring stations necessary for the proper operation of the hydroelectric projects listed herein” for “in the recreation areas”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7703df25-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7703df26-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Commission was terminated, and its functions, personnel, property, funds, etc., were transferred to the Secretary of Energy (except for certain functions which were transferred to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission) by sections 7151(b), 7171(a), 7172(a), 7291, and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
