<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78d4f50f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s916l"><num value="916l">§ 916l.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated from time to time, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of the convention and of this subchapter, including (1) contributions to the Commission for the United States share of any joint expenses of the Commission agreed by the United States and any of the other contracting governments, and (2) the expenses of the United States Commissioner and his staff, including (a) personal services in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, without regard to the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; (b) travel expenses without regard to subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5731/a">section 5731(a) of title 5</ref>; (c) transportation of things, communication services; (d) rent of offices; (e) printing and binding without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>; (f) stenographic and other services by contract, if deemed necessary, without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>; (g) supplies and materials; (h) equipment; (i) purchase, hire, operation, maintenance, and repair of aircraft, motor vehicles (including passenger-carrying vehicles), boats, and research vessels.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78d4f510-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-08-09/ch653/s14">Aug. 9, 1950, ch. 653, § 14</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/425">64 Stat. 425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78d4f511-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78d4f512-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78d4f513-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In par. 2(a), “chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted for “the Classification Act of 1923, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref> (the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees), and of section 1106(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782/tXI">act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782, title XI</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>, which provided that references in other laws to the Classification Act of 1923 shall be considered to mean the Classification Act of 1949.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In par. 2(b), “subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5731/a">section 5731(a) of title 5</ref>” substituted for “the Travel Expense Act of 1949 and <ref href="/us/act/1933-03-03/s10">section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1933</ref> (U.S.C., title 5, sec. 73b)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In par. 2(e), “<ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1919-03-01/s11">section 11 of the Act of March 1, 1919</ref> (U.S.C., title 44, sec. 111), and section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (U.S.C., title 41, sec. 5)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/90/620/s2/b">Pub. L. 90–620, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1305">82 Stat. 1305</ref>, which Act enacted Title 44, Public Printing and Documents, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In par. 2(f), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (U.S.C., title 41, sec. 5)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
