<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7703df48-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s92"><num value="92">§ 92.</num><heading> Control; regulations; grants for buildings; rights-of-way; fish and game; removal of trespassers</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Mount Rainier National Park shall be under the exclusive control of the Secretary of the Interior, whose duty it shall be to make and publish, as soon as practicable, such rules and regulations as he may deem necessary or proper for the care and management of the same. Such regulations shall provide for the preservation from injury or spoliation of all timber, mineral deposits, natural curiosities, or wonders within said park, and their retention in their natural condition. The Secretary may, in his discretion, grant parcels of ground at such places in said park as shall require the erection of buildings for the accommodation of visitors; all of the proceeds of said leases, and all other revenues that may be derived from any source connected with said park, to be expended under his direction in the management of the same, and the construction of roads and bridle paths therein. And through the lands of the Pacific National Forest adjoining said park rights-of-way are hereby granted, under such restrictions and regulations as the Secretary of the Interior may establish, to any railway or tramway company or companies, through the lands of said Pacific National Forest, and also into said park created by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s91">section 91 of this title</ref>, for the purpose of building, constructing, and operating a railway, constructing and operating a railway or tramway line or lines, through said lands, also into said park. He shall provide against the wanton destruction of the fish and game found within said park, and against their capture or destruction for the purposes of merchandise or profit. He shall also cause all persons trespassing upon the same after the passage of sections 91, 92, and 93 of this title to be removed therefrom, and generally shall be authorized to take all such measures as shall be necessary to fully carry out the objects and purposes of sections 91, 92 and 93 of this title.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7703df49-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1899-03-02/ch377/s2">Mar. 2, 1899, ch. 377, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/994">30 Stat. 994</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7703df4a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7703df4b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7703df4c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Pacific National Forest” was substituted for “Pacific Forest Reserve” on authority of <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">act Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/1269">34 Stat. 1269</ref>, which provided that forest reserves shall hereafter be known as national forests.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7703df4d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id7703df4e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Repeal of provisions of this section relating to granting rights-of-way to railway or tramway companies for purpose of building and operating a railway or tramway, so far as they relate to lands within Mount Rainier National Park, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s92a">section 92a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
