<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78d4f56c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s935"><num value="935">§ 935.</num><heading> Acquisition of real property; construction and operation of lamprey control works; entry into agreements for construction and operation of works</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out the obligations of the United States under the Convention, the United States Section is authorized—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d4f56d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s935/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> to acquire any real property, or any interest therein, by purchase, exchange, gift, dedication, condemnation, or otherwise;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d4f56e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s935/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> to construct, operate, and maintain any project or works designed to facilitate compliance with the provisions of the Convention relating to the sea lamprey control program; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d4f56f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s935/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> to enter into contract or agreement with any State or other public agency or private agency or individual for the construction, operation, or maintenance of any such project or works.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78d4f570-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-06-04/ch358/s6">June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/243">70 Stat. 243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78d4f571-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78d4f572-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78d4f573-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Fish and Wildlife Service; Work on Sea Lamprey Program; Reimbursements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/512/tI">Pub. L. 101–512, title I</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1918">104 Stat. 1918</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/512/tI">“beginning <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and thereafter, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service can perform work for the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s931–939c">16 U.S.C. 931–939c</ref>, Great Lakes Fisheries [Fishery] Act of 1956, on the sea lamprey program on a reimbursable basis: <i>Provided further</i>, That such reimbursements are to be treated as Intragovernmental funds as defined in the publication titled ‘A Glossary of Terms Used in the Federal Budget Process’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
