<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78d74082-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953"><num value="953">§ 953.</num><heading> General Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d74083-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General Advisory Committee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78d74084-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointments; public participation; compensation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74085-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint a General Advisory Committee which shall consist of not more than 25 individuals who shall be representative of the various groups concerned with the fisheries covered by the Convention, including nongovernmental conservation organizations, providing to the maximum extent practicable an equitable balance among such groups. Members of the General Advisory Committee will be eligible to participate as members of the United States delegation to the Commission and its working groups to the extent the Commission rules and space for delegations allow.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74086-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The chair of the Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Subpanel for Highly Migratory Fisheries and the chair of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Committee shall be ex-officio members of the General Advisory Committee by virtue of their positions in those Councils.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74087-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Each member of the General Advisory Committee appointed under subparagraph (A) shall serve for a term of 3 years and is eligible for reappointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74088-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The General Advisory Committee shall be invited to attend all non-executive meetings of the United States delegation and at such meetings shall be given opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigation, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74089-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The General Advisory Committee shall determine its organization, and prescribe its practices and procedures for carrying out its functions under this chapter, the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), and the Convention. The General Advisory Committee shall publish and make available to the public a statement of its organization, practices, and procedures. Meetings of the General Advisory Committee, except when in executive session, shall be open to the public, and prior notice of meetings shall be made public in timely fashion. The General Advisory Committee shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78d7408a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary and the Secretary of State shall furnish the General Advisory Committee with relevant information concerning fisheries and international fishery agreements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78d7408b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative matters</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d7408c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide to the General Advisory Committee in a timely manner such administrative and technical support services as are necessary for its effective functioning.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d7408d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Individuals appointed to serve as a member of the General Advisory Committee—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d7408e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall serve without pay, but while away from their homes or regular places of business to attend meetings of the General Advisory Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d7408f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall not be considered Federal employees except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d74090-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78d74091-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint a Scientific Advisory Subcommittee of not less than 5 nor more than 15 qualified scientists with balanced representation from the public and private sectors, including nongovernmental conservation organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78d74092-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scientific Advisory Subcommittee.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74093-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advice</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Scientific Advisory Subcommittee shall advise the General Advisory Committee and the Commissioners on matters including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d74094-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the conservation of ecosystems;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d74095-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the sustainable uses of living marine resources related to the tuna fishery in the eastern Pacific Ocean; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d74096-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the long-term conservation and management of stocks of living marine resources in the eastern tropical Pacific Ocean.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78d74097-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other functions and assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Scientific Advisory Subcommittee shall, as requested by the General Advisory Committee, the United States Commissioners, or the Secretary, perform functions and provide assistance required by formal agreements entered into by the United States for this fishery, including the International Dolphin Conservation Program. These functions may include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d74098-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the review of data from the Program, including data received from the Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d74099-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> recommendations on research needs, including ecosystems, fishing practices, and gear technology research, including the development and use of selective, environmentally safe and cost-effective fishing gear, and on the coordination and facilitation of such research;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d7409a-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> recommendations concerning scientific reviews and assessments required under the Program and engaging, as appropriate, in such reviews and assessments;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d7409b-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> consulting with other experts as needed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78d7409c-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> recommending measures to assure the regular and timely full exchange of data among the parties to the Program and each nation’s National Scientific Advisory Committee (or its equivalent).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id78d7409d-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s953/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Attendance at meetings</inline>.—</heading><content>The Scientific Advisory Subcommittee shall be invited to have representatives attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States sections and the General Advisory Committee and shall be given full opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of scientific investigation, scientific reports, and scientific recommendations of the commission. Representatives of the Scientific Advisory Subcommittee may attend meetings of the Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission in accordance with the rules of such Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78d7409e-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-07/ch907/s4">Sept. 7, 1950, ch. 907, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/778">64 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/523/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 102–523, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-26">Oct. 26, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3433">106 Stat. 3433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/42/s7/b">Pub. L. 105–42, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-15">Aug. 15, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1137">111 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/tII/s205">Pub. L. 114–81, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/661">129 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/105">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(105)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4317">136 Stat. 4317</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78d7409f-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78d740a0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id78d740a1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(E), was in the original “this title” and was translated as reading “this Act” to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Act <date date="1950-09-07">Sept. 7, 1950</date>, which comprises this chapter, does not contain titles.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(E), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/265">Pub. L. 94–265</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/331">90 Stat. 331</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 38 (§ 1801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78d740a2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s205/1">Pub. L. 114–81, § 205(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a), which related to General Advisory Committee appointment, public participation, and compensation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s205/2">Pub. L. 114–81, § 205(2)</ref>, substituted “Scientific Advisory Subcommittee” for “Functions” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s205/2">Pub. L. 114–81, § 205(2)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “The General Advisory Committee shall be invited to have representatives attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States sections and shall be given full opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigations, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commission. The General Advisory Committee may attend all meetings of the international commissions to which they are invited by such commissions.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s205/3">Pub. L. 114–81, § 205(3)</ref>, substituted “General Advisory Committee” for “General Advisory Subcommittee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/42">Pub. L. 105–42</ref> which directed insertion of catchline and general amendment of text of section 4 of the Tuna Conventions Act, was executed to this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The United States Commissioners shall (a) appoint an advisory committee which shall be composed of not less than five nor more than fifteen persons who shall be selected from the various groups participating in the fisheries included under the conventions, and from nongovernmental conservation organizations, and (b) shall fix the terms of office of the members of such committee, who shall receive no compensation for their services as such members. The advisory committee shall be invited to attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States sections and shall be given full opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigation, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the commissions. The advisory committee may attend all meetings of the international commissions to which they are invited by such commissions.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/523">Pub. L. 102–523</ref> inserted “and from nongovernmental conservation organizations,” after “under the conventions,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78d740a3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78d740a4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/42">Pub. L. 105–42</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/42/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 105–42</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1362">section 1362 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78d740a5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
