<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78d740b8-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957"><num value="957">§ 957.</num><heading> Violations; fines and forfeitures; application of related laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d740b9-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Fishing violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any master or other person in charge of a fishing vessel of the United States to engage in fishing in violation of any regulation adopted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref> or for any person knowingly to ship, transport, purchase, sell, offer for sale, import, export, or have in custody, possession, or control any fish taken or retained in violation of such regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d740ba-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Failures to keep required records; failures to stop upon being hailed; refusals to permit inspections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for the master or any person in charge of any fishing vessel of the United States or any person on board such vessel to fail to make, keep, or furnish any catch returns, statistical records, or other reports as are required by regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter to be made, kept, or furnished; or to fail to stop upon being hailed by a duly authorized official of the United States; or to refuse to permit the duly authorized officials of the United States or authorized officials of the commissions to board such vessel or inspect its catch, equipment, books, documents, records, or other articles or question the persons on board in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, or the convention, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d740bb-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Import violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to import, in violation of any regulation adopted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>, from any country, any fish in any form of those species subject to regulation pursuant to a recommendation of the commission, or any tuna in any form not under regulation but under investigation by the commission, during the period such fish have been denied entry in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>. In the case of any fish as described in this subsection offered for entry into the United States, the Secretary of Commerce shall require proof satisfactory to him that such fish is not ineligible for such entry under the terms of <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0bc-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Fines for subsection (a) violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person violating any provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be fined not more than $25,000, and for a subsequent violation of any provisions of said subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0bd-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Fines for subsection (b) violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person violating any provision of subsection (b) of this section shall be fined not more than $1,000, and for a subsequent violation of any provision of subsection (b) shall be fined not more than $5,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0be-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Fines for subsection (c) violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person violating any provision of subsection (c) of this section shall be fined not more than $100,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0bf-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Forfeitures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All fish taken or retained in violation of subsection (a) of this section, or the monetary value thereof, may be forfeited.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0c0-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of related laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All provisions of law relating to the seizure, judicial forfeiture, and condemnation of a cargo for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of such cargo or the proceeds from the sale thereof, and the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures shall apply to seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this chapter, insofar as such provisions of law are applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78d9b0c1-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5" identifier="/us/usc/t16/s957/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional prohibitions and enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1826g">section 1826g of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78d9b0c2-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-07/ch907/s8">Sept. 7, 1950, ch. 907, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/779">64 Stat. 779</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/814/s4">Pub. L. 87–814, § 4</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/924">76 Stat. 924</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/tII/s207">Pub. L. 114–81, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/663">129 Stat. 663</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78d9b0c3-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78d9b0c4-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78d9b0c5-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s207/1">Pub. L. 114–81, § 207(1)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955/c">section 955(c) of this title</ref>” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/81/s207/2">Pub. L. 114–81, § 207(2)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/814">Pub. L. 87–814</ref> substituted provisions respecting violations, fines, and forfeitures, and application of related laws for provisions respecting enforcement of chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78d9b0c6-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78d9b0c7-6992-11f1-ab3f-8b4c043f8cd5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Transfer of functions to Secretary of Commerce from Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
