<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9bc05548-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103"><num value="1103">§ 1103.</num><heading> Powers and duties of the Secretary, the Under Secretary, and the Attorney General</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05549-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary of Homeland Security</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Homeland Security shall be charged with the administration and enforcement of this chapter and all other laws relating to the immigration and naturalization of aliens, except insofar as this chapter or such laws relate to the powers, functions, and duties conferred upon the President, Attorney General, the Secretary of State, the officers of the Department of State, or diplomatic or consular officers: <i>Provided, however</i>, That determination and ruling by the Attorney General with respect to all questions of law shall be controlling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> He shall have control, direction, and supervision of all employees and of all the files and records of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> He shall establish such regulations; prescribe such forms of bond, reports, entries, and other papers; issue such instructions; and perform such other acts as he deems necessary for carrying out his authority under the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> He may require or authorize any employee of the Service or the Department of Justice to perform or exercise any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon any other employee of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> He shall have the power and duty to control and guard the boundaries and borders of the United States against the illegal entry of aliens and shall, in his discretion, appoint for that purpose such number of employees of the Service as to him shall appear necessary and proper.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0554f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> He is authorized to confer or impose upon any employee of the United States, with the consent of the head of the Department or other independent establishment under whose jurisdiction the employee is serving, any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon officers or employees of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05550-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> He may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, establish offices of the Service in foreign countries; and, after consultation with the Secretary of State, he may, whenever in his judgment such action may be necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter, detail employees of the Service for duty in foreign countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05551-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> After consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General may authorize officers of a foreign country to be stationed at preclearance facilities in the United States for the purpose of ensuring that persons traveling from or through the United States to that foreign country comply with that country’s immigration and related laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05552-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Those officers may exercise such authority and perform such duties as United States immigration officers are authorized to exercise and perform in that foreign country under reciprocal agreement, and they shall enjoy such reasonable privileges and immunities necessary for the performance of their duties as the government of their country extends to United States immigration officers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05553-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> In the event the Attorney General determines that an actual or imminent mass influx of aliens arriving off the coast of the United States, or near a land border, presents urgent circumstances requiring an immediate Federal response, the Attorney General may authorize any State or local law enforcement officer, with the consent of the head of the department, agency, or establishment under whose jurisdiction the individual is serving, to perform or exercise any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon officers or employees of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05554-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> The Attorney General, in support of persons in administrative detention in non-Federal institutions, is authorized—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9bc05555-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to make payments from funds appropriated for the administration and enforcement of the laws relating to immigration, naturalization, and alien registration for necessary clothing, medical care, necessary guard hire, and the housing, care, and security of persons detained by the Service pursuant to Federal law under an agreement with a State or political subdivision of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9bc05556-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to enter into a cooperative agreement with any State, territory, or political subdivision thereof, for the necessary construction, physical renovation, acquisition of equipment, supplies or materials required to establish acceptable conditions of confinement and detention services in any State or unit of local government which agrees to provide guaranteed bed space for persons detained by the Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05557-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Land acquisition authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05558-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Attorney General may contract for or buy any interest in land, including temporary use rights, adjacent to or in the vicinity of an international land border when the Attorney General deems the land essential to control and guard the boundaries and borders of the United States against any violation of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05559-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Attorney General may contract for or buy any interest in land identified pursuant to paragraph (1) as soon as the lawful owner of that interest fixes a price for it and the Attorney General considers that price to be reasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0555a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> When the Attorney General and the lawful owner of an interest identified pursuant to paragraph (1) are unable to agree upon a reasonable price, the Attorney General may commence condemnation proceedings pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3113">section 3113 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0555b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Attorney General may accept for the United States a gift of any interest in land identified pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc0555c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Commissioner; appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner shall be a citizen of the United States and shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. He shall be charged with any and all responsibilities and authority in the administration of the Service and of this chapter which are conferred upon the Attorney General as may be delegated to him by the Attorney General or which may be prescribed by the Attorney General. The Commissioner may enter into cooperative agreements with State and local law enforcement agencies for the purpose of assisting in the enforcement of the immigration laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc0555d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Statistical information system</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0555e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commissioner, in consultation with interested academicians, government agencies, and other parties, shall provide for a system for collection and dissemination, to Congress and the public, of information (not in individually identifiable form) useful in evaluating the social, economic, environmental, and demographic impact of immigration laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc0555f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such information shall include information on the alien population in the United States, on the rates of naturalization and emigration of resident aliens, on aliens who have been admitted, paroled, or granted asylum, on nonimmigrants in the United States (by occupation, basis for admission, and duration of stay), on aliens who have not been admitted or have been removed from the United States, on the number of applications filed and granted for cancellation of removal, and on the number of aliens estimated to be present unlawfully in the United States in each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05560-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Such system shall provide for the collection and dissemination of such information not less often than annually.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05561-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05562-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commissioner shall submit to Congress annually a report which contains a summary of the information collected under subsection (d) and an analysis of trends in immigration and naturalization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9bc05563-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each annual report shall include information on the number, and rate of denial administratively, of applications for naturalization, for each district office of the Service and by national origin group.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05564-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum number of agents in States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall allocate to each State not fewer than 10 full-time active duty agents of the Immigration and Naturalization Service to carry out the functions of the Service, in order to ensure the effective enforcement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05565-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Attorney General</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05566-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Attorney General shall have such authorities and functions under this chapter and all other laws relating to the immigration and naturalization of aliens as were exercised by the Executive Office for Immigration Review, or by the Attorney General with respect to the Executive Office for Immigration Review, on the day before the effective date of the Immigration Reform, Accountability and Security Enhancement Act of 2002.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc05567-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1103/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Attorney General shall establish such regulations, prescribe such forms of bond, reports, entries, and other papers, issue such instructions, review such administrative determinations in immigration proceedings, delegate such authority, and perform such other acts as the Attorney General determines to be necessary for carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9bc05568-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref href="/us/stat/66/173">66 Stat. 173</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/c">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2619">102 Stat. 2619</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tI/s142">Pub. L. 101–649, title I, § 142</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5004">104 Stat. 5004</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I</ref>, §§ 102(d), 125, 134(a), title III, §§ 308(d)(4)(C), (e)(4), 372, 373, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-555">110 Stat. 3009–555</ref>, 3009–562, 3009–564, 3009–618, 3009–620, 3009–646, 3009–647; <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXI/s1102">Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2273">116 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dL/s105/a/1">Pub. L. 108–7, div. L, § 105(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/531">117 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tV/s5505/a">Pub. L. 108–458, title V, § 5505(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3741">118 Stat. 3741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/122/s2/a">Pub. L. 111–122, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-22">Dec. 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3480">123 Stat. 3480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9bc05569-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9bc0556a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9bc0556b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Immigration Reform, Accountability and Security Enhancement Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (g)(1), was S. 2444 of the 107th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2002-05-02">May 2, 2002</date>, which was not enacted into law. Provisions relating to the Executive Office for Immigration Review are contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s521">section 521 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9bc0556c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3113">Section 3113 of title 40</ref>” substituted in subsec. (b)(3) for “the Act of <date date="1888-08-01">August 1, 1888</date> (Chapter 728; <ref href="/us/stat/25/357">25 Stat. 357</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9bc0556d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/122">Pub. L. 111–122</ref> struck out subsec. (h), which directed the Attorney General to establish within the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice an Office of Special Investigations and to consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security concerning the prosecution or extradition of certain aliens.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/1">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(1)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(2)</ref>. See 2002 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/2">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(2)</ref>, which directed the amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, was executed to <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2">section 1102(2) of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See 2002 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/1">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(1)</ref>, amended section catchline generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2/A">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(2)(A)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/1">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(1)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Attorney General” in heading, was executed by inserting “Secretary of Homeland Security” as heading, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2/B">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(2)(B)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/1">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “The Secretary of Homeland Security” for “The Attorney General”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2/C">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(2)(C)</ref>, formerly § 1102(2)(A), as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/2">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “Attorney General,” after “President,”. See 2003 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/2/D">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(2)(D)</ref>, formerly § 1102(2)(B), as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s105/a/2">Pub. L. 108–7, § 105(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (8), relating to Attorney General authorization of State and local law enforcement officers in event of mass influx of aliens arriving, and par. (9), relating to Attorney General authority to support administrative detention of persons in non-Federal institutions, as pars. (10) and (11), respectively. See 2003 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1102/3">Pub. L. 107–296, § 1102(3)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s372/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 372(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “(1)” before first sentence and designated each sentence after the first sentence, which included second through ninth sentences, as a separate par. with appropriate consecutive numbering and initial indentation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s125">Pub. L. 104–208, § 125</ref>, inserted at end “After consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General may authorize officers of a foreign country to be stationed at preclearance facilities in the United States for the purpose of ensuring that persons traveling from or through the United States to that foreign country comply with that country’s immigration and related laws. Those officers may exercise such authority and perform such duties as United States immigration officers are authorized to exercise and perform in that foreign country under reciprocal agreement, and they shall enjoy such reasonable privileges and immunities necessary for the performance of their duties as the government of their country extends to United States immigration officers.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s372/3">Pub. L. 104–208, § 372(3)</ref>, added at end par. (8) relating to Attorney General authorization of State and local law enforcement officers in event of mass influx of aliens arriving.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s373/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 373(1)</ref>, added at end par. (9) relating to Attorney General authority to support administrative detention of persons in non-Federal institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s373/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 373(2)</ref>, inserted at end “The Commissioner may enter into cooperative agreements with State and local law enforcement agencies for the purpose of assisting in the enforcement of the immigration laws.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/4">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(4)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (c)(2) by substituting “cancellation of removal” for “suspension of deportation”, was executed by making the substitution in subsec. (d)(2) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (c) as (d) by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(A)</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/d/4/C">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(d)(4)(C)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (c)(2) by substituting “not been admitted or have been removed” for “been excluded or deported”, was executed by making the substitution in subsec. (d)(2) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (c) as (d) by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(A)</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d)” for “subsection (c)” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s102/d/1/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 102(d)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s134/a">Pub. L. 104–208, § 134(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/c/1">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “instructions” for “intructions” and amended fourth sentence generally. Prior to amendment, fourth sentence read as follows: “He is authorized, in accordance with the civil-service laws and regulations and the Classification Act of 1949, to appoint such employees of the Service as he deems necessary, and to delegate to them or to any officer or employee of the Department of Justice in his discretion any of the duties and powers imposed upon him in this chapter; he may require or authorize any employee of the Service or the Department of Justice to perform or exercise any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon any other employee of the Service.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/c/2">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(c)(2)</ref>, struck out provision that Commissioner was to receive compensation at rate of $17,500 per annum.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9bc0556e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9bc0556f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> effective on the date of the transfer of functions from the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization to officials of the Department of Homeland Security (<date date="2003-03-01">Mar. 1, 2003</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1104">section 1104 of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/108/7">Pub. L. 108–7</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s521">section 521 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9bc05570-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s134/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 134(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-564">110 Stat. 3009–564</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s134/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 308(d)(4)(C), (e)(4) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9bc05571-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> effective <date date="1991-10-01">Oct. 1, 1991</date>, and applicable beginning with fiscal year 1992, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s161/a">section 161(a) of Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05572-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05573-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/159/dD/tI/s4103">Pub. L. 116–159, div. D, title I, § 4103</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/741">134 Stat. 741</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/159/dD/tI/s4103">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>], the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate Committees a 5-year plan, including projected cost estimates, procurement strategies, and a project schedule with milestones, to accomplish each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Establish electronic filing procedures for all applications and petitions for immigration benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Accept electronic payment of fees at all filing locations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Issue correspondence, including decisions, requests for evidence, and notices of intent to deny, to immigration benefit requestors electronically.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Improve processing times for all immigration and naturalization benefit requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Semi-annual Briefings</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after submission of the plan described in subsection (a), and on a semi-annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall advise the appropriate Committees on the implementation status of such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate Committees’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05574-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fingerprint Cards</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/119/tI">Pub. L. 105–119, title I</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2448">111 Stat. 2448</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/119/tI">“That beginning seven calendar days after the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>] and for each fiscal year thereafter, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Immigration and Naturalization Service may be used by the Immigration and Naturalization Service to accept, for the purpose of conducting criminal background checks on applications for any benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.], any FD–258 fingerprint card which has been prepared by or received from any individual or entity other than an office of the Immigration and Naturalization Service with the following exceptions: (1) State and local law enforcement agencies; and (2) United States consular offices at United States embassies and consulates abroad under the jurisdiction of the Department of State or United States military offices under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense authorized to perform fingerprinting services to prepare FD–258 fingerprint cards for applicants residing abroad applying for immigration benefits”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05575-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvement of Barriers at Border</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 102(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-554">110 Stat. 3009–554</ref>, 3009–555, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s102">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/306">119 Stat. 306</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/367/s3">Pub. L. 109–367, § 3</ref>, <date date="2006-10-26">Oct. 26, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2638">120 Stat. 2638</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dE/tV/s564/a">Pub. L. 110–161, div. E, title V, § 564(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2090">121 Stat. 2090</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/161/dE/tV/s564/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take such actions as may be necessary to install additional physical barriers and roads (including the removal of obstacles to detection of illegal entrants) in the vicinity of the United States border to deter illegal crossings in areas of high illegal entry into the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction of Fencing and Road Improvements Along the Border.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional fencing along southwest border.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reinforced fencing</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall construct reinforced fencing along not less than 700 miles of the southwest border where fencing would be most practical and effective and provide for the installation of additional physical barriers, roads, lighting, cameras, and sensors to gain operational control of the southwest border.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority areas</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out this section [amending this section], the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> identify the 370 miles, or other mileage determined by the Secretary, whose authority to determine other mileage shall expire on <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, along the southwest border where fencing would be most practical and effective in deterring smugglers and aliens attempting to gain illegal entry into the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> not later than <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, complete construction of reinforced fencing along the miles identified under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, States, local governments, Indian tribes, and property owners in the United States to minimize the impact on the environment, culture, commerce, and quality of life for the communities and residents located near the sites at which such fencing is to be constructed.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings provision</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> create or negate any right of action for a State, local government, or other person or entity affected by this subsection; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> affect the eminent domain laws of the United States or of any State.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), nothing in this paragraph shall require the Secretary of Homeland Security to install fencing, physical barriers, roads, lighting, cameras, and sensors in a particular location along an international border of the United States, if the Secretary determines that the use or placement of such resources is not the most appropriate means to achieve and maintain operational control over the international border at such location.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prompt acquisition of necessary easements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General, acting under the authority conferred in section 103(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1103/b">8 U.S.C. 1103(b)</ref>] (as inserted by subsection (d)), shall promptly acquire such easements as may be necessary to carry out this subsection and shall commence construction of fences immediately following such acquisition (or conclusion of portions thereof).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Safety features</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General, while constructing the additional fencing under this subsection, shall incorporate such safety features into the design of the fence system as are necessary to ensure the well-being of border patrol agents deployed within or in near proximity to the system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection. Amounts appropriated under this paragraph are authorized to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall have the authority to waive all legal requirements such Secretary, in such Secretary’s sole discretion, determines necessary to ensure expeditious construction of the barriers and roads under this section [amending this section]. Any such decision by the Secretary shall be effective upon being published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal court review.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear all causes or claims arising from any action undertaken, or any decision made, by the Secretary of Homeland Security pursuant to paragraph (1). A cause of action or claim may only be brought alleging a violation of the Constitution of the United States. The court shall not have jurisdiction to hear any claim not specified in this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Time for filing of complaint</inline>.—</heading><content>Any cause or claim brought pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be filed not later than 60 days after the date of the action or decision made by the Secretary of Homeland Security. A claim shall be barred unless it is filed within the time specified.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ability to seek appellate review</inline>.—</heading><content>An interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order of the district court may be reviewed only upon petition for a writ of certiorari to the Supreme Court of the United States.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05576-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improved Border Equipment and Technology</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s103">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-555">110 Stat. 3009–555</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s103">“The Attorney General is authorized to acquire and use, for the purpose of detection, interdiction, and reduction of illegal immigration into the United States, any Federal equipment (including fixed wing aircraft, helicopters, four-wheel drive vehicles, sedans, night vision goggles, night vision scopes, and sensor units) determined available for transfer by any other agency of the Federal Government upon request of the Attorney General.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc05577-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Hiring and Training Standards</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s106/a">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-556">110 Stat. 3009–556</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s106/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review of Hiring Standards</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>], the Attorney General shall complete a review of all prescreening and hiring standards used by the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, and, where necessary, revise such standards to ensure that they are consistent with relevant standards of professionalism.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>At the conclusion of each of fiscal years 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000, and 2001, the Attorney General shall certify in writing to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate that all personnel hired by the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization for such fiscal year were hired pursuant to the appropriate standards, as revised under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c678-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Border Strategy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s107">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-557">110 Stat. 3009–557</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s107">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation of Strategy</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall track, monitor, and evaluate the Attorney General’s strategy to deter illegal entry in the United States to determine the efficacy of such strategy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Defense shall cooperate with the Comptroller General of the United States in carrying out subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>], and every year thereafter for the succeeding 5 years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate on the results of the activities undertaken under subsection (a) during the previous year. Each such report shall include an analysis of the degree to which the Attorney General’s strategy has been effective in reducing illegal entry. Each such report shall include a collection and systematic analysis of data, including workload indicators, related to activities to deter illegal entry and recommendations to improve and increase border security at the border and ports of entry.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c679-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compensation for Immigration Judges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s371/c">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 371(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-645">110 Stat. 3009–645</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s371/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>There shall be four levels of pay for immigration judges, under the Immigration Judge Schedule (designated as IJ–1, 2, 3, and 4, respectively), and each such judge shall be paid at one of those levels, in accordance with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rates of pay.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The rates of basic pay for the levels established under paragraph (1) shall be as follows:<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p1,7/8,xs48,r10,tp0,p1,7/8,xs48,r10; " id="id9bc2c67a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:52pt ; max-width:52pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 154pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:1pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:td />
</html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style="width:52.0pt ; max-width:52.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>IJ–1</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style="min-width: 154.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">70% of the next to highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>IJ–2</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">80% of the next to highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>IJ–3</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">90% of the next to highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>IJ–4</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">92% of the next to highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Locality pay, where applicable, shall be calculated into the basic pay for immigration judges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Upon appointment, an immigration judge shall be paid at IJ–1, and shall be advanced to IJ–2 upon completion of 104 weeks of service, to IJ–3 upon completion of 104 weeks of service in the next lower rate, and to IJ–4 upon completion of 52 weeks of service in the next lower rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Attorney General may provide for appointment of an immigration judge at an advanced rate under such circumstances as the Attorney General may determine appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition</inline>.—</heading><content>Immigration judges serving as of the effective date shall be paid at the rate that corresponds to the amount of time, as provided under paragraph (3)(A), that they have served as an immigration judge, and in no case shall be paid less after the effective date than the rate of pay prior to the effective date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s371/d/2">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 371(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-646">110 Stat. 3009–646</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s371/d/2">“Subsection (c) [set out above] shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c67b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Machine-Readable Document Border Security Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tIV/s4604">Pub. L. 100–690, title IV, § 4604</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4289">102 Stat. 4289</ref>, which required Department of State, United States Customs Service, and Immigration and Naturalization Service to develop a comprehensive machine-readable travel and identity document border security program that would improve border entry and departure control through automated data capture of machine-readable travel and identity documents, directed specified agencies and organizations to contribute law enforcement data for the system, authorized appropriations for the program, and required continuing full implementation in fiscal years 1990, 1991, and 1992, by all participating agencies, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s6/e/1">Pub. L. 102–583, § 6(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4933">106 Stat. 4933</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c67c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Immigration and Naturalization Service Personnel Enhancement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7350">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7350</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4473">102 Stat. 4473</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7350">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program Regarding the Identification of Certain Aliens.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Within 6 months after the effective date of this subtitle [<date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>], the Attorney General shall establish, out of funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (c)(2), a pilot program in 4 cities to improve the capabilities of the Immigration and Naturalization Service (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Service’) to respond to inquiries from Federal, State, and local law enforcement authorities concerning aliens who have been arrested for or convicted of, or who are the subject of any criminal investigation relating to, a violation of any law relating to controlled substances (other than an aggravated felony as defined in section 101(a)(43) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/43">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</ref>], as added by section 7342 of this subtitle).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> At the end of the 12-month period after the establishment of such pilot program, the Attorney General shall provide for an evaluation of its effectiveness, including an assessment by Federal, State, and local prosecutors and law enforcement agencies. The Attorney General shall submit a report containing the conclusions of such evaluation to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate within 60 days after the completion of such evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hiring of Investigative Agents.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Any investigative agent hired by the Attorney General for purposes of this section shall be employed exclusively to assist Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies in combating drug trafficking and crimes of violence by aliens.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any investigative agent hired under this section who is older than 35 years of age shall not be eligible for Federal retirement benefits made available to individuals who perform hazardous law enforcement activities.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c67d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program To Establish or Improve Computer Capabilities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tI/s1751/e">Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1751(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-48">100 Stat. 3207–48</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/570/tI/s1751/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> From the sums appropriated to carry out this Act, the Attorney General, through the Investigative Division of the Immigration and Naturalization Service, shall provide a pilot program in 4 cities to establish or improve the computer capabilities of the local offices of the Service and of local law enforcement agencies to respond to inquiries concerning aliens who have been arrested or convicted for, or are the subject to criminal investigation relating to, a violation of any law relating to controlled substances. The Attorney General shall select cities in a manner that provides special consideration for cities located near the land borders of the United States and for large cities which have major concentrations of aliens. Some of the sums made available under the pilot program shall be used to increase the personnel level of the Investigative Division.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> At the end of the first year of the pilot program, the Attorney General shall provide for an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program and shall report to Congress on such evaluation and on whether the pilot program should be extended or expanded.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc2c67e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Plans for Regulation of Nationals of Enemy Countries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Attorney General to develop national security emergency plans for regulation of immigration, regulation of nationals of enemy countries, and plans to implement laws for control of persons entering or leaving the United States, see section 1101(4) of Ex. Ord. No. 12656, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 47491, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5195">section 5195 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id9bc2c67f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c680-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13404. Task Force on New Americans</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13404, <date date="2006-06-07">June 7, 2006</date>, 71 F.R. 33593, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to strengthen the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security and Federal, State, and local agencies to help legal immigrants embrace the common core of American civic culture, learn our common language, and fully become Americans, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Establishment</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) shall immediately establish within the Department of Homeland Security (Department) a Task Force on New Americans (Task Force).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Membership and Operation</i>. (a) The Task Force shall be limited to the following members or employees designated by them at no lower than the Assistant Secretary level or its equivalent:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the Secretary of Homeland Security, who shall serve as Chair;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the Secretary of State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) the Secretary of the Treasury;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) the Secretary of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) the Attorney General;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) the Secretary of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vii) the Secretary of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(viii) the Secretary of Labor;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ix) the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(x) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xi) the Secretary of Education;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xii) such other officers or employees of the Department of Homeland Security as the Secretary may from time to time designate; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xiii) such other officers of the United States as the Secretary may designate from time to time, with the concurrence of the respective heads of departments and agencies concerned.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary shall convene and preside at meetings of the Task Force, direct its work, and as appropriate, establish and direct subgroups of the Task Force that shall consist exclusively of Task Force members. The Secretary shall designate an official of the Department to serve as the Executive Secretary of the Task Force, and the Executive Secretary shall head the staff assigned to the Task Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Functions</i>. Consistent with applicable law, the Task Force shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) provide direction to executive departments and agencies (agencies) concerning the integration into American society of America’s legal immigrants, particularly through instruction in English, civics, and history;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) promote public-private partnerships that will encourage businesses to offer English and civics education to workers;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) identify ways to expand English and civics instruction for legal immigrants, including through faith-based, community, and other groups, and ways to promote volunteer community service; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) make recommendations to the President, through the Secretary, from time to time regarding:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) actions to enhance cooperation among agencies on the integration of legal immigrants into American society;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) actions to enhance cooperation among Federal, State, and local authorities responsible for the integration of legal immigrants;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) changes in rules, regulations, or policy to improve the effective integration of legal immigrants into American society; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) proposed legislation relating to the integration of legal immigrants into American society.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Administration</i>. (a) To the extent permitted by law, the Department shall provide the funding and administrative support the Task Force needs to implement this order, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) authority granted by law to an agency or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budget, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) This order is intended to improve the internal management of the Federal Government. This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or equity against the United States, its departments, agencies, entities, instrumentalities, officers, employees, agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c681-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13767</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13767, <date date="2017-01-25">Jan. 25, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 8793, which related to increased security on the southern border and removal of immigrants, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14010, § 4(a)(ii)(F)(1), <date date="2021-02-02">Feb. 2, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 8270, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c682-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13768</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13768, <date date="2017-01-25">Jan. 25, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 8799, which related to enforcement of immigration laws and removal of certain aliens, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13993, § 2, <date date="2021-01-20">Jan. 20, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 7051, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c683-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13841</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13841, <date date="2018-06-20">June 20, 2018</date>, 83 F.R. 29435, which related to detention and separation of immigrant families, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14011, § 6, <date date="2021-02-02">Feb. 2, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 8274, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c684-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13993</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13993, <date date="2021-01-20">Jan. 20, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 7051, which related to civil immigration enforcement policies and priorities, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(h), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8237, and Ex. Ord. No. 14159, § 3(a), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8443.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c685-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14010</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14010, <date date="2021-02-02">Feb. 2, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 8267, which created a comprehensive regional framework to address the causes of migration, to manage migration throughout North and Central America, and to provide safe and orderly processing of asylum seekers at the United States border, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(u), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8238, and Ex. Ord. No. 14159, § 3(a), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8443.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c686-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14011</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14011, <date date="2021-02-02">Feb. 2, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 8273, which established the Interagency Task Force on the Reunification of Families, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(v), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8238, and Ex. Ord. No. 14159, § 3(a), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8443.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c687-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14012</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14012, <date date="2021-02-02">Feb. 2, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 8277, which related to restoring faith in legal immigration systems and strengthening integration and inclusion efforts for new Americans, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(w), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8238, and Ex. Ord. No. 14159, § 3(a), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8443.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c688-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14159. Protecting the American People Against Invasion</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14159, <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8443, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.) and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. Over the last 4 years, the prior administration invited, administered, and oversaw an unprecedented flood of illegal immigration into the United States. Millions of illegal aliens crossed our borders or were permitted to fly directly into the United States on commercial flights and allowed to settle in American communities, in violation of longstanding Federal laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Many of these aliens unlawfully within the United States present significant threats to national security and public safety, committing vile and heinous acts against innocent Americans. Others are engaged in hostile activities, including espionage, economic espionage, and preparations for terror-related activities. Many have abused the generosity of the American people, and their presence in the United States has cost taxpayers billions of dollars at the Federal, State, and local levels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enforcing our Nation’s immigration laws is critically important to the national security and public safety of the United States. The American people deserve a Federal Government that puts their interests first and a Government that understands its sacred obligation to prioritize the safety, security, and financial and economic well-being of Americans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This order ensures that the Federal Government protects the American people by faithfully executing the immigration laws of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to faithfully execute the immigration laws against all inadmissible and removable aliens, particularly those aliens who threaten the safety or security of the American people. Further, it is the policy of the United States to achieve the total and efficient enforcement of those laws, including through lawful incentives and detention capabilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Faithful Execution of the Immigration Laws</i>. In furtherance of the policies described in section 2 of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Executive Order 13993 of <date date="2021-01-20">January 20, 2021</date> (Revision of Civil Immigration Enforcement Policies and Priorities) [formerly set out above], Executive Order 14010 of <date date="2021-02-02">February 2, 2021</date> (Creating a Comprehensive Regional Framework To Address the Causes of Migration, To Manage Migration Throughout North and Central America, and To Provide Safe and Orderly Processing of Asylum Seekers at the United States Border) [formerly set out above], Executive Order 14011 of <date date="2021-02-02">February 2, 2021</date> (Establishment of Interagency Task Force on the Reunification of Families) [formerly set out above], and Executive Order 14012 of <date date="2021-02-02">February 2, 2021</date> (Restoring Faith in Our Legal Immigration Systems and Strengthening Integration and Inclusion Efforts for New Americans) [formerly set out above] are hereby revoked; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Executive departments and agencies (agencies) shall take all appropriate action to promptly revoke all memoranda, guidance, or other policies based on the Executive Orders revoked in section 3(a) of this order and shall employ all lawful means to ensure the faithful execution of the immigration laws of the United States against all inadmissible and removable aliens.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Civil Enforcement Priorities</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to enable the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services to set priorities for their agencies that protect the public safety and national security interests of the American people, including by ensuring the successful enforcement of final orders of removal. Further, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the primary mission of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement’s Homeland Security Investigations division is the enforcement of the provisions of the INA and other Federal laws related to the illegal entry and unlawful presence of aliens in the United States and the enforcement of the purposes of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Criminal Enforcement Priorities</i>. The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall take all appropriate action to prioritize the prosecution of criminal offenses related to the unauthorized entry or continued unauthorized presence of aliens in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>Federal Homeland Security Task Forces</i>. (a) The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to jointly establish Homeland Security Task Forces (HSTFs) in all States nationwide.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The composition of each HSTF shall be subject to the direction of the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, but shall include representation from any other Federal agencies with law enforcement officers, or agencies with the ability to provide logistics, intelligence, and operational support to the HSTFs, and shall also include representation from relevant State and local law enforcement agencies. The heads of all Federal agencies shall take all appropriate action to provide support to the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that the HSTFs fulfill the objectives in subsection (c) of this section, and any other lawful purpose that fulfills the policy objectives of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The objective of each HSTF is to end the presence of criminal cartels, foreign gangs, and transnational criminal organizations throughout the United States, dismantle cross-border human smuggling and trafficking networks, end the scourge of human smuggling and trafficking, with a particular focus on such offenses involving children, and ensure the use of all available law enforcement tools to faithfully execute the immigration laws of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to provide an operational command center to coordinate the activities of the HSTFs and provide such support as they may require, and shall also take all appropriate action to provide supervisory direction to their activities as may be required.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. <i>Identification of Unregistered Illegal Aliens</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall take all appropriate action to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Immediately announce and publicize information about the legal obligation of all previously unregistered aliens in the United States to comply with the requirements of part VII of subchapter II of chapter 12 of title 8, United States Code [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1301">8 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Ensure that all previously unregistered aliens in the United States comply with the requirements of part VII of subchapter II of chapter 12 of title 8, United States Code; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Ensure that failure to comply with the legal obligations of part VII of subchapter II of chapter 12 of title 8, United States Code, is treated as a civil and criminal enforcement priority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 8. <i>Civil Fines and Penalties</i>. (a) The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Treasury, shall take all appropriate action to ensure the assessment and collection of all fines and penalties that the Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized by law to assess and collect from aliens unlawfully present in the United States, including aliens who unlawfully entered or unlawfully attempted to enter the United States, and from those who facilitate such aliens’ presence in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 90 days of the date of this order [<date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>], the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the President regarding their progress implementing the requirements of this section and recommending any additional actions that may need to be taken to achieve its objectives.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 9. <i>Efficient Removals of Recent Entrants and Other Aliens</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action, pursuant to section 235(b)(1)(A)(iii)(I) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1/A/iii/I">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(1)(A)(iii)(I)</ref>), to apply, in her sole and unreviewable discretion, the provisions of section 235(b)(1)(A)(i) and (ii) of the INA to the aliens designated under section 235(b)(1)(A)(iii)(II). Further, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly take appropriate action to use all other provisions of the immigration laws or any other Federal law, including, but not limited to sections 238 and 240(d) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1228">8 U.S.C. 1228</ref> and 1229a(d)), to ensure the efficient and expedited removal of aliens from the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 10. <i>Detention Facilities</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly take all appropriate action and allocate all legally available resources or establish contracts to construct, operate, control, or use facilities to detain removable aliens. The Secretary of Homeland Security, further, shall take all appropriate actions to ensure the detention of aliens apprehended for violations of immigration law pending the outcome of their removal proceedings or their removal from the country, to the extent permitted by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 11. <i>Federal-State Agreements</i>. To ensure State and local law enforcement agencies across the United States can assist with the protection of the American people, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, to the maximum extent permitted by law, and with the consent of State or local officials as appropriate, take appropriate action, through agreements under section 287(g) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1357/g">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</ref>) or otherwise, to authorize State and local law enforcement officials, as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines are qualified and appropriate, to perform the functions of immigration officers in relation to the investigation, apprehension, or detention of aliens in the United States under the direction and the supervision of the Secretary of Homeland Security. Such authorization shall be in addition to, rather than in place of, Federal performance of these duties. To the extent permitted by law, the Secretary of Homeland Security may structure each agreement under section 287(g) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1357/g">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</ref>) in the manner that provides the most effective model for enforcing Federal immigration laws in that jurisdiction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 12. <i>Encouraging Voluntary Compliance with the Law</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, and subject to adequate safeguards, assurances, bonds, and any other lawful measure, to adopt policies and procedures to encourage aliens unlawfully in the United States to voluntarily depart as soon as possible, including through enhanced usage of the provisions of section 240B of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229c">8 U.S.C. 1229c</ref>), international agreements or assistance, or any other measures that encourage aliens unlawfully in the United States to depart as promptly as possible, including through removals of aliens as provided by section 250 of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1260">8 U.S.C. 1260</ref>).</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 13. <i>Recalcitrant Countries</i>. The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Cooperate and effectively implement, as appropriate, the sanctions provided by section 243(d) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1253/d">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</ref>), with the Secretary of State, to the maximum extent permitted by law, ensuring that diplomatic efforts and negotiations with foreign states include the foreign states’ acceptance of their nationals who are subject to removal from the United States; and(b) Eliminate all documentary barriers, dilatory tactics, or other restrictions that prevent the prompt repatriation of aliens to any foreign state. Any failure or delay by a foreign state to verify the identity of a national of that state shall be considered in carrying out subsection (a) this section, and shall also be considered regarding the issuance of any other sanctions that may be available to the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 14. <i>Visa Bonds</i>. The Secretary of Treasury shall take all appropriate action, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security, to establish a system to facilitate the administration of all bonds that the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security may lawfully require to administer the provisions of the INA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 15. <i>Reestablishment of the VOICE Office and Addressing Victims of Crimes Committed by Removable Aliens</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall direct the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) to take all appropriate and lawful action to reestablish within ICE an office to provide proactive, timely, adequate, and professional services to victims of crimes committed by removable aliens, and those victims’ family members. The Attorney General shall also ensure that the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3771">18 U.S.C. 3771</ref> are followed in all Federal prosecutions involving crimes committed by removable aliens.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 16. <i>Addressing Actions by the Previous Administration</i>. The Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly take all appropriate action, consistent with law, to rescind the policy decisions of the previous administration that led to the increased or continued presence of illegal aliens in the United States, and align any and all departmental activities with the policies set out by this order and the immigration laws. Such action should include, but is not limited to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) ensuring that the parole authority under section 212(d)(5) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1182/d/5">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)</ref>) is exercised on only a case-by-case basis in accordance with the plain language of the statute, and in all circumstances only when an individual alien demonstrates urgent humanitarian reasons or a significant public benefit derived from their particular continued presence in the United States arising from such parole;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) ensuring that designations of Temporary Protected Status are consistent with the provisions of section 244 of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</ref>), and that such designations are appropriately limited in scope and made for only so long as may be necessary to fulfill the textual requirements of that statute; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) ensuring that employment authorization is provided in a manner consistent with section 274A of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</ref>), and that employment authorization is not provided to any unauthorized alien in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 17. <i>Sanctuary Jurisdictions</i>. The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, to the maximum extent possible under law, evaluate and undertake any lawful actions to ensure that so-called “sanctuary” jurisdictions, which seek to interfere with the lawful exercise of Federal law enforcement operations, do not receive access to Federal funds. Further, the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall evaluate and undertake any other lawful actions, criminal or civil, that they deem warranted based on any such jurisdiction’s practices that interfere with the enforcement of Federal law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 18. <i>Information Sharing</i>. (a) The Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly issue guidance to ensure maximum compliance by Department of Homeland Security personnel with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1644">8 U.S.C. 1644</ref> and ensure that State and local governments are provided with the information necessary to fulfill law enforcement, citizenship, or immigration status verification requirements authorized by law; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to stop the trafficking and smuggling of alien children into the United States, including through the sharing of any information necessary to assist in the achievement of that objective.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 19. <i>Funding Review</i>. The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Immediately review and, if appropriate, audit all contracts, grants, or other agreements providing Federal funding to non-governmental organizations supporting or providing services, either directly or indirectly, to removable or illegal aliens, to ensure that such agreements conform to applicable law and are free of waste, fraud, and abuse, and that they do not promote or facilitate violations of our immigration laws;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Pause distribution of all further funds pursuant to such agreements pending the results of the review in subsection (a) of this section;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Terminate all such agreements determined to be in violation of law or to be sources of waste, fraud, or abuse and prohibit any such future agreements;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Coordinate with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to ensure that no funding for agreements described in subsection (c) of this section is included in any appropriations request for the Department of Justice or the Department of Homeland Security; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Initiate clawback or recoupment procedures, if appropriate, for any agreements described in subsection (c) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 20. <i>Denial of Public Benefits to Illegal Aliens</i>. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall take all appropriate action to ensure that all agencies identify and stop the provision of any public benefits to any illegal alien not authorized to receive them under the provisions of the INA or other relevant statutory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 21. <i>Hiring More Agents and Officers</i>. Subject to available appropriations, the Secretary of Homeland Security, through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall take all appropriate action to significantly increase the number of agents and officers available to perform the duties of immigration officers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 22. <i>Severability</i>. It is the policy of the United States to enforce this order to the maximum extent possible to advance the interests of the United States. Accordingly:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) If any provision of this order, or the application of any provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this order and the application of its other provisions to any other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) If any provision of this order, or the application of any provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid because of the failure to follow certain procedures, the relevant executive branch officials shall implement those procedural requirements to conform with existing law and with any applicable court orders.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 23. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9bc2c689-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14165. Securing Our Borders</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14165, <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8467, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA), <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq., and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. Over the last 4 years, the United States has endured a large-scale invasion at an unprecedented level. Millions of illegal aliens from nations and regions all around the world successfully entered the United States where they are now residing, including potential terrorists, foreign spies, members of cartels, gangs, and violent transnational criminal organizations, and other hostile actors with malicious intent.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Deadly narcotics and other illicit materials have flowed across the border while agents and officers spend their limited resources processing illegal aliens for release into the United States. These catch-and-release policies undermine the rule of law and our sovereignty, create substantial risks to public safety and security, and divert critical resources away from stopping the entry of contraband and fugitives into the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">We have limited information on the precise whereabouts of a great number of these illegal aliens who have entered the United States over the last 4 years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This cannot stand. A nation without borders is not a nation, and the Federal Government must act with urgency and strength to end the threats posed by an unsecured border.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">One of my most important obligations is to protect the American people from the disastrous effects of unlawful mass migration and resettlement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">My Administration will marshal all available resources and authorities to stop this unprecedented flood of illegal aliens into the United States.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to take all appropriate action to secure the borders of our Nation through the following means:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Establishing a physical wall and other barriers monitored and supported by adequate personnel and technology;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Deterring and preventing the entry of illegal aliens into the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Detaining, to the maximum extent authorized by law, aliens apprehended on suspicion of violating Federal or State law, until such time as they are removed from the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Removing promptly all aliens who enter or remain in violation of Federal law;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Pursuing criminal charges against illegal aliens who violate the immigration laws, and against those who facilitate their unlawful presence in the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Cooperating fully with State and local law enforcement officials in enacting Federal-State partnerships to enforce Federal immigration priorities; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Obtaining complete operational control of the borders of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Physical Barriers</i>. The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to deploy and construct temporary and permanent physical barriers to ensure complete operational control of the southern border of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Deployment of Personnel</i>. (a) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate and lawful action to deploy sufficient personnel along the southern border of the United States to ensure complete operational control; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to supplement available personnel to secure the southern border and enforce the immigration laws of the United States through the use of sections 1103(a)(2) and (4)–(6) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1103/a/2">8 U.S.C. 1103(a)(2)</ref> and (4)–(6)).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Detention</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate actions to detain, to the fullest extent permitted by law, aliens apprehended for violations of immigration law until their successful removal from the United States. The Secretary shall, consistent with applicable law, issue new policy guidance or propose regulations regarding the appropriate and consistent use of lawful detention authority under the INA, including the termination of the practice commonly known as “catch-and-release,” whereby illegal aliens are routinely released into the United States shortly after their apprehension for violations of immigration law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>Resumption of Migrant Protection Protocols</i>. As soon as practicable, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall take all appropriate action to resume the Migrant Protection Protocols in all sectors along the southern border of the United States and ensure that, pending removal proceedings, aliens described in section 235(b)(2)(C) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/2/C">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(2)(C)</ref>) are returned to the territory from which they came.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. <i>Adjusting Parole Policies</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall, consistent with applicable law, take all appropriate action to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Cease using the “CBP One” application as a method of paroling or facilitating the entry of otherwise inadmissible aliens into the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Terminate all categorical parole programs that are contrary to the policies of the United States established in my Executive Orders, including the program known as the “Processes for Cubans, Haitians, Nicaraguans, and Venezuelans.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Align all policies and operations at the southern border of the United States to be consistent with the policy of Section 2 of this order and ensure that all future parole determinations fully comply with this order and with applicable law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 8. <i>Additional International Cooperation</i>. The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall take all appropriate action to facilitate additional international cooperation and agreements, consistent with the policy of Section 2, including entering into agreements based upon the provisions of section 208(a)(2)(A) of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158/a/2/A">8 U.S.C. 1158(a)(2)(A)</ref>) or any other applicable provision of law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 9. <i>DNA and Identification Requirements</i>. (a) The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to fulfill the requirements of the DNA Fingerprint Act of 2005, title X of <ref href="/us/pl/109/162">Public Law 109–162</ref> [amending sections 3142 and 3297 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and sections 12592, 40701, and 40702 of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement], for all aliens detained under the authority of the United States; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to use any available technologies and procedures to determine the validity of any claimed familial relationship between aliens encountered or apprehended by the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 10. <i>Prosecution of Offenses</i>. The Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take all appropriate action to prioritize the prosecution of offenses that relate to the borders of the United States, including the investigation and prosecution of offenses that involve human smuggling, human trafficking, child trafficking, and sex trafficking in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 11. <i>Additional Measures</i>. Within 14 days of the date of this order [<date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>], the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide recommendations to the President regarding the use of any other authority to protect the United States from foreign threats and secure the southern border.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 12. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5107a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Creating Welcoming Communities and Fully Integrating Immigrants and Refugees</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2014-11-21">Nov. 21, 2014</date>, 79 F.R. 70765, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Heads of Executive Departments and Agencies</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Our country has long been a beacon of hope and opportunity for people from around the world. Nearly 40 million foreign-born residents nationwide contribute to their communities every day, including 3 million refugees who have resettled here since 1975. These new Americans significantly improve our economy. They make up 13 percent of the population, but are over 16 percent of the labor force and start 28 percent of all new businesses. Moreover, immigrants or their children have founded more than 40 percent of Fortune 500 companies, which collectively employ over 10 million people worldwide and generate annual revenues of $4.2 trillion.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By focusing on the civic, economic, and linguistic integration of new Americans, we can help immigrants and refugees in the United States contribute fully to our economy and their communities. Civic integration provides new Americans with security in their rights and liberties. Economic integration empowers immigrants to be self-sufficient and allows them to give back to their communities and contribute to economic growth. English language acquisition allows new Americans to attain employment or career advancement and be more active civic participants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Our success as a Nation of immigrants is rooted in our ongoing commitment to welcoming and integrating newcomers into the fabric of our country. It is important that we develop a Federal immigrant integration strategy that is innovative and competitive with those of other industrialized nations and supports mechanisms to ensure that our Nation’s diverse people are contributing to society to their fullest potential.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Therefore, I am establishing a White House Task Force on New Americans, an interagency effort to identify and support State and local efforts at integration that are working and to consider how to expand and replicate successful models. The Task Force, which will engage with community, business, and faith leaders, as well as State and local elected officials, will help determine additional steps the Federal Government can take to ensure its programs and policies are serving diverse communities that include new Americans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, I hereby order as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>White House Task Force on New Americans</i>. (a) There is established a White House Task Force on New Americans (Task Force) to develop a coordinated Federal strategy to better integrate new Americans into communities and support State and local efforts to do the same. It shall be co-chaired by the Director of the Domestic Policy Council and Secretary of Homeland Security, or their designees. In addition to the Co-Chairs, the Task Force shall consist of the following members:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the Secretary of State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the Attorney General;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) the Secretary of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) the Secretary of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) the Secretary of Labor;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vii) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(viii) the Secretary of Transportation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ix) the Secretary of Education;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(x) the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xi) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xii) the Administrator of the Small Business Administration;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xiii) the Senior Advisor and Assistant to the President for Intergovernmental Affairs and Public Engagement;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xiv) the Director of the National Economic Council;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xv) the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(xvi) the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) A member of the Task Force may designate a senior-level official who is from the member’s department, agency, or office, and is a full-time officer or employee of the Federal Government, to perform day-to-day Task Force functions of the member. At the direction of the Co-Chairs, the Task Force may establish subgroups consisting exclusively of Task Force members or their designees under this subsection, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint an Executive Director who will determine the Task Force’s agenda, convene regular meetings of the Task Force, and supervise work under the direction of the Co-Chairs. The Department of Homeland Security shall provide funding and administrative support for the Task Force to the extent permitted by law and subject to the availability of appropriations. Each executive department or agency shall bear its own expenses for participating in the Task Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Mission and Function of the Task Force</i>. (a) The Task Force shall, consistent with applicable law, work across executive departments and agencies to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) review the policies and programs of all relevant executive departments and agencies to ensure they are responsive to the needs of new Americans and the receiving communities in which they reside, and identify ways in which such programs can be used to increase meaningful engagement between new Americans and the receiving community;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) identify and disseminate best practices at the State and local level;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) provide technical assistance, training, or other support to existing Federal grantees to increase their coordination and capacity to improve long-term integration and foster welcoming community climates;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) collect and disseminate immigrant integration data, policies, and programs that affect numerous executive departments and agencies, as well as State and local governments and nongovernmental actors;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) conduct outreach to representatives of nonprofit organizations, State and local government agencies, elected officials, and other interested persons that can assist with the Task Force’s development of recommendations;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) work with Federal, State, and local entities to measure and strengthen equitable access to services and programs for new Americans, consistent with applicable law; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vii) share information with and communicate to the American public regarding the benefits that result from integrating new Americans into communities.</p>
<p>(b) Within 120 days of the date of this memorandum, the Task Force shall develop and submit to the President an Integration Plan with recommendations for agency actions to further the integration of new Americans. The Integration Plan shall include:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) an assessment by each Task Force member of the status and scope of the efforts by the member’s department, agency, or office to further the civic, economic, and linguistic integration of new Americans, including a report on the status of any offices or programs that have been created to develop, implement, or monitor targeted initiatives concerning immigrant integration; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) recommendations for issues, programs, or initiatives that should be further evaluated, studied, and implemented, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Task Force shall provide, within 1 year of the date of this memorandum, a status report to the President regarding the implementation of this memorandum. The Task Force shall review and update the Integration Plan periodically, as appropriate, and shall present to the President any updated recommendations or findings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department, agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of Homeland Security is hereby authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5107b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Combating High Nonimmigrant Overstay Rates</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2019-04-22">Apr. 22, 2019</date>, 84 F.R. 19853, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State[,] the Attorney General[, and] the Secretary of Homeland Security</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA), <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> <i>et seq</i>., and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. (a) My Administration is committed to securing the borders of the United States and fostering respect for the laws of our country, both of which are cornerstones of our Republic. Nonimmigrant visa (visa) overstay rates are unacceptably high for nationals of certain countries. Aliens must abide by the terms and conditions of their visas for our immigration system to function as intended. Although the United States benefits from legitimate nonimmigrant entry, individuals who abuse the visa process and decline to abide by the terms and conditions of their visas, including their visa departure dates, undermine the integrity of our immigration system and harm the national interest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The large numbers of aliens who overstay their period of lawful admission, failing to comply with the terms of a visa or the Visa Waiver Program, place significant strain on Department of Justice and Department of Homeland Security resources, which are currently needed to address the national emergency on our southern border.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Addressing High Visa Overstay Rates</i>. (a) The Secretary of State shall engage with the governments of countries with a total overstay rate greater than 10 percent in the combined B–1 and B–2 nonimmigrant visa category based on the Department of Homeland Security Fiscal Year 2018 Entry/Exit Overstay Report. This engagement should identify conditions contributing to high overstay rates among nationals of those countries and methods to address those conditions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 120 days of the date of this memorandum [<date date="2019-04-22">Apr. 22, 2019</date>], the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall provide to the President recommendations to reduce B–1 and B–2 nonimmigrant visa overstay rates from the identified countries. With respect to any of the identified countries, the recommendations may include, as appropriate and to the extent consistent with applicable law, a proclamation, relying on authorities such as sections 212(f) and 215[(a)] of the INA (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1182/f">8 U.S.C. 1182(f)</ref> and 1185(a)), suspending or limiting entry of nationals of those countries who hold B–1 or B–2 visas; targeted suspension of visa issuance for certain nationals; limits to duration of admission, to be implemented by the Department of Homeland Security; and additional documentary requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall immediately begin taking all appropriate actions that are within the scope of their respective authorities to reduce overstay rates for all classes of nonimmigrant visas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the President a summary of the Department of Homeland Security’s ongoing efforts to reduce overstays from countries participating in the Visa Waiver Program, to include any recommendations for additional action necessary and appropriate to ensure the integrity and security of that Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Admission Bonds</i>. The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall take steps to develop measures required for imposing admission bonds as a means for improving compliance with the terms and conditions of nonimmigrant visas. The Secretaries shall provide a status report to the President within 120 days of the date of this memorandum.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) existing rights or obligations under international agreements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. The Secretary of State is hereby authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5107c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Preserving and Fortifying Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA)</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2021-01-20">Jan. 20, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 7053, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Attorney General [and] the Secretary of Homeland Security</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. In 2012, during the Obama-Biden Administration, the Secretary of Homeland Security issued a memorandum outlining how, in the exercise of prosecutorial discretion, the Department of Homeland Security should enforce the Nation’s immigration laws against certain young people. This memorandum, known as the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) guidance, deferred the removal of certain undocumented immigrants who were brought to the United States as children, have obeyed the law, and stayed in school or enlisted in the military. DACA and associated regulations permit eligible individuals who pass a background check to request temporary relief from removal and to apply for temporary work permits. DACA reflects a judgment that these immigrants should not be a priority for removal based on humanitarian concerns and other considerations, and that work authorization will enable them to support themselves and their families, and to contribute to our economy, while they remain.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Preserving and Fortifying DACA</i>. The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall take all actions he deems appropriate, consistent with applicable law, to preserve and fortify DACA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department, agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>J.R. Biden, Jr.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
