<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9bc5107d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104"><num value="1104">§ 1104.</num><heading> Powers and duties of Secretary of State</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc5107e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers and duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall be charged with the administration and the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and all other immigration and nationality laws relating to (1) the powers, duties, and functions of diplomatic and consular officers of the United States, except those powers, duties, and functions conferred upon the consular officers relating to the granting or refusal of visas; (2) the powers, duties, and functions of the Administrator; and (3) the determination of nationality of a person not in the United States. He shall establish such regulations; prescribe such forms of reports, entries and other papers; issue such instructions; and perform such other acts as he deems necessary for carrying out such provisions. He is authorized to confer or impose upon any employee of the United States, with the consent of the head of the department or independent establishment under whose jurisdiction the employee is serving, any of the powers, functions, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon officers or employees of the Department of State or of the American Foreign Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc5107f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation and duties of Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall designate an Administrator who shall be a citizen of the United States, qualified by experience. The Administrator shall maintain close liaison with the appropriate committees of Congress in order that they may be advised regarding the administration of this chapter by consular officers. The Administrator shall be charged with any and all responsibility and authority in the administration of this chapter which are conferred on the Secretary of State as may be delegated to the Administrator by the Secretary of State or which may be prescribed by the Secretary of State, and shall perform such other duties as the Secretary of State may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc51080-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Passport Office, Visa Office, and other offices; directors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the Department of State there shall be a Passport Office, a Visa Office, and such other offices as the Secretary of State may deem to be appropriate, each office to be headed by a director. The Directors of the Passport Office and the Visa Office shall be experienced in the administration of the nationality and immigration laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc51081-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The functions heretofore performed by the Passport Division and the Visa Division of the Department of State shall hereafter be performed by the Passport Office and the Visa Office, respectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9bc51082-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> General Counsel of Visa Office; appointment and duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be a General Counsel of the Visa Office, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of State and who shall serve under the general direction of the Legal Adviser of the Department of State. The General Counsel shall have authority to maintain liaison with the appropriate officers of the Service with a view to securing uniform interpretations of the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9bc51083-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title I, § 104, <ref href="/us/stat/66/174">66 Stat. 174</ref>; Pub. L. 87-510, § 4(a)(2), <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/123">76 Stat. 123</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/tIII/s305/43">Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 305(43)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/428">78 Stat. 428</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/b/1">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 109(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/847">91 Stat. 847</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/d">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2620">102 Stat. 2620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162/h/2">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/407">108 Stat. 407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9bc51084-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9bc51085-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9bc51086-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (e), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9bc51087-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162/h/2/A">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162(h)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “; Bureau of Consular Affairs” after “Secretary of State” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162/h/2/B">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162(h)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator” for “the Bureau of Consular Affairs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162/h/2/C">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162(h)(2)(C)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “There is established in the Department of State a Bureau of Consular Affairs, to be headed by an Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs. The Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs shall be a citizen of the United States, qualified by experience, and shall maintain close liaison with the appropriate committees of Congress in order that they may be advised regarding the administration of this chapter by consular officers. He shall be charged with any and all responsibility and authority in the administration of the Bureau and of this chapter which are conferred on the Secretary of State as may be delegated to him by the Secretary of State or which may be prescribed by the Secretary of State. He shall also perform such other duties as the Secretary of State may prescribe.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162/h/2/D">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162(h)(2)(D)</ref>, substituted “Department of State” for “Bureau”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162/h/2/E">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162(h)(2)(E)</ref>, struck out before period at end “, of the Bureau of Consular Affairs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> substituted “Bureau of Consular Affairs” for “Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s109/b/1/A">Pub. L. 95–105, § 109(b)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “Security and” after “Bureau of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s109/b/1/B">Pub. L. 95–105, § 109(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Consular Affairs, to be headed by an Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs” for “Security and Consular Affairs, to be headed by an administrator (with an appropriate title to be designated by the Secretary of State), with rank equal to that of an Assistant Secretary of State” and “Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs” for “administrator” and struck out provision that the administrator shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s109/b/1/C">Pub. L. 95–105, § 109(b)(1)(C)</ref>, struck out “Security and” after “Bureau of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s109/b/1/D">Pub. L. 95–105, § 109(b)(1)(D)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which placed Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs under immediate jurisdiction of Deputy Under Secretary of State for Administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/88/426">Pub. L. 88–426</ref> repealed provisions which related to compensation of Administrator. See section 5311 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/510">Pub. L. 87–510</ref> provided for appointment of Administrator of Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs by President by and with advice and consent of Senate.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9bc51088-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9bc51089-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9bc5108a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/426">Pub. L. 88–426</ref> effective on first day of first pay period which begins on or after <date date="1964-07-01">July 1, 1964</date>, except to extent provided in <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/s501/c">section 501(c) of Pub. L. 88–426</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/s501">section 501 of Pub. L. 88–426</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5108b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5108c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, and <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/d">section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5108d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assumption of Duties by Administrator of Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/b/4">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 109(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/847">91 Stat. 847</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/b/4">“The individual holding the position of administrator of the Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs on the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>] shall assume the duties of the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs and shall not be required to be reappointed by reason of the enactment of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9bc5108e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs or Administrator</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/b/5">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 109(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/847">91 Stat. 847</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/b/5">“Any reference in any law to the Bureau of Security and Consular Affairs or to the administrator of such Bureau shall be deemed to be a reference to the Bureau of Consular Affairs or to the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs, respectively.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
