<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c00b986-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a"><num value="1186a">§ 1186a.</num><heading> Conditional permanent resident status for certain alien spouses and sons and daughters</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b987-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b988-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditional basis for status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, an alien spouse (as defined in subsection (h)(1)) and an alien son or daughter (as defined in subsection (h)(2)) shall be considered, at the time of obtaining the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, to have obtained such status on a conditional basis subject to the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b989-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of requirements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b98a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> At time of obtaining permanent residence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">At the time an alien spouse or alien son or daughter obtains permanent resident status on a conditional basis under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide for notice to such a spouse, son, or daughter respecting the provisions of this section and the requirements of subsection (c)(1) to have the conditional basis of such status removed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b98b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> At time of required petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In addition, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall attempt to provide notice to such a spouse, son, or daughter, at or about the beginning of the 90-day period described in subsection (d)(2)(A), of the requirements of subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002029"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b98c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of failure to provide notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The failure of the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide a notice under this paragraph shall not affect the enforcement of the provisions of this section with respect to such a spouse, son, or daughter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b98d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of status if finding that qualifying marriage improper</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b98e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of an alien with permanent resident status on a conditional basis under subsection (a), if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines, before the second anniversary of the alien’s obtaining the status of lawful admission for permanent residence, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b98f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the qualifying marriage—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b990-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> was entered into for the purpose of procuring an alien’s admission as an immigrant, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b991-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has been judicially annulled or terminated, other than through the death of a spouse; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b992-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a fee or other consideration was given (other than a fee or other consideration to an attorney for assistance in preparation of a lawful petition) for the filing of a petition under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154/a">section 1154(a) of this title</ref> or subsection (d) or (p) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref> with respect to the alien;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Secretary of Homeland Security shall so notify the parties involved and, subject to paragraph (2), shall terminate the permanent resident status of the alien (or aliens) involved as of the date of the determination.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b993-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing in removal proceeding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any alien whose permanent resident status is terminated under paragraph (1) may request a review of such determination in a proceeding to remove the alien. In such proceeding, the burden of proof shall be on the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish, by a preponderance of the evidence, that a condition described in paragraph (1) is met.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b994-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of timely petition and interview for removal of condition</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b995-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order for the conditional basis established under subsection (a) for an alien spouse or an alien son or daughter to be removed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b996-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the alien spouse and the petitioning spouse (if not deceased) jointly must submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security, during the period described in subsection (d)(2), a petition which requests the removal of such conditional basis and which states, under penalty of perjury, the facts and information described in subsection (d)(1), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b997-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in accordance with subsection (d)(3), the alien spouse and the petitioning spouse (if not deceased) must appear for a personal interview before an officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security respecting the facts and information described in subsection (d)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b998-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of permanent resident status for failure to file petition or have personal interview</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b999-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of an alien with permanent resident status on a conditional basis under subsection (a), if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b99a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no petition is filed with respect to the alien in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1)(A), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b99b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> unless there is good cause shown, the alien spouse and petitioning spouse fail to appear at the interview described in paragraph (1)(B),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the Secretary of Homeland Security shall terminate the permanent resident status of the alien as of the second anniversary of the alien’s lawful admission for permanent residence.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b99c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing in removal proceeding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In any removal proceeding with respect to an alien whose permanent resident status is terminated under subparagraph (A), the burden of proof shall be on the alien to establish compliance with the conditions of paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b99d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination after petition and interview</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b99e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b99f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a petition is filed in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1)(A), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b9a0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the alien spouse and petitioning spouse appear at the interview described in paragraph (1)(B),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make a determination, within 90 days of the date of the interview, as to whether the facts and information described in subsection (d)(1) and alleged in the petition are true with respect to the qualifying marriage.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9a1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal of conditional basis if favorable determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that such facts and information are true, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall so notify the parties involved and shall remove the conditional basis of the parties effective as of the second anniversary of the alien’s obtaining the status of lawful admission for permanent residence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9a2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination if adverse determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that such facts and information are not true, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall so notify the parties involved and, subject to subparagraph (D), shall terminate the permanent resident status of an alien spouse or an alien son or daughter as of the date of the determination.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9a3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing in removal proceeding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any alien whose permanent resident status is terminated under subparagraph (C) may request a review of such determination in a proceeding to remove the alien. In such proceeding, the burden of proof shall be on the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the facts and information described in subsection (d)(1) and alleged in the petition are not true with respect to the qualifying marriage.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9a4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Hardship waiver</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s discretion, may remove the conditional basis of the permanent resident status for an alien who fails to meet the requirements of paragraph (1) if the alien demonstrates that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9a5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> extreme hardship would result if such alien is removed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9a6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the qualifying marriage was entered into in good faith by the alien spouse, but the qualifying marriage has been terminated (other than through the death of the spouse) and the alien was not at fault in failing to meet the requirements of paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9a7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the qualifying marriage was entered into in good faith by the alien spouse and during the marriage the alien spouse or child was battered by or was the subject of extreme cruelty perpetrated by his or her spouse or citizen or permanent resident parent and the alien was not at fault in failing to meet the requirements of paragraph (1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9a8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the alien meets the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154/a/1/A/iii/II/aa/BB">section 1154(a)(1)(A)(iii)(II)(aa)(BB) of this title</ref> and following the marriage ceremony was battered by or subject to extreme cruelty perpetrated by the alien’s intended spouse and was not at fault in failing to meet the requirements of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In determining extreme hardship, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider circumstances occurring only during the period that the alien was admitted for permanent residence on a conditional basis. In acting on applications under this paragraph, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider any credible evidence relevant to the application. The determination of what evidence is credible and the weight to be given that evidence shall be within the sole discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall, by regulation, establish measures to protect the confidentiality of information concerning any abused alien spouse or child, including information regarding the whereabouts of such spouse or child.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9a9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Details of petition and interview</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9aa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of petition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each petition under subsection (c)(1)(A) shall contain the following facts and information:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9ab-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of proper marriage and petitioning process</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The facts are that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b9ac-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the qualifying marriage—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id9c00b9ad-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> was entered into in accordance with the laws of the place where the marriage took place,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id9c00b9ae-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has not been judicially annulled or terminated, other than through the death of a spouse, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id9c00b9af-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> was not entered into for the purpose of procuring an alien’s admission as an immigrant; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b9b0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> no fee or other consideration was given (other than a fee or other consideration to an attorney for assistance in preparation of a lawful petition) for the filing of a petition under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154/a">section 1154(a) of this title</ref> or subsection (d) or (p) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002030"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref> with respect to the alien spouse or alien son or daughter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of additional information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The information is a statement of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b9b2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the actual residence of each party to the qualifying marriage since the date the alien spouse obtained permanent resident status on a conditional basis under subsection (a), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c00b9b3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the place of employment (if any) of each such party since such date, and the name of the employer of such party.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Period for filing petition</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> 90-day period before second anniversary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the petition under subsection (c)(1)(A) must be filed during the 90-day period before the second anniversary of the alien’s obtaining the status of lawful admission for permanent residence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Date petitions for good cause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Such a petition may be considered if filed after such date, but only if the alien establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security good cause and extenuating circumstances for failure to file the petition during the period described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of petitions during removal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of an alien who is the subject of removal hearings as a result of failure to file a petition on a timely basis in accordance with subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Homeland Security may stay such removal proceedings against an alien pending the filing of the petition under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal interview</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The interview under subsection (c)(1)(B) shall be conducted within 90 days after the date of submitting a petition under subsection (c)(1)(A) and at a local office of the Department of Homeland Security, designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security, which is convenient to the parties involved. The Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s discretion, may waive the deadline for such an interview or the requirement for such an interview in such cases as may be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9b9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of period for purposes of naturalization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subchapter III, in the case of an alien who is in the United States as a lawful permanent resident on a conditional basis under this section, the alien shall be considered to have been admitted as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence and to be in the United States as an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9ba-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain waivers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of an alien who has permanent residence status on a conditional basis under this section, if, in order to obtain such status, the alien obtained a waiver under subsection (h) or (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1182">section 1182 of this title</ref> of certain grounds of inadmissibility, such waiver terminates upon the termination of such permanent residence status under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9bb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Service in Armed Forces</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9bc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The 90-day period described in subsection (d)(2)(A) shall be tolled during any period of time in which the alien spouse or petitioning spouse is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States and serving abroad in an active-duty status in the Armed Forces, except that, at the option of the petitioners, the petition may be filed during such active-duty service at any time after the commencement of such 90-day period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9bd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal interview</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The 90-day period described in the first sentence of subsection (d)(3) shall be tolled during any period of time in which the alien spouse or petitioning spouse is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States and serving abroad in an active-duty status in the Armed Forces, except that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit the Secretary of Homeland Security from waiving the requirement for an interview under subsection (c)(1)(B) pursuant to the Secretary’s authority under the second sentence of subsection (d)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c00b9be-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c00b9bf-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “alien spouse” means an alien who obtains the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (whether on a conditional basis or otherwise)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9c0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as an immediate relative (described in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1151/b">section 1151(b) of this title</ref>) as the spouse of a citizen of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9c1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1184/d">section 1184(d) of this title</ref> as the fiancee or fiance of a citizen of the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c00b9c2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1153/a/2">section 1153(a)(2) of this title</ref> as the spouse of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">by virtue of a marriage which was entered into less than 24 months before the date the alien obtains such status by virtue of such marriage, but does not include such an alien who only obtains such status as a result of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1153/d">section 1153(d) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c00b9c3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “alien son or daughter” means an alien who obtains the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (whether on a conditional basis or otherwise) by virtue of being the son or daughter of an individual through a qualifying marriage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c00b9c4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “qualifying marriage” means the marriage described to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c00b9c5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1186a/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “petitioning spouse” means the spouse of a qualifying marriage, other than the alien.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c00b9c6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 2, § 216, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/639/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–639, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3537">100 Stat. 3537</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s7/a">Pub. L. 100–525, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2616">102 Stat. 2616</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 101–649, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5085">104 Stat. 5085</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s302/e/8/B">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 302(e)(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1746">105 Stat. 1746</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tIV/s40702/a">Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40702(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1955">108 Stat. 1955</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s308/d/4/E">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 308(d)(4)(E)</ref>, (e)(7), (f)(1)(I), (J), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-618">110 Stat. 3009–618</ref>, 3009–620, 3009–621; <ref href="/us/pl/106/553/s1/a/2/tXI/s1103/c/2">Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title XI, § 1103(c)(2)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2762">114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–145; <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1</ref>, <date date="2011-11-23">Nov. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/747">125 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 113–4, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/112">127 Stat. 112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c00b9c7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c00b9c8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c00b9c9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (p) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(A)(ii), was redesignated subsec. (r) of section 1184 by <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s8/a/3">Pub. L. 108–193, § 8(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2886">117 Stat. 2886</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c00b9ca-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another section 216 of act <date date="1952-06-27">June 27, 1952</date>, was renumbered section 218 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1188">section 1188 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c00b9cb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s806/b/2">Pub. L. 113–4, § 806(b)(2)</ref>, which, in concluding provisions, directed the substitution of “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Attorney General” in the first sentence and “Secretary” for “Attorney General” in the second to fourth sentences, could not be executed because of the prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/2/B">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(2)(B)</ref>. See 2011 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s806/b/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 806(b)(1)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “The Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s” for “The Attorney General, in the Attorney General’s” in introductory provisions, was executed by making the substitution for “The Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Attorney General’s”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/2/B">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(2)(B)</ref>. See 2011 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s806/a">Pub. L. 113–4, § 806(a)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/2/B">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Attorney General” wherever appearing except in subsec. (g)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “(h)(1))” for “(g)(1))” and “(h)(2))” for “(g)(2))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/2/C">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “Department of Homeland Security” for “Service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/b/2/A">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (C), substituted “Department of Homeland Security” for “Service” and “Secretary’s” for “Attorney General’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/58/s1/a">Pub. L. 112–58, § 1(a)</ref>, added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (b)(1)(B), (d)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154/a">section 1154(a) of this title</ref> or subsection (d) or (p) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref>” for “section 1154(a) or 1184(d) of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/f/1/I">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(f)(1)(I)</ref>, substituted “admission” for “entry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/7">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation” in heading and “remove” for “deport” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/7">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation” in heading and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/7">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation” in heading and “remove” for “deport” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/7">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “removed” for “deported”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A)(i)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/f/1/J">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(f)(1)(J)</ref>, substituted “admission” for “entry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/7">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation” wherever appearing in heading and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/d/4/E">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(d)(4)(E)</ref>, substituted “inadmissibility” for “exclusion”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> inserted after second sentence “In acting on applications under this paragraph, the Attorney General shall consider any credible evidence relevant to the application. The determination of what evidence is credible and the weight to be given that evidence shall be within the sole discretion of the Attorney General.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> substituted “section 1153(d)” for “section 1153(a)(8)” in closing provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> struck out “or” at end of subpar. (A), struck out “by the alien spouse for good cause” after “death of the spouse)” and substituted “, or” for period at end of subpar. (B), added subpar. (C), and inserted at end “The Attorney General shall, by regulation, establish measures to protect the confidentiality of information concerning any abused alien spouse or child, including information regarding the whereabouts of such spouse or child.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s7/a/1">Pub. L. 100–525, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/99/639/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–639, § 2(a)</ref>, which enacted this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s7/a/2">Pub. L. 100–525, § 7(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “90 days” for “90-days”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c00b9cc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c00b9cd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> effective <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, and applicable to alien who is beneficiary of classification petition filed under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154">section 1154 of this title</ref> before, on, or after <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, see section 1(a)(2) [title XI, § 1103(d)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c00b9ce-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c00b9cf-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tIV/s40702/b">Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40702(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1955">108 Stat. 1955</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/322/tIV/s40702/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>] and shall apply to applications made before, on, or after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c00b9d0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s302/e/8">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 302(e)(8)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1746">105 Stat. 1746</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 302(e)(8) is effective as if included in section 162(e) of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c032ad1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tVII/s701/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5086">104 Stat. 5086</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tVII/s701/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to marriages entered into before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c032ad2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> effective as if included in enactment of Immigration Marriage Fraud Amendments of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/639">Pub. L. 99–639</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s7/d">section 7(d) of Pub. L. 100–525</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1182">section 1182 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c032ad3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
