<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c0ca107-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203"><num value="1203">§ 1203.</num><heading> Reentry permit</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0ca108-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application; contents</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c0ca109-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or (2) any alien lawfully admitted to the United States pursuant to clause 6 of section 3 of the Immigration Act of 1924, between <date date="1924-07-01">July 1, 1924</date>, and <date date="1932-07-05">July 5, 1932</date>, both dates inclusive, who intends to depart temporarily from the United States may make application to the Attorney General for a permit to reenter the United States, stating the length of his intended absence or absences, and the reasons therefor. Such applications shall be made under oath, and shall be in such form, contain such information, and be accompanied by such photographs of the applicant as may be by regulations prescribed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0ca10a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of permit; nonrenewability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Attorney General finds (1) that the applicant under subsection (a)(1) has been lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence, or that the applicant under subsection (a)(2) has since admission maintained the status required of him at the time of his admission and such applicant desires to visit abroad and to return to the United States to resume the status existing at the time of his departure for such visit, (2) that the application is made in good faith, and (3) that the alien’s proposed departure from the United States would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, the Attorney General may, in his discretion, issue the permit, which shall be valid for not more than two years from the date of issuance and shall not be renewable. The permit shall be in such form as shall be by regulations prescribed for the complete identification of the alien.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f120b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple reentries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During the period of validity, such permit may be used by the alien in making one or more applications for reentry into the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f120c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Presented and surrendered</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the return of the alien to the United States the permit shall be presented to the immigration officer at the port of entry, and upon the expiration of its validity, the permit shall be surrendered to the Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f120d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1203/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit in lieu of visa</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A permit issued under this section in the possession of the person to whom issued, shall be accepted in lieu of any visa which otherwise would be required from such person under this chapter. Otherwise a permit issued under this section shall have no effect under the immigration laws except to show that the alien to whom it was issued is returning from a temporary visit abroad; but nothing in this section shall be construed as making such permit the exclusive means of establishing that the alien is so returning.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c0f120e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 3, § 223, <ref href="/us/stat/66/194">66 Stat. 194</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s6">Pub. L. 97–116, § 6</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1615">95 Stat. 1615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c0f120f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c0f1210-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c0f1211-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Clause (6) of section 3 of the Immigration Act of 1924, referred to in subsec. (a), which was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s203/6">section 203(6) of this title</ref>, was repealed by section 403(a)(2) of act <date date="1952-06-27">June 27, 1952</date>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15/E">section 1101(a)(15)(E) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (e), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c0f1212-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> substituted “two years from the date of issuance and shall not be renewable” for “one year from the date of issuance: <i>Provided</i>, That the Attorney General may in his discretion extend the validity of the permit for a period or periods not exceeding one year in the aggregate”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c0f1213-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f1214-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c0f1215-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
