<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c0f1222-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221"><num value="1221">§ 1221.</num><heading> Lists of alien and citizen passengers arriving and departing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1223-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Arrival manifests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each commercial vessel or aircraft transporting any person to any seaport or airport of the United States from any place outside the United States, it shall be the duty of an appropriate official specified in subsection (d) to provide to any United States border officer (as defined in subsection (i)) at that port manifest information about each passenger, crew member, and other occupant transported on such vessel or aircraft prior to arrival at that port.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1224-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Departure manifests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each commercial vessel or aircraft taking passengers on board at any seaport or airport of the United States, who are destined to any place outside the United States, it shall be the duty of an appropriate official specified in subsection (d) to provide any United States border officer (as defined in subsection (i)) before departure from such port manifest information about each passenger, crew member, and other occupant to be transported.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1225-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of manifest</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The information to be provided with respect to each person listed on a manifest required to be provided under subsection (a) or (b) shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f1226-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> complete name;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f1227-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> date of birth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f1228-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> citizenship;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f1229-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> sex;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> passport number and country of issuance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> country of residence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> United States visa number, date, and place of issuance, where applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> alien registration number, where applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> United States address while in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c0f122f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> such other information the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Treasury determines as being necessary for the identification of the persons transported and for the enforcement of the immigration laws and to protect safety and national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1230-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate officials specified</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An appropriate official specified in this subsection is the master or commanding officer, or authorized agent, owner, or consignee, of the commercial vessel or aircraft concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1231-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline for requirement of electronic transmission of manifest information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>, manifest information required to be provided under subsection (a) or (b) shall be transmitted electronically by the appropriate official specified in subsection (d) to an immigration officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1232-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No operator of any private or public carrier that is under a duty to provide manifest information under this section shall be granted clearance papers until the appropriate official specified in subsection (d) has complied with the requirements of this subsection, except that, in the case of commercial vessels or aircraft that the Attorney General determines are making regular trips to the United States, the Attorney General may, when expedient, arrange for the provision of manifest information of persons departing the United States at a later date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1233-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties against noncomplying shipments, aircraft, or carriers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If it shall appear to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that an appropriate official specified in subsection (d), any public or private carrier, or the agent of any transportation line, as the case may be, has refused or failed to provide manifest information required by subsection (a) or (b), or that the manifest information provided is not accurate and full based on information provided to the carrier, such official, carrier, or agent, as the case may be, shall pay to the Commissioner the sum of $1,000 for each person with respect to whom such accurate and full manifest information is not provided, or with respect to whom the manifest information is not prepared as prescribed by this section or by regulations issued pursuant thereto. No commercial vessel or aircraft shall be granted clearance pending determination of the question of the liability to the payment of such penalty, or while it remains unpaid, and no such penalty shall be remitted or refunded, except that clearance may be granted prior to the determination of such question upon the deposit with the Commissioner of a bond or undertaking approved by the Attorney General or a sum sufficient to cover such penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1234-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may waive the requirements of subsection (a) or (b) upon such circumstances and conditions as the Attorney General may by regulation prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1235-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> United States border officer defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “United States border officer” means, with respect to a particular port of entry into the United States, any United States official who is performing duties at that port of entry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c0f1236-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1221/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Record of citizens and resident aliens leaving permanently for foreign countries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may authorize immigration officers to record the following information regarding every resident person leaving the United States by way of the Canadian or Mexican borders for permanent residence in a foreign country: Names, age, and sex; whether married or single; calling or occupation; whether able to read or write; nationality; country of birth; country of which citizen or subject; race; last permanent residence in the United States; intended future permanent residence; and time and port of last arrival in the United States; and if a United States citizen or national, the facts on which claim to that status is based.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c0f1237-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 4, § 231, <ref href="/us/stat/66/195">66 Stat. 195</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/g">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(g)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1620">95 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s543/a/1">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 543(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5057">104 Stat. 5057</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s306/c/4/A">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 306(c)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1752">105 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s308/g/1">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 308(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-622">110 Stat. 3009–622</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/tI/s115">Pub. L. 107–77, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/768">115 Stat. 768</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/173/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/557">116 Stat. 557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c0f1238-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c0f1239-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c0f123a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/173">Pub. L. 107–173</ref> added subsecs. (a) to (i), redesignated former subsec. (c) as (j), and struck out former subsecs. (a), (b), (d), and (e), which related to shipment or aircraft manifest, arrival, form and contents, exclusions in subsec. (a), departure, shipment or aircraft manifest, form and contents, and exclusions in subsec. (b), penalties against noncomplying shipments or aircraft in subsec. (d), and waiver of requirements in subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/s115/a">Pub. L. 107–77, § 115(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment subsec. (a) read as follows: “Upon the arrival of any person by water or by air at any port within the United States from any place outside the United States, it shall be the duty of the master or commanding officer, or authorized agent, owner, or consignee of the vessel or aircraft, having any such person on board to deliver to the immigration officers at the port of arrival typewritten or printed lists or manifests of the persons on board such vessel or aircraft. Such lists or manifests shall be prepared at such time, be in such form and shall contain such information as the Attorney General shall prescribe by regulation as being necessary for the identification of the persons transported and for the enforcement of the immigration laws. This subsection shall not require the master or commanding officer, or authorized agent, owner, or consignee of a vessel or aircraft to furnish a list or manifest relating (1) to an alien crewman or (2) to any other person arriving by air on a trip originating in foreign contiguous territory, except (with respect to such arrivals by air) as may be required by regulations issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1224">section 1224 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/s115/b">Pub. L. 107–77, § 115(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “It shall be the duty of the master or commanding officer or authorized agent of every vessel or aircraft taking passengers on board at any port of the United States, who are destined to any place outside the United States, to file with the immigration officers before departure from such port a list of all such persons taken on board. Such list shall be in such form, contain such information, and be accompanied by such documents, as the Attorney General shall prescribe by regulation as necessary for the identification of the persons so transported and for the enforcement of the immigration laws. No master or commanding officer of any such vessel or aircraft shall be granted clearance papers for his vessel or aircraft until he or the authorized agent has deposited such list or lists and accompanying documents with the immigration officer at such port and made oath that they are full and complete as to the information required to be contained therein, except that in the case of vessels or aircraft which the Attorney General determines are making regular trips to ports of the United States, the Attorney General may, when expedient, arrange for the delivery of lists of outgoing persons at a later date. This subsection shall not require the master or commanding officer, or authorized agent, owner, or consignee of a vessel or aircraft to furnish a list or manifest relating (1) to an alien crewman or (2) to any other person departing by air on a trip originating in the United States who is destined to foreign contiguous territory, except (with respect to such departure by air) as may be required by regulations issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1224">section 1224 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/s115/c">Pub. L. 107–77, § 115(c)</ref>, directed amendment of heading by substituting “shipments, aircraft or carriers” for “shipments or aircraft” and, in text inserted “, any public or private carrier,” after “or aircraft,” in first sentence and substituted “vessel, aircraft, train or bus” for “vessel or aircraft” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> substituted “section 1224” for “section 1229”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> substituted “Commissioner” for “collector of customs” after “deposit with the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> substituted “Commissioner the sum of $300” for “collector of customs at the port of arrival or departure the sum of $10”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> substituted “subsection” for “subsections”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c0f123b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f123c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/173/tIV/s402/c">Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/559">116 Stat. 559</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/173/tIV/s402/c">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to persons arriving in, or departing from, the United States on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f123d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f123e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s310/1">section 310(1) of Pub. L. 102–232</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f123f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s543/c">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 543(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5059">104 Stat. 5059</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s543/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and sections 1227, 1229, 1282, 1284 to 1287, 1321 to 1323, and 1325 to 1328 of this title] shall apply to actions taken after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c0f1240-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c0f1241-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c0f1242-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension to Land Carriers</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/173/tIV/s402/b">Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/559">116 Stat. 559</ref>, directed the President to conduct a study, to be reported to Congress within 2 years after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, regarding the feasibility of extending the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section to any commercial carrier transporting persons by land to or from the United States, with a focus on the manner in which such requirement would be implemented to enhance the national security of the United States and the efficient cross-border flow of commerce and persons.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
