<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c115ba9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a"><num value="1225a">§ 1225a.</num><heading> Preinspection at foreign airports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c115baa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of preinspection stations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c115bab-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">New stations</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (5), not later than <date date="1998-10-31">October 31, 1998</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish and maintain preinspection stations in at least 5 of the foreign airports that are among the 10 foreign airports which the Attorney General identifies as serving as last points of departure for the greatest numbers of inadmissible alien passengers who arrive from abroad by air at ports of entry within the United States. Such preinspection stations shall be in addition to any preinspection stations established prior to <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c115bac-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1998-10-31">October 31, 1998</date>, the Attorney General shall report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate on the implementation of paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c115bad-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data collection</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="1997-11-01">November 1, 1997</date>, and each subsequent November 1, the Attorney General shall compile data identifying—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115bae-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the foreign airports which served as last points of departure for aliens who arrived by air at United States ports of entry without valid documentation during the preceding fiscal years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115baf-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number and nationality of such aliens arriving from each such foreign airport; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115bb0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the primary routes such aliens followed from their country of origin to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c115bb1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (5), not later than <date date="2008-01-01">January 1, 2008</date>, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish preinspection stations in at least 25 additional foreign airports, which the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines, based on the data compiled under paragraph (3) and such other information as may be available, would most effectively facilitate the travel of admissible aliens and reduce the number of inadmissible aliens, especially aliens who are potential terrorists, who arrive from abroad by air at points of entry within the United States. Such preinspection stations shall be in addition to those established before <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>, or pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c115bb2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Prior to the establishment of a preinspection station, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115bb3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> employees of the United States stationed at the preinspection station and their accompanying family members will receive appropriate protection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115bb4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such employees and their families will not be subject to unreasonable risks to their welfare and safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c115bb5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the country in which the preinspection station is to be established maintains practices and procedures with respect to asylum seekers and refugees in accordance with the Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees (done at Geneva, <date date="1951-07-28">July 28, 1951</date>), or the Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees (done at New York, <date date="1967-01-31">January 31, 1967</date>), or that an alien in the country otherwise has recourse to avenues of protection from return to persecution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c115bb6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1225a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of carrier consultant program and immigration security initiative</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall assign additional immigration officers to assist air carriers in the detection of fraudulent documents at foreign airports which, based on the records maintained pursuant to subsection (a)(3), served as a point of departure for a significant number of arrivals at United States ports of entry without valid documentation, but where no preinspection station exists. Beginning not later than <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, the number of airports selected for an assignment under this subsection shall be at least 50.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c115bb7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 4, § 235A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tI/s123/a">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title I, § 123(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-560">110 Stat. 3009–560</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII</ref>, §§ 7206(a), 7210(d)(1), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3817">118 Stat. 3817</ref>, 3825.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c115bb8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c115bb9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c115bba-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original “the date of the enactment of such Act”, which was translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, which enacted this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c115bbb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s7210/d/1">Pub. L. 108–458, § 7210(d)(1)</ref>, amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “(4)<inline class="small-caps"> Additional stations</inline>.—Subject to paragraph (5), not later than <date date="2000-10-31">October 31, 2000</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish preinspection stations in at least 5 additional foreign airports which the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines, based on the data compiled under paragraph (3) and such other information as may be available, would most effectively reduce the number of aliens who arrive from abroad by air at points of entry within the United States who are inadmissible to the United States. Such preinspection stations shall be in addition to those established prior to <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>, or pursuant to paragraph (1).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s7206/a">Pub. L. 108–458, § 7206(a)</ref>, inserted “and immigration security initiative” after “program” in heading, substituted “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Attorney General” in text, and inserted at end “Beginning not later than <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, the number of airports selected for an assignment under this subsection shall be at least 50.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c115bbc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c115bbd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c115bbe-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exchange of Terrorist Information and Increased Preinspection at Foreign Airports</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7210/a">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7210(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3824">118 Stat. 3824</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7210/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Consistent with the report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The exchange of terrorist information with other countries, consistent with privacy requirements, along with listings of lost and stolen passports, will have immediate security benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The further away from the borders of the United States that screening occurs, the more security benefits the United States will gain.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Federal Government should exchange terrorist information with trusted allies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Federal Government should move toward real-time verification of passports with issuing authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> where practicable, the Federal Government should conduct screening before a passenger departs on a flight destined for the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Federal Government should work with other countries to ensure effective inspection regimes at all airports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the Federal Government should work with other countries to improve passport standards and provide foreign assistance to countries that need help making the transition to the global standard for identification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the Department of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Department of State and other Federal agencies, should implement the initiatives called for in this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
