<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c1d69e0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252"><num value="1252">§ 1252.</num><heading> Judicial review of orders of removal</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69e1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69e2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General orders of removal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Judicial review of a final order of removal (other than an order of removal without a hearing pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref>) is governed only by chapter 158 of title 28, except as provided in subsection (b) and except that the court may not order the taking of additional evidence under section 2347(c) of such title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69e3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Matters not subject to judicial review</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69e4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Review relating to section 1225(b)(1)</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, no court shall have jurisdiction to review—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69e5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (e), any individual determination or to entertain any other cause or claim arising from or relating to the implementation or operation of an order of removal pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref>,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69e6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (e), a decision by the Attorney General to invoke the provisions of such section,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69e7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the application of such section to individual aliens, including the determination made under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1/B">section 1225(b)(1)(B) of this title</ref>, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69e8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (e), procedures and policies adopted by the Attorney General to implement the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69e9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Denials of discretionary relief</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, and except as provided in subparagraph (D), and regardless of whether the judgment, decision, or action is made in removal proceedings, no court shall have jurisdiction to review—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69ea-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any judgment regarding the granting of relief under section 1182(h), 1182(i), 1229b, 1229c, or 1255 of this title, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d69eb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any other decision or action of the Attorney General or the Secretary of Homeland Security the authority for which is specified under this subchapter to be in the discretion of the Attorney General or the Secretary of Homeland Security, other than the granting of relief under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158/a">section 1158(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69ec-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders against criminal aliens</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, and except as provided in subparagraph (D), no court shall have jurisdiction to review any final order of removal against an alien who is removable by reason of having committed a criminal offense covered in section 1182(a)(2) or 1227(a)(2)(A)(iii), (B), (C), or (D) of this title, or any offense covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1227/a/2/A/ii">section 1227(a)(2)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> for which both predicate offenses are, without regard to their date of commission, otherwise covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1227/a/2/A/i">section 1227(a)(2)(A)(i) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69ed-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review of certain legal claims</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (B) or (C), or in any other provision of this chapter (other than this section) which limits or eliminates judicial review, shall be construed as precluding review of constitutional claims or questions of law raised upon a petition for review filed with an appropriate court of appeals in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69ee-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain decisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No alien shall have a right to appeal from a decision of an immigration judge which is based solely on a certification described in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a/c/1/B">section 1229a(c)(1)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69ef-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Claims under the United Nations Convention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, a petition for review filed with an appropriate court of appeals in accordance with this section shall be the sole and exclusive means for judicial review of any cause or claim under the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Forms of Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, except as provided in subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusive means of review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, a petition for review filed with an appropriate court of appeals in accordance with this section shall be the sole and exclusive means for judicial review of an order of removal entered or issued under any provision of this chapter, except as provided in subsection (e). For purposes of this chapter, in every provision that limits or eliminates judicial review or jurisdiction to review, the terms “judicial review” and “jurisdiction to review” include habeas corpus review pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, and review pursuant to any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for review of orders of removal</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to review of an order of removal under subsection (a)(1), the following requirements apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The petition for review must be filed not later than 30 days after the date of the final order of removal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Venue and forms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The petition for review shall be filed with the court of appeals for the judicial circuit in which the immigration judge completed the proceedings. The record and briefs do not have to be printed. The court of appeals shall review the proceeding on a typewritten record and on typewritten briefs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Service</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The respondent is the Attorney General. The petition shall be served on the Attorney General and on the officer or employee of the Service in charge of the Service district in which the final order of removal under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a">section 1229a of this title</ref> was entered.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Stay of order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Service of the petition on the officer or employee does not stay the removal of an alien pending the court’s decision on the petition, unless the court orders otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Alien’s brief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The alien shall serve and file a brief in connection with a petition for judicial review not later than 40 days after the date on which the administrative record is available, and may serve and file a reply brief not later than 14 days after service of the brief of the Attorney General, and the court may not extend these deadlines except upon motion for good cause shown. If an alien fails to file a brief within the time provided in this paragraph, the court shall dismiss the appeal unless a manifest injustice would result.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69f8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope and standard for review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (5)(B)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d69f9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the court of appeals shall decide the petition only on the administrative record on which the order of removal is based,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d69fa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the administrative findings of fact are conclusive unless any reasonable adjudicator would be compelled to conclude to the contrary,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d69fb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a decision that an alien is not eligible for admission to the United States is conclusive unless manifestly contrary to law, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d69fc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the Attorney General’s discretionary judgment whether to grant relief under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158/a">section 1158(a) of this title</ref> shall be conclusive unless manifestly contrary to the law and an abuse of discretion.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">No court shall reverse a determination made by a trier of fact with respect to the availability of corroborating evidence, as described in section 1158(b)(1)(B), 1229a(c)(4)(B), or 1231(b)(3)(C) of this title, unless the court finds, pursuant to subsection (b)(4)(B), that a reasonable trier of fact is compelled to conclude that such corroborating evidence is unavailable.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69fd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of nationality claims</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69fe-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Court determination if no issue of fact</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the petitioner claims to be a national of the United States and the court of appeals finds from the pleadings and affidavits that no genuine issue of material fact about the petitioner’s nationality is presented, the court shall decide the nationality claim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d69ff-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer if issue of fact</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the petitioner claims to be a national of the United States and the court of appeals finds that a genuine issue of material fact about the petitioner’s nationality is presented, the court shall transfer the proceeding to the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the petitioner resides for a new hearing on the nationality claim and a decision on that claim as if an action had been brought in the district court under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2201">section 2201 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a00-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The petitioner may have such nationality claim decided only as provided in this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a01-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Consolidation with review of motions to reopen or reconsider</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">When a petitioner seeks review of an order under this section, any review sought of a motion to reopen or reconsider the order shall be consolidated with the review of the order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a02-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Challenge to validity of orders in certain criminal proceedings</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a03-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the validity of an order of removal has not been judicially decided, a defendant in a criminal proceeding charged with violating <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1253/a">section 1253(a) of this title</ref> may challenge the validity of the order in the criminal proceeding only by filing a separate motion before trial. The district court, without a jury, shall decide the motion before trial.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a04-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Claims of United States nationality</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the defendant claims in the motion to be a national of the United States and the district court finds that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d6a05-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no genuine issue of material fact about the defendant’s nationality is presented, the court shall decide the motion only on the administrative record on which the removal order is based and the administrative findings of fact are conclusive if supported by reasonable, substantial, and probative evidence on the record considered as a whole; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d6a06-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a genuine issue of material fact about the defendant’s nationality is presented, the court shall hold a new hearing on the nationality claim and decide that claim as if an action had been brought under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2201">section 2201 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The defendant may have such nationality claim decided only as provided in this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a07-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Consequence of invalidation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the district court rules that the removal order is invalid, the court shall dismiss the indictment for violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1253/a">section 1253(a) of this title</ref>. The United States Government may appeal the dismissal to the court of appeals for the appropriate circuit within 30 days after the date of the dismissal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a08-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on filing petitions for review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The defendant in a criminal proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1253/a">section 1253(a) of this title</ref> may not file a petition for review under subsection (a) during the criminal proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a09-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a0a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> does not prevent the Attorney General, after a final order of removal has been issued, from detaining the alien under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1231/a">section 1231(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a0b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not relieve the alien from complying with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1231/a/4">section 1231(a)(4) of this title</ref> and section 1253(g) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002055">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002055"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a0c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not require the Attorney General to defer removal of the alien.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a0d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/b/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Consolidation of questions for judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Judicial review of all questions of law and fact, including interpretation and application of constitutional and statutory provisions, arising from any action taken or proceeding brought to remove an alien from the United States under this subchapter shall be available only in judicial review of a final order under this section. Except as otherwise provided in this section, no court shall have jurisdiction, by habeas corpus under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref> or any other habeas corpus provision, by section 1361 or 1651 of such title, or by any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), to review such an order or such questions of law or fact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a0e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for petition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A petition for review or for habeas corpus of an order of removal—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c1d6a0f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall attach a copy of such order, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c1d6a10-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall state whether a court has upheld the validity of the order, and, if so, shall state the name of the court, the date of the court’s ruling, and the kind of proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a11-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of final orders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A court may review a final order of removal only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c1d6a12-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the alien has exhausted all administrative remedies available to the alien as of right, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c1d6a13-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> another court has not decided the validity of the order, unless the reviewing court finds that the petition presents grounds that could not have been presented in the prior judicial proceeding or that the remedy provided by the prior proceeding was inadequate or ineffective to test the validity of the order.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a14-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review of orders under section 1225(b)(1)</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a15-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on relief</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Without regard to the nature of the action or claim and without regard to the identity of the party or parties bringing the action, no court may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a16-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enter declaratory, injunctive, or other equitable relief in any action pertaining to an order to exclude an alien in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref> except as specifically authorized in a subsequent paragraph of this subsection, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a17-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> certify a class under Rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure in any action for which judicial review is authorized under a subsequent paragraph of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a18-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Habeas corpus proceedings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Judicial review of any determination made under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref> is available in habeas corpus proceedings, but shall be limited to determinations of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a19-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whether the petitioner is an alien,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a1a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whether the petitioner was ordered removed under such section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a1b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whether the petitioner can prove by a preponderance of the evidence that the petitioner is an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, has been admitted as a refugee under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">section 1157 of this title</ref>, or has been granted asylum under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158">section 1158 of this title</ref>, such status not having been terminated, and is entitled to such further inquiry as prescribed by the Attorney General pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1/C">section 1225(b)(1)(C) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a1c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Challenges on validity of the system</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a1d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Judicial review of determinations under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b">section 1225(b) of this title</ref> and its implementation is available in an action instituted in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, but shall be limited to determinations of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d6a1e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> whether such section, or any regulation issued to implement such section, is constitutional; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c1d6a1f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> whether such a regulation, or a written policy directive, written policy guideline, or written procedure issued by or under the authority of the Attorney General to implement such section, is not consistent with applicable provisions of this subchapter or is otherwise in violation of law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a20-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadlines for bringing actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any action instituted under this paragraph must be filed no later than 60 days after the date the challenged section, regulation, directive, guideline, or procedure described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) is first implemented.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a21-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of appeal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A notice of appeal of an order issued by the District Court under this paragraph may be filed not later than 30 days after the date of issuance of such order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a22-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Expeditious consideration of cases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">It shall be the duty of the District Court, the Court of Appeals, and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any case considered under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1d6a23-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Decision</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any case where the court determines that the petitioner—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a24-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is an alien who was not ordered removed under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c1d6a25-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has demonstrated by a preponderance of the evidence that the alien is an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, has been admitted as a refugee under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">section 1157 of this title</ref>, or has been granted asylum under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158">section 1158 of this title</ref>, the court may order no remedy or relief other than to require that the petitioner be provided a hearing in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a">section 1229a of this title</ref>. Any alien who is provided a hearing under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a">section 1229a of this title</ref> pursuant to this paragraph may thereafter obtain judicial review of any resulting final order of removal pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb316-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of inquiry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In determining whether an alien has been ordered removed under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/1">section 1225(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the court’s inquiry shall be limited to whether such an order in fact was issued and whether it relates to the petitioner. There shall be no review of whether the alien is actually inadmissible or entitled to any relief from removal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb317-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Limit on injunctive relief</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb318-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regardless of the nature of the action or claim or of the identity of the party or parties bringing the action, no court (other than the Supreme Court) shall have jurisdiction or authority to enjoin or restrain the operation of the provisions of part IV of this subchapter, as amended by the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996, other than with respect to the application of such provisions to an individual alien against whom proceedings under such part have been initiated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb319-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Particular cases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court shall enjoin the removal of any alien pursuant to a final order under this section unless the alien shows by clear and convincing evidence that the entry or execution of such order is prohibited as a matter of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb31a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an action brought pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1225/b/3">section 1225(b)(3) of this title</ref>, subsections (e) or (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1226">section 1226 of this title</ref>, or <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1231/a/2/B">section 1231(a)(2)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c1fb31b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1252/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusive jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in this section and notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, no court shall have jurisdiction to hear any cause or claim by or on behalf of any alien arising from the decision or action by the Attorney General to commence proceedings, adjudicate cases, or execute removal orders against any alien under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c1fb31c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 5, § 242, <ref href="/us/stat/66/208">66 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s17">Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 17</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1232">68 Stat. 1232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/h/1">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1620">95 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s220/b">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 220(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2028">98 Stat. 2028</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/603/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 99–603, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3445">100 Stat. 3445</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/n">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(n)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2620">102 Stat. 2620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7343/a">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7343(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4470">102 Stat. 4470</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV">Pub. L. 101–649, title V</ref>, §§ 504(a), 545(e), title VI, § 603(b)(2), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5049">104 Stat. 5049</ref>, 5066, 5085; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII">Pub. L. 102–232, title III</ref>, §§ 306(a)(4), (c)(7), 307(m)(2), 309(b)(9), <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1751">105 Stat. 1751</ref>, 1753, 1757, 1759; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tII/s20301/a">Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20301(a)</ref>, title XIII, § 130001(a), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1823">108 Stat. 1823</ref>, 2023; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII">Pub. L. 103–416, title II</ref>, §§ 219(h), 224(b), <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4317">108 Stat. 4317</ref>, 4324; <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tIV">Pub. L. 104–132, title IV</ref>, §§ 436(a), (b)(1), 438(a), 440(c), (h), <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1275">110 Stat. 1275</ref>, 1277, 1279; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 306(a), (d), 308(g)(10)(H), 371(b)(6), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-607">110 Stat. 3009–607</ref>, 3009–612, 3009–625, 3009–645; <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I</ref>, §§ 101(e), (f), 106(a), <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/305">119 Stat. 305</ref>, 310; <ref href="/us/pl/119/1/s3/f">Pub. L. 119–1, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-29">Jan. 29, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/5">139 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c1fb31d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c1fb31e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c1fb31f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2)(D), (5), and (g), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1253">Section 1253 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(8)(B), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s307/a">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-612">110 Stat. 3009–612</ref>, and, as so amended, no longer contains a subsec. (g). Provisions similar to those contained in former subsec. (g) of section 1253 are now contained in subsec. (d) of section 1253.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsec. (e)(1)(B), is set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-546">110 Stat. 3009–546</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1996 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c1fb320-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/1">Pub. L. 119–1</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/1/A/i">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “(statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title” after “Notwithstanding any other provision of law” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “(statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, and except as provided in subparagraph (D)” after “Notwithstanding any other provision of law” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s101/f/2">Pub. L. 109–13, § 101(f)(2)</ref>, inserted “and regardless of whether the judgment, decision, or action is made in removal proceedings,” before “no court shall” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s101/f/1">Pub. L. 109–13, § 101(f)(1)</ref>, inserted “or the Secretary of Homeland Security” after “Attorney General” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “(statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, and except as provided in subparagraph (D)” after “Notwithstanding any other provision of law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/1/B">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s101/e">Pub. L. 109–13, § 101(e)</ref>, added concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/2">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “Except as otherwise provided in this section, no court shall have jurisdiction, by habeas corpus under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref> or any other habeas corpus provision, by section 1361 or 1651 of such title, or by any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), to review such an order or such questions of law or fact.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/13/s106/a/3">Pub. L. 109–13, § 106(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “(statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title” after “notwithstanding any other provision of law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s306/a/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 306(a)(2)</ref>, amended section generally, substituting subsecs. (a) to (g) relating to judicial review of orders of removal for former subsecs. (a) to (i) relating to apprehension and deportation of aliens.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/c/2">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(c)(2)</ref>, struck out subpar. (B) which read as follows: “The Attorney General may not release from custody any lawfully admitted alien who has been convicted of an aggravated felony, either before or after a determination of deportability, unless the alien demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that such alien is not a threat to the community and that the alien is likely to appear before any scheduled hearings.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/c/1/C">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(c)(1)(C)</ref>, struck out “but subject to subparagraph (B)” before “, the Attorney General shall not release”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/c/1/B">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(c)(1)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, §§ 306(d), 308(g)(10)(H), substituted “any criminal offense covered in section 1251(a)(2)(A)(iii), (B), (C), or (D) of this title, or any offense covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1227/a/2/A/ii">section 1227(a)(2)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> for which both predicate offenses are, without regard to the date of their commission, otherwise covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1227/a/2/A/i">section 1227(a)(2)(A)(i) of this title</ref>” for “an aggravated felony upon release of the alien (regardless of whether or not such release is on parole, supervised release, or probation, and regardless of the possibility of rearrest or further confinement in respect of the same offense)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/c/1/A">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “(2) The Attorney” for “(2)(A) The Attorney”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s371/b/6">Pub. L. 104–208, § 371(b)(6)</ref>, substituted “An immigration judge” for “A special inquiry officer”, “an immigration judge” for “a special inquiry officer” in two places, and “immigration judge” for “special inquiry officer” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s436/a">Pub. L. 104–132, § 436(a)</ref>, inserted before period at end of second sentence “; except that nothing in this subsection shall preclude the Attorney General from authorizing proceedings by electronic or telephonic media (with the consent of the alien) or, where waived or agreed to by the parties, in the absence of the alien”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/h/1">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(h)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions of subsec. (c) as par. (1) and substituted “Subject to paragraph (2), when a final order” for “When a final order”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/h/2">Pub. L. 104–132, § 440(h)(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, §§ 306(d), 308(g)(10)(H), added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s438/a">Pub. L. 104–132, § 438(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (h) generally, restating prior single par. as par. (1) and adding pars. (2) and (3) authorizing the Attorney General to deport an alien prior to the completion of a sentence of imprisonment and requiring notice to deported aliens of penalties for reentry.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s436/b/1">Pub. L. 104–132, § 436(b)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to create any substantive or procedural right or benefit that is legally enforceable by any party against the United States or its agencies or officers or any other person.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s306/a/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 306(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j) as subsec. (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1231">section 1231 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s224/b">Pub. L. 103–416, § 224(b)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252a/d">section 1252a(d) of this title</ref>, the” for “The” in ninth sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s130001/a">Pub. L. 103–322, § 130001(a)</ref>, struck out “paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of” before “<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1251/a">section 1251(a) of this title</ref>” and substituted “shall be imprisoned not more than four years, or shall be imprisoned not more than ten years if the alien is a member of any of the classes described in paragraph (1)(E), (2), (3), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1251/a">section 1251(a) of this title</ref>.” for “shall be imprisoned not more than ten years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s219/h">Pub. L. 103–416, § 219(h)</ref>, substituted “Parole,” for “Parole,,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s20301/a">Pub. L. 103–322, § 20301(a)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/a/4">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(a)(4)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “The Attorney General shall release from custody an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence on bond or such other conditions as the Attorney General may prescribe if the Attorney General determines that the alien is not a threat to the community and that the alien is likely to appear before any scheduled hearings.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/c/7">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(c)(7)</ref>, amended eighth sentence generally, substituting “Such regulations shall include requirements that are consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252b">section 1252b of this title</ref> and that provide that—” and pars. (1) to (4) for “Such regulations shall include requirements consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252b">section 1252b of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s307/m/2">Pub. L. 102–232, § 307(m)(2)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (2), (3), or (4)” for “paragraphs (4), (5), (6), (7), (11), (12), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), or (19)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s309/b/9">Pub. L. 102–232, § 309(b)(9)</ref>, inserted a comma after “Parole”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s504/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 504(a)</ref>, designated existing text as subpar. (A), substituted “upon release of the alien (regardless of whether or not such release is on parole, supervised release, or probation, and regardless of the possibility of rearrest or further confinement in respect of the same offense)” for “upon completion of the alien’s sentence for such conviction” and “Notwithstanding paragraph (1) or subsections (c) and (d) of this section but subject to subparagraph (B)” for “Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s603/b/2/A">Pub. L. 101–649, § 603(b)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “(2), (3), or (4)” for “(4), (5), (6), (7), (11), (12), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), or (19)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s545/e">Pub. L. 101–649, § 545(e)</ref>, amended eighth sentence generally. Prior to amendment, eighth sentence read as follows: “Such regulations shall include requirements that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the alien shall be given notice, reasonable under all the circumstances, of the nature of the charges against him and of the time and place at which the proceedings will be held;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the alien shall have the privilege of being represented (at no expense to the Government) by such counsel, authorized to practice in such proceedings, as he shall choose;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) the alien shall have a reasonable opportunity to examine the evidence against him, to present evidence in his own behalf, and to cross-examine witnesses presented by the Government; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) no decision of deportability shall be valid unless it is based upon reasonable, substantial, and probative evidence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s603/b/2/B">Pub. L. 101–649, § 603(b)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “paragraph (2), (3) or (4)” for “paragraph (4), (5), (6), (7), (11), (12), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), or (19)”, could not be executed because the quoted language differed from the text. See 1991 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), any” for “Any”, redesignated cls. (1) to (3) as (A) to (C), respectively, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> struck out “or from <date date="1950-09-23">September 23, 1950</date>, whichever is the later,” after “from the date of the final order of the court,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/603">Pub. L. 99–603</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, which directed that “supervised release,” be inserted after “parole,”, was executed by inserting “supervised release,” after “Parole,” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/h/1/A">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(h)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “(18), or (19)” for “or (18)” in provision following par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/h/1/B">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(h)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “(18), or (19)” for “or (18)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1954-09-03">Sept. 3, 1954</date>, struck out “shall upon conviction be guilty of a felony.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c1fb321-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb322-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s101/h/3">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I, § 101(h)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/305">119 Stat. 305</ref>, 306, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s101/h/3">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The amendment made by subsection (e) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this division [<date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>] and shall apply to all cases in which the final administrative removal order is or was issued before, on, or after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The amendments made by subsection (f) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this division [<date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>] and shall apply to all cases pending before any court on or after such date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/b">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I, § 106(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/311">119 Stat. 311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect upon the date of the enactment of this division [<date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>] and shall apply to cases in which the final administrative order of removal, deportation, or exclusion was issued before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this division.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb323-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s306/c">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 306(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-612">110 Stat. 3009–612</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/302/s2/1">Pub. L. 104–302, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3657">110 Stat. 3657</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/302/s2/1">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1231">section 1231 of this title</ref> and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1105a">section 1105a of this title</ref>] shall apply as provided under section 309 [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> note], except that subsection (g) of section 242 of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252/g">8 U.S.C. 1252(g)</ref>] (as added by subsection (a)), shall apply without limitation to claims arising from all past, pending, or future exclusion, deportation, or removal proceedings under such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall not be considered to invalidate or to require the reconsideration of any judgment or order entered under section 106 of the Immigration and Nationality Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1105a">8 U.S.C. 1105a</ref>], as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440">section 440 of Public Law 104–132</ref>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/104/302/s2">Pub. L. 104–302, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3657">110 Stat. 3657</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 2(1) to <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s306/c/1">section 306(c)(1) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out above, is effective <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s306/d">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 306(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-612">110 Stat. 3009–612</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 306(d) is effective as if included in the enactment of the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/132">Pub. L. 104–132</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/g/10/H">section 308(g)(10)(H) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s371/b/6">section 371(b)(6) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s371/d/1">section 371(d)(1) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delayed effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s440/c">section 440(c) of Pub. L. 104–132</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s303/b/2">section 303(b)(2) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1226">section 1226 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tIV/s436/b/3">Pub. L. 104–132, title IV, § 436(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1275">110 Stat. 1275</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/132/tIV/s436/b/3">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>] shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 (<ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Public Law 103–416</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb324-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s219/h">section 219(h) of Pub. L. 103–416</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s219/dd">section 219(dd) of Pub. L. 103–416</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s224/c">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 224(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4324">108 Stat. 4324</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s224/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252a">section 1252a of this title</ref>] shall apply to all aliens whose adjudication of guilt or guilty plea is entered in the record after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tII/s20301/b">Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20301(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1824">108 Stat. 1824</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/322/tII/s20301/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect <date date="1994-10-01">October 1, 1994</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb325-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 306(a)(4), (c)(7) of <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s310/1">section 310(1) of Pub. L. 102–232</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s307/m">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 307(m)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1757">105 Stat. 1757</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s307/m/2">section 307(m)(2) of Pub. L. 102–232</ref> is effective as if included in section 603(b) of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb326-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s504/c">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 504(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5050">104 Stat. 5050</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s504/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1226">section 1226 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s545/g">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 545(g)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5066">104 Stat. 5066</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s308/b/6/B">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 308(b)(6)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-623">110 Stat. 3009–623</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s308/b/6/B">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice-related provisions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e)(1) of section 242B of the Immigration and Nationality Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252b/a">8 U.S.C. 1252b(a)</ref>, (b), (c) and (e)(1)] (as inserted by the amendment made by subsection (a)), and the amendment made by subsection (e) [amending this section], shall be effective on a date specified by the Attorney General in the certification described in subparagraph (B), which date may not be earlier than 6 months after the date of such certification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Attorney General shall certify to the Congress when the central address file system (described in section 239(a)(4) [probably means 239(a)(3)] of the Immigration and Nationality Act) [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229/a/3">8 U.S.C. 1229(a)(3)</ref>] has been established.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Comptroller General shall submit to Congress, within 3 months after the date of the Attorney General’s certification under subparagraph (B), a report on the adequacy of such system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain limits on discretionary relief; sanctions for frivolous behavior</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsections (d), (e)(2), and (e)(3) of section 242B of the Immigration and Nationality Act (as inserted by the amendment made by subsection (a)) shall be effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limits on discretionary relief for failure to appear in asylum hearing</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (e)(4) of section 242B of the Immigration and Nationality Act (as inserted by the amendment made by subsection (a)) shall be effective on <date date="1991-02-01">February 1, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consolidation of relief in judicial review</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1105a">section 1105a of this title</ref>] shall apply to final orders of deportation entered on or after <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s603/b/2">section 603(b)(2) of Pub. L. 101–649</ref> not applicable to deportation proceedings for which notice has been provided to the alien before <date date="1991-03-01">Mar. 1, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s602/d">section 602(d) of Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1227">section 1227 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb327-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7343/c">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7343(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4470">102 Stat. 4470</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7343/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1254">section 1254 of this title</ref>] shall apply to any alien who has been convicted, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>], of an aggravated felony.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb328-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> effective <date date="1987-11-01">Nov. 1, 1987</date>, and applicable only to offenses committed after the taking effect of such amendment, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s235/a/1">section 235(a)(1) of Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3551">section 3551 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c1fb329-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s545/d">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 545(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5066">104 Stat. 5066</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s545/d">
<inline>“Within 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>], the Attorney General shall issue regulations with respect to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the period of time in which motions to reopen and to reconsider may be offered in deportation proceedings, which regulations include a limitation on the number of such motions that may be filed and a maximum time period for the filing of such motions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the time period for the filing of administrative appeals in deportation proceedings and for the filing of appellate and reply briefs, which regulations include a limitation on the number of administrative appeals that may be made, a maximum time period for the filing of such motions and briefs, the items to be included in the notice of appeal, and the consolidation of motions to reopen or to reconsider with the appeal of the order of deportation.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Cases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/c">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/311">119 Stat. 311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/c">“If an alien’s case, brought under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, United States Code, and challenging a final administrative order of removal, deportation, or exclusion, is pending in a district court on the date of the enactment of this division [<date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>], then the district court shall transfer the case (or the part of the case that challenges the order of removal, deportation, or exclusion) to the court of appeals for the circuit in which a petition for review could have been properly filed under section 242(b)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252">8 U.S.C. 1252</ref>), as amended by this section, or under section 309(c)(4)(D) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 [<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> note). The court of appeals shall treat the transferred case as if it had been filed pursuant to a petition for review under such section 242, except that subsection (b)(1) of such section shall not apply.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transitional Rule Cases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/d">Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title I, § 106(d)</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/311">119 Stat. 311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/13/dB/tI/s106/d">“A petition for review filed under former section 106(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1105a/a">8 U.S.C. 1105a(a)</ref>] (as in effect before its repeal by section 306(b) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 [<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252">8 U.S.C. 1252</ref> note)) shall be treated as if it had been filed as a petition for review under section 242 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1252">8 U.S.C. 1252</ref>), as amended by this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2241">section 2241 of title 28</ref>, United States Code, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, such petition for review shall be the sole and exclusive means for judicial review of an order of deportation or exclusion.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Order of Removal Deemed To Include Order of Exclusion and Deportation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out this chapter, any reference in law to an order of removal is deemed to include a reference to an order of exclusion and deportation or an order of deportation, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309/d/2">section 309(d)(2) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 1996 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c1fb32f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Accept Certain Assistance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXIII/s130008">Pub. L. 103–322, title XIII, § 130008</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2029">108 Stat. 2029</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/322/tXIII/s130008">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsection (b) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Attorney General, in the discretion of the Attorney General, may accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts of property and services (which may not include cash assistance) from State and local governments for the purpose of assisting the Immigration and Naturalization Service in the transportation of deportable aliens who are arrested for misdemeanor or felony crimes under State or Federal law and who are either unlawfully within the United States or willing to submit to voluntary departure under safeguards. Any property acquired pursuant to this section shall be acquired in the name of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General shall terminate or rescind the exercise of the authority under subsection (a) if the Attorney General determines that the exercise of such authority has resulted in discrimination by law enforcement officials on the basis of race, color, or national origin.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
