<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c2b99e0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1255b"><num value="1255b">§ 1255b.</num><heading> Adjustment of status of certain nonimmigrants to that of persons admitted for permanent residence</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c2b99e1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1255b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any alien admitted to the United States as a nonimmigrant under the provisions of either section 101(a)(15)(A)(i) or (ii) or 101(a)(15)(G)(i) or (ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15/A/i">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(A)(i)</ref>, (ii), (G)(i), (ii)], who has failed to maintain a status under any of those provisions, may apply to the Attorney General for adjustment of his status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c2b99e2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1255b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Record of admission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, after consultation with the Secretary of State, it shall appear to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that the alien has shown compelling reasons demonstrating both that the alien is unable to return to the country represented by the government which accredited the alien or the member of the alien’s immediate family and that adjustment of the alien’s status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence would be in the national interest, that the alien is a person of good moral character, that he is admissible for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.], and that such action would not be contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security, the Attorney General, in his discretion, may record the alien’s lawful admission for permanent residence as of the date the order of the Attorney General approving the application for adjustment of status is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c2b99e3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1255b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to the Congress; resolution not favoring adjustment of status; reduction of quota</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A complete and detailed statement of the facts and pertinent provisions of law in the case shall be reported to the Congress with the reasons for such adjustment of status. Such reports shall be submitted on the first day of each calendar month in which Congress is in session. The Secretary of State shall, if the alien was classifiable as a quota immigrant at the time of his entry, reduce by one the quota of the quota area to which the alien is chargeable under section 202 of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1152">8 U.S.C. 1152</ref>] for the fiscal year then current or the next following year in which a quota is available. No quota shall be so reduced by more than 50 per centum in any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c2b99e4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1255b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The number of aliens who may be granted the status of aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence in any fiscal year, pursuant to this section, shall not exceed fifty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c2b99e5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/316/s13">Pub. L. 85–316, § 13</ref>, <date date="1957-09-11">Sept. 11, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/642">71 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s17">Pub. L. 97–116, § 17</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1619">95 Stat. 1619</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/kk">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(kk)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2622">102 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s207">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4312">108 Stat. 4312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tVI/s671/b/4">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title VI, § 671(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-721">110 Stat. 3009–721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c2b99e6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c2b99e7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c2b99e8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Immigration and Nationality Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c2b99e9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as a part of the Immigration and Nationality Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c2b99ea-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s207/2">Pub. L. 103–416, § 207(2)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s207/1">Pub. L. 103–416, § 207(1)</ref>, struck out after second sentence “If, during the session of the Congress at which a case is reported, or prior to the close of the session of Congress next following the session at which a case is reported, either the Senate or the House of Representatives passes a resolution stating in substance that it does not favor the adjustment of status of such alien, the Attorney General shall thereupon require the departure of such alien in the manner provided by law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s207/2">Pub. L. 103–416, § 207(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, substituted “The” for “If neither the Senate nor the House of Representatives passes such a resolution within the time above specified, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> struck out “of” after “as of the date”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> inserted provision requiring that the alien has shown compelling reasons demonstrating both that the alien is unable to return to the country represented by the government which accredited the alien or the member of the alien’s immediate family and that adjustment of the alien’s status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence would be in the national interest.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c2b99eb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c2b99ec-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994, <ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s671/b/14">section 671(b)(14) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c2b99ed-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c2b99ee-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id9c2b99ef-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions; Applicability of Section 1101(a) and (b) of This Title</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions in subsecs. (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> apply to this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/316/s14">section 14 of Pub. L. 85–316</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
