<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c2b99f0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1256"><num value="1256">§ 1256.</num><heading> Rescission of adjustment of status; effect upon naturalized citizen</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c2b99f1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1256/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> If, at any time within five years after the status of a person has been otherwise adjusted under the provisions of section 1255 or 1259 of this title or any other provision of law to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, it shall appear to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that the person was not in fact eligible for such adjustment of status, the Attorney General shall rescind the action taken granting an adjustment of status to such person and cancelling removal in the case of such person if that occurred and the person shall thereupon be subject to all provisions of this chapter to the same extent as if the adjustment of status had not been made. Nothing in this subsection shall require the Attorney General to rescind the alien’s status prior to commencement of procedures to remove the alien under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a">section 1229a of this title</ref>, and an order of removal issued by an immigration judge shall be sufficient to rescind the alien’s status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c2b99f2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1256/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any person who has become a naturalized citizen of the United States upon the basis of a record of a lawful admission for permanent residence, created as a result of an adjustment of status for which such person was not in fact eligible, and which is subsequently rescinded under subsection (a) of this section, shall be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1451">section 1451 of this title</ref> as a person whose naturalization was procured by concealment of a material fact or by willful misrepresentation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c2b99f3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 5, § 246, <ref href="/us/stat/66/217">66 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s219/m">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 219(m)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4317">108 Stat. 4317</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 308(e)(1)(H), 378(a), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-619">110 Stat. 3009–619</ref>, 3009–649.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c2b99f4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c2b99f5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c2b99f6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c2b99f7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s378/a">Pub. L. 104–208, § 378(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Nothing in this subsection shall require the Attorney General to rescind the alien’s status prior to commencement of procedures to remove the alien under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1229a">section 1229a of this title</ref>, and an order of removal issued by an immigration judge shall be sufficient to rescind the alien’s status.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/1/H">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(1)(H)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref> struck out first three sentences which read as follows: “If, at any time within five years after the status of a person has been adjusted under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1254">section 1254 of this title</ref> or under section 19(c) of the Immigration Act of <date date="1917-02-05">February 5, 1917</date>, to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, it shall appear to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that the person was not in fact eligible for such adjustment of status, the Attorney General shall submit to the Congress a complete and detailed statement of the facts and pertinent provisions of law in the case. Such reports shall be submitted on the first and fifteenth day of each calendar month in which Congress is in session. If during the session of the Congress at which a case is reported, or prior to the close of the session of the Congress next following the session at which a case is reported, the Congress passes a concurrent resolution withdrawing suspension of deportation, the person shall thereupon be subject to all provisions of this chapter to the same extent as if the adjustment of status had not been made.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c2b99f8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c2b99f9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/1/H">section 308(e)(1)(H) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s378/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 378(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-649">110 Stat. 3009–649</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s378/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the title III–A effective date (as defined in section 309(a) of this division [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>]).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c2b99fa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s219/m">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 219(m)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4317">108 Stat. 4317</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 219(m) is effective as of <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c2b99fb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c2b99fc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Order of Removal Deemed To Include Order of Exclusion and Deportation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For purposes of carrying out this chapter, any reference in law to an order of removal is deemed to include a reference to an order of exclusion and deportation or an order of deportation, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309/d/2">section 309(d)(2) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 1996 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
