<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c3780fe-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b"><num value="1324b">§ 1324b.</num><heading> Unfair immigration-related employment practices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c3780ff-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition of discrimination based on national origin or citizenship status</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378100-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It is an unfair immigration-related employment practice for a person or other entity to discriminate against any individual (other than an unauthorized alien, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a/h/3">section 1324a(h)(3) of this title</ref>) with respect to the hiring, or recruitment or referral for a fee, of the individual for employment or the discharging of the individual from employment—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378101-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> because of such individual’s national origin, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378102-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a protected individual (as defined in paragraph (3)), because of such individual’s citizenship status.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378103-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378104-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a person or other entity that employs three or fewer employees,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378105-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a person’s or entity’s discrimination because of an individual’s national origin if the discrimination with respect to that person or entity and that individual is covered under section 703 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e–2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2</ref>], or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378106-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> discrimination because of citizenship status which is otherwise required in order to comply with law, regulation, or executive order, or required by Federal, State, or local government contract, or which the Attorney General determines to be essential for an employer to do business with an agency or department of the Federal, State, or local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378107-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> “Protected individual” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As used in paragraph (1), the term “protected individual” means an individual who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378108-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is a citizen or national of the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378109-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, is granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for temporary residence under section 1160(a) or 1255a(a)(1) of this title, is admitted as a refugee under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">section 1157 of this title</ref>, or is granted asylum under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158">section 1158 of this title</ref>; but does not include (i) an alien who fails to apply for naturalization within six months of the date the alien first becomes eligible (by virtue of period of lawful permanent residence) to apply for naturalization or, if later, within six months after <date date="1986-11-06">November 6, 1986</date>, and (ii) an alien who has applied on a timely basis, but has not been naturalized as a citizen within 2 years after the date of the application, unless the alien can establish that the alien is actively pursuing naturalization, except that time consumed in the Service’s processing the application shall not be counted toward the 2-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional exception providing right to prefer equally qualified citizens</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, it is not an unfair immigration-related employment practice for a person or other entity to prefer to hire, recruit, or refer an individual who is a citizen or national of the United States over another individual who is an alien if the two individuals are equally qualified.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition of intimidation or retaliation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It is also an unfair immigration-related employment practice for a person or other entity to intimidate, threaten, coerce, or retaliate against any individual for the purpose of interfering with any right or privilege secured under this section or because the individual intends to file or has filed a charge or a complaint, testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in an investigation, proceeding, or hearing under this section. An individual so intimidated, threatened, coerced, or retaliated against shall be considered, for purposes of subsections (d) and (g), to have been discriminated against.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain documentary practices as employment practices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person’s or other entity’s request, for purposes of satisfying the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a/b">section 1324a(b) of this title</ref>, for more or different documents than are required under such section or refusing to honor documents tendered that on their face reasonably appear to be genuine shall be treated as an unfair immigration-related employment practice if made for the purpose or with the intent of discriminating against an individual in violation of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges of violations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), any person alleging that the person is adversely affected directly by an unfair immigration-related employment practice (or a person on that person’s behalf) or an officer of the Service alleging that an unfair immigration-related employment practice has occurred or is occurring may file a charge respecting such practice or violation with the Special Counsel (appointed under subsection (c)). Charges shall be in writing under oath or affirmation and shall contain such information as the Attorney General requires. The Special Counsel by certified mail shall serve a notice of the charge (including the date, place, and circumstances of the alleged unfair immigration-related employment practice) on the person or entity involved within 10 days.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37810f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> No overlap with EEOC complaints</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No charge may be filed respecting an unfair immigration-related employment practice described in subsection (a)(1)(A) if a charge with respect to that practice based on the same set of facts has been filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.], unless the charge is dismissed as being outside the scope of such title. No charge respecting an employment practice may be filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission under such title if a charge with respect to such practice based on the same set of facts has been filed under this subsection, unless the charge is dismissed under this section as being outside the scope of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378110-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Special Counsel</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378111-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Special Counsel for Immigration-Related Unfair Employment Practices (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Special Counsel”) within the Department of Justice to serve for a term of four years. In the case of a vacancy in the office of the Special Counsel the President may designate the officer or employee who shall act as Special Counsel during such vacancy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378112-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Special Counsel shall be responsible for investigation of charges and issuance of complaints under this section and in respect of the prosecution of all such complaints before administrative law judges and the exercise of certain functions under subsection (j)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378113-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Special Counsel is entitled to receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the rate now or hereafter provided for grade GS–17 of the General Schedule, under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378114-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional offices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Special Counsel, in accordance with regulations of the Attorney General, shall establish such regional offices as may be necessary to carry out his duties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378115-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation of charges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378116-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> By Special Counsel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Special Counsel shall investigate each charge received and, within 120 days of the date of the receipt of the charge, determine whether or not there is reasonable cause to believe that the charge is true and whether or not to bring a complaint with respect to the charge before an administrative law judge. The Special Counsel may, on his own initiative, conduct investigations respecting unfair immigration-related employment practices and, based on such an investigation and subject to paragraph (3), file a complaint before such a judge.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378117-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Private actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Special Counsel, after receiving such a charge respecting an unfair immigration-related employment practice which alleges knowing and intentional discriminatory activity or a pattern or practice of discriminatory activity, has not filed a complaint before an administrative law judge with respect to such charge within such 120-day period, the Special Counsel shall notify the person making the charge of the determination not to file such a complaint during such period and the person making the charge may (subject to paragraph (3)) file a complaint directly before such a judge within 90 days after the date of receipt of the notice. The Special Counsel’s failure to file such a complaint within such 120-day period shall not affect the right of the Special Counsel to investigate the charge or to bring a complaint before an administrative law judge during such 90-day period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378118-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Time limitations on complaints</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No complaint may be filed respecting any unfair immigration-related employment practice occurring more than 180 days prior to the date of the filing of the charge with the Special Counsel. This subparagraph shall not prevent the subsequent amending of a charge or complaint under subsection (e)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378119-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever a complaint is made that a person or entity has engaged in or is engaging in any such unfair immigration-related employment practice, an administrative law judge shall have power to issue and cause to be served upon such person or entity a copy of the complaint and a notice of hearing before the judge at a place therein fixed, not less than five days after the serving of the complaint. Any such complaint may be amended by the judge conducting the hearing, upon the motion of the party filing the complaint, in the judge’s discretion at any time prior to the issuance of an order based thereon. The person or entity so complained of shall have the right to file an answer to the original or amended complaint and to appear in person or otherwise and give testimony at the place and time fixed in the complaint.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Judges hearing cases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Hearings on complaints under this subsection shall be considered before administrative law judges who are specially designated by the Attorney General as having special training respecting employment discrimination and, to the extent practicable, before such judges who only consider cases under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Complainant as party</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person filing a charge with the Special Counsel respecting an unfair immigration-related employment practice shall be considered a party to any complaint before an administrative law judge respecting such practice and any subsequent appeal respecting that complaint. In the discretion of the judge conducting the hearing, any other person may be allowed to intervene in the proceeding and to present testimony.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Testimony and authority of hearing officers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Testimony</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The testimony taken by the administrative law judge shall be reduced to writing. Thereafter, the judge, in his discretion, upon notice may provide for the taking of further testimony or hear argument.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37811f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of administrative law judges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In conducting investigations and hearings under this subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002068">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002068"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> and in accordance with regulations of the Attorney General, the Special Counsel and administrative law judges shall have reasonable access to examine evidence of any person or entity being investigated. The administrative law judges by subpoena may compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence at any designated place or hearing. In case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena lawfully issued under this paragraph and upon application of the administrative law judge, an appropriate district court of the United States may issue an order requiring compliance with such subpoena and any failure to obey such order may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378120-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378121-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The administrative law judge shall issue and cause to be served on the parties to the proceeding an order, which shall be final unless appealed as provided under subsection (i).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378122-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders finding violations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378123-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If, upon the preponderance of the evidence, an administrative law judge determines that any person or entity named in the complaint has engaged in or is engaging in any such unfair immigration-related employment practice, then the judge shall state his findings of fact and shall issue and cause to be served on such person or entity an order which requires such person or entity to cease and desist from such unfair immigration-related employment practice.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378124-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Such an order also may require the person or entity—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378125-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to comply with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a/b">section 1324a(b) of this title</ref> with respect to individuals hired (or recruited or referred for employment for a fee) during a period of up to three years;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378126-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to retain for the period referred to in clause (i) and only for purposes consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a/b/5">section 1324a(b)(5) of this title</ref>, the name and address of each individual who applies, in person or in writing, for hiring for an existing position, or for recruiting or referring for a fee, for employment in the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378127-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to hire individuals directly and adversely affected, with or without back pay;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378128-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378129-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> except as provided in subclauses (II) through (IV), to pay a civil penalty of not less than $250 and not more than $2,000 for each individual discriminated against,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> except as provided in subclauses (III) and (IV), in the case of a person or entity previously subject to a single order under this paragraph, to pay a civil penalty of not less than $2,000 and not more than $5,000 for each individual discriminated against,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> except as provided in subclause (IV), in the case of a person or entity previously subject to more than one order under this paragraph, to pay a civil penalty of not less than $3,000 and not more than $10,000 for each individual discriminated against, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/iv/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> in the case of an unfair immigration-related employment practice described in subsection (a)(6), to pay a civil penalty of not less than $100 and not more than $1,000 for each individual discriminated against;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> to post notices to employees about their rights under this section and employers’ obligations under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> to educate all personnel involved in hiring and complying with this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref> about the requirements of this section or such section;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c37812f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> to remove (in an appropriate case) a false performance review or false warning from an employee’s personnel file; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9c378130-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> to lift (in an appropriate case) any restrictions on an employee’s assignments, work shifts, or movements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378131-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on back pay remedy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In providing a remedy under subparagraph (B)(iii), back pay liability shall not accrue from a date more than two years prior to the date of the filing of a charge with the Special Counsel. Interim earnings or amounts earnable with reasonable diligence by the individual or individuals discriminated against shall operate to reduce the back pay otherwise allowable under such paragraph. No order shall require the hiring of an individual as an employee or the payment to an individual of any back pay, if the individual was refused employment for any reason other than discrimination on account of national origin or citizenship status.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378132-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of distinct entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In applying this subsection in the case of a person or entity composed of distinct, physically separate subdivisions each of which provides separately for the hiring, recruiting, or referring for employment, without reference to the practices of, and not under the control of or common control with, another subdivision, each such subdivision shall be considered a separate person or entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378133-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders not finding violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If upon the preponderance of the evidence an administrative law judge determines that the person or entity named in the complaint has not engaged and is not engaging in any such unfair immigration-related employment practice, then the judge shall state his findings of fact and shall issue an order dismissing the complaint.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378134-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Awarding of attorney’s fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any complaint respecting an unfair immigration-related employment practice, an administrative law judge, in the judge’s discretion, may allow a prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee, if the losing party’s argument is without reasonable foundation in law and fact.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378135-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of final orders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378136-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the entry of such final order, any person aggrieved by such final order may seek a review of such order in the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the violation is alleged to have occurred or in which the employer resides or transacts business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378137-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Further review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the filing of the record with the court, the jurisdiction of the court shall be exclusive and its judgment shall be final, except that the same shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon writ of certiorari or certification as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378138-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Court enforcement of administrative orders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378139-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an order of the agency is not appealed under subsection (i)(1), the Special Counsel (or, if the Special Counsel fails to act, the person filing the charge) may petition the United States district court for the district in which a violation of the order is alleged to have occurred, or in which the respondent resides or transacts business, for the enforcement of the order of the administrative law judge, by filing in such court a written petition praying that such order be enforced.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37813a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Court enforcement order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the filing of such petition, the court shall have jurisdiction to make and enter a decree enforcing the order of the administrative law judge. In such a proceeding, the order of the administrative law judge shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37813b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement decree in original review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, upon appeal of an order under subsection (i)(1), the United States court of appeals does not reverse such order, such court shall have the jurisdiction to make and enter a decree enforcing the order of the administrative law judge.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37813c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Awarding of attorney’s fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any judicial proceeding under subsection (i) or this subsection, the court, in its discretion, may allow a prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of costs but only if the losing party’s argument is without reasonable foundation in law and fact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c37813d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination dates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c37813e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> This section shall not apply to discrimination in hiring, recruiting, or referring, or discharging of individuals occurring after the date of any termination of the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref>, under subsection (<i>l</i>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002069">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002069"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c37813f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The provisions of this section shall terminate 30 calendar days after receipt of the last report required to be transmitted under section 1324a(j) <sup>2</sup> of this title if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c378140-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the Comptroller General determines, and so reports in such report that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378141-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no significant discrimination has resulted, against citizens or nationals of the United States or against any eligible workers seeking employment, from the implementation of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref>, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9c378142-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such section has created an unreasonable burden on employers hiring such workers; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c378143-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there has been enacted, within such period of 30 calendar days, a joint resolution stating in substance that the Congress approves the findings of the Comptroller General contained in such report.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The provisions of subsections (m) and (n) <sup>2</sup> of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref> shall apply to any joint resolution under subparagraph (B) in the same manner as they apply to a joint resolution under subsection (<i>l</i>) <sup>2</sup> of such section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c378144-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Dissemination of information concerning anti-discrimination provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c378145-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 3 months after <date date="1990-11-29">November 29, 1990</date>, the Special Counsel, in cooperation with the chairman of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Secretary of Labor, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall conduct a campaign to disseminate information respecting the rights and remedies prescribed under this section and under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.] in connection with unfair immigration-related employment practices. Such campaign shall be aimed at increasing the knowledge of employers, employees, and the general public concerning employer and employee rights, responsibilities, and remedies under this section and such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c378146-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In order to carry out the campaign under this subsection, the Special Counsel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c378147-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may, to the extent deemed appropriate and subject to the availability of appropriations, contract with public and private organizations for outreach activities under the campaign, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c378148-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall consult with the Secretary of Labor, the chairman of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and the heads of such other agencies as may be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c378149-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1324b/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for each fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 1991).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c37814a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 8, § 274B, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 99–603, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3374">100 Stat. 3374</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2610">102 Stat. 2610</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV">Pub. L. 101–649, title V</ref>, §§ 531, 532(a), 533(a), 534(a), 535(a), 536(a), 537(a), 539(a), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5054-5056">104 Stat. 5054–5056</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s306/b/1">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 306(b)(1)</ref>, (3), (c)(1), <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1752">105 Stat. 1752</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s219/q">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 219(q)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4317">108 Stat. 4317</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIV/s421/a">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title IV, § 421(a)</ref>, title VI, § 671(d)(1)(B), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-670">110 Stat. 3009–670</ref>, 3009–723.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c37814b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c37814c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c37814d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Civil Rights Act of 1964, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2) and (<i>l</i>)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/352">Pub. L. 88–352</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/241">78 Stat. 241</ref>. Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 is classified generally to subchapter VI (§ 2000e et seq.) of chapter 21 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000a">section 2000a of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsections (j), (<i>l</i>), (m), and (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a">section 1324a of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (k), were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIV/s412/c">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title IV, § 412(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-668">110 Stat. 3009–668</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c37814e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s671/d/1/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 671(d)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “, 1161(a),” after “section 1160(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s421/a">Pub. L. 104–208, § 421(a)</ref>, substituted “A person’s” for “For purposes of paragraph (1), a person’s” and “if made for the purpose or with the intent of discriminating against an individual in violation of paragraph (1)” for “relating to the hiring of individuals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref> substituted “the Special Counsel” for “an administrative law judge” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(iv)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/b/1">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “subclauses (III) and (IV)” for “subclause (IV)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(iv)(IV). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/b/3/A">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(b)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted a semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(v), (vi). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/b/3/B">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(b)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted semicolons for commas at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(vii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/b/3/C">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(b)(3)(C)</ref>, (D), substituted a semicolon for comma at end and “to remove (in an appropriate case)” for “to order (in an appropriate case) the removal of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/b/3/E">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(b)(3)(E)</ref>, substituted “to lift (in an appropriate case)” for “to order (in an appropriate case) the lifting of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s306/c/1">Pub. L. 102–232, § 306(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “physically” for “physicially”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s533/a/1">Pub. L. 101–649, § 533(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “protected individual” for “citizen or intending citizen”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s533/a/2">Pub. L. 101–649, § 533(a)(2)</ref>, (3), in heading and text substituted “protected individual” for “citizen or intending citizen”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s533/a/4">Pub. L. 101–649, § 533(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “is an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, is granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for temporary residence under section 1160(a), 1161(a), or 1255a(a)(1) of this title, is admitted as a refugee under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">section 1157 of this title</ref>, or is granted asylum under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158">section 1158 of this title</ref>; but does not” for “is an alien who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, is granted the status of an alien lawfully admitted for temporary residence under section 1160(a), 1161(a), or 1255a(a)(1) of this title, is admitted as a refugee under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">section 1157 of this title</ref>, or is granted asylum under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1158">section 1158 of this title</ref>, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) evidences an intention to become a citizen of the United States through completing a declaration of intention to become a citizen;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">but does not”, and in closing provisions substituted “(i)” and “(ii)” for “(I)” and “(II)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s532/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 532(a)</ref>, inserted reference to sections 1160(a) and 1161(a) of this title in cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s534/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 534(a)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s535/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 535(a)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s537/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 537(a)</ref>, inserted “the Special Counsel shall notify the person making the charge of the determination not to file such a complaint during such period and” after “120-day period,”, inserted “within 90 days after the date of receipt of the notice” before period at end, and inserted at end “The Special Counsel’s failure to file such a complaint within such 120-day period shall not affect the right of the Special Counsel to investigate the charge or to bring a complaint before an administrative law judge during such 90-day period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s539/a/1">Pub. L. 101–649, § 539(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s539/a/2">Pub. L. 101–649, § 539(a)(2)</ref>, which directed the substitution of a comma for the period at end of cl. (iv)(II), could not be executed because of the general amendment of cl. (iv) by <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s536/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 536(a)</ref>, see below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s536/a">Pub. L. 101–649, § 536(a)</ref>, amended cl. (iv) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (iv) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(I) except as provided in subclause (II), to pay a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each individual discriminated against, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(II) in the case of a person or entity previously subject to such an order, to pay a civil penalty of not more than $2,000 for each individual discriminated against.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(v) to (viii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s539/a/3">Pub. L. 101–649, § 539(a)(3)</ref>, added cls. (v) to (viii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s531">Pub. L. 101–649, § 531</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324a/h/3">section 1324a(h)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “said” before “proceeding”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “that” for “that that”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/4">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “1324a” for “1324”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/5">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “engaged and” for “engaged or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/b/6">Pub. L. 100–525, § 2(b)(6)</ref>, substituted “attorney’s” for “attorneys’ ” in heading.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c37814f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c378150-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIV/s421/b">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title IV, § 421(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-670">110 Stat. 3009–670</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIV/s421/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to requests made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c378151-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/s219/dd">section 219(dd) of Pub. L. 103–416</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c378152-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s310/1">section 310(1) of Pub. L. 102–232</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c378153-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s532/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5054">104 Stat. 5054</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s532/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to actions occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s533/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 533(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5055">104 Stat. 5055</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s533/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to unfair immigration-related employment practices occurring before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s534/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 534(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5055">104 Stat. 5055</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s534/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to actions occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s535/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 535(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5055">104 Stat. 5055</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s535/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>], but shall apply to actions occurring on or after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s536/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 536(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5056">104 Stat. 5056</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s536/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to unfair immigration-related employment practices occurring after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s537/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 537(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5056">104 Stat. 5056</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s537/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to charges received on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s539/b">Pub. L. 101–649, title V, § 539(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5057">104 Stat. 5057</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/649/tV/s539/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to orders with respect to unfair immigration-related employment practices occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c378154-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> effective as if included in enactment of Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/603">Pub. L. 99–603</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s2/s">section 2(s) of Pub. L. 100–525</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c378155-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c378156-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c378157-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">No Effect on EEOC Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 99–603, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3379">100 Stat. 3379</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s102/b">“Except as may be specifically provided in this section, nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the authority of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to investigate allegations, in writing and under oath or affirmation, of unlawful employment practices, as provided in section 706 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e–5">42 U.S.C. 2000e–5</ref>), or any other authority provided therein.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
