<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c3c632a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1354"><num value="1354">§ 1354.</num><heading> Applicability to members of the Armed Forces</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c3c632b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1354/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed so as to limit, restrict, deny, or affect the coming into or departure from the United States of an alien member of the Armed Forces of the United States who is in the uniform of, or who bears documents identifying him as a member of, such Armed Forces, and who is coming to or departing from the United States under official orders or permit of such Armed Forces: <i>Provided,</i> That nothing contained in this section shall be construed to give to or confer upon any such alien any other privileges, rights, benefits, exemptions, or immunities under this chapter, which are not otherwise specifically granted by this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c3c632c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1354/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> If a person lawfully admitted for permanent residence is the spouse or child of a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, is authorized to accompany the member and reside abroad with the member pursuant to the member’s official orders, and is so accompanying and residing with the member (in marital union if a spouse), then the residence and physical presence of the person abroad shall not be treated as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c3c632d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1354/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an abandonment or relinquishment of lawful permanent resident status for purposes of clause (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/13/C">section 1101(a)(13)(C) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c3c632e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1354/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an absence from the United States for purposes of clause (ii) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c3c632f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 9, § 284, <ref href="/us/stat/66/232">66 Stat. 232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVI/s673">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 673</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/185">122 Stat. 185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c3c6330-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c3c6331-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c3c6332-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c3c6333-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/181">Pub. L. 110–181</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
