<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c411e05-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1361"><num value="1361">§ 1361.</num><heading> Burden of proof upon alien</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever any person makes application for a visa or any other document required for entry, or makes application for admission, or otherwise attempts to enter the United States, the burden of proof shall be upon such person to establish that he is eligible to receive such visa or such document, or is not inadmissible under any provision of this chapter, and, if an alien, that he is entitled to the nonimmigrant, immigrant, special immigrant, immediate relative, or refugee status claimed, as the case may be. If such person fails to establish to the satisfaction of the consular officer that he is eligible to receive a visa or other document required for entry, no visa or other document required for entry shall be issued to such person, nor shall such person be admitted to the United States unless he establishes to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that he is not inadmissible under any provision of this chapter. In any removal proceeding under part IV of this subchapter against any person, the burden of proof shall be upon such person to show the time, place, and manner of his entry into the United States, but in presenting such proof he shall be entitled to the production of his visa or other entry document, if any, and of any other documents and records, not considered by the Attorney General to be confidential, pertaining to such entry in the custody of the Service. If such burden of proof is not sustained, such person shall be presumed to be in the United States in violation of law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id9c411e06-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title II, ch. 9, § 291, <ref href="/us/stat/66/234">66 Stat. 234</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/k/1">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1620">95 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tIII/s308/d/4/N">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 308(d)(4)(N)</ref>, (e)(1)(N), (g)(9)(A), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-618">110 Stat. 3009–618</ref>, 3009–619, 3009–624.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c411e07-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c411e08-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c411e09-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c411e0a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/g/9/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(g)(9)(A)</ref>, substituted “part IV” for “Part V”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/e/1/N">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(e)(1)(N)</ref>, substituted “removal” for “deportation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s308/d/4/N">Pub. L. 104–208, § 308(d)(4)(N)</ref>, substituted “inadmissible” for “subject to exclusion” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> substituted “immigrant, special immigrant, immediate relative, or refugee” for “quota immigrant, or nonquota immigrant”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c411e0b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c411e0c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective, with certain transitional provisions, on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s309">section 309 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c411e0d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c411e0e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
