<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c4a9427-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1382"><num value="1382">§ 1382.</num><heading> Acceptance and administration of gifts for immigration integration grants program</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services is authorized in fiscal year 2017, and in each fiscal year thereafter, to solicit, accept, administer, and utilize gifts, including donations of property, for the purpose of providing an immigrant integration grants program and related activities to promote citizenship and immigrant integration: <i> Provided</i>, That all sums received under this subsection shall be deposited in a separate account in the general fund of the Treasury to be known as the “Citizenship Gift and Bequest Account”: <i> Provided further</i>, That all funds deposited into the Citizenship Gift and Bequest Account shall remain available until expended, and shall be available in addition to any funds appropriated or otherwise made available for an immigrant integration grants program or other activities to promote citizenship and immigrant integration.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id9c4a9428-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dF/tIV/s404/c">Pub. L. 115–31, div. F, title IV, § 404(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/422">131 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c4a9429-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c4a942a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c4a942b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2017, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2017, and not as part of the Immigration and Nationality Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
