<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c4d0567-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406"><num value="1406">§ 1406.</num><heading> Persons living in and born in the Virgin Islands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d0568-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The following persons and their children born subsequent to <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>, and prior to February 25,1927, are declared to be citizens of the United States as of <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d0569-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> All former Danish citizens who, on <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>, resided in the Virgin Islands of the United States, and were residing in those islands or in the United States or Puerto Rico on <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, and who did not make the declaration required to preserve their Danish citizenship by article 6 of the treaty entered into on <date date="1916-08-04">August 4, 1916</date>, between the United States and Denmark, or who, having made such a declaration have heretofore renounced or may hereafter renounce it by a declaration before a court of record;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d056a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> All natives of the Virgin Islands of the United States who, on <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>, resided in those islands, and were residing in those islands or in the United States or Puerto Rico on <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, and who were not on <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, citizens or subjects of any foreign country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d056b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> All natives of the Virgin Islands of the United States who, on <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>, resided in the United States, and were residing in those islands on <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, and who were not on <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, citizens or subjects of any foreign country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d056c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> All natives of the Virgin Islands of the United States who, on <date date="1932-06-28">June 28, 1932</date>, were residing in continental United States, the Virgin Islands of the United States, Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, or any other insular possession or territory of the United States, and who, on <date date="1932-06-28">June 28, 1932</date>, were not citizens or subjects of any foreign country, regardless of their place of residence on <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d056d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1406/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> All persons born in the Virgin Islands of the United States on or after <date date="1917-01-17">January 17, 1917</date>, and prior to <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, and subject to the jurisdiction of the United States are declared to be citizens of the United States as of <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>; and all persons born in those islands on or after <date date="1927-02-25">February 25, 1927</date>, and subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, are declared to be citizens of the United States at birth.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c4d056e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title III, ch. 1, § 306, <ref href="/us/stat/66/237">66 Stat. 237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
