<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c4d05c8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423"><num value="1423">§ 1423.</num><heading> Requirements as to understanding the English language, history, principles and form of government of the United States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4d05c9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> No person except as otherwise provided in this subchapter shall hereafter be naturalized as a citizen of the United States upon his own application who cannot demonstrate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4d05ca-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an understanding of the English language, including an ability to read, write, and speak words in ordinary usage in the English language: <i>Provided</i>, That the requirements of this paragraph relating to ability to read and write shall be met if the applicant can read or write simple words and phrases to the end that a reasonable test of his literacy shall be made and that no extraordinary or unreasonable condition shall be imposed upon the applicant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75cb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a knowledge and understanding of the fundamentals of the history, and of the principles and form of government, of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75cc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75cd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The requirements of subsection (a) shall not apply to any person who is unable because of physical or developmental disability or mental impairment to comply therewith.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75ce-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The requirement of subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to any person who, on the date of the filing of the person’s application for naturalization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1445">section 1445 of this title</ref>, either—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75cf-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is over fifty years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least twenty years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75d0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is over fifty-five years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least fifteen years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75d1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Attorney General, pursuant to regulations, shall provide for special consideration, as determined by the Attorney General, concerning the requirement of subsection (a)(2) with respect to any person who, on the date of the filing of the person’s application for naturalization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1445">section 1445 of this title</ref>, is over sixty-five years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least twenty years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c4f75d2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title III, ch. 2, § 312, <ref href="/us/stat/66/239">66 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/579/s3">Pub. L. 95–579, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2474">92 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 101–649, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5039">104 Stat. 5039</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s305/m/2">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 305(m)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1750">105 Stat. 1750</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tI/s108/a">Pub. L. 103–416, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4309">108 Stat. 4309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c4f75d3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c4f75d4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c4f75d5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), struck out “this requirement shall not apply to any person physically unable to comply therewith, if otherwise qualified to be naturalized, or to any person who, on the date of the filing of his application for naturalization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1445">section 1445 of this title</ref>, either (A) is over 50 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 20 years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence, or (B) is over 55 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 15 years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence: <i>Provided further</i>, That”, after “<i>Provided</i>, That”, substituted “this paragraph” for “this section” after “requirements of”, and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> substituted “application” for “petition” in introductory provisions and par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> substituted “either (A) is over 50 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 20 years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence, or (B) is over 55 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 15 years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence” for “is over fifty years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least twenty years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/579">Pub. L. 95–579</ref> substituted “person who, on the date of the filing of his petition for naturalization as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1445">section 1445 of this title</ref>, is over fifty years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least twenty years subsequent to a lawful admission for permanent residence” for “person who, on the effective date of this chapter, is over fifty years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least twenty years”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c4f75d6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c4f75d7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tI/s108/c">Pub. L. 103–416, title I, § 108(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4310">108 Stat. 4310</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/416/tI/s108/c">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>] and shall apply to applications for naturalization filed on or after such date and to such applications pending on such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c4f75d8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s305/m">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 305(m)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1750">105 Stat. 1750</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 305(m) is effective as if included in section 407(d) of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c4f75d9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tI/s108/d">Pub. L. 103–416, title I, § 108(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4310">108 Stat. 4310</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/416/tI/s108/d">“Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>], the Attorney General shall promulgate regulations to carry out section 312(b)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1423/b/3">8 U.S.C. 1423(b)(3)</ref>] (as amended by subsection (a)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c4f75da-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c4f75db-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Hmong Veterans’ Naturalization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/207">Pub. L. 106–207</ref>, <date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/316">114 Stat. 316</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/415">Pub. L. 106–415</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1810">114 Stat. 1810</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/77/tI/s112">Pub. L. 107–77, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/765">115 Stat. 765</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/77/tI/s112">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Hmong Veterans’ Naturalization Act of 2000’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> EXEMPTION FROM ENGLISH LANGUAGE REQUIREMENT FOR CERTAIN ALIENS WHO SERVED WITH SPECIAL GUERRILLA UNITS OR IRREGULAR FORCES IN LAOS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The requirement of paragraph (1) of section 312(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1423/a/1">8 U.S.C. 1423(a)(1)</ref>) shall not apply to the naturalization of any person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was admitted into the United States as a refugee from Laos pursuant to section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> served with a special guerrilla unit, or irregular forces, operating from a base in Laos in support of the United States military at any time during the period beginning <date date="1961-02-28">February 28, 1961</date>, and ending <date date="1978-09-18">September 18, 1978</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> satisfies the requirement of paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> was the spouse of a person described in paragraph (1) on the day on which such described person applied for admission into the United States as a refugee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> satisfies the requirement of paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is the surviving spouse of a person described in paragraph (1)(B) which described person was killed or died in Laos, Thailand, or Vietnam.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> SPECIAL CONSIDERATION CONCERNING CIVICS REQUIREMENT FOR CERTAIN ALIENS WHO SERVED WITH SPECIAL GUERRILLA UNITS OR IRREGULAR FORCES IN LAOS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Attorney General shall provide for special consideration, as determined by the Attorney General, concerning the requirement of paragraph (2) of section 312(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1423/a/2">8 U.S.C. 1423(a)(2)</ref>) with respect to the naturalization of any person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 2 of this Act.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> DOCUMENTATION OF QUALIFYING SERVICE.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“A person seeking an exemption under section 2 or special consideration under section 3 shall submit to the Attorney General documentation of their, or their spouse’s, service with a special guerrilla unit, or irregular forces, described in section 2(1)(B), in the form of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> original documents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an affidavit of the serving person’s superior officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> two affidavits from other individuals who also were serving with such a special guerrilla unit, or irregular forces, and who personally knew of the person’s service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> other appropriate proof.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> DETERMINATION OF ELIGIBILITY FOR EXEMPTION AND SPECIAL CONSIDERATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> In determining a person’s eligibility for an exemption under section 2 or special consideration under section 3, the Attorney General—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall review the refugee processing documentation for the person, or, in an appropriate case, for the person and the person’s spouse, to verify that the requirements of section 2 relating to refugee applications and admissions have been satisfied;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall consider the documentation submitted by the person under section 4;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> may request an advisory opinion from the Secretary of Defense regarding the person’s, or their spouse’s, service in a special guerrilla unit, or irregular forces, described in section 2(1)(B); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> may consider any documentation provided by organizations maintaining records with respect to Hmong veterans or their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall provide any opinion requested under paragraph (3) to the extent practicable, and the Attorney General shall take into account any opinion that the Secretary of Defense is able to provide.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> DEADLINE FOR APPLICATION AND PAYMENT OF FEES.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act shall apply to a person only if the person’s application for naturalization is filed, as provided in section 334 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1445">8 U.S.C. 1445</ref>), with appropriate fees not later than 36 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-05-26">May 26, 2000</date>]. In the case of a person described in section 2(3), the application referred to in the preceding sentence, and appropriate fees, shall be filed not later than 36 months after the date of the enactment of this sentence [<date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>].</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> LIMITATION ON NUMBER OF BENEFICIARIES.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the total number of aliens who may be granted an exemption under section 2 or special consideration under section 3, or both, may not exceed 45,000.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
