<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c4f75dc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424"><num value="1424">§ 1424.</num><heading> Prohibition upon the naturalization of persons opposed to government or law, or who favor totalitarian forms of government</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75dd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 405(b) of this Act, no person shall hereafter be naturalized as a citizen of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75de-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who advocates or teaches, or who is a member of or affiliated with any organization that advocates or teaches, opposition to all organized government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75df-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> who is a member of or affiliated with (A) the Communist Party of the United States; (B) any other totalitarian party of the United States; (C) the Communist Political Association; (D) the Communist or other totalitarian party of any State of the United States, of any foreign state, or of any political or geographical subdivision of any foreign state; (E) any section, subsidiary, branch, affiliate, or subdivision of any such association or party; or (F) the direct predecessors or successors of any such association or party, regardless of what name such group or organization may have used, may now bear, or may hereafter adopt, unless such alien establishes that he did not have knowledge or reason to believe at the time he became a member of or affiliated with such an organization (and did not thereafter and prior to the date upon which such organization was so registered or so required to be registered have such knowledge or reason to believe) that such organization was a Communist-front organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> who, although not within any of the other provisions of this section, advocates the economic, international, and governmental doctrines of world communism or the establishment in the United States of a totalitarian dictatorship, or who is a member of or affiliated with any organization that advocates the economic, international, and governmental doctrines of world communism or the establishment in the United States of a totalitarian dictatorship, either through its own utterances or through any written or printed publications issued or published by or with the permission or consent of or under authority of such organization or paid for by the funds of such organization; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> who advocates or teaches or who is a member of or affiliated with any organization that advocates or teaches (A) the overthrow by force or violence or other unconstitutional means of the Government of the United States or of all forms of law; or (B) the duty, necessity, or propriety of the unlawful assaulting or killing of any officer or officers (either of specific individuals or of officers generally) of the Government of the United States or of any other organized government because of his or their official character; or (C) the unlawful damage, injury, or destruction of property; or (D) sabotage; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> who writes or publishes or causes to be written or published, or who knowingly circulates, distributes, prints, or displays, or knowingly causes to be circulated, distributed, printed, published, or displayed, or who knowingly has in his possession for the purpose of circulation, publication, distribution, or display, any written or printed matter, advocating or teaching opposition to all organized government, or advocating (A) the overthrow by force, violence or other unconstitutional means of the Government of the United States or of all forms of law; or (B) the duty, necessity, or propriety of the unlawful assaulting or killing of any officer or officers (either of specific individuals or of officers generally) of the Government of the United States or of any other organized government, because of his or their official character; or (C) the unlawful damage, injury, or destruction of property; or (D) sabotage; or (E) the economic, international, and governmental doctrines of world communism or the establishment in the United States of a totalitarian dictatorship; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> who is a member of or affiliated with any organization that writes, circulates, distributes, prints, publishes, or displays, or causes to be written, circulated, distributed, printed, published, or displayed, or that has in its possession for the purpose of circulation, distribution, publication, issue, or display, any written or printed matter of the character described in subparagraph (5) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75e4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The provisions of this section or of any other section of this chapter shall not be construed as declaring that any of the organizations referred to in this section or in any other section of this chapter do not advocate the overthrow of the Government of the United States by force, violence, or other unconstitutional means.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75e5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The provisions of this section shall be applicable to any applicant for naturalization who at any time within a period of ten years immediately preceding the filing of the application for naturalization or after such filing and before taking the final oath of citizenship is, or has been found to be within any of the classes enumerated within this section, notwithstanding that at the time the application is filed he may not be included within such classes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75e6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Any person who is within any of the classes described in subsection (a) solely because of past membership in, or past affiliation with, a party or organization may be naturalized without regard to the provisions of subsection (c) if such person establishes that such membership or affiliation is or was involuntary, or occurred and terminated prior to the attainment by such alien of the age of sixteen years, or that such membership or affiliation is or was by operation of law, or was for purposes of obtaining employment, food rations, or other essentials of living and where necessary for such purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c4f75e7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> A person may be naturalized under this subchapter without regard to the prohibitions in subsections (a)(2) and (c) of this section if the person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is otherwise eligible for naturalization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75e9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is within the class described in subsection (a)(2) solely because of past membership in, or past affiliation with, a party or organization described in that subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75ea-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> does not fall within any other of the classes described in that subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c4f75eb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1424/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> is determined by the Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense when Department of Defense activities are relevant to the determination, and with the concurrence of the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, to have made a contribution to the national security or to the national intelligence mission of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c4f75ec-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title III, ch. 2, § 313, <ref href="/us/stat/66/240">66 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/u">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(u)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2621">102 Stat. 2621</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tIV/s407/c/1">Pub. L. 101–649, title IV, § 407(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5041">104 Stat. 5041</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s309/b/13">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 309(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1759">105 Stat. 1759</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s219/v">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 219(v)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4318">108 Stat. 4318</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/120/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 106–120, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1999-12-03">Dec. 3, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1612">113 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/177/tIII/s373">Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 373</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2628">117 Stat. 2628</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c4f75ed-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c4f75ee-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c4f75ef-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 405(b) of this Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is section 405(b) of <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477/tIV">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477, title IV</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/280">66 Stat. 280</ref>, which is set out as a Savings Clause note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c4f75f0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/177">Pub. L. 108–177</ref> inserted “when Department of Defense activities are relevant to the determination” after “Secretary of Defense” and “and the Secretary of Homeland Security” after “Attorney General”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/120">Pub. L. 106–120</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/416">Pub. L. 103–416</ref> substituted “or” for “and” before “(F)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> inserted “and” before “(F)” and struck out “; (G) who, regardless of whether he is within any of the other provisions of this section, is a member of or affiliated with any Communist-action organization during the time it is registered or required to be registered under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s786">section 786 of title 50</ref>; or (H) who, regardless of whether he is within any of the other provisions of this section, is a member of or affiliated with any Communist-front organization during the time it is registered or required to be registered under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s786">section 786 of title 50</ref>” after “may hereafter adopt”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref> substituted “application” for “petition” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> substituted “party of” for “party or”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c4f75f1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id9c4f75f2-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c4f75f3-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/416/tII/s219/v">Pub. L. 103–416, title II, § 219(v)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4318">108 Stat. 4318</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id9c4f75f4-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 180 days after <date date="1952-06-27">June 27, 1952</date>, see section 407 of act <date date="1952-06-27">June 27, 1952</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c4f75f5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
