<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c56a21d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443"><num value="1443">§ 1443.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a21e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations governing examination of applicants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry into effect the provisions of this part and is authorized to prescribe the scope and nature of the examination of applicants for naturalization as to their admissibility to citizenship. Such examination shall be limited to inquiry concerning the applicant’s residence, physical presence in the United States, good moral character, understanding of and attachment to the fundamental principles of the Constitution of the United States, ability to read, write, and speak English, and other qualifications to become a naturalized citizen as required by law, and shall be uniform throughout the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a21f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Instruction in citizenship</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General is authorized to promote instruction and training in citizenship responsibilities of applicants for naturalization including the sending of names of candidates for naturalization to the public schools, preparing and distributing citizenship textbooks to such candidates as are receiving instruction in preparation for citizenship within or under the supervision of the public schools, preparing and distributing monthly an immigration and naturalization bulletin and securing the aid of and cooperating with official State and national organizations, including those concerned with vocational education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a220-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Prescription of forms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall prescribe and furnish such forms as may be required to give effect to the provisions of this part, and only such forms as may be so provided shall be legal. All certificates of naturalization and of citizenship shall be printed on safety paper and shall be consecutively numbered in separate series.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a221-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration of oaths and depositions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Employees of the Service may be designated by the Attorney General to administer oaths and to take depositions without charge in matters relating to the administration of the naturalization and citizenship laws. In cases where there is a likelihood of unusual delay or of hardship, the Attorney General may, in his discretion, authorize such depositions to be taken before a postmaster without charge, or before a notary public or other person authorized to administer oaths for general purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a222-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of certificate of naturalization or citizenship</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A certificate of naturalization or of citizenship issued by the Attorney General under the authority of this subchapter shall have the same effect in all courts, tribunals, and public offices of the United States, at home and abroad, of the District of Columbia, and of each State, Territory, and outlying possession of the United States, as a certificate of naturalization or of citizenship issued by a court having naturalization jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a223-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Copies of records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Certifications and certified copies of all papers, documents, certificates, and records required or authorized to be issued, used, filed, recorded, or kept under any and all provisions of this chapter shall be admitted in evidence equally with the originals in any and all cases and proceedings under this chapter and in all cases and proceedings in which the originals thereof might be admissible as evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a224-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Furnished quarters for photographic studios</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The officers in charge of property owned or leased by the Government are authorized, upon the recommendation of the Attorney General, to provide quarters, without payment of rent, in any building occupied by the Service, for a photographic studio, operated by welfare organizations without profit and solely for the benefit of persons seeking to comply with requirements under the immigration and nationality laws. Such studio shall be under the supervision of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9c56a225-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1443/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Public education regarding naturalization benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to promote the opportunities and responsibilities of United States citizenship, the Attorney General shall broadly distribute information concerning the benefits which persons may receive under this subchapter and the requirements to obtain such benefits. In carrying out this subsection, the Attorney General shall seek the assistance of appropriate community groups, private voluntary agencies, and other relevant organizations. There are authorized to be appropriated (for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 1991) such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c56a226-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title III, ch. 2, § 332, <ref href="/us/stat/66/252">66 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/tIV">Pub. L. 101–649, title IV</ref>, §§ 406, 407(d)(10), <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5040">104 Stat. 5040</ref>, 5042; <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s305/m/6">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 305(m)(6)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1750">105 Stat. 1750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c56a227-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c56a228-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c56a229-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (f), was in the original, “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c56a22a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/232">Pub. L. 102–232</ref> substituted “applicants” for “petitioners” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s407/d/10">Pub. L. 101–649, § 407(d)(10)</ref>, struck out “for the purpose of making appropriate recommendations to the naturalization courts” before period at end of first sentence and struck out second sentence which read as follows: “Such examination, in the discretion of the Attorney General, and under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by him, may be conducted before or after the applicant has filed his petition for naturalization.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/649/s406">Pub. L. 101–649, § 406</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c56a22b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c56a22c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/232/tIII/s305/m">Pub. L. 102–232, title III, § 305(m)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1750">105 Stat. 1750</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 305(m) is effective as if included in section 407(d) of the Immigration Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/649">Pub. L. 101–649</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c56a22d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
