<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c5b5cf6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481"><num value="1481">§ 1481.</num><heading> Loss of nationality by native-born or naturalized citizen; voluntary action; burden of proof; presumptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c5b5cf7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> A person who is a national of the United States whether by birth or naturalization, shall lose his nationality by voluntarily performing any of the following acts with the intention of relinquishing United States nationality—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cf8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> obtaining naturalization in a foreign state upon his own application or upon an application filed by a duly authorized agent, after having attained the age of eighteen years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cf9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> taking an oath or making an affirmation or other formal declaration of allegiance to a foreign state or a political subdivision thereof, after having attained the age of eighteen years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cfa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> entering, or serving in, the armed forces of a foreign state if (A) such armed forces are engaged in hostilities against the United States, or (B) such persons serve as a commissioned or non-commissioned officer; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cfb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cfc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment under the government of a foreign state or a political subdivision thereof, after attaining the age of eighteen years if he has or acquires the nationality of such foreign state; or (B) accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment under the government of a foreign state or a political subdivision thereof, after attaining the age of eighteen years for which office, post, or employment an oath, affirmation, or declaration of allegiance is required; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cfd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> making a formal renunciation of nationality before a diplomatic or consular officer of the United States in a foreign state, in such form as may be prescribed by the Secretary of State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cfe-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> making in the United States a formal written renunciation of nationality in such form as may be prescribed by, and before such officer as may be designated by, the Attorney General, whenever the United States shall be in a state of war and the Attorney General shall approve such renunciation as not contrary to the interests of national defense; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c5b5cff-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> committing any act of treason against, or attempting by force to overthrow, or bearing arms against, the United States, violating or conspiring to violate any of the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2383">section 2383 of title 18</ref>, or willfully performing any act in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2385">section 2385 of title 18</ref>, or violating <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2384">section 2384 of title 18</ref> by engaging in a conspiracy to overthrow, put down, or to destroy by force the Government of the United States, or to levy war against them, if and when he is convicted thereof by a court martial or by a court of competent jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c5b5d00-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1481/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whenever the loss of United States nationality is put in issue in any action or proceeding commenced on or after <date date="1961-09-26">September 26, 1961</date> under, or by virtue of, the provisions of this chapter or any other Act, the burden shall be upon the person or party claiming that such loss occurred, to establish such claim by a preponderance of the evidence. Any person who commits or performs, or who has committed or performed, any act of expatriation under the provisions of this chapter or any other Act shall be presumed to have done so voluntarily, but such presumption may be rebutted upon a showing, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the act or acts committed or performed were not done voluntarily.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c5b5d01-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title III, ch. 3, § 349, <ref href="/us/stat/66/267">66 Stat. 267</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1256/s2">Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1256, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1146">68 Stat. 1146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/301/s19">Pub. L. 87–301, § 19</ref>, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/656">75 Stat. 656</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/412/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 94–412, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1258">90 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/432">Pub. L. 95–432</ref>, §§ 2, 4, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1046">92 Stat. 1046</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s18/k/2">Pub. L. 97–116, § 18(k)(2)</ref>, (q), <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1620">95 Stat. 1620</ref>, 1621; <ref href="/us/pl/99/653">Pub. L. 99–653</ref>, §§ 18, 19, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3658">100 Stat. 3658</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref>, §§ 8(m), (n), 9(hh), <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2618">102 Stat. 2618</ref>, 2622.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c5b5d02-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c5b5d03-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c5b5d04-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original a reference to this Act, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">act June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/163">66 Stat. 163</ref>, known as the Immigration and Nationality Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c5b5d05-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s9/hh">Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(hh)</ref>, substituted “A person” for “From and after the effective date of this chapter a person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/m">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(m)</ref>, (n), amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/653">Pub. L. 99–653</ref>. See 1986 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s18/a">Pub. L. 99–653, § 18(a)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/m/1">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(m)(1)</ref>, inserted “voluntarily performing any of the following acts with the intention of relinquishing United States nationality” after “his nationality by”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s18/b">Pub. L. 99–653, § 18(b)</ref>, substituted “or upon an application filed by a duly authorized agent, after having attained the age of eighteen years” for “upon an application filed in his behalf by a parent, guardian, or duly authorized agent, or through the naturalization of a parent having legal custody of such person: <i>Provided</i> That nationality shall not be lost by any person under this section as the result of the naturalization of a parent or parents while such person is under the age of twenty-one years, or as the result of a naturalization obtained on behalf of a person under twenty-one years of age by a parent, guardian, or duly authorized agent, unless such person shall fail to enter the United States to establish a permanent residence prior to his twenty-fifth birthday: <i>And provided further</i>, That a person who shall have lost nationality prior to <date date="1948-01-01">January 1, 1948</date>, through the naturalization in a foreign state of a parent or parents, may, within one year from the effective date of this chapter, apply for a visa and for admission to the United States as a special immigrant under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/27/E">section 1101(a)(27)(E) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s18/c">Pub. L. 99–653, § 18(c)</ref>, inserted “, after having attained the age of eighteen years” after “political subdivision thereof”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s18/d">Pub. L. 99–653, § 18(d)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/m/2">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(m)(2)</ref>, substituted “if (A) such armed forces are engaged in hostilities against the United States, or (B) such persons serve as a commissioned or non-commissioned officer; or” for “unless, prior to such entry or service, such entry or service is specifically authorized in writing by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense: <i>Provided</i>, That the entry into such service by a person prior to the attainment of his eighteenth birthday shall serve to expatriate such person only if there exists an option to secure a release from such service and such person fails to exercise such option at the attainment of his eighteenth birthday; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s18/e">Pub. L. 99–653, § 18(e)</ref>, (f), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/m/3">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(m)(3)</ref>, inserted “after attaining the age of eighteen years” after “political subdivision thereof,” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s19">Pub. L. 99–653, § 19</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/n">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(n)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (c) as (b) and substituted “Any” for “Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any”, and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Any person who commits or performs any act specified in subsection (a) of this section shall be conclusively presumed to have done so voluntarily and without having been subjected to duress of any kind, if such person at the time of the act was a national of the state in which the act was performed and had been physically present in such state for a period or periods totaling ten years or more immediately prior to such act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> struck out “(a)” designation as added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/432/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 95–432</ref>, which was not executed since it would have resulted in a subsec. (a) designation of “(a)(a)”, and substituted in par. (1) “special immigrant” for “nonquota immigrant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/432">Pub. L. 95–432</ref>, §§ 2, 4, redesignated par. (6) as (5). Former par. (5), which dealt with expatriation of persons who voted in a political election in a foreign state or participated in an election or plebiscite to determine sovereignty over foreign territory, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/432/s4">Pub. L. 95–432, § 4</ref>, redesignated pars. (7) and (9) as (6) and (7), respectively. Former pars. (6) and (7) redesignated (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/95/432/s2">Pub. L. 95–432, § 2</ref>, struck out par. (8) which dealt with expatriation of persons who were dismissed or dishonorably discharged as result of deserting the military, air, or naval forces of the United States in time of war.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/95/432/s4">Pub. L. 95–432, § 4</ref>, redesignated par. (9) as (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/94/412">Pub. L. 94–412</ref> struck out par. (10) which dealt with the expatriation of persons who remained outside of the jurisdiction of the United States in time of war or national emergency to avoid service in the military.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/301">Pub. L. 87–301</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a)(9). Act <date date="1954-09-03">Sept. 3, 1954</date>, provided for forfeiture of citizenship of persons advocating the overthrow of the Government by force or violence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c5b5d06-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c5b5d07-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 8(m), (n) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/525">Pub. L. 100–525</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Immigration and Nationality Act Amendments of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/653">Pub. L. 99–653</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/232/s309/b/15">section 309(b)(15) of Pub. L. 102–232</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 1988 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c5b5d08-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/653/s23/g">Pub. L. 99–653, § 23(g)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/525/s8/r">Pub. L. 100–525, § 8(r)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2619">102 Stat. 2619</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/525/s8/r">“The amendments made by sections 18, 19, and 20 [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1483">section 1483 of this title</ref>] shall apply to actions taken before, on, or after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c5b5d09-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/116">Pub. L. 97–116</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/116/s21/a">section 21(a) of Pub. L. 97–116</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id9c5b5d0a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1256/s1">Act Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1256, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1146">68 Stat. 1146</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1256/s1">“That this Act [amending this section] may be cited as the ‘Expatriation Act of 1954’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id9c5b5d0b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/412">Pub. L. 94–412</ref> not to affect any action taken or proceeding pending at the time of amendment, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/412/s501/h">section 501(h) of Pub. L. 94–412</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">section 1601 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c5b5d0c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c5b5d0d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Right of Expatriation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 1999 provided that: “Whereas the right of expatriation is a natural and inherent right of all people, indispensable to the enjoyment of the rights of life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness; and whereas in the recognition of this principle this Government has freely received emigrants from all nations, and invested them with the rights of citizenship; and whereas it is claimed that such American citizens, with their descendants, are subjects of foreign states, owing allegiance to the governments thereof; and whereas it is necessary to the maintenance of public peace that this claim of foreign allegiance should be promptly and finally disavowed: Therefore any declaration, instruction, opinion, order, or decision of any officer of the United States which denies, restricts, impairs, or questions the right of expatriation, is declared inconsistent with the fundamental principles of the Republic.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
