<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c5b5d4e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1521"><num value="1521">§ 1521.</num><heading> Office of Refugee Resettlement; establishment; appointment of Director; functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c5b5d4f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1521/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> There is established, within the Department of Health and Human Services, an office to be known as the Office of Refugee Resettlement (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Office”). The head of the Office shall be a Director (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Director”), to be appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9c5b5d50-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1521/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The function of the Office and its Director is to fund and administer (directly or through arrangements with other Federal agencies), in consultation with the Secretary of State, programs of the Federal Government under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9c5b5d51-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-06-27/ch477">June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title IV, ch. 2, § 411, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/212/tIII/s311/a/2">Pub. L. 96–212, title III, § 311(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-17">Mar. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/110">94 Stat. 110</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162/n/1">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(n)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/409">108 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c5b5d52-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c5b5d53-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c5b5d54-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> substituted “the Secretary of State” for “and under the general policy guidance of the United States Coordinator for Refugee Affairs (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the ‘Coordinator’)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c5b5d55-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c5b5d56-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id9c5b5d57-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter applicable with respect to fiscal years beginning on or after <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/212/s313">section 313 of Pub. L. 96–212</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1522">section 1522 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c5b5d58-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of Refugee Act of 1980</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of Refugee Act of 1980, see Short Title of 1980 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c5b5d59-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Secretary of Education or Secretary of Department of Health and Human Services</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/212/tII/s204/e">Pub. L. 96–212, title II, § 204(e)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-17">Mar. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/109">94 Stat. 109</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/212/tII/s204/e">“Any reference in this Act [see Short Title of 1980 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>] or in chapter 2 of title IV of the Immigration and Nationality Act [this subchapter] to the Secretary of Education or the Secretary of Health and Human Services or to the Department of Health and Human Services shall be deemed, before the effective date of the Department of Education Organization Act [see Effective Date note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3401">section 3401 of Title 20</ref>, Education], to be a reference to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare or to the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, respectively.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c5b5d5a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Declaration of Policies and Objectives</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/212/tI/s101">Pub. L. 96–212, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1980-03-17">Mar. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/102">94 Stat. 102</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/212/tI/s101">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> the Congress declares that it is the historic policy of the United States to respond to the urgent needs of persons subject to persecution in their homelands, including, where appropriate, humanitarian assistance for their care and maintenance in asylum areas, efforts to promote opportunities for resettlement or voluntary repatriation, aid for necessary transportation and processing, admission to this country of refugees of special humanitarian concern to the United States, and transitional assistance to refugees in the United States. The Congress further declares that it is the policy of the United States to encourage all nations to provide assistance and resettlement opportunities to refugees to the fullest extent possible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The objectives of this Act [see Short Title of 1980 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>] are to provide a permanent and systematic procedure for the admission to this country of refugees of special humanitarian concern to the United States, and to provide comprehensive and uniform provisions for the effective resettlement and absorption of those refugees who are admitted.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
