<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c6289f5-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1551"><num value="1551">§ 1551.</num><heading> Immigration and Naturalization Service</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is created and established in the Department of Justice an Immigration and Naturalization Service.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id9c6289f6-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/act/1903-02-14/ch552/s4">Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/826">32 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1906-06-29/ch3592/s1">June 29, 1906, ch. 3592, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/596">34 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch141/s3">Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/737">37 Stat. 737</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 14, <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. V, eff. <date date="1940-06-14">June 14, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2223, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1238">54 Stat. 1238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c6289f7-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c6289f8-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c6289f9-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s342">section 342 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c6289fa-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id9c6289fb-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/313/tII/s201">Pub. L. 106–313, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1262">114 Stat. 1262</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/313/tII/s201">“This title [enacting subchapter II of this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c6289fc-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Immigration and Naturalization Service was abolished by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s291/a">section 291(a) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security, upon completion of all transfers from the Immigration and Naturalization Service as provided for by chapter 1 of Title 6.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization performed under the Border Patrol program, the detention and removal program, the intelligence program, the investigations program, and the inspections program, and all personnel, assets, and liabilities pertaining to such programs, were transferred to the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security of the Department of Homeland Security by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s251">section 251 of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization relating to adjudications of immigrant visa petitions, adjudications of naturalization petitions, adjudications of asylum and refugee applications, adjudications performed at service centers, and all other adjudications performed by the Immigration and Naturalization Service, and all personnel, infrastructure, and funding provided to the Commissioner in support of such functions, were transferred to the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of Homeland Security by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s271/b">section 271(b) of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions performed by the Statistics Branch of the Office of Policy and Planning of the Immigration and Naturalization Service with respect to the functions of the Commissioner referred to in the two preceding paragraphs were transferred to the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security by former <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s341/b/2">section 341(b)(2) of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions under the immigration laws of the United States with respect to the care of unaccompanied alien children that were vested by statute in, or performed by, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization (or any officer, employee, or component of the Immigration and Naturalization Service) were transferred to the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement of the Department of Health and Human Services by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279/a">section 279(a) of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Personnel of the Department of Justice employed in connection with the functions transferred by part E (§ 271 et seq.) of subchapter IV of chapter 1 of Title 6 (and functions that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines are properly related to the functions of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services), were transferred to the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s275/b/2">section 275(b)(2) of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified. Personnel of the Department of Justice employed in connection with the functions transferred by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279">section 279 of Title 6</ref> were transferred to the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement by <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279/f/3">section 279(f)(3) of Title 6</ref> and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For treatment of references to any agency, officer, or office, etc. the functions of which were transferred to the Department of Homeland Security, see sections 552(d) and 557 of Title 6.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c6289fd-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Independent Comprehensive Management Analysis of Service Operations; Arrangements Respecting, Etc.</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/132/s10">Pub. L. 96–132, § 10</ref>, <date date="1979-11-30">Nov. 30, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1047">93 Stat. 1047</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/132/s10">“The Attorney General shall make arrangements with an appropriate entity for an independent comprehensive management analysis of the operations of the Immigration and Naturalization Service for the purpose of making such operations efficient and cost effective. After the completion of such analysis, the Attorney General shall promptly submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the results of such analysis together with any administrative or legislative recommendations of the Attorney General to improve the operations of the Service.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c6289fe-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Office of Special Investigator; Functions, Establishment, Powers, Etc.</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/132/s22">Pub. L. 96–132, § 22</ref>, <date date="1979-11-30">Nov. 30, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1050">93 Stat. 1050</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/25">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(25)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4346">136 Stat. 4346</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/25">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> In order to create an independent and objective unit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to programs and operations of the Immigration and Naturalization Service,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies for activities designed (A) to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of, and (B) to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in, such programs and operations, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to provide a means for keeping the Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service and the Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration of such programs and operations and the necessity for and progress of corrective action,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">there is hereby established in the Immigration and Naturalization Service of the Department of Justice an Office of Special Investigator (hereinafter in this section referred to as ‘the Office’).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There shall be at the head of the Office a Special Investigator (hereinafter in this section referred to as ‘the Special Investigator’) who shall be appointed by the Attorney General without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. The Special Investigator shall report to and be under the general supervision of the Commissioner, who shall not prevent or prohibit the Special Investigator from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, or from issuing any subpena during the course of any audit or investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Special Investigator may be removed from office by the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall communicate the reasons for any such removal to both Houses of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> For the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7324">section 7324 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code, the Special Investigator shall not be considered to be an employee who determines policies to be pursued by the United States in the nationwide administration of Federal laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> The Special Investigator shall, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing the civil service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> appoint an Assistant Special Investigator for Auditing who shall have the responsibility for supervising the performance of auditing activities relating to programs and operations of the Service, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> appoint an Assistant Special Investigator for Investigations who shall have the responsibility for the performance of investigative activities relating to such programs and operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> The following provisions of chapter 4 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to the Special Investigator, the Office, the Commissioner, and the Service under this section in the same manner as those provisions apply to an Inspector General, an Office, the head of the establishment, and an establishment under such chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Section 404 (relating to duties and responsibilities of an Inspector General and the manner in which they are carried out).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Section 405 (relating to reports required to be prepared and furnished by or to an Inspector General and their transmittal and availability).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Section 406 (relating to the authority of an Inspector General and related administrative provisions).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Section 407 (relating to the treatment of employee complaints by an Inspector General).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Attorney General is authorized to appoint such staff as may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Service’ means the Immigration and Naturalization Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘Department’ means the Department of Justice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘Commissioner’ means the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> The Special Investigator shall be compensated at the rate then payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5316">section 5316 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code for level V of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><chapeau> The provisions of this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1979-11-30">Nov. 30, 1979</date>] and shall cease to have effect the earlier of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the establishment of an office of inspector general for the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><content> In addition to any other sums authorized to be appropriated by this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated $376,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date> to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c64d2ef-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">History of Immigration and Naturalization Agencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By acts <ref href="/us/act/1882-08-03/ch376">Aug. 3, 1882, ch. 376</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <ref href="/us/stat/22/214">22 Stat. 214</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1887-02-23/ch220">Feb. 23, 1887, ch. 220</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/24/415">24 Stat. 415</ref>, the administration of the immigration laws then in force was reposed in the Secretary of the Treasury. Subsequently, by <ref href="/us/act/1891-03-03/ch551/s7">act Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 551, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/1087">26 Stat. 1087</ref>, the office of the Superintendent of Immigration was created as a permanent immigration agency and he in turn was designated Commissioner General of Immigration under the heading “Bureau of Immigration” by <ref href="/us/act/1895-03-02/ch177/s1">act Mar. 2, 1895, ch. 177, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/780">28 Stat. 780</ref>. Upon the establishment of the Department of Commerce and Labor, the Commissioner General of Immigration and the Bureau of Immigration were transferred to that Department by <ref href="/us/act/1903-02-14/ch552/s4">act Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/825">32 Stat. 825</ref>, and thereafter were redesignated the Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization by <ref href="/us/act/1906-06-29/ch3592/s1">act June 29, 1906, ch. 3592, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/596">34 Stat. 596</ref>. The Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization was transferred to the Department of Labor upon its establishment by <ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch141">act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/736">37 Stat. 736</ref>, and divided into two bureaus to be known as the Bureau of Immigration and the Bureau of Naturalization, respectively. Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 14, <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>, set out as note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s901">section 901 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, again consolidated these bureaus to form the Immigration and Naturalization Service, under a “Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization”, which was then transferred from the Department of Labor to the Department of Justice by 1940 Reorg. Plan No. V, eff. <date date="1940-06-14">June 14, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2223, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1238">54 Stat. 1238</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id9c64d2f0-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id9c64d2f1-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by law in Attorney General, Department of Justice, or any other officer or any agency of that Department, with respect to inspection at regular inspection locations at ports of entry of persons, and documents of persons, entering or leaving United States, were to have been transferred to Secretary of the Treasury by 1973 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 2, eff. <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, 38 F.R. 15932, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1091">87 Stat. 1091</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. The transfer was negated by section 1(a)(1), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/253">Pub. L. 93–253</ref>, <date date="1974-03-16">Mar. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/50">88 Stat. 50</ref>, which repealed section 2 of 1973 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all other officers of Department of Justice and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department, with a few exceptions, transferred to Attorney General, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 2, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3173, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1261">64 Stat. 1261</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5. See sections 509 and 510 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
