<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c6e7018-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1645"><num value="1645">§ 1645.</num><heading> Qualifying quarters</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, in determining the number of qualifying quarters of coverage under title II of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.] an alien shall be credited with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c6e7019-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1645/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> all of the qualifying quarters of coverage as defined under title II of the Social Security Act worked by a parent of such alien before the date on which the alien attains age 18, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9c6e701a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1645/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all of the qualifying quarters worked by a spouse of such alien during their marriage and the alien remains married to such spouse or such spouse is deceased.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">No such qualifying quarter of coverage that is creditable under title II of the Social Security Act for any period beginning after <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, may be credited to an alien under paragraph (1) or (2) if the parent or spouse (as the case may be) of such alien received any Federal means-tested public benefit (as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1613">section 1613 of this title</ref>) during the period for which such qualifying quarter of coverage is so credited. Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of title 26</ref>, the Commissioner of Social Security is authorized to disclose quarters of coverage information concerning an alien and an alien’s spouse or parents to a government agency for the purposes of this chapter.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id9c6e701b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tIV/s435">Pub. L. 104–193, title IV, § 435</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2275">110 Stat. 2275</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5573">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5573</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/641">111 Stat. 641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c6e701c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c6e701d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9c6e701e-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title” meaning title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2260">110 Stat. 2260</ref>, which enacted this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1183a">section 1183a of this title</ref>, and sections 611a and 1437y of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1383">section 1383 of this title</ref>, sections 32 and 6213 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code, and sections 1436a and 1471 of Title 42, and enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1183a">section 1183a of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s32">section 32 of Title 26</ref>. For complete classification of title IV to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c6e701f-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5573/a">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5573(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of title 26</ref>, the Commissioner of Social Security is authorized to disclose quarters of coverage information concerning an alien and an alien’s spouse or parents to a government agency for the purposes of this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5573/b">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5573(b)</ref>, substituted “before the date on which the alien attains age 18,” for “while the alien was under age 18,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c6e7020-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9c6e7021-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of title IV of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5582">section 5582 of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1367">section 1367 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
