<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9c6e7086-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7" identifier="/us/usc/t8/s1714"><num value="1714">§ 1714.</num><heading> Surcharges related to consular services</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter, the Secretary of State is authorized to charge surcharges related to consular services in support of enhanced border security that are in addition to the passport and immigrant visa fees in effect on <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That funds collected pursuant to this authority shall be deposited in the Consular and Border Security Programs account, and shall be available until expended for the purposes of such account: <i>Provided further</i>, That such surcharges shall be $12 on passport fees, and $45 on immigrant visa fees.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id9c6e7087-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dB/tIV">Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title IV</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2896">118 Stat. 2896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dJ/tVII/s7081/c">Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7081(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/716">131 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9c6e7088-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9c6e7089-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9c6e708a-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section appears under the headings “Administration of Foreign Affairs” and “Diplomatic and Consular Programs” in title IV of div. B of <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref>. It was enacted as part of the Department of State and Related Agency Appropriations Act, 2005, and also as part of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2005, and as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005, and not as part of the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9c6e708b-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—<ref href="/us/pl/115/31">Pub. L. 115–31</ref> substituted “deposited in the Consular and Border Security Programs account” for “credited to this account”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9c6e708c-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9c6e708d-3a6f-11f1-ace3-bb5201d4c7c7"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority to Administratively Amend Surcharges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/472/s6">Pub. L. 109–472, § 6</ref>, <date date="2007-01-11">Jan. 11, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3555">120 Stat. 3555</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/472/s6">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning in fiscal year 2007 and thereafter, the Secretary of State is authorized to amend administratively the amounts of the surcharges related to consular services in support of enhanced border security (provided for in the last paragraph under the heading ‘diplomatic and consular programs’ under title IV of division B of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 (<ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Public Law 108–447</ref>) [this section]) that are in addition to the passport and immigrant visa fees in effect on <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a) and the provision of law described in such subsection, the Secretary shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The amounts of the surcharges shall be reasonably related to the costs of providing services in connection with the activity or item for which the surcharges are charged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The aggregate amount of surcharges collected may not exceed the aggregate amount obligated and expended for the costs related to consular services in support of enhanced border security incurred in connection with the activity or item for which the surcharges are charged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A surcharge may not be collected except to the extent the surcharge will be obligated and expended to pay the costs related to consular services in support of enhanced border security incurred in connection with the activity or item for which the surcharge is charged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A surcharge shall be available for obligation and expenditure only to pay the costs related to consular services in support of enhanced border security incurred in providing services in connection with the activity or item for which the surcharge is charged.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
