<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4cece50-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104"><num value="104">§ 104.</num><heading> National biodefense strategy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece51-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategy and implementation plan required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly develop a national biodefense strategy and associated implementation plan, which shall include a review and assessment of biodefense policies, practices, programs and initiatives. Such Secretaries shall review and, as appropriate, revise the strategy biennially.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece52-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The strategy and associated implementation plan required under subsection (a) shall include each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece53-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An inventory and assessment of all existing strategies, plans, policies, laws, and interagency agreements related to biodefense, including prevention, deterrence, preparedness, detection, response, attribution, recovery, and mitigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece54-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of the biological threats, including biological warfare, bioterrorism, naturally occurring infectious diseases, and accidental exposures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece55-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A description of the current programs, efforts, or activities of the United States Government with respect to preventing the acquisition, proliferation, and use of a biological weapon, preventing an accidental or naturally occurring biological outbreak, and mitigating the effects of a biological epidemic.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece56-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A description of the roles and responsibilities of the Executive Agencies, including internal and external coordination procedures, in identifying and sharing information related to, warning of, and protection against, acts of terrorism using biological agents and weapons and accidental or naturally occurring biological outbreaks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece57-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> An articulation of related or required interagency capabilities and whole-of-Government activities required to support the national biodefense strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece58-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Recommendations for strengthening and improving the current biodefense capabilities, authorities, and command structures of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece59-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Recommendations for improving and formalizing interagency coordination and support mechanisms with respect to providing a robust national biodefense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece5a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Any other matters the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Agriculture determine necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece5b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Submittal to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 275 days after <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the strategy and associated implementation plan required by subsection (a). The strategy and implementation plan shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece5c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Briefings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2017-03-01">March 1, 2017</date>, and annually thereafter until <date date="2025-03-01">March 1, 2025</date>, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide to the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a joint briefing on the strategy developed under subsection (a) and the status of the implementation of such strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece5d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> GAO Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the date of the submittal of the strategy and implementation plan under subsection (c), the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the strategy and implementation plan to analyze gaps and resources mapped against the requirements of the National Biodefense Strategy and existing United States biodefense policy documents.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4cece5e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece5f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece60-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece61-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4cece62-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s104/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4cece63-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tX/s1086">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1086</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2423">130 Stat. 2423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXVII/s1704">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1704</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1797">133 Stat. 1797</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4d13e64-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4d13e65-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4d13e66-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4d13e67-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> substituted “<date date="2025-03-01">March 1, 2025</date>” for “<date date="2019-03-01">March 1, 2019</date>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4d13e68-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4d13e69-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancement of International Biodefense Capacity</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1207">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1207</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1082">139 Stat. 1082</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1207">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Clarification of Roles and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall direct the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Nuclear Deterrence, Chemical and Biological Defense Programs, in consultation with the Director of the Defense Threat Reduction Agency, to seek to enter into memoranda of understanding with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government to clarify the roles and responsibilities of those departments and agencies for building biodefense capabilities internationally in execution of national security and other policies of the Federal Government, with the Secretary focused on working with defense counterparts in countries that are allies or partners of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Memoranda of Understanding</inline>.—</heading><content>The memoranda of understanding entered into under subsection (a) shall address how each relevant department or agency selects partner countries and the feasibility of coordinating efforts with each such country.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4d13e6a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">“Congressional Defense Committees” Defined</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Congressional defense committees means the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2025">130 Stat. 2025</ref>. See note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
