<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4d13e78-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106"><num value="106">§ 106.</num><heading> Update of national biodefense implementation plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e79-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Defense, Agriculture, Homeland Security, and all other Departments and agencies with responsibilities for biodefense, such as the Department of State, in consultation with the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, as appropriate, shall jointly, after reviewing the biodefense threat assessment described in subsection (d) and any relevant input from external stakeholders, as appropriate, update the National Biodefense Implementation Plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s104">section 104 of this title</ref> to clearly document established processes, roles, and responsibilities related to the National Biodefense Strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e7a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific updates</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The updated National Biodefense Implementation Plan shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e7b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describe the roles and responsibilities of the Federal departments and agencies, including internal and external coordination procedures, in identifying and sharing information between and among Federal departments and agencies, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s104/b/4">section 104(b)(4) of this title</ref> and consistent with the statutory roles and authorities of such departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e7c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> describe roles, responsibilities, and processes for decisionmaking, including decisions regarding use of resources for effective risk management across the enterprise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e7d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> describe resource plans for each department and agency with responsibility for biodefense to support implementation of the strategy within the jurisdiction of such department or agency, including for the Biodefense Coordination Team, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e7e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> describe guidance and methods for analyzing the data collected from agencies to include non-Federal resources and capabilities to the extent practicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e7f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> describe and update, as appropriate, short-, medium-, and long-term goals for executing the National Biodefense Strategy and metrics for meeting each objective of the Strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e80-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Submittal to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, not later than 6 months after the date of the completion of the assessment in subsection (d)(1)(A), submit the updated Implementation Plan to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e81-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Updated biodefense threat assessment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e82-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Defense, Agriculture, and Homeland Security, shall jointly, and in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, and other agency heads as appropriate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4d13e83-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct an assessment of current and potential biological threats against the United States, both naturally occurring and man-made, either accidental or deliberate, including the potential for catastrophic biological threats, such as a pandemic;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4d13e84-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than 1 year after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, submit the findings of the assessment conducted under subparagraph (A) to the Federal officials described in subsection (d)(1)and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002002"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> the appropriate congressional committees described in subsection (e);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4d13e85-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> not later than 30 days after the date on which the assessment is submitted under subparagraph (B), conduct a briefing for the appropriate congressional committees on the findings of the assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4d13e86-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> update the assessment under subparagraph (A) biennially, as appropriate, and provide the findings of such updated assessments to the Federal officials described in subsection (d)(1) and the appropriate congressional committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4d13e87-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> conduct briefings for the appropriate congressional committees as needed any time an assessment under this paragraph is updated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e88-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Classification and format</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Assessments under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in an unclassified format and include a classified annex, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e89-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4d13e8f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4d13e90-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s106/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter, limit, or duplicate the roles, responsibilities, authorities, or current activities, as established in statute or otherwise through existing practice or policy, of each Federal department or agency with responsibilities for biodefense or otherwise relevant to implementation of the National Biodefense Strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4d13e91-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIII/s364">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 364</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3548">134 Stat. 3548</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4d13e92-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4d13e93-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4d13e94-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
