<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56764e0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1117"><num value="1117">§ 1117.</num><heading> Roles of the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Transportation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security is the principal Federal official responsible for transportation security. The roles and responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Transportation in carrying out this chapter are the roles and responsibilities of such Departments pursuant to the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<ref href="/us/pl/107/71">Public Law 107–71</ref>); the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Public Law 108–458</ref>); the National Infrastructure Protection Plan required by Homeland Security Presidential Directive–7; The <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002141"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> Homeland Security Act of 2002 [<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">6 U.S.C. 101</ref> et seq.]; The <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref> National Response Plan; Executive Order No. 13416: Strengthening Surface Transportation Security, dated <date date="2006-12-05">December 5, 2006</date>; the Memorandum of Understanding between the Department and the Department of Transportation on Roles and Responsibilities, dated <date date="2004-09-28">September 28, 2004</date>, and any and all subsequent annexes to this Memorandum of Understanding; and any other relevant agreements between the two Departments.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb56764e1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXIII/s1310">Pub. L. 110–53, title XIII, § 1310</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/400">121 Stat. 400</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56764e2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56764e3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb56764e4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to titles XII, XIII, XIV, and XV of <ref href="/us/pl/110/53">Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, which enacted this chapter, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1992">section 1992 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70105">section 70105 of Title 46</ref>, Shipping, and sections 114, 5103a, 14504, 20106, 20109, 24301, 28101, 31105, and 46301 of Title 49, Transportation, enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref> and sections 114, 13908, and 14504 of Title 49, and amended provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s14504">section 14504 of Title 49</ref>. For complete classification of titles XII to XV to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Aviation and Transportation Security Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/107/71">Pub. L. 107–71</ref>, <date date="2001-11-19">Nov. 19, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/597">115 Stat. 597</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2001 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3638">118 Stat. 3638</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Homeland Security Act of 2002, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2135">116 Stat. 2135</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 1 (§ 101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13416, referred to in text, is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
