<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56c46c6-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152"><num value="1152">§ 1152.</num><heading> Oversight and grant procedures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46c7-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial oversight</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002156">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002156"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “the” probably should appear.</note> Secretary of Transportation for grants awarded to Amtrak, shall establish necessary procedures, including monitoring and audits, to ensure that grants made under this subchapter are expended in accordance with the purposes of this subchapter and the priorities and other criteria developed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46c8-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional audits and reviews</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, and the Secretary of Transportation for grants awarded to Amtrak, may award contracts to undertake additional audits and reviews of the safety, security, procurement, management, and financial compliance of a recipient of amounts under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46c9-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for grant award</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, the Secretary shall prescribe procedures and schedules for the awarding of grants under this subchapter, including application and qualification procedures, and a record of decision on applicant eligibility. The procedures shall include the execution of a grant agreement between the grant recipient and the Secretary and shall be consistent, to the extent practicable, with the grant procedures established under section 70107(i) and (j) of title 46.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46ca-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46cb-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may issue non-binding letters of intent to recipients of a grant under this subchapter, to commit funding from future budget authority of an amount, not more than the Federal Government’s share of the project’s cost, for a capital improvement project.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46cc-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The letter of intent under this subsection shall establish a schedule under which the Secretary will reimburse the recipient for the Government’s share of the project’s costs, as amounts become available, if the recipient, after the Secretary issues that letter, carries out the project without receiving amounts under a grant issued under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46cd-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A recipient that has been issued a letter of intent under this section shall notify the Secretary of the recipient’s intent to carry out a project before the project begins.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46ce-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a written notification at least 5 days before the issuance of a letter of intent under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46cf-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A letter of intent issued under this subsection is not an obligation of the Federal Government under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1501">section 1501 of title 31</ref>, and the letter is not deemed to be an administrative commitment for financing. An obligation or administrative commitment may be made only as amounts are provided in authorization and appropriations laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46d0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Return of misspent grant funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As part of the grant agreement under subsection (c), the Secretary shall require grant applicants to return any misspent grant funds received under this subchapter that the Secretary considers to have been spent for a purpose other than those specified in the grant award. The Secretary shall take all necessary actions to recover such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46d1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 5 days before the award of any grant is made under this subchapter, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the intent to award such grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c46d2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1152/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that grant recipients under this subchapter who use contractors or subcontractors use small, minority, women-owned, or disadvantaged business concerns as contractors or subcontractors when appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb56c46d3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXV/s1502">Pub. L. 110–53, title XV, § 1502</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/424">121 Stat. 424</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56c46d4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56c46d5-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb56c46d6-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title XV of <ref href="/us/pl/110/53">Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of title XV to the Code, see References in Text note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
