<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56c4703-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161"><num value="1161">§ 1161.</num><heading> Railroad transportation security risk assessment and National Strategy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4704-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Risk assessment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a Federal task force, including the Transportation Security Administration and other agencies within the Department, the Department of Transportation, and other appropriate Federal agencies, to complete, within 6 months of <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, a nationwide risk assessment of a terrorist attack on railroad carriers. The assessment shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c4705-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a methodology for conducting the risk assessment, including timelines, that addresses how the Department will work with the entities described in subsection (c) and make use of existing Federal expertise within the Department, the Department of Transportation, and other appropriate agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c4706-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identification and evaluation of critical assets and infrastructure, including tunnels used by railroad carriers in high-threat urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c4707-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identification of risks to those assets and infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c4708-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identification of risks that are specific to the transportation of hazardous materials via railroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c4709-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> identification of risks to passenger and cargo security, transportation infrastructure protection systems, operations, communications systems, and any other area identified by the assessment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c470a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> an assessment of employee training and emergency response planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c470b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> an assessment of public and private operational recovery plans, taking into account the plans for the maritime sector required under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70103">section 70103 of title 46</ref>, to expedite, to the maximum extent practicable, the return of an adversely affected railroad transportation system or facility to its normal performance level after a major terrorist attack or other security event on that system or facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56c470c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> an account of actions taken or planned by both public and private entities to address identified railroad security issues and an assessment of the effective integration of such actions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c470d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> National Strategy</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c470e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 9 months after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, and based upon the assessment conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary, consistent with and as required by section 114(t) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002157"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 49, shall develop and implement the modal plan for railroad transportation, entitled the “National Strategy for Railroad Transportation Security”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c470f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The modal plan shall include prioritized goals, actions, objectives, policies, mechanisms, and schedules for, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4710-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improving the security of railroad tunnels, railroad bridges, railroad switching and car storage areas, other railroad infrastructure and facilities, information systems, and other areas identified by the Secretary as posing significant railroad-related risks to public safety and the movement of interstate commerce, taking into account the impact that any proposed security measure might have on the provision of railroad service or on operations served or otherwise affected by railroad service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4711-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> deploying equipment and personnel to detect security threats, including those posed by explosives and hazardous chemical, biological, and radioactive substances, and any appropriate countermeasures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4712-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1167">section 1167 of this title</ref>, training railroad employees in terrorism prevention, preparedness, passenger evacuation, and response activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4713-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> conducting public outreach campaigns for railroads regarding security, including educational initiatives designed to inform the public on how to prevent, prepare for, respond to, and recover from a terrorist attack on railroad transportation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4714-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> providing additional railroad security support for railroads at high or severe threat levels of alert;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4715-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> ensuring, in coordination with freight and intercity and commuter passenger railroads, the continued movement of freight and passengers in the event of an attack affecting the railroad system, including the possibility of rerouting traffic due to the loss of critical infrastructure, such as a bridge, tunnel, yard, or station;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4716-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> coordinating existing and planned railroad security initiatives undertaken by the public and private sectors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4717-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> assessing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb56c4718-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the usefulness of covert testing of railroad security systems;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb56c4719-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the ability to integrate security into infrastructure design; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb56c471a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/H/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the implementation of random searches of passengers and baggage; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c471b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identifying the immediate and long-term costs of measures that may be required to address those risks and public and private sector sources to fund such measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c471c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall include in the modal plan a description of the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of Federal, State, and local agencies, government-sponsored entities, tribal governments, and appropriate stakeholders described in subsection (c). The plan shall also include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c471d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the identification of, and a plan to address, gaps and unnecessary overlaps in the roles, responsibilities, and authorities described in this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c471e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a methodology for how the Department will work with the entities described in subsection (c), and make use of existing Federal expertise within the Department, the Department of Transportation, and other appropriate agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c471f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a process for facilitating security clearances for the purpose of intelligence and information sharing with the entities described in subsection (c), as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4720-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a strategy and timeline, coordinated with the research and development program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1168">section 1168 of this title</ref>, for the Department, the Department of Transportation, other appropriate Federal agencies and private entities to research and develop new technologies for securing railroad systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4721-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a process for coordinating existing or future security strategies and plans for railroad transportation, including the National Infrastructure Protection Plan required by Homeland Security Presidential Directive–7; Executive Order No. 13416: “Strengthening Surface Transportation Security” dated <date date="2006-12-05">December 5, 2006</date>; the Memorandum of Understanding between the Department and the Department of Transportation on Roles and Responsibilities dated <date date="2004-09-28">September 28, 2004</date>, and any and all subsequent annexes to this Memorandum of Understanding, and any other relevant agreements between the two Departments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4722-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with stakeholders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the National Strategy required under this section, the Secretary shall consult with railroad management, nonprofit employee organizations representing railroad employees, owners or lessors of railroad cars used to transport hazardous materials, emergency responders, offerors of security-sensitive materials, public safety officials, and other relevant parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4723-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Adequacy of existing plans and strategies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the risk assessment and National Strategy required under this section, the Secretary shall utilize relevant existing plans, strategies, and risk assessments developed by the Department or other Federal agencies, including those developed or implemented pursuant to section 114(t) <sup>1</sup> of title 49 or Homeland Security Presidential Directive–7, and, as appropriate, assessments developed by other public and private stakeholders.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4724-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4725-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4726-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the assessment and the National Strategy required by this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56c4727-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an estimate of the cost to implement the National Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4728-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Format</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may submit the report in both classified and redacted formats if the Secretary determines that such action is appropriate or necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c4729-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Consistent with the requirements of section 114(t) <sup>1</sup> of title 49, the Secretary shall update the assessment and National Strategy each year and transmit a report, which may be submitted in both classified and redacted formats, to the appropriate congressional committees containing the updated assessment and recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56c472a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1161/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Out of funds appropriated pursuant to section 114(w) <sup>1</sup> of title 49, there shall be made available to the Secretary to carry out this section $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb56c472b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXV/s1511">Pub. L. 110–53, title XV, § 1511</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/426">121 Stat. 426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56c472c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56c472d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb56c472e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t49/s114/t">Section 114(t) of title 49</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1), (d), and (f), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s114/s">section 114(s) of title 49</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dE/tV/s568/a">Pub. L. 110–161, div. E, title V, § 568(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2092">121 Stat. 2092</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13416, referred to in subsec. (b)(3)(E), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t49/s114/w">Section 114(w) of title 49</ref>, referred to in subsec. (g), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s114/v">section 114(v) of title 49</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dK/s1904/b/1/I">Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, § 1904(b)(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3545">132 Stat. 3545</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
