<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb57372bc-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208"><num value="1208">§ 1208.</num><heading> Pipeline security and incident recovery plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372bd-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, and in accordance with the Annex to the Memorandum of Understanding executed on <date date="2006-08-09">August 9, 2006</date>, the National Strategy for Transportation Security, and Homeland Security Presidential Directive–7, shall develop a pipeline security and incident recovery protocols plan. The plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57372be-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> for the Government to provide increased security support to the most critical interstate and intrastate natural gas and hazardous liquid transmission pipeline infrastructure and operations as determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1207">section 1207 of this title</ref> when—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb57372bf-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> under severe security threat levels of alert; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb57372c0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under specific security threat information relating to such pipeline infrastructure or operations exists; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57372c1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an incident recovery protocol plan, developed in conjunction with interstate and intrastate transmission and distribution pipeline operators and terminals and facilities operators connected to pipelines, to develop protocols to ensure the continued transportation of natural gas and hazardous liquids to essential markets and for essential public health or national defense uses in the event of an incident affecting the interstate and intrastate natural gas and hazardous liquid transmission and distribution pipeline system, which shall include protocols for restoring essential services supporting pipelines and granting access to pipeline operators for pipeline infrastructure repair, replacement, or bypass following an incident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372c2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing private and public sector efforts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The plan shall take into account actions taken or planned by both private and public entities to address identified pipeline security issues and assess the effective integration of such actions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372c3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Transportation, interstate and intrastate transmission and distribution pipeline operators, nonprofit employee organizations representing pipeline employees, emergency responders, offerors, State pipeline safety agencies, public safety officials, and other relevant parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372c4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372c5-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the plan required by subsection (a), including an estimate of the private and public sector costs to implement any recommendations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb57372c6-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s1208/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Format</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may submit the report in both classified and redacted formats if the Secretary determines that such action is appropriate or necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb57372c7-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXV/s1558">Pub. L. 110–53, title XV, § 1558</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/476">121 Stat. 476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
