<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4edc766-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193"><num value="193">§ 193.</num><heading> Technology clearinghouse to encourage and support innovative solutions to enhance homeland security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc767-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, shall establish and promote a program to encourage technological innovation in facilitating the mission of the Department (as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc768-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements of program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The program described in subsection (a) shall include the following components:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4edc769-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The establishment of a centralized Federal clearinghouse for information relating to technologies that would further the mission of the Department for dissemination, as appropriate, to Federal, State, and local government and private sector entities for additional review, purchase, or use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4edc76a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The issuance of announcements seeking unique and innovative technologies to advance the mission of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4edc76b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The establishment of a technical assistance team to assist in screening, as appropriate, proposals submitted to the Secretary (except as provided in subsection (c)(2)) to assess the feasibility, scientific and technical merits, and estimated cost of such proposals, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4edc76c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The provision of guidance, recommendations, and technical assistance, as appropriate, to assist Federal, State, and local government and private sector efforts to evaluate and implement the use of technologies described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4edc76d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The provision of information for persons seeking guidance on how to pursue proposals to develop or deploy technologies that would enhance homeland security, including information relating to Federal funding, regulation, or acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc76e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Miscellaneous provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc76f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary or the technical assistance team established under subsection (b)(3) to set standards for technology to be used by the Department, any other executive agency, any State or local government entity, or any private sector entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc770-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain proposals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The technical assistance team established under subsection (b)(3) shall not consider or evaluate proposals submitted in response to a solicitation for offers for a pending procurement or for a specific agency requirement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4edc771-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s193/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Technical Support Working Group (organized under the April 1982 National Security Decision Directive Numbered 30).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4edc772-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tIII/s313">Pub. L. 107–296, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2176">116 Stat. 2176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
