<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4f9d54a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212"><num value="212">§ 212.</num><heading> Retention of Customs revenue functions by Secretary of the Treasury</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d54b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of Customs revenue functions by Secretary of the Treasury</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d54c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding section 203(a)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002031"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be section “203(1)”.</note> of this title, authority related to Customs revenue functions that was vested in the Secretary of the Treasury by law before the effective date of this chapter under those provisions of law set forth in paragraph (2) shall not be transferred to the Secretary by reason of this chapter, and on and after the effective date of this chapter, the Secretary of the Treasury may delegate any such authority to the Secretary at the discretion of the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with the Secretary regarding the exercise of any such authority not delegated to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d54d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Statutes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of law referred to in paragraph (1) are the following: the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.]; section 249 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3">19 U.S.C. 3</ref>); <ref href="/us/act/1923-03-04/s2">section 2 of the Act of March 4, 1923</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s6">19 U.S.C. 6</ref>); section 13031 of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s58c">19 U.S.C. 58c</ref>); section 251 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s66">19 U.S.C. 66</ref>); <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-26/s1">section 1 of the Act of June 26, 1930</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s68">19 U.S.C. 68</ref>); the Foreign Trade Zones Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s81a">19 U.S.C. 81a</ref> et seq.); <ref href="/us/act/1911-03-02/s1">section 1 of the Act of March 2, 1911</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s198">19 U.S.C. 198</ref>); the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">19 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.]; the Trade Agreements Act of 1979; the North American Free Trade Area Implementation Act; the Uruguay Round Agreements Act; the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.]; the Andean Trade Preference Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">19 U.S.C. 3201</ref> et seq.]; the African Growth and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3701">19 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.]; and any other provision of law vesting customs revenue functions in the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d54e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of Customs revenue functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d54f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary may not consolidate, discontinue, or diminish those functions described in paragraph (2) performed by U.S. Customs and Border Protection (as established under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of this title</ref>) on or after the effective date of this chapter, reduce the staffing level, or reduce the resources attributable to such functions, and the Secretary shall ensure that an appropriate management structure is implemented to carry out such functions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d550-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The functions referred to in paragraph (1) are those functions performed by the following personnel, and associated support staff, of U.S. Customs and Border Protection on the day before the effective date of this chapter: Import Specialists, Entry Specialists, Drawback Specialists, National Import Specialist, Fines and Penalties Specialists, attorneys of the Office of Regulations and Rulings, Customs Auditors, International Trade Specialists, Financial Systems Specialists.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f9d551-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s212/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> New personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to appoint up to 20 new personnel to work with personnel of the Department in performing customs revenue functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4f9d552-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tIV/s412">Pub. L. 107–296, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2179">116 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tVIII/s802/g/1/B/iii/II">Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(g)(1)(B)(iii)(II)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/211">130 Stat. 211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4f9d553-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4f9d554-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4f9d555-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b), is 60 days after <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2135">116 Stat. 2135</ref>, known as the Homeland Security Act of 2002, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tariff Act of 1930, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">act June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/590">46 Stat. 590</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 4 (§ 1202 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1654">section 1654 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Trade Zones Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/ch590">act June 18, 1934, ch. 590</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/998">48 Stat. 998</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 1A (§ 81a et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1978">88 Stat. 1978</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 12 (§ 2101 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">section 2101 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Agreements Act of 1979, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/144">93 Stat. 144</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2501">section 2501 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The North American Free Trade Area Implementation Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), probably means the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, <ref href="/us/pl/103/182">Pub. L. 103–182</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2057">107 Stat. 2057</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3301">section 3301 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Uruguay Round Agreements Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4809">108 Stat. 4809</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501">section 3501 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/67">Pub. L. 98–67</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/384">97 Stat. 384</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 2701 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">section 2701 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Andean Trade Preference Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/102/182">Pub. L. 102–182</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1236">105 Stat. 1236</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 20 (§ 3201 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">section 3201 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The African Growth and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/106/200">Pub. L. 106–200</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/252">114 Stat. 252</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 3701 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3701">section 3701 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4f9d556-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref> substituted “U.S. Customs and Border Protection” for “the United States Customs Service” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
