<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4fc2071-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225"><num value="225">§ 225.</num><heading> Reports, evaluations, and research regarding drug interdiction at and between ports of entry</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc2072-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Research on additional technologies to detect fentanyl</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, shall research additional technological solutions to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fc2073-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> target and detect illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals, including low-purity fentanyl, especially in counterfeit pressed tablets, and illicit pill press molds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fc2074-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enhance detection of such counterfeit pressed tablets through nonintrusive, noninvasive, and other advanced screening technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc2075-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of current technologies and strategies in illicit drug interdiction and procurement decisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc2076-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, shall establish a program to collect available data and develop metrics to measure how technologies and strategies used by the Department of Homeland Security, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and other relevant Federal agencies have helped detect trafficked illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals or deter illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals from being trafficked into the United States at and between land, air, and sea ports of entry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc2077-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The data and metrics program established pursuant to paragraph (1) may consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4fc2078-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the rate of detection of illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals at land, air, and sea ports of entry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4fc2079-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> investigations and intelligence sharing into the origins of illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals within the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4fc207a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> other data or metrics considered appropriate by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc207b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate and in the coordination with the officials referred to in paragraph (1), may update the data and metrics program established pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc207c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc207d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary of Homeland Security</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than one year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy shall, based on the data collected and metrics developed pursuant to the program established pursuant to paragraph (1), submit to the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4fc207e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> examines and analyzes current technologies, including pilot technologies, deployed at land, air, and sea ports of entry to assess how well such technologies detect, deter, and address illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4fc207f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> examines and analyzes current technologies, including pilot technologies, deployed between land ports of entry to assess how well and accurately such technologies detect, deter, interdict, and address illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogs, and precursor chemicals; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002035"><num>1</num> So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.</note></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc2080-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s225/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than one year after the submission of each of the first three reports required under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that evaluates and, as appropriate, makes recommendations to improve, the collection of data under the program established pursuant to paragraph (1) and metrics used in the subsequent reports required under such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4fc2081-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dG/tLXXI/s7136">Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7136</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3650">136 Stat. 3650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4fc2082-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4fc2083-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4fc2084-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
