<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5165ec7-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347"><num value="347">§ 347.</num><heading> Quadrennial homeland security review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ec8-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ec9-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Quadrennial reviews required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In fiscal year 2009, and every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a review of the homeland security of the Nation (in this section referred to as a “quadrennial homeland security review”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165eca-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of reviews</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each quadrennial homeland security review shall be a comprehensive examination of the homeland security strategy of the Nation, including recommendations regarding the long-term strategy and priorities of the Nation for homeland security and guidance on the programs, assets, capabilities, budget, policies, and authorities of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ecb-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct each quadrennial homeland security review under this subsection in consultation with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ecc-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the heads of other Federal agencies, including the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture the Secretary of Energy,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002060"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> and the Director of National Intelligence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ecd-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> key officials of the Department, including the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ece-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> representatives from appropriate advisory committees established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s451">section 451 of this title</ref>, including the Homeland Security Advisory Council and the Homeland Security Science and Technology Advisory Committee, or otherwise established, including the Aviation Security Advisory Committee established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44946">section 44946 of title 49</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ecf-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> other relevant governmental and nongovernmental entities, including State, local, and tribal government officials, members of Congress, private sector representatives, academics, and other policy experts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ed0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship with future years homeland security program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that each review conducted under this section is coordinated with the Future Years Homeland Security Program required under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s454">section 454 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ed1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In each quadrennial homeland security review, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5165ed2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> delineate and update, as appropriate, the national homeland security strategy, consistent with appropriate national and Department strategies, strategic plans, and Homeland Security Presidential Directives, including the National Strategy for Homeland Security, the National Response Plan, and the Department Security Strategic Plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5165ed3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> outline and prioritize the full range of the critical homeland security mission areas of the Nation based on the risk assessment required pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(B);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5165ed4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> describe, to the extent practicable, the interagency cooperation, preparedness of Federal response assets, infrastructure, resources required, and other elements of the homeland security program and policies of the Nation associated with the national homeland security strategy, required to execute successfully the full range of missions called for in the national homeland security strategy described in paragraph (1) and the homeland security mission areas outlined under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5165ed5-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identify, to the extent practicable, the resources required to execute the full range of missions called for in the national homeland security strategy described in paragraph (1) and the homeland security mission areas outlined under paragraph (2), including any resources identified from redundant, wasteful, or unnecessary capabilities or capacities that may be redirected to better support other existing capabilities or capacities, as the case may be; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5165ed6-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> include an assessment of the organizational alignment of the Department with the national homeland security strategy referred to in paragraph (1) and the homeland security mission areas outlined under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ed7-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ed8-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the date of the submission of the President’s budget for the fiscal year after the fiscal year in which a quadrennial homeland security review is conducted, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report regarding that quadrennial homeland security review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ed9-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165eda-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the results of the quadrennial homeland security review;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165edb-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a risk assessment of the assumed or defined national homeland security interests of the Nation that were examined for the purposes of that review or for purposes of the quadrennial EMP and GMD risk assessment under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s195f/d/1/E">section 195f(d)(1)(E) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165edc-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the national homeland security strategy, including a prioritized list of the critical homeland security missions of the Nation, as required under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165edd-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to the extent practicable, a description of the interagency cooperation, preparedness of Federal response assets, infrastructure, resources required, and other elements of the homeland security program and policies of the Nation associated with the national homeland security strategy, required to execute successfully the full range of missions called for in the applicable national homeland security strategy referred to in subsection (b)(1) and the homeland security mission areas outlined under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ede-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> an assessment of the organizational alignment of the Department with the applicable national homeland security strategy referred to in subsection (b)(1) and the homeland security mission areas outlined under subsection (b)(2), including the Department’s organizational structure, management systems, budget and accounting systems, human resources systems, procurement systems, and physical and technical infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165edf-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> to the extent practicable, a discussion of cooperation among Federal agencies in the effort to promote national homeland security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ee0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> to the extent practicable, a discussion of cooperation between the Federal Government and State, local, and tribal governments in preventing terrorist attacks and preparing for emergency response to threats and risks to national homeland security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ee1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> any other matter the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165ee2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Documentation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall retain and, upon request, provide to Congress the following documentation regarding each quadrennial homeland security review:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ee3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Records regarding the consultation carried out pursuant to subsection (a)(3), including the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165ee4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> All written communications, including communications sent out by the Secretary and feedback submitted to the Secretary through technology, online communications tools, in-person discussions, and the interagency process.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165ee5-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Information on how feedback received by the Secretary informed each such quadrennial homeland security review.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5165ee6-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Information regarding the risk assessment required pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(B), including the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165ee7-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The risk model utilized to generate such risk assessment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165ee8-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Information, including data used in the risk model, utilized to generate such risk assessment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165ee9-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Sources of information, including other risk assessments, utilized to generate such risk assessment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5165eea-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Information on assumptions, weighing factors, and subjective judgments utilized to generate such risk assessment, together with information on the rationale or basis thereof.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165eeb-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall, consistent with the protection of national security and other sensitive matters, make each report submitted under paragraph (1) publicly available on the Internet website of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165eec-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after the submission of each report required under subsection (c)(1), the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate information on the degree to which the findings and recommendations developed in the quadrennial homeland security review that is the subject of such report were integrated into the acquisition strategy and expenditure plans for the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5165eed-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s347/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5165eee-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tVII/s707">Pub. L. 107–296, title VII, § 707</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXXIV/s2401/a">Pub. L. 110–53, title XXIV, § 2401(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/543">121 Stat. 543</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXIX/s1902/b">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XIX, § 1902(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2672">130 Stat. 2672</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXVII/s1740/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1740(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1824">133 Stat. 1824</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dG/tLXXI/s7141/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7141(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3652">136 Stat. 3652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5165eef-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5165ef0-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5165ef1-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(3)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/2/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “based on the risk assessment required pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(B)” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/2/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “, to the extent practicable,” after “describe” and substituted “resources required” for “budget plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/2/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(2)(C)</ref>, inserted “, to the extent practicable,” after “identify” and substituted “resources required to” for “budget plan required to provide sufficient resources to successfully” and “, including any resources identified from redundant, wasteful, or unnecessary capabilities or capacities that may be redirected to better support other existing capabilities or capacities, as the case may be; and” for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/2/D">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(2)(D)</ref>, (E), struck out par. (6) which read as follows: “review and assess the effectiveness of the mechanisms of the Department for executing the process of turning the requirements developed in the quadrennial homeland security review into an acquisition strategy and expenditure plan within the Department.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “60 days after the date of the submission of the President’s budget for the fiscal year after the fiscal year” for “December 31 of the year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/i">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “risk assessment of” for “description of the threats to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “, as required under subsection (b)(2)” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/iii">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(iii)</ref>, inserted “to the extent practicable,” before “a description” and substituted “resources required” for “budget plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/iv">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(iv)</ref>, inserted “to the extent practicable,” before “a discussion” and struck out “the status of” before “cooperation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/v">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(v)</ref>, inserted “to the extent practicable,” before “a discussion”, “and risks” before “to national homeland”, and “and” after semicolon at end and struck out “the status of” before “cooperation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(H), (I). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/B/vi">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(B)(vi)</ref>, (vii), redesignated subpar. (I) as (H) and struck out former subpar. (H) which read as follows: “an explanation of any underlying assumptions used in conducting the review; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/3/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(3)(C)</ref>, (D), added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s7141/a/4">Pub. L. 117–263, § 7141(a)(4)</ref>, (5), added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1740/b/1">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1740(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “the Secretary of Energy,” after “the Secretary of Agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1740/b/2">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1740(b)(2)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or for purposes of the quadrennial EMP and GMD risk assessment under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s195f/d/1/E">section 195f(d)(1)(E) of this title</ref>” after review, was executed by making the insertion after “review” as if quotation marks had appeared around the word in the directory language, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> inserted “, including the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans” after “Department”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5165ef2-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5165ef3-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dG/tLXXI/s7141/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7141(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3654">136 Stat. 3654</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dG/tLXXI/s7141/b">“The amendments made by this Act [probably means “this section”, amending this section] shall apply with respect to a quadrennial homeland security review conducted after <date date="2021-12-31">December 31, 2021</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5165ef4-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Preparation for First Quadrennial Homeland Security Review</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXXIV/s2401/b">Pub. L. 110–53, title XXIV, § 2401(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/546">121 Stat. 546</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/53/tXXIV/s2401/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>During fiscal years 2007 and 2008, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make preparations to conduct the first quadrennial homeland security review under section 707 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 [<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s347">6 U.S.C. 347</ref>], as added by subsection (a), in fiscal year 2009, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> determining the tasks to be performed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> estimating the human, financial, and other resources required to perform each task;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> establishing the schedule for the execution of all project tasks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> ensuring that these resources will be available as needed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> all other preparations considered necessary by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>], the Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the Internet website of the Department of Homeland Security a detailed resource plan specifying the estimated budget and number of staff members that will be required for preparation of the first quadrennial homeland security review.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
