<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb51d8a67-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396"><num value="396">§ 396.</num><heading> Lead system integrator; financial interests</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51d8a68-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to contracts entered into after <date date="2007-07-01">July 1, 2007</date>, and except as provided in subsection (b), no entity performing lead system integrator functions in the acquisition of a major system by the Department of Homeland Security may have any direct financial interest in the development or construction of any individual system or element of any system of systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51d8a69-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An entity described in subsection (a) may have a direct financial interest in the development or construction of an individual system or element of a system of systems if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb51d8a6a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Homeland Security certifies to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation of the Senate that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb51d8a6b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the entity was selected by the Department of Homeland Security as a contractor to develop or construct the system or element concerned through the use of competitive procedures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb51d8a6c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Department took appropriate steps to prevent any organizational conflict of interest in the selection process; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb51d8a6d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the entity was selected by a subcontractor to serve as a lower-tier subcontractor, through a process over which the entity exercised no control.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51d8a6e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude an entity described in subsection (a) from performing work necessary to integrate two or more individual systems or elements of a system of systems with each other.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51d8a6f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s396/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations update</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2007-07-01">July 1, 2007</date>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall update the acquisition regulations of the Department of Homeland Security in order to specify fully in such regulations the matters with respect to lead system integrators set forth in this section. Included in such regulations shall be: (1) a precise and comprehensive definition of the term “lead system integrator”, modeled after that used by the Department of Defense; and (2) a specification of various types of contracts and fee structures that are appropriate for use by lead system integrators in the production, fielding, and sustainment of complex systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb51d8a70-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/28/tVI/s6405">Pub. L. 110–28, title VI, § 6405</ref>, <date date="2007-05-25">May 25, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/176">121 Stat. 176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb51d8a71-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb51d8a72-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb51d8a73-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans’ Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
