<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb524b610-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s469a"><num value="469a">§ 469a.</num><heading> Collection of fees from non-Federal participants in meetings</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For fiscal year 2010 and thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security may collect fees from any non-Federal participant in a conference, seminar, exhibition, symposium, or similar meeting conducted by the Department of Homeland Security in advance of the conference, either directly or by contract, and those fees shall be credited to the appropriation or account from which the costs of the conference, seminar, exhibition, symposium, or similar meeting are paid and shall be available to pay the costs of the Department of Homeland Security with respect to the conference or to reimburse the Department for costs incurred with respect to the conference: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event the total amount of fees collected with respect to a conference exceeds the actual costs of the Department of Homeland Security with respect to the conference, the amount of such excess shall be deposited into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall provide a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than <date date="2011-01-05">January 5, 2011</date>, providing the level of collections and a summary by agency of the purposes and levels of expenditures for the prior fiscal year,.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002080"><num>1</num> So in original.</note></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb524b611-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/83/tV/s554">Pub. L. 111–83, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2179">123 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dF/tV/s510/c">Pub. L. 114–113, div. F, title V, § 510(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2514">129 Stat. 2514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb524b612-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb524b613-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb524b614-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2010, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb524b615-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—<ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> struck out “and shall report annually thereafter” before period at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
