<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb53c8417-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611"><num value="611">§ 611.</num><heading> Administration and coordination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c8418-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional coordination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53c8419-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> all recipients of grants administered by the Department to prevent, prepare for, protect against, or respond to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters (excluding assistance provided under section 203, title IV, or title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</ref>, 5170 et seq., and 5191 et seq.)) coordinate, as appropriate, their prevention, preparedness, and protection efforts with neighboring State, local, and tribal governments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53c841a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all high-risk urban areas and other recipients of grants administered by the Department to prevent, prepare for, protect against, or respond to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters (excluding assistance provided under section 203, title IV, or title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</ref>, 5170 et seq., and 5191 et seq.)) that include or substantially affect parts or all of more than 1 State coordinate, as appropriate, across State boundaries, including, where appropriate, through the use of regional working groups and requirements for regional plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c841b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Planning committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c841c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any State or high-risk urban area receiving a grant under section 604 or 605 of this title shall establish a State planning committee or urban area working group to assist in preparation and revision of the State, regional, or local homeland security plan or the threat and hazard identification and risk assessment, as the case may be, and to assist in determining effective funding priorities for grants under such sections.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c841d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c841e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State planning committees and urban area working groups referred to in paragraph (1) shall include at least one representative from each of the following significant stakeholders:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c841f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Local or tribal government officials.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c8420-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Emergency response providers, which shall include representatives of the fire service, law enforcement, emergency medical services, and emergency managers.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c8421-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Public health officials and other appropriate medical practitioners.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c8422-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Individuals representing educational institutions, including elementary schools, community colleges, and other institutions of higher education.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c8423-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> State and regional interoperable communications coordinators, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53c8424-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> State and major urban area fusion centers, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c8425-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographic representation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The members of the State planning committee or urban area working group, as the case may be, shall be a representative group of individuals from the counties, cities, towns, and Indian tribes within the State or high-risk urban area, including, as appropriate, representatives of rural, high-population, and high-threat jurisdictions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c8426-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing planning committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require that any State or high-risk urban area create a State planning committee or urban area working group, as the case may be, if that State or high-risk urban area has established and uses a multijurisdictional planning committee or commission that meets the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53c8427-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that, in order to ensure that the Nation is most effectively able to prevent, prepare for, protect against, and respond to all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53c8428-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Department should administer a coherent and coordinated system of both terrorism-focused and all-hazards grants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53c8429-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> there should be a continuing and appropriate balance between funding for terrorism-focused and all-hazards preparedness, as reflected in the authorizations of appropriations for grants under the amendments made by titles I and II, as applicable, of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53c842a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s611/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with respect to terrorism-focused grants, it is necessary to ensure both that the target capabilities of the highest risk areas are achieved quickly and that basic levels of preparedness, as measured by the attainment of target capabilities, are achieved nationwide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb53c842b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXX/s2021">Pub. L. 107–296, title XX, § 2021</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tI/s101">Pub. L. 110–53, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/285">121 Stat. 285</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXIX/s1911">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XIX, § 1911</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2682">130 Stat. 2682</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/278/s2/g/7/C">Pub. L. 115–278, § 2(g)(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-11-16">Nov. 16, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4180">132 Stat. 4180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb53c842c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb53c842d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb53c842e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/143">88 Stat. 143</ref>. Section 203 of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5133">section 5133 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. Titles IV and V of the Act are classified generally to subchapters IV (§ 5170 et seq.) and IV–A (§ 5191 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 68 of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/110/53">Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/266">121 Stat. 266</ref>. Title I of the Act enacted this subchapter and amended sections 318, 321a, 594, 596, and 752 of this title. Title II of the Act amended <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s762">section 762 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5196c">section 5196c of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of titles I and II to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb53c842f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/278">Pub. L. 115–278</ref> redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) related to interagency coordination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) related to planning committees to assist in preparation and revision of State, regional, or local homeland security plans, and to assist in determining effective funding priorities for grants under sections 604 and 605 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
