<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5520816-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l"><num value="665l">§ 665l.</num><heading> School and daycare protection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5520817-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report regarding the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5520818-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Department of Homeland Security’s activities, policies, and plans to enhance the security of early childhood education programs, elementary schools, and secondary schools during the preceding year that includes information on the Department’s activities through the Federal School Safety Clearinghouse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5520819-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Information on all structures or efforts within the Department intended to bolster coordination among departmental components and offices involved in carrying out paragraph (1) and, with respect to each structure or effort, specificity on which components and offices are involved and which component or office leads such structure or effort.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb552081a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A detailed description of the measures used to ensure privacy rights, civil rights, and civil liberties protections in carrying out these activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb552081b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after the submission of each report required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a briefing regarding such report and the status of efforts to carry out plans included in such report for the preceding year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb552081c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s665l/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the terms “early childhood education program”, “elementary school”, and “secondary school” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb552081d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dG/tLXXI/s7103">Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7103</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3621">136 Stat. 3621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb552081e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb552081f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5520820-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
