<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb554521e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a"><num value="681a">§ 681a.</num><heading> Cyber incident review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb554521f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Center shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545220-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> receive, aggregate, analyze, and secure, using processes consistent with the processes developed pursuant to the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) reports from covered entities related to a covered cyber incident to assess the effectiveness of security controls, identify tactics, techniques, and procedures adversaries use to overcome those controls and other cybersecurity purposes, including to assess potential impact of cyber incidents on public health and safety and to enhance situational awareness of cyber threats across critical infrastructure sectors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545221-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> coordinate and share information with appropriate Federal departments and agencies to identify and track ransom payments, including those utilizing virtual currencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545222-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> leverage information gathered about cyber incidents to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5545223-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enhance the quality and effectiveness of information sharing and coordination efforts with appropriate entities, including agencies, sector coordinating councils, Information Sharing and Analysis Organizations, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, technology providers, critical infrastructure owners and operators, cybersecurity and cyber incident response firms, and security researchers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5545224-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide appropriate entities, including sector coordinating councils, Information Sharing and Analysis Organizations, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, technology providers, cybersecurity and cyber incident response firms, and security researchers, with timely, actionable, and anonymized reports of cyber incident campaigns and trends, including, to the maximum extent practicable, related contextual information, cyber threat indicators, and defensive measures, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681e">section 681e of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545225-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> establish mechanisms to receive feedback from stakeholders on how the Agency can most effectively receive covered cyber incident reports, ransom payment reports, and other voluntarily provided information, and how the Agency can most effectively support private sector cybersecurity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545226-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> facilitate the timely sharing, on a voluntary basis, between relevant critical infrastructure owners and operators of information relating to covered cyber incidents and ransom payments, particularly with respect to ongoing cyber threats or security vulnerabilities and identify and disseminate ways to prevent or mitigate similar cyber incidents in the future;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545227-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> for a covered cyber incident, including a ransomware attack, that also satisfies the definition of a significant cyber incident, or is part of a group of related cyber incidents that together satisfy such definition, conduct a review of the details surrounding the covered cyber incident or group of those incidents and identify and disseminate ways to prevent or mitigate similar incidents in the future;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545228-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> with respect to covered cyber incident reports under section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002121">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002121"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “sections”.</note> 681b(a) and 681c of this title involving an ongoing cyber threat or security vulnerability, immediately review those reports for cyber threat indicators that can be anonymized and disseminated, with defensive measures, to appropriate stakeholders, in coordination with other divisions within the Agency, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545229-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> publish quarterly unclassified, public reports that describe aggregated, anonymized observations, findings, and recommendations based on covered cyber incident reports, which may be based on the unclassified information contained in the briefings required under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb554522a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> proactively identify opportunities, consistent with the protections in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681e">section 681e of this title</ref>, to leverage and utilize data on cyber incidents in a manner that enables and strengthens cybersecurity research carried out by academic institutions and other private sector organizations, to the greatest extent practicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb554522b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681e">section 681e of this title</ref> and subsection (b) of this section, as soon as possible but not later than 24 hours after receiving a covered cyber incident report, ransom payment report, voluntarily submitted information pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681c">section 681c of this title</ref>, or information received pursuant to a request for information or subpoena under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681d">section 681d of this title</ref>, make available the information to appropriate Sector Risk Management Agencies and other appropriate Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb554522c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency sharing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President or a designee of the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb554522d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> may establish a specific time requirement for sharing information under subsection (a)(10); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb554522e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall determine the appropriate Federal agencies under subsection (a)(10).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb554522f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic briefing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the effective date of the final rule required under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s681b/b">section 681b(b) of this title</ref>, and on the first day of each month thereafter, the Director, in consultation with the National Cyber Director, the Attorney General, and the Director of National Intelligence, shall provide to the majority leader of the Senate, the minority leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a briefing that characterizes the national cyber threat landscape, including the threat facing Federal agencies and covered entities, and applicable intelligence and law enforcement information, covered cyber incidents, and ransomware attacks, as of the date of the briefing, which shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545230-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> include the total number of reports submitted under sections 681b and 681c of this title during the preceding month, including a breakdown of required and voluntary reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545231-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> include any identified trends in covered cyber incidents and ransomware attacks over the course of the preceding month and as compared to previous reports, including any trends related to the information collected in the reports submitted under sections 681b and 681c of this title, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5545232-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the infrastructure, tactics, and techniques malicious cyber actors commonly use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5545233-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> intelligence gaps that have impeded, or currently are impeding, the ability to counter covered cyber incidents and ransomware threats;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545234-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> include a summary of the known uses of the information in reports submitted under sections 681b and 681c of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5545235-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s681a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> include an unclassified portion, but may include a classified component.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5545236-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXXII/s2241">Pub. L. 107–296, title XXII, § 2241</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dY/s103/a/2">Pub. L. 117–103, div. Y, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1040">136 Stat. 1040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5545237-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5545238-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb5545239-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is title I of div. N of <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2936">129 Stat. 2936</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1501 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
