<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb55b7d67-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s763a"><num value="763a">§ 763a.</num><heading> Training for Federal Government, foreign governments, or private entities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In fiscal year 2013 and thereafter: (a) the Center for Domestic Preparedness may provide training to emergency response providers from the Federal Government, foreign governments, or private entities, if the Center for Domestic Preparedness is reimbursed for the cost of such training, and any reimbursement under this subsection shall be credited to the account from which the expenditure being reimbursed was made and shall be available, without fiscal year limitation, for the purposes for which amounts in the account may be expended; (b) the head of the Center for Domestic Preparedness shall ensure that any training provided under (a) does not interfere with the primary mission of the Center to train State and local emergency response providers; and (c) subject to (b), nothing in (a) prohibits the Center for Domestic Preparedness from providing training to employees of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in existing chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, explosives, mass casualty, and medical surge courses pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s4103">5 U.S.C. 4103</ref> without reimbursement for the cost of such training.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb55b7d68-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/6/dD/tIII">Pub. L. 113–6, div. D, title III</ref>, <date date="2013-03-26">Mar. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/359">127 Stat. 359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb55b7d69-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb55b7d6a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb55b7d6b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2013, and not as part of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
