<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5603885-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941"><num value="941">§ 941.</num><heading> Strategic plan to enhance the security of the international supply chain</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603886-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal, State, local, and tribal government agencies and private sector stakeholders responsible for security matters that affect or relate to the movement of containers through the international supply chain, shall develop, implement, and update, triennially, a strategic plan to enhance the security of the international supply chain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603887-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The strategic plan required under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603888-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of Federal, State, local, and tribal government agencies and private-sector stakeholders that relate to the security of the movement of containers through the international supply chain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603889-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identify and address gaps and unnecessary overlaps in the roles, responsibilities, or authorities described in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identify and make recommendations regarding legislative, regulatory, and organizational changes necessary to improve coordination among the entities or to enhance the security of the international supply chain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide measurable goals, including objectives, mechanisms, and a schedule, for furthering the security of commercial operations from point of origin to point of destination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> build on available resources and consider costs and benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> provide incentives for additional voluntary measures to enhance cargo security, as recommended by the Commissioner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> consider the impact of supply chain security requirements on small- and medium-sized companies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb560388f-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> include a process for sharing intelligence and information with private-sector stakeholders to assist in their security efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603890-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> identify a framework for prudent and measured response in the event of a transportation security incident involving the international supply chain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603891-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> provide protocols for the expeditious resumption of the flow of trade in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s942">section 942 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603892-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> consider the linkages between supply chain security and security programs within other systems of movement, including travel security and terrorism finance programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5603893-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> expand upon and relate to existing strategies and plans, including the National Response Plan, the National Maritime Transportation Security Plan, the National Strategy for Maritime Security, and the 8 supporting plans of the Strategy, as required by Homeland Security Presidential Directive 13.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603894-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing protocols under subsection (b)(10), the Secretary shall consult with Federal, State, local, and private sector stakeholders, including the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee and the Commercial Operations Advisory Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603895-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Communication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent practicable, the strategic plan developed under subsection (a) shall provide for coordination with, and lines of communication among, appropriate Federal, State, local, and private-sector stakeholders on law enforcement actions, intermodal rerouting plans, and other strategic infrastructure issues resulting from a transportation security incident or transportation disruption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603896-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of Advisory Committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As part of the consultations described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, utilize the Homeland Security Advisory Committee, the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee, and the Commercial Operations Advisory Committee to review, as necessary, the draft strategic plan and any subsequent updates to the strategic plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603897-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> International standards and practices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In furtherance of the strategic plan required under subsection (a), the Secretary is encouraged to consider proposed or established standards and practices of foreign governments and international organizations, including the International Maritime Organization, the World Customs Organization, the International Labor Organization, and the International Organization for Standardization, as appropriate, to establish standards and best practices for the security of containers moving through the international supply chain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603898-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5603899-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2006-10-13">October 13, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the strategic plan required by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb560389a-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d" identifier="/us/usc/t6/s941/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 270 days after <date date="2018-10-05">October 5, 2018</date>, and triennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains any updates to the strategic plan under subsection (a) since the prior report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb560389b-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/347/tII/s201">Pub. L. 109–347, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1901">120 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dJ/s1804">Pub. L. 115–254, div. J, § 1804</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3533">132 Stat. 3533</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb560389c-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb560389d-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb560389e-47c4-11f1-9665-b3e99855dc0d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1804/1">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1804(1)</ref>, substituted “triennially” for “as appropriate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1804/2/A">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1804(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Reports” for “Report” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1804/2/B">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1804(2)(B)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Not later than 3 years after the date on which the strategic plan is submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains an update of the strategic plan.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
