<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7951a920-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022"><num value="1022">§ 1022.</num><heading> Economic Report of President; coverage; supplementary reports; reference to Congressional joint committee; percentage rate of unemployment; definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7951a921-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Time of submission; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall annually transmit to the Congress not later than 10 days after the submission of the budget under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, with copies transmitted to the Governor of each State and to other appropriate State and local officials, an economic report (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Economic Report”) together with the annual report of the Council of Economic Advisers submitted in accord with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1023/c">section 1023(c) of this title</ref>, setting forth—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a922-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the current and foreseeable trends in the levels of employment, unemployment, production, capital formation, real income, Federal budget outlays and receipts, productivity, international trade and payments, and prices, and a review and analysis of recent domestic and international developments affecting economic trends in the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a923-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a924-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> annual numerical goals for employment and unemployment, production, real income, productivity, Federal outlays as a proportion of gross national product, and prices for the calendar year in which the Economic Report is transmitted and for the following calendar year, designated as short-term goals, which shall be consistent with achieving as rapidly as feasible the goals of full employment and production, increased real income, balanced growth, fiscal policies that would establish the share of an expanding gross national product accounted for by Federal outlays at the lowest level consistent with national needs and priorities, a balanced Federal budget, adequate productivity growth, price stability, achievement of an improved trade balance, and proper attention to national priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a925-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> annual numerical goals as specified in subparagraph (A) for the three successive calendar years, designated as medium term goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a926-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> employment objectives for certain significant subgroups of the labor force, including youth, women, minorities, handicapped persons, veterans, and middle-aged and older persons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7951a927-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a program for carrying out the policy declared in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref>, together with such recommendations for legislation as the President may deem necessary or desirable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7951a928-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplementary reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may transmit from time to time to the Congress reports supplementary to the Economic Report, each of which shall include such supplementary or revised recommendations as he may deem necessary or desirable to achieve the policy declared in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7951a929-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Referral to joint committee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Economic Report, and all supplementary reports transmitted under subsection (b), shall, when transmitted to Congress, be referred to the joint committee created by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1024">section 1024 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7951a92a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rate of unemployment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3101">15 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.] the percentage rate of unemployment as <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002292">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002292"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “is”.</note> a percentage of the civilian labor force as set forth by the Bureau of Labor Statistics in the Department of Labor as computed under the procedures in effect as of <date date="1978-10-27">October 27, 1978</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7951a92b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “Inflation”; “prices”; “reasonable price stability” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3101">15 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.], the terms “inflation”, “prices”, and “reasonable price stability” refer to the rate of change or level of the consumer price index as set forth by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7951a92c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-02-20/ch33/s3">Feb. 20, 1946, ch. 33, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/24">60 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753">Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 226, <ref href="/us/stat/60/838">60 Stat. 838</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-06-18/ch399/s1">June 18, 1956, ch. 399, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/289">70 Stat. 289</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/tI/s103">Pub. L. 95–523, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1892">92 Stat. 1892</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/10/s6/d">Pub. L. 96–10, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="1979-05-10">May 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/24">93 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13112/e">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13112(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-609">104 Stat. 1388–609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7951a92d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7951a92e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7951a92f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978, referred to in subsecs. (d) and (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/523">Pub. L. 95–523</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1887">92 Stat. 1887</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 58 (§ 3101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7951a930-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1023/c">section 1023(c) of this title</ref>” was in the original “section 11(c) of this Act”, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1024/c">section 1024(c) of this title</ref>. The citation has been editorially translated as indicated to reflect the probable intent of Congress because the reporting requirements appear in section 10(c) of the Act, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1023/c">section 1023(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7951a931-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, which directed the substitution of “annually transmit to the Congress not later than 10 days after the submission of the budget under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>” for “transmit to the Congress during the first twenty days of each regular session” in section “103(a) of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a">15 U.S.C. 1022(a)</ref>”, was executed to this section, section 3 of the Employment Act of 1946, as amended by that Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/96/10">Pub. L. 96–10</ref> inserted reference to Federal outlays as a proportion of gross national product.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/s103/a">Pub. L. 95–523, § 103(a)</ref>, among other changes, inserted provisions relating to the annual report of the Council of Economic Advisers and the inclusion in the President’s Economic Report of annual numerical goals for employment, unemployment, production etc., and employment objectives for certain subgroups and struck out provisions relating to the review of the Federal Government’s economic program and economic conditions affecting employment in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/s103/b">Pub. L. 95–523, § 103(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1956-06-18">June 18, 1956</date>, substituted “not later than January 20 of each year” for “at the beginning of each regular session (commencing with the year 1947)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1946-08-02">Aug. 2, 1946</date>, substituted “at” for “within 60 days after”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7951a932-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7951a933-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1946 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1946-08-02">Aug. 2, 1946</date>, effective <date date="1946-08-02">Aug. 2, 1946</date>, see section 245 of that act, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4301">section 4301 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
