<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79541a57-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c"><num value="1022c">§ 1022c.</num><heading> Inclusion of priority policies and programs in President’s Budget</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To contribute to the achievement of the goals under the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3101">15 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.], the President’s Budget for each fiscal year beginning after <date date="1978-10-27">October 27, 1978</date>, shall include priority policies and programs, which shall include, to the extent deemed appropriate by the President, consideration of the following—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a58-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> development of energy sources and supplies, transportation, and environmental improvement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a59-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> proper attention to the problems and needs of smaller businesses including (i) the availability of investment capital, management and technical expertise, and technology and labor needs, (ii) analysis of economic and social trends which may affect smaller businesses, (iii) government policies and programs (including agency regulations and excessive paperwork requirements) that may create undue hardship for or reduce the competitiveness of smaller businesses, and (iv) other policies and programs to remove barriers to competition and to strengthen and promote the creation and growth of smaller businesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a5a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> development of a comprehensive national agricultural policy that assures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79541a5b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> production levels adequate to meet the nutritional needs of all Americans and respond to rising food requirements throughout the world;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79541a5c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> farm and ranch income at full parity levels that will improve opportunities for farm families, encourage production, provide for essential capital investment in farming, and provide for farm prices at full parity in the market place;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79541a5d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> renewed commitment to the protection and conservation of rural land and water through support for improved conservation practices and research, and attention to agricultural land use in the formulation of plans for energy, water and mineral resources, transportation, and commercial, industrial, and residential development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79541a5e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> support for programs and public services designed to respond to the unique economic and social conditions of rural communities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a5f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> proper attention to the relationship between Federal programs and policies and the problems and needs of urban areas, including inner cities and the employment problems of their residents, especially youths;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a60-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> proper attention to the quality and quantity of health care, education and training programs, child care and other human services, and housing, essential to a full employment economy and to moving toward their availability for all individuals at costs within their means;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a61-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> policies concerning Federal aid to State and local governments, especially for public investment and unemployment related costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a62-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> national defense and other needed international programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a63-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> proper attention to the relationship between Federal grants, contracts, and procurement and the closure of military bases and other Federal facilities and the distribution of jobs and income among different regions of the Nation, and among urban, suburban, and rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a64-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> proper attention to balancing the Federal budget;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a65-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> proper attention to the dislocation of jobs caused by Federal laws, regulations, and policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a66-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> policies and programs designed to increase exports and improve the international competitive position of agriculture, business, and industry, including measures to promote a free and fair international trading system, a sound and stable international monetary system and innovation in agriculture, business, and industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79541a67-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1022c/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> such other priority policies and programs as the President deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<sourceCredit id="id79541a68-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-02-20/ch33/s6">Feb. 20, 1946, ch. 33, § 6</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/tI/s106">Pub. L. 95–523, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1895">92 Stat. 1895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79541a69-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79541a6a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79541a6b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978, referred to in provision preceding par. (A), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/523">Pub. L. 95–523</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1887">92 Stat. 1887</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 58 (§ 3101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
