<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id795b4639-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b"><num value="1066b">§ 1066b.</num><heading> Ex parte reexamination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b463a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition for reexamination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person may file a petition to reexamine a registration of a mark on the basis that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services recited in the registration on or before the relevant date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b463b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Relevant date</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “relevant date” means, with respect to an application for the registration of a mark with an initial filing basis of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b463c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/a">section 1051(a) of this title</ref> and not amended at any point to be filed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/b">section 1051(b) of this title</ref>, the date on which the application was initially filed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b463d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/b">section 1051(b) of this title</ref> or amended at any point to be filed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/b">section 1051(b) of this title</ref>, the date on which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id795b463e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an amendment to allege use under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/c">section 1051(c) of this title</ref> was filed; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id795b463f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the period for filing a statement of use under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/d">section 1051(d) of this title</ref> expired, including all approved extensions thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4640-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for the petition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A petition filed under subsection (a), together with any supporting documents, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b4641-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identify the registration that is the subject of the petition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b4642-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identify each good and service recited in the registration for which it is alleged that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with on or before the relevant date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b4643-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> include a verified statement that sets forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id795b4644-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the elements of the reasonable investigation the petitioner conducted to determine that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with the goods and services identified in the petition on or before the relevant date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id795b4645-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any additional facts that support the allegation that the mark was not in use in commerce on or before the relevant date on or in connection with the identified goods and services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b4646-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> include supporting evidence on which the petitioner relies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b4647-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> be accompanied by the fee prescribed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4648-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial determination; institution</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4649-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Prima facie case determination, institution, and notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall, for each good or service identified under subsection (c)(2), determine whether the petition sets forth a prima facie case of the mark having not been in use in commerce on or in connection with each such good or service, institute an ex parte reexamination proceeding for each good or service for which the Director determines that the prima facie case has been set forth, and provide a notice to the registrant and petitioner of the determination of whether or not the proceeding was instituted. Such notice shall include a copy of the petition and any supporting documents and evidence that were included with the petition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b464a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasonable investigation guidance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall promulgate regulations regarding what constitutes a reasonable investigation under subsection (c)(3) and the general types of evidence that could support a prima facie case that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with a good or service on or before the relevant date, but the Director shall retain discretion to determine whether a prima facie case is set out in a particular proceeding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b464b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination by Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any determination by the Director whether or not to institute a reexamination proceeding under this section shall be final and non-reviewable, and shall not prejudice any party’s right to raise any issue and rely on any evidence in any other proceeding, except as provided in subsection (j).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b464c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reexamination procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The procedures for reexamination shall be the same as the procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062/b">section 1062(b) of this title</ref> except that the Director shall promulgate regulations establishing and governing a proceeding under this section, which may include regulations that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b464d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> set response and extension times particular to this type of proceeding, which, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062/b/3">section 1062(b)(3) of this title</ref>, need not be extendable to 6 months;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b464e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> set limits governing the timing and number of petitions filed for a particular registration or by a particular petitioner or real parties in interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id795b464f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> define the relation of a reexamination proceeding under this section to other proceedings concerning the mark.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4650-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Registrant’s evidence of use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A registrant’s documentary evidence of use shall be consistent with when a mark shall be deemed to be in use in commerce under the definition of “use in commerce” in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1127">section 1127 of this title</ref>, but shall not be limited in form to that of specimens as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051/a">section 1051(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4651-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Examiner’s decision; order to cancel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each good or service for which it is determined that the registration should not have issued because the mark was not in use in commerce on or before the relevant date, the examiner shall find that the registration should be cancelled for each such good or service. Unless overturned on review of the examiner’s decision, the Director shall issue an order cancelling the registration, in whole or in part, after the time for appeal has expired or any appeal proceeding has terminated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4652-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Reexamination by Director</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4653-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director may, on the Director’s own initiative, institute an ex parte reexamination proceeding if the Director discovers information that supports a prima facie case of the mark having not been used in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services covered by the registration on or before the relevant date. The Director shall promptly notify the registrant of such determination, at which time reexamination shall proceed according to the same procedures established pursuant to subsection (e). If the Director determines, based on the Director’s own initiative, to institute an ex parte reexamination proceeding, the Director shall transmit or make available the information that formed the basis for that determination as part of the institution notice.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4654-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit any other authority of the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4655-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for institution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A petition for ex parte reexamination may be filed, or the Director may institute on the Director’s own initiative an ex parte reexamination proceeding, at any time not later than 5 years after the date of registration of a mark registered based on use in commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4656-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on later ex parte reexamination proceedings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4657-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> No co-pending proceedings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to a particular registration, while an ex parte reexamination proceeding is pending, no later ex parte reexamination proceeding may be instituted with respect to the same goods or services that are the subject of a pending ex parte reexamination proceeding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4658-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Estoppel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to a particular registration, for any goods or services previously subject to an instituted ex parte reexamination proceeding for which, in that proceeding, it was determined that the registrant had used the mark for particular goods or services before the relevant date, and the registration was not cancelled as to those goods or services, no further ex parte reexamination proceedings may be initiated as to those goods or services, regardless of the identity of the petitioner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id795b4659-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1066b/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplemental register</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (b) apply, as appropriate, to registrations under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1091">section 1091 of this title</ref>. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the timing of a cancellation action under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1092">section 1092 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id795b465a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540">July 5, 1946, ch. 540</ref>, title I, § 16B, as added <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dQ/tII/s225/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Q, title II, § 225(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2205">134 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id795b465b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id795b465c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id795b465d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, and applicable to any mark registered before, on, or after that effective date, see section 225(g) of div Q of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2020 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1064">section 1064 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id795b465e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Director required to issue regulations to carry out this section no later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s225/f">section 225(f) of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1066a">section 1066a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
