<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79600148-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115"><num value="1115">§ 1115.</num><heading> Registration on principal register as evidence of exclusive right to use mark; defenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79600149-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Evidentiary value; defenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any registration issued under the Act of <date date="1881-03-03">March 3, 1881</date>, or the Act of <date date="1905-02-20">February 20, 1905</date>, or of a mark registered on the principal register provided by this chapter and owned by a party to an action shall be admissible in evidence and shall be prima facie evidence of the validity of the registered mark and of the registration of the mark, of the registrant’s ownership of the mark, and of the registrant’s exclusive right to use the registered mark in commerce on or in connection with the goods or services specified in the registration subject to any conditions or limitations stated therein, but shall not preclude another person from proving any legal or equitable defense or defect, including those set forth in subsection (b), which might have been asserted if such mark had not been registered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7960014a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Incontestability; defenses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent that the right to use the registered mark has become incontestable under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1065">section 1065 of this title</ref>, the registration shall be conclusive evidence of the validity of the registered mark and of the registration of the mark, of the registrant’s ownership of the mark, and of the registrant’s exclusive right to use the registered mark in commerce. Such conclusive evidence shall relate to the exclusive right to use the mark on or in connection with the goods or services specified in the affidavit filed under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1065">section 1065 of this title</ref>, or in the renewal application filed under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1059">section 1059 of this title</ref> if the goods or services specified in the renewal are fewer in number, subject to any conditions or limitations in the registration or in such affidavit or renewal application. Such conclusive evidence of the right to use the registered mark shall be subject to proof of infringement as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>, and shall be subject to the following defenses or defects:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7960014b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> That the registration or the incontestable right to use the mark was obtained fraudulently; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7960014c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> That the mark has been abandoned by the registrant; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7960014d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> That the registered mark is being used by or with the permission of the registrant or a person in privity with the registrant, so as to misrepresent the source of the goods or services on or in connection with which the mark is used; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7960014e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> That the use of the name, term, or device charged to be an infringement is a use, otherwise than as a mark, of the party’s individual name in his own business, or of the individual name of anyone in privity with such party, or of a term or device which is descriptive of and used fairly and in good faith only to describe the goods or services of such party, or their geographic origin; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7960014f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> That the mark whose use by a party is charged as an infringement was adopted without knowledge of the registrant’s prior use and has been continuously used by such party or those in privity with him from a date prior to (A) the date of constructive use of the mark established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1057/c">section 1057(c) of this title</ref>, (B) the registration of the mark under this chapter if the application for registration is filed before the effective date of the Trademark Law Revision Act of 1988, or (C) publication of the registered mark under subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062">section 1062 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this defense or defect shall apply only for the area in which such continuous prior use is proved; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79600150-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> That the mark whose use is charged as an infringement was registered and used prior to the registration under this chapter or publication under subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062">section 1062 of this title</ref> of the registered mark of the registrant, and not abandoned: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this defense or defect shall apply only for the area in which the mark was used prior to such registration or such publication of the registrant’s mark; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79600151-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> That the mark has been or is being used to violate the antitrust laws of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79600152-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> That the mark is functional; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79600153-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1115/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> That equitable principles, including laches, estoppel, and acquiescence, are applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79600154-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540">July 5, 1946, ch. 540</ref>, title VI, § 33, <ref href="/us/stat/60/438">60 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/772/s18">Pub. L. 87–772, § 18</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/774">76 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/tI/s128/a">Pub. L. 100–667, title I, § 128(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3944">102 Stat. 3944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/330/tII/s201/a/9">Pub. L. 105–330, title II, § 201(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3070">112 Stat. 3070</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tIII/s13207/b/7">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13207(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1908">116 Stat. 1908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79600155-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79600156-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79600157-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Acts <date date="1881-03-03">March 3, 1881</date>, and <date date="1905-02-20">February 20, 1905</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), are acts <ref href="/us/act/1881-03-03/ch138">Mar. 3, 1881, ch. 138</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/21/502">21 Stat. 502</ref> and <ref href="/us/act/1905-02-20/ch592">Feb. 20, 1905, ch. 592</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/33/724">33 Stat. 724</ref>, which were repealed insofar as inconsistent with this chapter by <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540/s46/a">act July 5, 1946, ch. 540, § 46(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/444">60 Stat. 444</ref>. Act <date date="1905-02-20">Feb. 20, 1905</date>, was classified to sections 81 to 109 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of the Trademark Law Revision Act of 1988, referred to in subsec. (b)(5), is one year after <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>. See <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s136">section 136 of Pub. L. 100–667</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id79600158-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1905-02-20/ch592">Act Feb. 20, 1905, ch. 592</ref>, §§ 16, 21, <ref href="/us/stat/33/728">33 Stat. 728</ref>, 729.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79600159-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/330">Pub. L. 105–330</ref> added par. (8) and redesignated former par. (8) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/a">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(a)</ref>, inserted “the validity of the registered mark and of the registration of the mark, of the registrant’s ownership of the mark, and of the” after “facie evidence of”, inserted “or in connection with” after “in commerce on”, substituted “another person” for “an opposing party”, and inserted “, including those set forth in subsection (b),” after “or defect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/b/1">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(b)(1)</ref>, amended introductory provisions generally. Prior to amendment, introductory provisions read as follows: “If the right to use the registered mark has become incontestable under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1065">section 1065 of this title</ref>, the registration shall be conclusive evidence of the registrant’s exclusive right to use the registered mark in commerce on or in connection with the goods or services specified in the affidavit filed under the provisions of said section 1065 subject to any conditions or limitations stated therein except when one of the following defenses or defects is established:”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/b/2">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “on or” after “goods or services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/b/3">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(b)(3)</ref>, struck out “trade or service” after “than as a” and “to users” after “only to describe”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/b/4">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “(A) the date of constructive use of the mark established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1057/c">section 1057(c) of this title</ref>, (B) the registration of the mark under this chapter if the application for registration is filed before the effective date of the Trademark Law Revision Act of 1988, or (C)” for “registration of the mark under this chapter or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s128/b/5">Pub. L. 100–667, § 128(b)(5)</ref>, (6), added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/772">Pub. L. 87–772</ref> substituted “registration subject to” for “certificate subject to”, and struck out “certificate of” before “registration issued”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/772">Pub. L. 87–772</ref> substituted “registration shall” for “certificate shall”, and “affidavit filed under the provisions of said section 1065” for “certificate” in text preceding par. (1), substituted “registrant or a person in privity with the registrant,” for “assignee”, and struck out “has been assigned and” after “registered mark” in par. (3), substituted “registration of the mark under this chapter or” for “the”, and struck out “(a) or” before “(c) of section 1062” in par. (5), inserted “registration under this chapter”, substituted “such registration or such” for “the date of”, and struck out “(a) or” before “(c) of section 1062”, “only where the said mark has been published pursuant to subsections (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062">section 1062 of this title</ref> and shall apply” after “defect shall apply”, and “under subsection (a) or (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1062">section 1062 of this title</ref>” after “registrant’s mark”, in par. (6).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7960015a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7960015b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/330">Pub. L. 105–330</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, and applicable only to any civil action filed or proceeding before the United States Patent and Trademark Office commenced on or after such date relating to the registration of a mark, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/330/s201/b">section 201(b) of Pub. L. 105–330</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7960015c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/667">Pub. L. 100–667</ref> effective one year after <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/667/s136">section 136 of Pub. L. 100–667</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7960015d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeal and Effect on Existing Rights</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Repeal of inconsistent provisions, effect of this chapter on pending proceedings and existing registrations and rights under prior acts, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
