<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id796271df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1122"><num value="1122">§ 1122.</num><heading> Liability of United States and States, and instrumentalities and officials thereof</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id796271e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1122/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of sovereign immunity by the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States, all agencies and instrumentalities thereof, and all individuals, firms, corporations, other persons acting for the United States and with the authorization and consent of the United States, shall not be immune from suit in Federal or State court by any person, including any governmental or nongovernmental entity, for any violation under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id796271e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1122/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of sovereign immunity by States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State, instrumentality of a State or any officer or employee of a State or instrumentality of a State acting in his or her official capacity, shall not be immune, under the eleventh amendment of the Constitution of the United States or under any other doctrine of sovereign immunity, from suit in Federal court by any person, including any governmental or nongovernmental entity for any violation under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id796271e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1122/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Remedies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In a suit described in subsection (a) or (b) for a violation described therein, remedies (including remedies both at law and in equity) are available for the violation to the same extent as such remedies are available for such a violation in a suit against any person other than the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or any individual, firm, corporation, or other person acting for the United States and with authorization and consent of the United States, or a State, instrumentality of a State, or officer or employee of a State or instrumentality of a State acting in his or her official capacity. Such remedies include injunctive relief under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1116">section 1116 of this title</ref>, actual damages, profits, costs and attorney’s fees under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1117">section 1117 of this title</ref>, destruction of infringing articles under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1118">section 1118 of this title</ref>, the remedies provided for under sections 1114, 1119, 1120, 1124 and 1125 of this title, and for any other remedies provided under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id796271e3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540">July 5, 1946, ch. 540</ref>, title VI, § 40, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/542/s3/b">Pub. L. 102–542, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3567">106 Stat. 3567</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/43/s4/b">Pub. L. 106–43, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/219">113 Stat. 219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id796271e4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id796271e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id796271e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1122, <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540/tVI/s40">act July 5, 1946, ch. 540, title VI, § 40</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/440">60 Stat. 440</ref>, related to review of cases by the Supreme Court, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s142">act May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 142</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/109">63 Stat. 109</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id796271e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/43/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 106–43, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (a). Former subsec. (a) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/43/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 106–43, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (a) as (b) and inserted heading. Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/43/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 106–43, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (b) as (c) and in first sentence substituted “subsection (a) or (b) for a violation described therein” for “subsection (a) of this section for a violation described in that subsection” and inserted “the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or any individual, firm, corporation, or other person acting for the United States and with authorization and consent of the United States, or” after “other than”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id796271e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id796271e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to violations that occur on or after <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/542/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 102–542</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1992 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
