<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id796271f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1124"><num value="1124">§ 1124.</num><heading> Importation of goods bearing infringing marks or names forbidden</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1526">section 1526 of title 19</ref>, no article of imported merchandise which shall copy or simulate the name of any domestic manufacture, or manufacturer, or trader, or of any manufacturer or trader located in any foreign country which, by treaty, convention, or law affords similar privileges to citizens of the United States, or which shall copy or simulate a trademark registered in accordance with the provisions of this chapter or shall bear a name or mark calculated to induce the public to believe that the article is manufactured in the United States, or that it is manufactured in any foreign country or locality other than the country or locality in which it is in fact manufactured, shall be admitted to entry at any customhouse of the United States; and, in order to aid the officers of the customs in enforcing this prohibition, any domestic manufacturer or trader, and any foreign manufacturer or trader, who is entitled under the provisions of a treaty, convention, declaration, or agreement between the United States and any foreign country to the advantages afforded by law to citizens of the United States in respect to trademarks and commercial names, may require his name and residence, and the name of the locality in which his goods are manufactured, and a copy of the certificate of registration of his trademark, issued in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, to be recorded in books which shall be kept for this purpose in the Department of the Treasury, under such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe, and may furnish to the Department facsimiles of his name, the name of the locality in which his goods are manufactured, or of his registered trademark, and thereupon the Secretary of the Treasury shall cause one or more copies of the same to be transmitted to each collector or other proper officer of customs.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id796271f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540">July 5, 1946, ch. 540</ref>, title VII, § 42, <ref href="/us/stat/60/440">60 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 95–410, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/903">92 Stat. 903</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/330/tII/s201/a/11">Pub. L. 105–330, title II, § 201(a)(11)</ref>, (12), <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3070">112 Stat. 3070</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/43/s6/b">Pub. L. 106–43, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/220">113 Stat. 220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id796271f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id796271f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id796271fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1905-02-20/ch592/s27">Act Feb. 20, 1905, ch. 592, § 27</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/33/730">33 Stat. 730</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id796271fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/43">Pub. L. 106–43</ref> substituted “trademarks” for “trade-marks”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/330/s201/a/11">Pub. L. 105–330, § 201(a)(11)</ref>, substituted “name of any domestic” for “name of the any domestic”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/330/s201/a/12">Pub. L. 105–330, § 201(a)(12)</ref>, substituted “trademark” for “trade-mark” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/410">Pub. L. 95–410</ref> substituted “Except as provided in subsection (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1526">section 1526 of title 19</ref>, no article” for “No article”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id796271fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id796271fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/330">Pub. L. 105–330</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, and applicable only to any civil action filed or proceeding before the United States Patent and Trademark Office commenced on or after such date relating to the registration of a mark, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/330/s201/b">section 201(b) of Pub. L. 105–330</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id796271fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeal and Effect on Existing Rights</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Repeal of inconsistent provisions, effect of this chapter on pending proceedings and existing registrations and rights under prior acts, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id796271ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79627200-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Offices of collector of customs, comptroller of customs, surveyor of customs, and appraiser of merchandise of Bureau of Customs of Department of the Treasury to which appointments were required to be made by President with advice and consent of Senate ordered abolished, with such offices to be terminated not later than <date date="1966-12-31">Dec. 31, 1966</date>, by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-05-25">May 25, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 7035, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1317">79 Stat. 1317</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Functions of offices eliminated were already vested in Secretary of the Treasury by Reorg. Plan No. 26 of 1950, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
