<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79699e1e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1197"><num value="1197">§ 1197.</num><heading> Guaranties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79699e1f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1197/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Defense to prosecution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall be subject to prosecution under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1196">section 1196 of this title</ref> for a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1192">section 1192 of this title</ref> if such person (1) establishes a guaranty received in good faith signed by and containing the name and address of the person by whom the product, fabric, or related material guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received, to the effect that reasonable and representative tests made in accordance with standards issued or amended under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref> show that the fabric or related material covered by the guaranty, or used in the product covered by the guaranty, conforms with applicable flammability standards issued or amended under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref>, and (2) has not, by further processing, affected the flammability of the fabric, related material, or product covered by the guaranty which he received. Such guaranty shall be either (1) a separate guaranty specifically designating the product, fabric, or related material guaranteed, in which case it may be on the invoice or other paper relating to such product, fabric, or related material; (2) a continuing guaranty given by seller to buyer applicable to any product, fabric, or related material sold or to be sold to buyer by seller in a form as the Commission by rules and regulations may prescribe; or (3) a continuing guaranty filed with the Commission applicable to any product, fabric, or related material handled by a guarantor, in such form as the Commission by rules or regulations may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79699e20-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1197/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> False guaranty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to furnish, with respect to any product, fabric, or related material, a false guaranty (except a person relying upon a guaranty to the same effect received in good faith signed by and containing the name and address of the person by whom the product, fabric, or related material guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received) with reason to believe the product, fabric, or related material falsely guaranteed may be introduced, sold, or transported in commerce, and any person who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of an unfair method of competition, and an unfair or deceptive act or practice, in commerce within the meaning of the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79699e21-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-06-30/ch164/s8">June 30, 1953, ch. 164, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/114">67 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/189/s6">Pub. L. 90–189, § 6</ref>, <date date="1967-12-14">Dec. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/572">81 Stat. 572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79699e22-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79699e23-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79699e24-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79699e25-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/189">Pub. L. 90–189</ref> substituted “product, fabric, or related material” for “wearing apparel or fabric” wherever appearing and “in accordance with standards issued or amended under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref> show that the fabric or related material covered by the guaranty, or used in the product covered by the guaranty, conforms with applicable flammability standards issued or amended under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref>” for “under the procedures provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref> show that the fabric covered by the guaranty, or used in the wearing apparel covered by the guaranty, is not, under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1193">section 1193 of this title</ref>, so highly flammable as to be dangerous when worn by individuals”, added cl. (2), and redesignated former cl. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/90/189">Pub. L. 90–189</ref> substituted “product, fabric, or related material” for “wearing apparel or fabric” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79699e26-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79699e27-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, Secretary of Commerce, and Federal Trade Commission under this chapter transferred to Consumer Product Safety Commission, along with functions of Federal Trade Commission under Federal Trade Commission Act, to extent such functions relate to administration and enforcement of this chapter, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2079">section 2079 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
