<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77b07ce8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s12"><num value="12">§ 12.</num><heading> Definitions; short title</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77b07ce9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s12/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> “Antitrust laws,” as used herein, includes the Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies,” approved July second, eighteen hundred and ninety; sections seventy-three to seventy-six, inclusive, of an Act entitled “An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes,” of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four; an Act entitled “An Act to amend sections seventy-three and seventy-six of the Act of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four, entitled ‘An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes,’ ” approved February twelfth, nineteen hundred and thirteen; and also this Act.<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">“Commerce,” as used herein, means trade or commerce among the several States and with foreign nations, or between the District of Columbia or any Territory of the United States and any State, Territory, or foreign nation, or between any insular possessions or other places under the jurisdiction of the United States, or between any such possession or place and any State or Territory of the United States or the District of Columbia or any foreign nation, or within the District of Columbia or any Territory or any insular possession or other place under the jurisdiction of the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this Act contained shall apply to the Philippine Islands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The word “person” or “persons” wherever used in this Act shall be deemed to include corporations and associations existing under or authorized by the laws of either the United States, the laws of any of the Territories, the laws of any State, or the laws of any foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77b07cea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s12/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> This Act may be cited as the “Clayton Act”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77b07ceb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323/s1">Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/435/tIII/s305/b">Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 305(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1397">90 Stat. 1397</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tIV/s14102/c/2/A">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title IV, § 14102(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1921">116 Stat. 1921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77b07cec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77b07ced-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77b07cee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “herein” and “this Act”, referred to in the three paragraphs of subsec. (a), mean the Clayton Act. For classification of the Clayton Act to the Code, see last paragraph hereunder.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies,” approved July second, eighteen hundred and ninety, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-07-02/ch647">act July 2, 1890, ch. 647</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/209">26 Stat. 209</ref>, known as the Sherman Act, which is classified to sections 1 to 7 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes,” of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1894-08-27/ch349">act Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/509">28 Stat. 509</ref>, known as the Wilson Tariff Act. Sections seventy-three to seventy-six thereof are set out as sections 8 to 11 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to amend sections seventy-three and seventy-six of the Act of August twenty-seventh, eighteen hundred and ninety-four, entitled ‘An Act to reduce taxation, to provide revenue for the Government, and for other purposes’,” approved February twelfth, nineteen hundred and thirteen, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1913-02-12/ch40">act Feb. 12, 1913, ch. 40</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/667">37 Stat. 667</ref>, which is classified to sections 8 and 11 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clayton Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323">act Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/730">38 Stat. 730</ref>, which is classified to sections 12, 13, 14 to 19, 21, and 22 to 27 of this title, and sections 52 and 53 of Title 29, Labor. Sections 9 and 21 to 25 of the act were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645/s21">act June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 21</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/862">62 Stat. 862</ref>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>, and their provisions are now covered by sections 402, 660, 3285 and 3691 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, except that former section 23 of the act is obsolete and not now covered. Sections 17 to 19 of the act were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s39">act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 39</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/992">62 Stat. 992</ref>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>, and their provisions are now covered by rule 65 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77b2c5df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The 3d par. of subsec. (a) is also classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s53">section 53 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77b2c5e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> substituted “seventy-three to seventy-six” for “seventy-three to seventy-seven” in first par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/435">Pub. L. 94–435</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77b2c5e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77b2c5e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> effective <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, and applicable only with respect to cases commenced on or after <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s14103">section 14103 of Pub. L. 107–273</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3">section 3 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
