<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7977cebd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1334"><num value="1334">§ 1334.</num><heading> Preemption</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cebe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1334/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except to the extent the Secretary requires additional or different statements on any cigarette package by a regulation, by an order, by a standard, by an authorization to market a product, or by a condition of marketing a product, pursuant to the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), or as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387c/a/2">section 387c(a)(2) of title 21</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387t/a">section 387t(a) of title 21</ref>, no statement relating to smoking and health, other than the statement required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333">section 1333 of this title</ref>, shall be required on any cigarette package.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cebf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1334/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> State regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No requirement or prohibition based on smoking and health shall be imposed under State law with respect to the advertising or promotion of any cigarettes the packages of which are labeled in conformity with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cec0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1334/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), a State or locality may enact statutes and promulgate regulations, based on smoking and health, that take effect after the effective date of the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, imposing specific bans or restrictions on the time, place, and manner, but not content, of the advertising or promotion of any cigarettes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7977cec1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/92/s5">Pub. L. 89–92, § 5</ref>, <date date="1965-07-27">July 27, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/283">79 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/222/s2">Pub. L. 91–222, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-04-01">Apr. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/88">84 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tII">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 202(a), 203, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1845">123 Stat. 1845</ref>, 1846.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7977cec2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7977cec3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7977cec4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1776">123 Stat. 1776</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2009 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">section 301 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, referred to in subsec. (c), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/111/31">Pub. L. 111–31</ref>, which was approved <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7977cec5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s202/a">Pub. L. 111–31, § 202(a)</ref>, substituted “Except to the extent the Secretary requires additional or different statements on any cigarette package by a regulation, by an order, by a standard, by an authorization to market a product, or by a condition of marketing a product, pursuant to the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), or as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387c/a/2">section 387c(a)(2) of title 21</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s387t/a">section 387t(a) of title 21</ref>, no” for “No”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s203">Pub. L. 111–31, § 203</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/222">Pub. L. 91–222</ref> substituted provision that no requirement or prohibition based on smoking and health should be imposed under State law with respect to the advertising or promotion of any cigarettes which packages are labeled in conformity with the provisions of this chapter for provision that no statement relating to smoking and health should be required in the advertising of any cigarettes which packages are labeled in conformity with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/222">Pub. L. 91–222</ref> struck out subsecs. (c) and (d) relating to the authority of the Federal Trade Commission with respect to unfair or deceptive advertising acts or practices, and reports to Congress by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and the Federal Trade Commission. See sections 1336 and 1337 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7977cec6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7977cec7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/222/s3">Pub. L. 91–222, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-04-01">Apr. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/90">84 Stat. 90</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/222/s3">“Section 5 of the amendment made by this Act [amending this section] shall take effect as of <date date="1969-07-01">July 1, 1969</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
