<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7977ced0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a"><num value="1335a">§ 1335a.</num><heading> List of cigarette ingredients; annual submission to Secretary; transmittal to Congress; confidentiality</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Each person who manufactures, packages, or imports cigarettes shall annually provide the Secretary with a list of the ingredients added to tobacco in the manufacture of cigarettes which does not identify the company which uses the ingredients or the brand of cigarettes which contain the ingredients. A person or group of persons required to provide a list by this subsection may designate an individual or entity to provide the list required by this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> At such times as the Secretary considers appropriate, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a report, based on the information provided under subsection (a), respecting—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977ced4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a summary of research activities and proposed research activities on the health effects of ingredients added to tobacco in the manufacture of cigarettes and the findings of such research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977ced5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information pertaining to any such ingredient which in the judgement of the Secretary poses a health risk to cigarette smokers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977ced6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any other information which the Secretary determines to be in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any information provided to the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be treated as trade secret or confidential information subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/4">section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref> and shall not be revealed, except as provided in paragraph (1), to any person other than those authorized by the Secretary in carrying out their official duties under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ced9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) does not authorize the withholding of a list provided under subsection (a) from any duly authorized subcommittee or committee of the Congress. If a subcommittee or committee of the Congress requests the Secretary to provide it such a list, the Secretary shall make the list available to the subcommittee or committee and shall, at the same time, notify in writing the person who provided the list of such request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977ceda-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall establish written procedures to assure the confidentiality of information provided under subsection (a). Such procedures shall include the designation of a duly authorized agent to serve as custodian of such information. The agent—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cedb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall take physical possession of the information and, when not in use by a person authorized to have access to such information, shall store it in a locked cabinet or file, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cedc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1335a/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall maintain a complete record of any person who inspects or uses the information.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such procedures shall require that any person permitted access to the information shall be instructed in writing not to disclose the information to anyone who is not entitled to have access to the information.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7977cedd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/92/s7">Pub. L. 89–92, § 7</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/474/s5/a">Pub. L. 98–474, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2203">98 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7977cede-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7977cedf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id7977cee0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/89/92/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 89–92</ref> was renumbered section 8 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1336">section 1336 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7977cee1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7977cee2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/474/s5/b">Pub. L. 98–474, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2204">98 Stat. 2204</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/474/s5/b">“Section 7 of the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act [this section] added by subsection (a) shall take effect upon the expiration of the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
