<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7977cf07-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341"><num value="1341">§ 1341.</num><heading> Smoking, research, education and information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cf08-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of program; Secretary; functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish and carry out a program to inform the public of any dangers to human health presented by cigarette smoking. In carrying out such program, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf09-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct and support research on the effect of cigarette smoking on human health and develop materials for informing the public of such effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf0a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> coordinate all research and educational programs and other activities within the Department of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Department”) which relate to the effect of cigarette smoking on human health and coordinate, through the Interagency Committee on Smoking and Health (established under subsection (b)), such activities with similar activities of other Federal agencies and of private agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf0b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish and maintain a liaison with appropriate private entities, other Federal agencies, and State and local public agencies respecting activities relating to the effect of cigarette smoking on human health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf0c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> collect, analyze, and disseminate (through publications, bibliographies, and otherwise) information, studies, and other data relating to the effect of cigarette smoking on human health, and develop standards, criteria, and methodologies for improved information programs related to smoking and health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf0d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> compile and make available information on State and local laws relating to the use and consumption of cigarettes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf0e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> undertake any other additional information and research activities which the Secretary determines necessary and appropriate to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cf0f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency Committee on Smoking and Health; composition; chairman; compensation; staffing and other assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977cf10-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> To carry out the activities described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) there is established an Interagency Committee on Smoking and Health. The Committee shall be composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> members appointed by the Secretary from appropriate institutes and agencies of the Department, which may include the National Cancer Institute, the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at least one member appointed from the Federal Trade Commission, the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, and any other Federal agency designated by the Secretary, the appointment of whom shall be made by the head of the entity from which the member is appointed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf13-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> five members appointed by the Secretary from physicians and scientists who represent private entities involved in informing the public about the health effects of smoking.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall designate the chairman of the Committee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977cf14-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee, members of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistance,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002323">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002323"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsistence,”.</note> in the manner provided by sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7977cf15-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall make available to the Committee such staff, information, and other assistance as it may require to carry out its activities effectively.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7977cf16-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit a report to Congress not later than <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, and biennially thereafter which shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7977cf17-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an overview and assessment of Federal activities undertaken to inform the public of the health consequences of smoking and the extent of public knowledge of such consequences,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a4018-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of the Secretary’s and Committee’s activities under subsection (a),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a4019-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> information regarding the activities of the private sector taken in response to the effects of smoking on health, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a401a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1341/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> such recommendations as the Secretary may consider appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id797a401b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/474/s3">Pub. L. 98–474, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2200">98 Stat. 2200</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/92/s13">Pub. L. 99–92, § 13</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/404">99 Stat. 404</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/531/tIII/s312/a">Pub. L. 102–531, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3504">106 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/154/s1/c/1">Pub. L. 110–154, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1827">121 Stat. 1827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id797a401c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id797a401d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id797a401e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Comprehensive Smoking Education Act, and not as part of the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id797a401f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/154">Pub. L. 110–154</ref> substituted “Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development” for “National Institute of Child Health and Human Development”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(1)(A), <ref href="/us/pl/102/531">Pub. L. 102–531</ref> substituted “Centers for Disease Control and Prevention” for “Centers for Disease Control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/92">Pub. L. 99–92</ref> substituted “1986” for “1985”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
