<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id797a40ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453"><num value="1453">§ 1453.</num><heading> Requirements of labeling; placement, form, and contents of statement of quantity; supplemental statement of quantity</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797a40cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of label</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person subject to the prohibition contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1452">section 1452 of this title</ref> shall distribute or cause to be distributed in commerce any packaged consumer commodity unless in conformity with regulations which shall be established by the promulgating authority pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1455">section 1455 of this title</ref> which shall provide that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The commodity shall bear a label specifying the identity of the commodity and the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The net quantity of contents (in terms of weight or mass, measure, or numerical count) shall be separately and accurately stated in a uniform location upon the principal display panel of that label, using the most appropriate units of both the customary inch/pound system of measure, as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, and, except as provided in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) or paragraph (6) of this subsection, the SI metric system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The separate label statement of net quantity of contents appearing upon or affixed to any package—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if on a package labeled in terms of weight, shall be expressed in pounds, with any remainder in terms of ounces or common or decimal fractions of the pound; or in the case of liquid measure, in the largest whole unit (quarts, quarts and pints, or pints, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of fluid ounces or common or decimal fractions of the pint or quart;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if on a random package, may be expressed in terms of pounds and decimal fractions of the pound carried out to not more than three decimal places and is not required to, but may, include a statement in terms of the SI metric system carried out to not more than three decimal places;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> if on a package labeled in terms of linear measure, shall be expressed in terms of the largest whole unit (yards, yards and feet, or feet, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of inches or common or decimal fractions of the foot or yard;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> if on a package labeled in terms of measure of area, shall be expressed in terms of the largest whole square unit (square yards, square yards and square feet, or square feet, as appropriate) with any remainder in terms of square inches or common or decimal fractions of the square foot or square yard;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall appear in conspicuous and easily legible type in distinct contrast (by topography, layout, color, embossing, or molding) with other matter on the package;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall contain letters or numerals in a type size which shall be (i) established in relationship to the area of the principal display panel of the package, and (ii) uniform for all packages of substantially the same size; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id797a40d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall be so placed that the lines of printed matter included in that statement are generally parallel to the base on which the package rests as it is designed to be displayed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The label of any package of a consumer commodity which bears a representation as to the number of servings of such commodity contained in such package shall bear a statement of the net quantity (in terms of weight or mass, measure, or numerical count) of each such serving.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40d8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (3)(A)(ii) of this subsection the term “random package” means a package which is one of a lot, shipment, or delivery of packages of the same consumer commodity with varying weights or masses, that is, packages with no fixed weight or mass pattern.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797a40d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The requirement of paragraph (2) that the statement of net quantity of contents include a statement in terms of the SI metric system shall not apply to foods that are packaged at the retail store level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797a40da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1453/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplemental statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person subject to the prohibition contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1452">section 1452 of this title</ref> shall distribute or cause to be distributed in commerce any packaged consumer commodity if any qualifying words or phrases appear in conjunction with the separate statement of the net quantity of contents required by subsection (a), but nothing in this subsection or in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) shall prohibit supplemental statements, at other places on the package, describing in nondeceptive terms the net quantity of contents: <i>Provided</i>, That such supplemental statements of net quantity of contents shall not include any term qualifying a unit of weight or mass, measure, or count that tends to exaggerate the amount of the commodity contained in the package.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id797a40db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/755/s4">Pub. L. 89–755, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-11-03">Nov. 3, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1297">80 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/245/tI/s107/a">Pub. L. 102–245, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/13">106 Stat. 13</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/329">Pub. L. 102–329</ref>, §§ 1, 3, <date date="1992-08-03">Aug. 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/847">106 Stat. 847</ref>, 848.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id797a40dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id797a40dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id797a40de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/245/s107">Pub. L. 102–245, § 107</ref>, which directed amendment of section, effective two years after <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, by substituting “weight or mass” for “weight” in subsecs. (a)(2), (4), (5) and (b) and “weights or masses” for “weights” in subsec. (a)(5), by inserting “, using the most appropriate units of the SI metric system as the primary system for measuring quantity” after “panel of that label” in subsec. (a)(2), by substituting “that also displays the avoirdupois system of measure, and that contains” for “containing” in subsec. (a)(3)(A)(i), by inserting “that also displays the avoirdupois system of measure” after “random package” in subsec. (a)(3)(A)(ii), by inserting “that also displays the avoirdupois system of measure” after “linear measure” in subsec. (a)(3)(A)(iii), and by inserting “that also displays the avoirdupois system of measure” in subsec. (a)(3)(A)(iv), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s3">Pub. L. 102–329, § 3</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(1)</ref>, (3), substituted “weight or mass” for “weight” and inserted before semicolon at end “, using the most appropriate units of both the customary inch/pound system of measure, as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, and, except as provided in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) or paragraph (6) of this subsection, the SI metric system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/4/A">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “labeled in terms of weight, shall be expressed in pounds” for “containing less than four pounds or one gallon and labeled in terms of weight or fluid measure, shall, unless subparagraph (ii) applies and such statement is set forth in accordance with such subparagraph, be expressed both in ounces (with identification as to avoirdupois or fluid ounces) and, if applicable, in pounds for weight units”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/4/B">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(4)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “three” for “two” and inserted before semicolon at end “and is not required to, but may, include a statement in terms of the SI metric system carried out to not more than three decimal places”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/4/D">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(4)(D)</ref>, substituted “in terms of” for “both in terms of inches and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/4/E">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(4)(E)</ref>, substituted “in terms of” for “both in terms of square inches and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “weight or mass” for “weight”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “weight or mass” for “weight” and “weights or masses” for “weights”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/5">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(5)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–329, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “weight or mass” for “weight”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id797a40df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id797a40e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s2">Pub. L. 102–329, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-08-03">Aug. 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/847">106 Stat. 847</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/329/s2">“The amendments made by section 1 [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1454">section 1454 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1994-02-14">February 14, 1994</date>. The amendments made by section 1 shall have no effect on the sale or distribution of products whose labels have been printed before such effective date. Nothing in the amendments made by section 1 shall apply to unit pricing, advertising, recipe programs, nutrition labeling, or other general pricing information. Nothing in the amendments made by section 1 shall be construed to require changes in package size or to affect in any way the size of packages.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/245/s107/b">Section 107(b) of Pub. L. 102–245</ref>, which provided that <ref href="/us/pl/102/245/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 102–245</ref> which amended this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1454">section 1454 of this title</ref> was to take effect 2 years after <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/329/s3">Pub. L. 102–329, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-08-03">Aug. 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/848">106 Stat. 848</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
