<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id797cb18f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476"><num value="1476">§ 1476.</num><heading> Preemption of Federal standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797cb190-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for identical State standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), whenever a standard established by the Commission under this Act applicable to a household substance is in effect, no State or political subdivision thereof shall have any authority either to establish or continue in effect, with respect to such household substance, any standard for special packaging (and any exemption therefrom and requirement related thereto) which is not identical to the standard established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1472">section 1472 of this title</ref> (and any exemption therefrom and requirement related thereto) of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797cb191-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal or State standards which afford a higher degree of protection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Government and the government of any State or political subdivision of a State may establish and continue in effect, with respect to a household substance for its own use, a standard for special packaging or related requirement which is designed to protect against a risk of illness or injury with respect to which a standard for special packaging or related requirement is in effect under this Act and which is not identical to such standard or requirement if the Federal, State, or political subdivision standard or requirement provides a higher degree of protection from such risk of illness or injury than the standard or requirement in effect under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id797cb192-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption for State standards; requirements; determination of burden on interstate commerce; notice and hearing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797cb193-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon application of a State or political subdivision of a State, the Commission may, by regulation promulgated in accordance with paragraph (2), exempt from subsection (a), under such conditions as may be prescribed in such regulation, any standard for special packaging or related requirement of such State or political subdivision applicable to a household substance subject to a standard or requirement in effect under this Act if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797cb194-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> compliance with the State or political subdivision standard or requirement would not cause the household substance to be in violation of the standard or requirement in effect under this Act, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id797cb195-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the State or political subdivision standard or requirement (i) provides a significantly higher degree of protection from the risk of illness or injury with respect to which the Federal standard or requirement is in effect, and (ii) does not unduly burden interstate commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In determining the burden, if any, of a State or political subdivision standard or requirement on interstate commerce the Commission shall consider and make appropriate (as determined by the Commission in its discretion) findings on the technological and economic feasibility of complying with such standard or requirement, the cost of complying with such standard or requirement, the geographic distribution of the household substance to which the standard or requirement would apply, the probability of other States or political subdivisions applying for an exemption under this subsection for a similar standard or requirement, and the need for a national, uniform standard or requirement under this Act for such household substance.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id797cb196-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1476/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A regulation under paragraph (1) granting an exemption for a standard or requirement of a State or political subdivision of a State may be promulgated by the Commission only after it has provided, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553/b">section 553(b) of title 5</ref> notice with respect to the promulgation of the regulation and has provided opportunity for the oral presentation of views respecting its promulgation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id797cb197-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/601/s7">Pub. L. 91–601, § 7</ref>, formerly § 8, <date date="1970-12-30">Dec. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1673">84 Stat. 1673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s30/a">Pub. L. 92–573, § 30(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1231">86 Stat. 1231</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/284/s17/c">Pub. L. 94–284, § 17(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/513">90 Stat. 513</ref>; renumbered § 7, <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXII/s1205/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title XII, § 1205(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/716">95 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id797cb198-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id797cb199-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id797cb19a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For classification to the Code of “this Act”, referred to in text, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1471">section 1471 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id797cb19b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/284">Pub. L. 94–284</ref> substituted “(a) Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), whenever” for “Whenever” in existing provision, and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id797cb19c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id797cb19d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Commission” substituted for “Secretary” in subsec. (a) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s30/a">section 30(a) of Pub. L. 92–573</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2079/a">section 2079(a) of this title</ref> and which transferred functions of Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under this chapter to Consumer Product Safety Commission.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id797cb19e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Preemption</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions of this section establishing the extent to which the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1471">15 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.] preempts, limits, or otherwise affects any other Federal, State, or local law, any rule, procedure, or regulation, or any cause of action under State or local law not to be expanded or contracted in scope, or limited, modified or extended in application, by any rule or regulation under the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970, or by reference in any preamble, statement of policy, executive branch statements, or other matter associated with the publication of any such rule or regulation, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s231">section 231 of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
