<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79816b9b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514"><num value="1514">§ 1514.</num><heading> Basic authority for performance of certain functions and activities of Department</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appropriations are authorized for the following activities of the Department of Commerce:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79816b9c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> furnishing to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities or supplies are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States, free emergency medical services by contract or otherwise and free emergency medical supplies, where in the judgment of the Secretary furnishing of such supplies and services is necessary;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7983dc9d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> when deemed necessary by the Secretary of Commerce, purchasing, transporting, storing, and distributing food and other subsistence supplies for resale to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities or supplies are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States at a reasonable value as determined by the Secretary of Commerce, the proceeds from such resales to be credited to the appropriation from which the expenditure was made;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7983dc9e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> when deemed necessary by the Secretary of Commerce, the establishment, maintenance, and operation of messing facilities, by contract or otherwise, in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States where suitable family facilities are not available, such service to be furnished to employees of the Department of Commerce and other Federal agencies (including Army, Navy, and Air Force personnel where Army, Navy, or Air Force facilities are not available and upon request of the service concerned), and their dependents, in accordance with regulations established by the Secretary of Commerce, and at a reasonable value determined in accordance therewith, the proceeds from the furnishing of such services to be credited to the appropriation from which the expenditures are made;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7983dc9f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> reimbursement, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, of officers and employees in or under the Department of Commerce, for food, clothing, medicines, and other supplies furnished by them in emergencies for the temporary relief of distressed persons in remote localities;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7983dca0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> providing motion-picture equipment and film for recreation of crews of vessels of the National Ocean Survey, for recreation of employees in remote localities where such facilities are not available, and for training purposes;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7983dca1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1514/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> erecting, altering, repairing, equipping, furnishing, and maintaining, by contract or otherwise, such living and working quarters and facilities as may be necessary to carry out its authorized work at remote localities not on foreign soil where such living and working accommodations are not otherwise available.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7983dca2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-10-26/ch733">Oct. 26, 1949, ch. 733</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/907">63 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1076/s1/11">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1076, § 1(11)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/967">68 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/608/s1/3">Pub. L. 93–608, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1967">88 Stat. 1967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7983dca3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7983dca4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7983dca5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s596a">section 596a of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7983dca6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/608">Pub. L. 93–608</ref> struck out proviso requiring an annual report to Congress of the total expenditures made for such supplies and total proceeds from resales.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>, struck out proviso requiring the Secretary of Commerce to submit annually to Congress a report showing the expenditures for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of messing facilities in Alaska and other points outside the continental United States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7983dca7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7983dca8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Coast and Geodetic Survey consolidated with National Weather Bureau in 1965 to form Environmental Science Services Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>. Environmental Science Services Administration abolished in 1970 and its personnel, property, records, etc., transferred to National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1511">section 1511 of this title</ref>. By order of Acting Associate Administrator of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 35 F.R. 19249, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, Coast and Geodetic Survey redesignated National Ocean Survey. See notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s311">section 311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
