<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7983dcb0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1516"><num value="1516">§ 1516.</num><heading> Statistical information</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall have control of the work of gathering and distributing statistical information naturally relating to the subjects confided to his department; and he shall have the power and authority to rearrange the statistical work of the bureaus and offices confided to the Department of Commerce, and to consolidate any of the statistical bureaus and offices above described. He shall also have authority to call upon other departments of the Government for statistical data and results obtained by them; and he may collate, arrange, and publish such statistical information so obtained in such manner as to him may seem wise.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7983dcb1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1903-02-14/ch552/s4">Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4</ref> (part), <ref href="/us/stat/32/826">32 Stat. 826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7983dcb2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7983dcb3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7983dcb4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s601">section 601 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on part of the first par. of section 4 of act <date date="1903-02-14">Feb. 14, 1903</date>. The rest of the first par. and the second par. of section 4 are classified to sections 1511 and 1515 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7983dcb5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7983dcb6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch141">Act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/736">37 Stat. 736</ref>, provided that the Department of Commerce and Labor and Secretary of Commerce and Labor were to be thereafter called the Department of Commerce and Secretary of Commerce and that the act creating the Department of Commerce and Labor (act <date date="1903-02-14">Feb. 14, 1903</date>) was amended accordingly.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
