<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7986264c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538"><num value="1538">§ 1538.</num><heading> Notice of reprogramming</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7986264d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall provide notice to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, not less than 15 days before reprogramming funds available for a program, project, or activity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in an amount greater than the lesser of $250,000 or 5 percent of the total funding of such program, project, or activity if the reprogramming—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7986264e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> augments an existing program, project, or activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7986264f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> reduces by 5 percent or more (A) the funding for an existing program, project, or activity or (B) the numbers of personnel therefor as approved by Congress; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79862650-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> results from any general savings from a reduction in personnel which would result in a change in an existing program, project, or activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79862651-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1538/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of reorganization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce shall provide notice to the Committees on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, Science, Space, and Technology, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Appropriations of the Senate not later than 15 days before any major reorganization of any program, project, or activity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79862652-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/567/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 102–567, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4291">106 Stat. 4291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79862653-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79862654-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79862655-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of House of Representatives abolished and its jurisdiction transferred by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. For treatment of references to Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b/3">section 1(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
