<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id798897e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602"><num value="1602">§ 1602.</num><heading> Definitions and rules of construction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The definitions and rules of construction set forth in this section are applicable for the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bureau</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The term “Board” refers to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The term “organization” means a corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, trust, estate, partnership, cooperative, or association.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The term “person” means a natural person or an organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The term “credit” means the right granted by a creditor to a debtor to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The term “creditor” refers only to a person who both (1) regularly extends, whether in connection with loans, sales of property or services, or otherwise, consumer credit which is payable by agreement in more than four installments or for which the payment of a finance charge is or may be required, and (2) is the person to whom the debt arising from the consumer credit transaction is initially payable on the face of the evidence of indebtedness or, if there is no such evidence of indebtedness, by agreement. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in the case of an open-end credit plan involving a credit card, the card issuer and any person who honors the credit card and offers a discount which is a finance charge are creditors. For the purpose of the requirements imposed under part D of this subchapter and sections 1637(a)(5), 1637(a)(6), 1637(a)(7), 1637(b)(1), 1637(b)(2), 1637(b)(3), 1637(b)(8), and 1637(b)(10) of this title, the term “creditor” shall also include card issuers whether or not the amount due is payable by agreement in more than four installments or the payment of a finance charge is or may be required, and the Bureau shall, by regulation, apply these requirements to such card issuers, to the extent appropriate, even though the requirements are by their terms applicable only to creditors offering open-end credit plans. Any person who originates 2 or more mortgages referred to in subsection (aa) in any 12-month period or any person who originates 1 or more such mortgages through a mortgage broker shall be considered to be a creditor for purposes of this subchapter. The term “creditor” includes a private educational lender (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1650">section 1650 of this title</ref>) for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The term “credit sale” refers to any sale in which the seller is a creditor. The term includes any contract in the form of a bailment or lease if the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation for use a sum substantially equivalent to or in excess of the aggregate value of the property and services involved and it is agreed that the bailee or lessee will become, or for no other or a nominal consideration has the option to become, the owner of the property upon full compliance with his obligations under the contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The adjective “consumer”, used with reference to a credit transaction, characterizes the transaction as one in which the party to whom credit is offered or extended is a natural person, and the money, property, or services which are the subject of the transaction are primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The terms “open end credit plan” and “open end consumer credit plan” mean a plan under which the creditor reasonably contemplates repeated transactions, which prescribes the terms of such transactions, and which provides for a finance charge which may be computed from time to time on the outstanding unpaid balance. A credit plan or open end consumer credit plan which is an open end credit plan or open end consumer credit plan within the meaning of the preceding sentence is an open end credit plan or open end consumer credit plan even if credit information is verified from time to time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> The term “adequate notice,” as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1643">section 1643 of this title</ref>, means a printed notice to a cardholder which sets forth the pertinent facts clearly and conspicuously so that a person against whom it is to operate could reasonably be expected to have noticed it and understood its meaning. Such notice may be given to a cardholder by printing the notice on any credit card, or on each periodic statement of account, issued to the cardholder, or by any other means reasonably assuring the receipt thereof by the cardholder.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> The term “credit card” means any card, plate, coupon book or other credit device existing for the purpose of obtaining money, property, labor, or services on credit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content> The term “accepted credit card” means any credit card which the cardholder has requested and received or has signed or has used, or authorized another to use, for the purpose of obtaining money, property, labor, or services on credit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> The term “cardholder” means any person to whom a credit card is issued or any person who has agreed with the card issuer to pay obligations arising from the issuance of a credit card to another person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content> The term “card issuer” means any person who issues a credit card, or the agent of such person with respect to such card.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> The term “unauthorized use,” as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1643">section 1643 of this title</ref>, means a use of a credit card by a person other than the cardholder who does not have actual, implied, or apparent authority for such use and from which the cardholder receives no benefit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content> The term “discount” as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666f">section 1666f of this title</ref> means a reduction made from the regular price. The term “discount” as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666f">section 1666f of this title</ref> shall not mean a surcharge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content> The term “surcharge” as used in this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666f">section 1666f of this title</ref> means any means of increasing the regular price to a cardholder which is not imposed upon customers paying by cash, check, or similar means.”</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content> The term “State” refers to any State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content> The term “agricultural purposes” includes the production, harvest, exhibition, marketing, transportation, processing, or manufacture of agricultural products by a natural person who cultivates, plants, propagates, or nurtures those agricultural products, including but not limited to the acquisition of farmland, real property with a farm residence, and personal property and services used primarily in farming.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content> The term “agricultural products” includes agricultural, horticultural, viticultural, and dairy products, livestock, wildlife, poultry, bees, forest products, fish and shellfish, and any products thereof, including processed and manufactured products, and any and all products raised or produced on farms and any processed or manufactured products thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The term “material disclosures” means the disclosure, as required by this subchapter, of the annual percentage rate, the method of determining the finance charge and the balance upon which a finance charge will be imposed, the amount of the finance charge, the amount to be financed, the total of payments, the number and amount of payments, the due dates or periods of payments scheduled to repay the indebtedness, and the disclosures required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639/a">section 1639(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content> The term “dwelling” means a residential structure or mobile home which contains one to four family housing units, or individual units of condominiums or cooperatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> The term “residential mortgage transaction” means a transaction in which a mortgage, deed of trust, purchase money security interest arising under an installment sales contract, or equivalent consensual security interest is created or retained against the consumer’s dwelling to finance the acquisition or initial construction of such dwelling.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id798897ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content> As used in this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666f">section 1666f of this title</ref>, the term “regular price” means the tag or posted price charged for the property or service if a single price is tagged or posted, or the price charged for the property or service when payment is made by use of an open-end credit plan or a credit card if either (1) no price is tagged or posted, or (2) two prices are tagged or posted, one of which is charged when payment is made by use of an open-end credit plan or a credit card and the other when payment is made by use of cash, check, or similar means. For purposes of this definition, payment by check, draft, or other negotiable instrument which may result in the debiting of an open-end credit plan or a credit cardholder’s open-end account shall not be considered payment made by use of the plan or the account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889800-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/z"><num value="z">(z)</num><content> Any reference to any requirement imposed under this subchapter or any provision thereof includes reference to the regulations of the Bureau under this subchapter or the provision thereof in question.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889801-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The disclosure of an amount or percentage which is greater than the amount or percentage required to be disclosed under this subchapter does not in itself constitute a violation of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889802-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">High-cost Mortgage.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889803-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889804-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “high-cost mortgage”, and a mortgage referred to in this subsection, means a consumer credit transaction that is secured by the consumer’s principal dwelling, other than a reverse mortgage transaction, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889805-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of a credit transaction secured—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79889806-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> by a first mortgage on the consumer’s principal dwelling, the annual percentage rate at consummation of the transaction will exceed by more than 6.5 percentage points (8.5 percentage points, if the dwelling is personal property and the transaction is for less than $50,000) the average prime offer rate, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639c/b/2/B">section 1639c(b)(2)(B) of this title</ref>, for a comparable transaction; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79889807-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> by a subordinate or junior mortgage on the consumer’s principal dwelling, the annual percentage rate at consummation of the transaction will exceed by more than 8.5 percentage points the average prime offer rate, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639c/b/2/B">section 1639c(b)(2)(B) of this title</ref>, for a comparable transaction;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889808-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the total points and fees payable in connection with the transaction, other than bona fide third party charges not retained by the mortgage originator, creditor, or an affiliate of the creditor or mortgage originator, exceed—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79889809-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the case of a transaction for $20,000 or more, 5 percent of the total transaction amount; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7988980a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> in the case of a transaction for less than $20,000, the lesser of 8 percent of the total transaction amount or $1,000 (or such other dollar amount as the Board shall prescribe by regulation); or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7988980b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the credit transaction documents permit the creditor to charge or collect prepayment fees or penalties more than 36 months after the transaction closing or such fees or penalties exceed, in the aggregate, more than 2 percent of the amount prepaid.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7988980c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Introductory rates taken into account</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the annual percentage rate of interest shall be determined based on the following interest rate:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7988980d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In the case of a fixed-rate transaction in which the annual percentage rate will not vary during the term of the loan, the interest rate in effect on the date of consummation of the transaction.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7988980e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> In the case of a transaction in which the rate of interest varies solely in accordance with an index, the interest rate determined by adding the index rate in effect on the date of consummation of the transaction to the maximum margin permitted at any time during the loan agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7988980f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> In the case of any other transaction in which the rate may vary at any time during the term of the loan for any reason, the interest charged on the transaction at the maximum rate that may be charged during the term of the loan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889810-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Mortgage insurance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the purposes of computing the total points and fees under paragraph (4), the total points and fees shall exclude—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889811-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any premium provided by an agency of the Federal Government or an agency of a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889812-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any amount that is not in excess of the amount payable under policies in effect at the time of origination under section 203(c)(2)(A) of the National Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1709/c/2/A">12 U.S.C. 1709(c)(2)(A)</ref>), provided that the premium, charge, or fee is required to be refundable on a pro-rated basis and the refund is automatically issued upon notification of the satisfaction of the underlying mortgage loan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889813-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any premium paid by the consumer after closing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889814-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889815-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> After the 2-year period beginning on the effective date of the regulations promulgated under section 155 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994, and no more frequently than biennially after the first increase or decrease under this subparagraph, the Bureau may by regulation increase or decrease the number of percentage points specified in paragraph (1)(A), if the Bureau determines that the increase or decrease is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889816-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consistent with the consumer protections against abusive lending provided by the amendments made by subtitle B of title I of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889817-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> warranted by the need for credit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889818-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> An increase or decrease under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889819-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> may not result in the number of percentage points referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i)(I) being less than 6 percentage points or greater than 10 percentage points; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988981a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may not result in the number of percentage points referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i)(II) being less than 8 percentage points or greater than 12 percentage points.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7988981b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In determining whether to increase or decrease the number of percentage points referred to in subparagraph (A), the Bureau shall consult with representatives of consumers, including low-income consumers, and lenders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7988981c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The amount specified in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) shall be adjusted annually on January 1 by the annual percentage change in the Consumer Price Index, as reported on June 1 of the year preceding such adjustment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7988981d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), points and fees shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988981e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all items included in the finance charge, except interest or the time-price differential;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988981f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all compensation paid directly or indirectly by a consumer or creditor to a mortgage originator from any source, including a mortgage originator that is also the creditor in a table-funded transaction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889820-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> each of the charges listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1605/e">section 1605(e) of this title</ref> (except an escrow for future payment of taxes), unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889821-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the charge is reasonable;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889822-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the creditor receives no direct or indirect compensation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889823-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the charge is paid to a third party unaffiliated with the creditor; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889824-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> premiums or other charges payable at or before closing for any credit life, credit disability, credit unemployment, or credit property insurance, or any other accident, loss-of-income, life or health insurance, or any payments directly or indirectly for any debt cancellation or suspension agreement or contract, except that insurance premiums or debt cancellation or suspension fees calculated and paid in full on a monthly basis shall not be considered financed by the creditor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889825-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the maximum prepayment fees and penalties which may be charged or collected under the terms of the credit transaction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889826-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> all prepayment fees or penalties that are incurred by the consumer if the loan refinances a previous loan made or currently held by the same creditor or an affiliate of the creditor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889827-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> such other charges as the Bureau determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889828-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Calculation of points and fees for open-end consumer credit plans</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of open-end consumer credit plans, points and fees shall be calculated, for purposes of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639">section 1639 of this title</ref>, by adding the total points and fees known at or before closing, including the maximum prepayment penalties which may be charged or collected under the terms of the credit transaction, plus the minimum additional fees the consumer would be required to pay to draw down an amount equal to the total credit line.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889829-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> This subsection shall not be construed to limit the rate of interest or the finance charge that a person may charge a consumer for any extension of credit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7988982a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><chapeau> The term “reverse mortgage transaction” means a nonrecourse transaction in which a mortgage, deed of trust, or equivalent consensual security interest is created against the consumer’s principal dwelling—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988982b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> securing one or more advances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988982c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> with respect to which the payment of any principal, interest, and shared appreciation or equity is due and payable (other than in the case of default) only after—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7988982d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transfer of the dwelling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7988982e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the consumer ceases to occupy the dwelling as a principal dwelling; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7988982f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/cc/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the death of the consumer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79889830-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions Relating to Mortgage Origination and Residential Mortgage Loans.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889831-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commission</inline>.—</heading><content>Unless otherwise specified, the term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889832-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Mortgage originator</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “mortgage originator”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889833-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> means any person who, for direct or indirect compensation or gain, or in the expectation of direct or indirect compensation or gain—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889834-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> takes a residential mortgage loan application;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889835-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> assists a consumer in obtaining or applying to obtain a residential mortgage loan; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889836-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> offers or negotiates terms of a residential mortgage loan;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889837-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes any person who represents to the public, through advertising or other means of communicating or providing information (including the use of business cards, stationery, brochures, signs, rate lists, or other promotional items), that such person can or will provide any of the services or perform any of the activities described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889838-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> does not include any person who is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889839-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> not otherwise described in subparagraph (A) or (B) and who performs purely administrative or clerical tasks on behalf of a person who is described in any such subparagraph; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7988983a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> a retailer of manufactured or modular homes or an employee of the retailer if the retailer or employee, as applicable—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7988983b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> does not receive compensation or gain for engaging in activities described in subparagraph (A) that is in excess of any compensation or gain received in a comparable cash transaction;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7988983c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> discloses to the consumer—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id7988983d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> in writing any corporate affiliation with any creditor; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id7988983e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> if the retailer has a corporate affiliation with any creditor, at least 1 unaffiliated creditor; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7988983f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> does not directly negotiate with the consumer or lender on loan terms (including rates, fees, and other costs).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889840-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> does not include a person or entity that only performs real estate brokerage activities and is licensed or registered in accordance with applicable State law, unless such person or entity is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other mortgage originator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other mortgage originator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889841-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> does not include, with respect to a residential mortgage loan, a person, estate, or trust that provides mortgage financing for the sale of 3 properties in any 12-month period to purchasers of such properties, each of which is owned by such person, estate, or trust and serves as security for the loan, provided that such loan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889842-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is not made by a person, estate, or trust that has constructed, or acted as a contractor for the construction of, a residence on the property in the ordinary course of business of such person, estate, or trust;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889843-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is fully amortizing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889844-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is with respect to a sale for which the seller determines in good faith and documents that the buyer has a reasonable ability to repay the loan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889845-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> has a fixed rate or an adjustable rate that is adjustable after 5 or more years, subject to reasonable annual and lifetime limitations on interest rate increases; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79889846-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> meets any other criteria the Board may prescribe;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889847-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> does not include the creditor (except the creditor in a table-funded transaction) under paragraph (1), (2), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639b/c">section 1639b(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889848-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> does not include a servicer or servicer employees, agents and contractors, including but not limited to those who offer or negotiate terms of a residential mortgage loan for purposes of renegotiating, modifying, replacing and subordinating principal of existing mortgages where borrowers are behind in their payments, in default or have a reasonable likelihood of being in default or falling behind.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889849-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nationwide mortgage licensing system and registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry” has the same meaning as in the Secure and Fair Enforcement for Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5101">12 U.S.C. 5101</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988984a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other definitions relating to mortgage originator</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subsection, a person “assists a consumer in obtaining or applying to obtain a residential mortgage loan” by, among other things, advising on residential mortgage loan terms (including rates, fees, and other costs), preparing residential mortgage loan packages, or collecting information on behalf of the consumer with regard to a residential mortgage loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988984b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Residential mortgage loan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “residential mortgage loan” means any consumer credit transaction that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other equivalent consensual security interest on a dwelling or on residential real property that includes a dwelling, other than a consumer credit transaction under an open end credit plan or, for purposes of sections 1639b and 1639c of this title and section 1638(a) (16), (17), (18), and (19) of this title, and sections 1638(f) and 1640(k) of this title, and any regulations promulgated thereunder, an extension of credit relating to a plan described in section 101(53D) of title 11.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988984c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Secretary”, when used in connection with any transaction or person involved with a residential mortgage loan, means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988984d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/dd/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Servicer</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “servicer” has the same meaning as in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2605/i/2">section 2605(i)(2) of title 12</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7988984e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bona Fide Discount Points and Prepayment Penalties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the purposes of determining the amount of points and fees for purposes of subsection (aa), either the amounts described in paragraph (1) or (2) of the following paragraphs, but not both, shall be excluded:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7988984f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Up to and including 2 bona fide discount points payable by the consumer in connection with the mortgage, but only if the interest rate from which the mortgage’s interest rate will be discounted does not exceed by more than 1 percentage point—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889850-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the average prime offer rate, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639c">section 1639c of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889851-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if secured by a personal property loan, the average rate on a loan in connection with which insurance is provided under title I of the National Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1702">12 U.S.C. 1702</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889852-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Unless 2 bona fide discount points have been excluded under paragraph (1), up to and including 1 bona fide discount point payable by the consumer in connection with the mortgage, but only if the interest rate from which the mortgage’s interest rate will be discounted does not exceed by more than 2 percentage points—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889853-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the average prime offer rate, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639c">section 1639c of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79889854-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if secured by a personal property loan, the average rate on a loan in connection with which insurance is provided under title I of the National Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1702">12 U.S.C. 1702</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889855-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “bona fide discount points” means loan discount points which are knowingly paid by the consumer for the purpose of reducing, and which in fact result in a bona fide reduction of, the interest rate or time-price differential applicable to the mortgage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79889856-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1602/ee/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply to discount points used to purchase an interest rate reduction unless the amount of the interest rate reduction purchased is reasonably consistent with established industry norms and practices for secondary mortgage market transactions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79889857-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tI/s103">Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1968-05-29">May 29, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/147">82 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/508/tV/s501">Pub. L. 91–508, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1126">84 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 93–495, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1511">88 Stat. 1511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/222/s3/a">Pub. L. 94–222, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-02-27">Feb. 27, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/197">90 Stat. 197</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVI">Pub. L. 96–221, title VI</ref>, §§ 602, 603(a), (b), 604, 612(a)(2), (b), <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/168">94 Stat. 168</ref>, 169, 175, 176; <ref href="/us/pl/97/25/tI/s102">Pub. L. 97–25, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1981-07-27">July 27, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/144">95 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tVII/s702/a">Pub. L. 97–320, title VII, § 702(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1538">96 Stat. 1538</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tI">Pub. L. 103–325, title I</ref>, §§ 152(a)–(c), 154(a), <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2190">108 Stat. 2190</ref>, 2191, 2196; <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/tX/s1011/b">Pub. L. 110–315, title X, § 1011(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3481">122 Stat. 3481</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/tI/s108">Pub. L. 111–24, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1743">123 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1100A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100A(1)</ref>, (2), title XIV, §§ 1401, 1431, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2107">124 Stat. 2107</ref>, 2137, 2157; <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tI/s107">Pub. L. 115–174, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1304">132 Stat. 1304</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79889858-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79889859-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7988985a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994, referred to in subsec. (bb)(2)(A)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2160">108 Stat. 2160</ref>. Section 155 of the Act is set out below. For classification of subtitle B of title I of the Act, known as the “Home Ownership and Equity Protection Act of 1994”, see Short Title of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s4701">section 4701 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Secure and Fair Enforcement for Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008, referred to in subsec. (dd)(3), is title V of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/110/289">Pub. L. 110–289</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2810">122 Stat. 2810</ref>, also known as the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008, which is classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 5101 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5101">section 5101 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Housing Act, referred to in subsec. (ee)(1)(B), (2)(B), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1702 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7988985b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsecs. (cc), (dd). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s107/1">Pub. L. 115–174, § 107(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (cc), relating to definitions relating to mortgage origination and residential mortgage loans, as (dd). Former subsec. (dd) redesignated (ee).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (dd)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s107/2">Pub. L. 115–174, § 107(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “does not include any person who is (i) not otherwise described in subparagraph (A) or (B) and who performs purely administrative or clerical tasks on behalf of a person who is described in any such subparagraph, or (ii) an employee of a retailer of manufactured homes who is not described in clause (i) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) and who does not advise a consumer on loan terms (including rates, fees, and other costs);”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (ee). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s107/1">Pub. L. 115–174, § 107(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (dd) as (ee).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100A/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100A(2)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Bureau” for “Board” wherever appearing, was executed by making the substitution wherever appearing in subsecs. (g), (z), and (bb)(2)(A), (C), (4)(D), but not in subsec. (c), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (z). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsecs. (b) to (z) as (c) to (aa), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/a">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(a)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (aa) by inserting subsec. heading, adding par. (1), and striking out former par. (1), was executed by making the amendment to subsec. (bb) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (aa) as (bb) by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>. See below. Text of former par. (1) read as follows: “A mortgage referred to in this subsection means a consumer credit transaction that is secured by the consumer’s principal dwelling, other than a residential mortgage transaction, a reverse mortgage transaction, or a transaction under an open end credit plan, if—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the annual percentage rate at consummation of the transaction will exceed by more than 10 percentage points the yield on Treasury securities having comparable periods of maturity on the fifteenth day of the month immediately preceding the month in which the application for the extension of credit is received by the creditor; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the total points and fees payable by the consumer at or before closing will exceed the greater of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) 8 percent of the total loan amount; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) $400.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (aa) as (bb). Former subsec. (bb) redesignated (cc).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/b">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(b)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (aa)(2) by adding subpar. (B) and striking out former subpar. (B), was executed by making the amendment to subsec. (bb)(2) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (aa) as (bb) by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>. See above. Text of former subpar. (B) read as follows: “An increase or decrease under subparagraph (A) may not result in the number of percentage points referred to in subparagraph (A) being—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) less that 8 percentage points; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) greater than 12 percentage points.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/c/1/A">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(c)(1)(A)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (aa)(4) by adding subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B), was executed by making the amendment to subsec. (bb)(4) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (aa) as (bb) by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>. See above. Text of former subpar. (B) read as follows: “all compensation paid to mortgage brokers;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb)(4)(D) to (G). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/c/1/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), which directed amendment of subsec. (aa)(4) by adding subpars. (D) to (F) and redesignating former subpar. (D) as (G), was executed by making the amendment to subsec. (bb)(4) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (aa) as (bb) by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/c/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(c)(2)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (aa) by adding par. (5) and redesignating former par. (5) as (6), was executed by making the amendment to subsec. (bb) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of subsec. (aa) as (bb) by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (cc). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1401">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1401</ref>, added subsec. (cc) relating to definitions relating to mortgage origination and residential mortgage loans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100/A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100(A)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (bb) as (cc) defining the term “reverse mortgage transaction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (dd). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1431/d">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1431(d)</ref>, added subsec. (dd).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/24">Pub. L. 111–24</ref> substituted “terms ‘open end credit plan’ and ‘open end consumer credit plan’ mean” for “term ‘open end credit plan’ means” in first sentence and inserted “or open end consumer credit plan” after “credit plan” wherever appearing in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315">Pub. L. 110–315</ref> inserted at end “The term ‘creditor’ includes a private educational lender (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1650">section 1650 of this title</ref>) for purposes of this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s152/c">Pub. L. 103–325, § 152(c)</ref>, inserted at end “Any person who originates 2 or more mortgages referred to in subsection (aa) in any 12-month period or any person who originates 1 or more such mortgages through a mortgage broker shall be considered to be a creditor for purposes of this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s152/b">Pub. L. 103–325, § 152(b)</ref>, substituted “the due dates” for “and the due dates” and inserted before period at end “, and the disclosures required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1639/a">section 1639(a) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (aa). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s152/a">Pub. L. 103–325, § 152(a)</ref>, added subsec. (aa).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (bb). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s154/a">Pub. L. 103–325, § 154(a)</ref>, added subsec. (bb).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/320">Pub. L. 97–320</ref> struck out provision that a person who regularly arranged for the extension of consumer credit payable in more than four installments or for which the payment of a finance charge was or might have been required from persons not creditors was a creditor, and provision that this subchapter applied to any creditor, irrespective of his or its status as a natural person or any type of organization, who was a card issuer.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsecs. (x) to (z). <ref href="/us/pl/97/25">Pub. L. 97–25</ref> added subsec. (z) and, effective <date date="1982-04-10">Apr. 10, 1982</date>, redesignated subsecs. (x), (y), and (z) as (y), (z), and (x), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s602/a">Pub. L. 96–221, § 602(a)</ref>, substituted provisions defining term “creditor” as referring only to a person who both regularly extends consumer credit, subject to specified conditions, and is the person to whom the debt arising is initially payable on the face of the indebtedness or by agreement, and notwithstanding such provisions, also refers to a person regularly arranging for the extension of consumer credit, and a card issuer and any person honoring the credit card, subject to specified conditions, for provisions defining term “creditor” as referring only to creditors who regularly extend, or arrange for the extension of credit payable in more than four installments or where a finance charge is or may be required, and substituted “(a)(5)” for “(a)(6)”, “(a)(6)” for “(a)(7)”, “(a)(7)” for “(a)(8)”, “(b)(8)” for “(b)(9)”, and “(b)(10)” for “(b)(11)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s602/b">Pub. L. 96–221, § 602(b)</ref>, substituted “in which the seller is a creditor” for “with respect to which credit is extended or arranged by the seller”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s603/a">Pub. L. 96–221, § 603(a)</ref>, struck out applicability to agricultural purposes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s604">Pub. L. 96–221, § 604</ref>, inserted provisions respecting the reasonable contemplations of the creditor, and verification of credit information from time to time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (s), (t). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s603/b">Pub. L. 96–221, § 603(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (s) and (t). Former subsecs. (s) and (t) redesignated (x) and (y), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s612/a/2">Pub. L. 96–221, § 612(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (u).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (v), (w). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s612/b">Pub. L. 96–221, § 612(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (v) and (w).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (x), (y). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s603/b">Pub. L. 96–221, § 603(b)</ref>, redesignated former subsecs. (s) and (t) as (x) and (y), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsecs. (p) to (t). <ref href="/us/pl/94/222">Pub. L. 94–222</ref> added subsecs. (p) and (q) and redesignated former subsecs. (p) to (r) as (r) to (t), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/495">Pub. L. 93–495</ref> inserted provision requiring the credit to be payable by agreement in more than four installments and defining term “creditor” for the purposes of the requirements imposed under the enumerated sections of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsecs. (j) to (r). <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Pub. L. 91–508</ref> added subsecs. (j) to (<i>o</i>) and redesignated former subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>) as (p) to (r), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7988985c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7988985d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1100A(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1401 and 1431 of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the date on which final regulations implementing that amendment take effect, or on the date that is 18 months after the designated transfer date if such regulations have not been issued by that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1400/c">section 1400(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7988985e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/24/s3">Pub. L. 111–24, § 3</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1735">123 Stat. 1735</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/24/s3">“This Act [enacting sections 1616, 1651, 1665c to 1665e, 1666i–1, 1666i–2, and 1693<i>l</i>–1 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1a–7b">section 1a–7b of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, amending this section and sections 1632, 1637, 1640, 1650, 1666b, 1666c, 1666j, 1681b, 1681j, and 1693m to 1693r of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 1637, 1638, 1666b, 1681j, and 1693<i>l</i>–1 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s5311">section 5311 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and amending provisions set out as notes under sections 1638 and 1693 of this title] and the amendments made by this Act shall become effective 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>], except as otherwise specifically provided in this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7988985f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/320/tVII/s702/b">Pub. L. 97–320, title VII, § 702(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1538">96 Stat. 1538</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/320/tVII/s702/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the effective date of title VI of the Depository Institutions Deregulation and Monetary Control Act of 1980 [two years and six months after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, see Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note below].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79889860-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/25/s102/b">Section 102(b) of Pub. L. 97–25</ref> provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1982-04-10">Apr. 10, 1982</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79889861-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVI/s625">Pub. L. 96–221, title VI, § 625</ref>, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/185">94 Stat. 185</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/25/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 97–25, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1981-07-27">July 27, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/145">95 Stat. 145</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/110/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 97–110, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1981-12-26">Dec. 26, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1515">95 Stat. 1515</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/110/tIII/s301">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Except as provided in section 608(b) [set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1607">section 1607 of this title</ref>], the amendments made by this title [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1646">section 1646 of this title</ref>, amending sections 57a, 1602 to 1606, 1610, 1612, 1613, 1631, 1632, 1635, 1637, 1638, 1640, 1641, 1643, 1663, 1664, 1665a, 1666, 1666d, 1667d, and 1691f of this title, repealing sections 1614, 1636, and 1639 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>] shall take effect upon the expiration of two years and six months after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> All regulations, forms, and clauses required to be prescribed under the amendments made by this title shall be promulgated at least one year prior to such effective date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any creditor may comply with the amendments made by this title, in accordance with the regulations, forms, and clauses prescribed by the Board, prior to such effective date. Any creditor who elects to comply with such amendments and any assignee of such a creditor shall be subject to the provisions of sections 130 and 131 of the Truth in Lending Act, as amended by sections 615 and 616, respectively, of this title [sections 1640 and 1641 of this title].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79889862-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/495">Pub. L. 93–495</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/s308">section 308 of Pub. L. 93–495</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666">section 1666 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79889863-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/24/s2">Pub. L. 111–24, § 2</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1735">123 Stat. 1735</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/24/s2">“The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (in this Act [see Short Title of 2009 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>] referred to as the ‘Board’) may issue such rules and publish such model forms as it considers necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tI/s155">Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 155</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2197">108 Stat. 2197</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/325/tI/s155">“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>], the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 151–158) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref>, see Short Title of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>], and such regulations shall become effective on the date on which disclosure regulations are required to become effective under section 105(d) of the Truth in Lending Act [15 U.S.C. § 1604(d)].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79889864-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of 1994 Amendments and Regulations to Subsection (aa) Mortgages</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tI/s156">Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 156</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2197">108 Stat. 2197</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/325/tI/s156">“This subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 151–158) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref>, see Short Title of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>], and the amendments made by this subtitle, shall apply to every mortgage referred to in section 103(aa) of the Truth in Lending Act [now <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1602/bb">15 U.S.C. 1602(bb)</ref>] (as added by section 152(a) of this Act) consummated on or after the date on which regulations issued under section 155 [set out above] become effective.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
