<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7999391e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e"><num value="1639e">§ 1639e.</num><heading> Appraisal independence requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7999391f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful, in extending credit or in providing any services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of the consumer, to engage in any act or practice that violates appraisal independence as described in or pursuant to regulations prescribed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993920-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appraisal independence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), acts or practices that violate appraisal independence shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993921-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any appraisal of a property offered as security for repayment of the consumer credit transaction that is conducted in connection with such transaction in which a person with an interest in the underlying transaction compensates, coerces, extorts, colludes, instructs, induces, bribes, or intimidates a person, appraisal management company, firm, or other entity conducting or involved in an appraisal, or attempts, to compensate, coerce, extort, collude, instruct, induce, bribe, or intimidate such a person, for the purpose of causing the appraised value assigned, under the appraisal, to the property to be based on any factor other than the independent judgment of the appraiser;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993922-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> mischaracterizing, or suborning any mischaracterization of, the appraised value of the property securing the extension of the credit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993923-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> seeking to influence an appraiser or otherwise to encourage a targeted value in order to facilitate the making or pricing of the transaction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993924-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> withholding or threatening to withhold timely payment for an appraisal report or for appraisal services rendered when the appraisal report or services are provided for in accordance with the contract between the parties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993925-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The requirements of subsection (b) shall not be construed as prohibiting a mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage banker, real estate broker, appraisal management company, employee of an appraisal management company, consumer, or any other person with an interest in a real estate transaction from asking an appraiser to undertake 1 or more of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993926-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Consider additional, appropriate property information, including the consideration of additional comparable properties to make or support an appraisal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993927-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Provide further detail, substantiation, or explanation for the appraiser’s value conclusion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79993928-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Correct errors in the appraisal report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993929-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on conflicts of interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No certified or licensed appraiser conducting, and no appraisal management company procuring or facilitating, an appraisal in connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer may have a direct or indirect interest, financial or otherwise, in the property or transaction involving the appraisal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage banker, real estate broker, appraisal management company, employee of an appraisal management company, or any other person involved in a real estate transaction involving an appraisal in connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer who has a reasonable basis to believe an appraiser is failing to comply with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, is violating applicable laws, or is otherwise engaging in unethical or unprofessional conduct, shall refer the matter to the applicable State appraiser certifying and licensing agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> No extension of credit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling, a creditor who knows, at or before loan consummation, of a violation of the appraisal independence standards established in subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002353">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002353"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (b) or (d) shall not extend credit based on such appraisal unless the creditor documents that the creditor has acted with reasonable diligence to determine that the appraisal does not materially misstate or misrepresent the value of such dwelling.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and interpretive guidelines</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Board, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau may jointly issue rules, interpretive guidelines, and general statements of policy with respect to acts or practices that violate appraisal independence in the provision of mortgage lending services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of the consumer and mortgage brokerage services for such a transaction, within the meaning of subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (h), and (i).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim final regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board shall, for purposes of this section, prescribe interim final regulations no later than 90 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, defining with specificity acts or practices that violate appraisal independence in the provision of mortgage lending services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of the consumer or mortgage brokerage services for such a transaction and defining any terms in this section or such regulations. Rules prescribed by the Board under this paragraph shall be deemed to be rules prescribed by the agencies jointly under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7999392f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Appraisal report portability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the Board, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau may jointly issue regulations that address the issue of appraisal report portability, including regulations that ensure the portability of the appraisal report between lenders for a consumer credit transaction secured by a 1-4 unit single family residence that is the principal dwelling of the consumer, or mortgage brokerage services for such a transaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993930-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Customary and reasonable fee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79993931-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Lenders and their agents shall compensate fee appraisers at a rate that is customary and reasonable for appraisal services performed in the market area of the property being appraised. Evidence for such fees may be established by objective third-party information, such as government agency fee schedules, academic studies, and independent private sector surveys. Fee studies shall exclude assignments ordered by known appraisal management companies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79993932-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee appraiser definition</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79993933-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this section, the term “fee appraiser” means a person who is not an employee of the mortgage loan originator or appraisal management company engaging the appraiser and is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79993934-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a State licensed or certified appraiser who receives a fee for performing an appraisal and certifies that the appraisal has been prepared in accordance with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79993935-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a company not subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3353">section 3353 of title 12</ref> that utilizes the services of State licensed or certified appraisers and receives a fee for performing appraisals in accordance with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79993936-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction related to appraisal donations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a fee appraiser voluntarily donates appraisal services to an organization eligible to receive tax-deductible charitable contributions, such voluntary donation shall be considered customary and reasonable for the purposes of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79993937-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for complex assignments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of an appraisal involving a complex assignment, the customary and reasonable fee may reflect the increased time, difficulty, and scope of the work required for such an appraisal and include an amount over and above the customary and reasonable fee for non-complex assignments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993938-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective on the date the interim final regulations are promulgated pursuant to subsection (g), the Home Valuation Code of Conduct announced by the Federal Housing Finance Agency on <date date="2008-12-23">December 23, 2008</date>, shall have no force or effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79993939-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7999393a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> First violation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the enforcement provisions referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1640">section 1640 of this title</ref>, each person who violates this section shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each day any such violation continues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7999393b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any person on whom a civil penalty has been imposed under paragraph (1), paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “$20,000” for “$10,000” with respect to all subsequent violations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7999393c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1639e/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The agency referred to in subsection (a) or (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1607">section 1607 of this title</ref> with respect to any person described in paragraph (1) shall assess any penalty under this subsection to which such person is subject.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7999393d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tI/s129E">Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 129E</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tXIV/s1472/a">Pub. L. 111–203, title XIV, § 1472(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2187">124 Stat. 2187</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tI/s102">Pub. L. 115–174, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1299">132 Stat. 1299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7999393e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7999393f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79993940-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174">Pub. L. 115–174</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and inserted heading, redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, of subpar. (A) and realigned margins, and added subpar. (B).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79993941-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id79993942-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date on which final regulations implementing such section take effect, or on the date that is 18 months after the designated transfer date if such regulations have not been issued by that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1400/c">section 1400(c) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2010 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
