<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799bab54-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650"><num value="1650">§ 1650.</num><heading> Preventing unfair and deceptive private educational lending practices and eliminating conflicts of interest</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab55-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab56-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the term “cosigner”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab57-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> means any individual who is liable for the obligation of another without compensation, regardless of how designated in the contract or instrument with respect to that obligation, other than an obligation under a private education loan extended to consolidate a consumer’s pre-existing private education loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab58-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes any person the signature of which is requested as condition to grant credit or to forbear on collection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab59-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not include a spouse of an individual described in subparagraph (A), the signature of whom is needed to perfect the security interest in a loan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab5a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the term “covered educational institution”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab5b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> means any educational institution that offers a postsecondary educational degree, certificate, or program of study (including any institution of higher education); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab5c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes an agent, officer, or employee of the educational institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab5d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the term “gift”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab5e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab5f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> means any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, or other item having more than a de minimis monetary value, including services, transportation, lodging, or meals, whether provided in kind, by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance, or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab60-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> includes an item described in clause (i) provided to a family member of an officer, employee, or agent of a covered educational institution, or to any other individual based on that individual’s relationship with the officer, employee, or agent, if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab61-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the item is provided with the knowledge and acquiescence of the officer, employee, or agent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab62-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the officer, employee, or agent has reason to believe the item was provided because of the official position of the officer, employee, or agent; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab63-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> does not include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab64-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> standard informational material related to a loan, default aversion, default prevention, or financial literacy;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab65-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> food, refreshments, training, or informational material furnished to an officer, employee, or agent of a covered educational institution, as an integral part of a training session or through participation in an advisory council that is designed to improve the service of the private educational lender to the covered educational institution, if such training or participation contributes to the professional development of the officer, employee, or agent of the covered educational institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab66-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> favorable terms, conditions, and borrower benefits on a private education loan provided to a student employed by the covered educational institution, if such terms, conditions, or benefits are not provided because of the student’s employment with the covered educational institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab67-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> the provision of financial literacy counseling or services, including counseling or services provided in coordination with a covered educational institution, to the extent that such counseling or services are not undertaken to secure—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id799bab68-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> applications for private education loans or private education loan volume;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id799bab69-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> applications or loan volume for any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id799bab6a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the purchase of a product or service of a specific private educational lender;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab6b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> philanthropic contributions to a covered educational institution from a private educational lender that are unrelated to private education loans and are not made in exchange for any advantage related to private education loans; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab6c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/3/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> State education grants, scholarships, or financial aid funds administered by or on behalf of a State;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab6d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “institution of higher education” has the same meaning as in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab6e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “postsecondary educational expenses” means any of the expenses that are included as part of the cost of attendance of a student, as defined under section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087">20 U.S.C. 1087</ref><i>ll</i>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab6f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “preferred lender arrangement” has the same meaning as in section 151 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1019">20 U.S.C. 1019</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab70-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> the term “private educational lender” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab71-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a financial institution, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">section 1813 of title 12</ref> that solicits, makes, or extends private education loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab72-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a Federal credit union, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752">section 1752 of title 12</ref> that solicits, makes, or extends private education loans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab73-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any other person engaged in the business of soliciting, making, or extending private education loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab74-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> the term “private education loan”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab75-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> means a loan provided by a private educational lender that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab76-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is not made, insured, or guaranteed under of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002359">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002359"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “of” probably should not appear.</note> title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id799bab77-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is issued expressly for postsecondary educational expenses to a borrower, regardless of whether the loan is provided through the educational institution that the subject student attends or directly to the borrower from the private educational lender; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab78-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include an extension of credit under an open end consumer credit plan, a reverse mortgage transaction, a residential mortgage transaction, or any other loan that is secured by real property or a dwelling; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab79-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> the term “revenue sharing” means an arrangement between a covered educational institution and a private educational lender under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab7a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a private educational lender provides or issues private education loans with respect to students attending the covered educational institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab7b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the covered educational institution recommends to students or others the private educational lender or the private education loans of the private educational lender; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab7c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/a/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the private educational lender pays a fee or provides other material benefits, including profit sharing, to the covered educational institution in connection with the private education loans provided to students attending the covered educational institution or a borrower acting on behalf of a student.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab7d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on certain gifts and arrangements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A private educational lender may not, directly or indirectly—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab7e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> offer or provide any gift to a covered educational institution in exchange for any advantage or consideration provided to such private educational lender related to its private education loan activities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799bab7f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> engage in revenue sharing with a covered educational institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab80-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on co-branding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A private educational lender may not use the name, emblem, mascot, or logo of the covered educational institution, or other words, pictures, or symbols readily identified with the covered educational institution, in the marketing of private education loans in any way that implies that the covered educational institution endorses the private education loans offered by the private educational lender.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab81-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory Board compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who is employed in the financial aid office of a covered educational institution, or who otherwise has responsibilities with respect to private education loans or other financial aid of the institution, and who serves on an advisory board, commission, or group established by a private educational lender or group of such lenders shall be prohibited from receiving anything of value from the private educational lender or group of lenders. Nothing in this subsection prohibits the reimbursement of reasonable expenses incurred by an employee of a covered educational institution as part of their service on an advisory board, commission, or group described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab82-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on prepayment or repayment fees or penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any private educational lender to impose a fee or penalty on a borrower for early repayment or prepayment of any private education loan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab83-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit card protections for college students</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab84-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An institution of higher education shall publicly disclose any contract or other agreement made with a card issuer or creditor for the purpose of marketing a credit card.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab85-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Inducements prohibited</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No card issuer or creditor may offer to a student at an institution of higher education any tangible item to induce such student to apply for or participate in an open end consumer credit plan offered by such card issuer or creditor, if such offer is made—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab86-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> on the campus of an institution of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab87-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> near the campus of an institution of higher education, as determined by rule of the Bureau; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab88-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> at an event sponsored by or related to an institution of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab89-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of the Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It is the sense of the Congress that each institution of higher education should consider adopting the following policies relating to credit cards:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab8a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> That any card issuer that markets a credit card on the campus of such institution notify the institution of the location at which such marketing will take place.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab8b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> That the number of locations on the campus of such institution at which the marketing of credit cards takes place be limited.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799bab8c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> That credit card and debt education and counseling sessions be offered as a regular part of any orientation program for new students of such institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab8d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional protections relating to borrower or cosigner of a private education loan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab8e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on automatic default in case of death or bankruptcy of non-student obligor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to a private education loan involving a student obligor and 1 or more cosigners, the creditor shall not declare a default or accelerate the debt against the student obligor on the sole basis of a bankruptcy or death of a cosigner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab8f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Cosigner release in case of death of borrower</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab90-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Release of cosigner</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The holder of a private education loan, when notified of the death of a student obligor, shall release within a reasonable timeframe any cosigner from the obligations of the cosigner under the private education loan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab91-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of release</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A holder or servicer of a private education loan, as applicable, shall within a reasonable time-frame notify any cosigners for the private education loan if a cosigner is released from the obligations of the cosigner for the private education loan under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id799bab92-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1650/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of individual to act on behalf of the borrower</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any lender that extends a private education loan shall provide the student obligor an option to designate an individual to have the legal authority to act on behalf of the student obligor with respect to the private education loan in the event of the death of the student obligor.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id799bab93-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tI/s140">Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 140</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/tX/s1011/a">Pub. L. 110–315, title X, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3479">122 Stat. 3479</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 111–24, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1749">123 Stat. 1749</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1100A/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100A(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2107">124 Stat. 2107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 115–174, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1365">132 Stat. 1365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id799bab94-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id799bab95-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id799bab96-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(B)(iv)(II), (8)(A)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1219">79 Stat. 1219</ref>. Title IV of the Act is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 1070 et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id799bab97-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s601/a/1">Pub. L. 115–174, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) to (8) as (2) to (9), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/174/s601/a/2">Pub. L. 115–174, § 601(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (f)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> substituted “Bureau” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/24">Pub. L. 111–24</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id799df488-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id799df489-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tVI/s601/b">Pub. L. 115–174, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1365">132 Stat. 1365</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/174/tVI/s601/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall only apply to private education loan agreements entered into on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id799df48a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id799df48b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/24">Pub. L. 111–24</ref> effective 9 months after <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 111–24</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1602">section 1602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id799df48c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c) of this section effective on the earlier of the date on which regulations issued under <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s1002">section 1002 of Pub. L. 110–315</ref> (set out as a Regulations note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1638">section 1638 of this title</ref>) become effective or 18 months after <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s1003/b">section 1003(b) of Pub. L. 110–315</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2008 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1638">section 1638 of this title</ref>. Such regulations were issued effective <date date="2009-09-14">Sept. 14, 2009</date>, with compliance optional until <date date="2010-02-14">Feb. 14, 2010</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
