<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id799df50c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666"><num value="1666">§ 1666.</num><heading> Correction of billing errors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799df50d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Written notice by obligor to creditor; time for and contents of notice; procedure upon receipt of notice by creditor</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a creditor, within sixty days after having transmitted to an obligor a statement of the obligor’s account in connection with an extension of consumer credit, receives at the address disclosed under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1637/b/10">section 1637(b)(10) of this title</ref> a written notice (other than notice on a payment stub or other payment medium supplied by the creditor if the creditor so stipulates with the disclosure required under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1637/a/7">section 1637(a)(7) of this title</ref>) from the obligor in which the obligor—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df50e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> sets forth or otherwise enables the creditor to identify the name and account number (if any) of the obligor,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df50f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> indicates the obligor’s belief that the statement contains a billing error and the amount of such billing error, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df510-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> sets forth the reasons for the obligor’s belief (to the extent applicable) that the statement contains a billing error,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the creditor shall, unless the obligor has, after giving such written notice and before the expiration of the time limits herein specified, agreed that the statement was correct—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df511-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not later than thirty days after the receipt of the notice, send a written acknowledgment thereof to the obligor, unless the action required in subparagraph (B) is taken within such thirty-day period, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df512-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> not later than two complete billing cycles of the creditor (in no event later than ninety days) after the receipt of the notice and prior to taking any action to collect the amount, or any part thereof, indicated by the obligor under paragraph (2) either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799df513-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> make appropriate corrections in the account of the obligor, including the crediting of any finance charges on amounts erroneously billed, and transmit to the obligor a notification of such corrections and the creditor’s explanation of any change in the amount indicated by the obligor under paragraph (2) and, if any such change is made and the obligor so requests, copies of documentary evidence of the obligor’s indebtedness; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id799df514-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/a/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> send a written explanation or clarification to the obligor, after having conducted an investigation, setting forth to the extent applicable the reasons why the creditor believes the account of the obligor was correctly shown in the statement and, upon request of the obligor, provide copies of documentary evidence of the obligor’s indebtedness. In the case of a billing error where the obligor alleges that the creditor’s billing statement reflects goods not delivered to the obligor or his designee in accordance with the agreement made at the time of the transaction, a creditor may not construe such amount to be correctly shown unless he determines that such goods were actually delivered, mailed, or otherwise sent to the obligor and provides the obligor with a statement of such determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">After complying with the provisions of this subsection with respect to an alleged billing error, a creditor has no further responsibility under this section if the obligor continues to make substantially the same allegation with respect to such error.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799df515-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Billing error</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section, a “billing error” consists of any of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df516-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A reflection on a statement of an extension of credit which was not made to the obligor or, if made, was not in the amount reflected on such statement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df517-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A reflection on a statement of an extension of credit for which the obligor requests additional clarification including documentary evidence thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df518-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A reflection on a statement of goods or services not accepted by the obligor or his designee or not delivered to the obligor or his designee in accordance with the agreement made at the time of a transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df519-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The creditor’s failure to reflect properly on a statement a payment made by the obligor or a credit issued to the obligor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df51a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A computation error or similar error of an accounting nature of the creditor on a statement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df51b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Failure to transmit the statement required under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1637/b">section 1637(b) of this title</ref> to the last address of the obligor which has been disclosed to the creditor, unless that address was furnished less than twenty days before the end of the billing cycle for which the statement is required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df51c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any other error described in regulations of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799df51d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Action by creditor to collect amount or any part thereof regarded by obligor to be a billing error</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, “action to collect the amount, or any part thereof, indicated by an obligor under paragraph (2)” does not include the sending of statements of account, which may include finance charges on amounts in dispute, to the obligor following written notice from the obligor as specified under subsection (a), if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df51e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the obligor’s account is not restricted or closed because of the failure of the obligor to pay the amount indicated under paragraph (2) of subsection (a), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id799df51f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the creditor indicates the payment of such amount is not required pending the creditor’s compliance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any action by a creditor to collect any amount which has not been indicated by the obligor to contain a billing error.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799df520-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Restricting or closing by creditor of account regarded by obligor to contain a billing error</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to regulations of the Bureau, a creditor operating an open end consumer credit plan may not, prior to the sending of the written explanation or clarification required under paragraph (B)(ii), restrict or close an account with respect to which the obligor has indicated pursuant to subsection (a) that he believes such account to contain a billing error solely because of the obligor’s failure to pay the amount indicated to be in error. Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to prohibit a creditor from applying against the credit limit on the obligor’s account the amount indicated to be in error.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id799df521-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1666/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of noncompliance with requirements by creditor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any creditor who fails to comply with the requirements of this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1666a">section 1666a of this title</ref> forfeits any right to collect from the obligor the amount indicated by the obligor under paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section, and any finance charges thereon, except that the amount required to be forfeited under this subsection may not exceed $50.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id799df522-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tI/s161">Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 161</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 93–495, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1512">88 Stat. 1512</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/tVI">Pub. L. 96–221, title VI</ref> §§ 613(g), 620, <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/177">94 Stat. 177</ref>, 184; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX">Pub. L. 111–203, title X</ref>, §§ 1087, 1100A(2), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2086">124 Stat. 2086</ref>, 2107.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id799df523-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id799df524-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id799df525-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pub L. 111–203, § 1100A(2), which directed the substitution of “Bureau” for “Board” wherever appearing in title I of <ref href="/us/pl/90/321">Pub. L. 90–321</ref>, was executed to this section, which is <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tI/s161">section 161 of title I of Pub. L. 90–321</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1087">Section 1087 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, which directed the making of an identical amendment in title III of <ref href="/us/pl/93/495">Pub. L. 93–495</ref>, which added this section to title I of <ref href="/us/pl/90/321">Pub. L. 90–321</ref>, has not been executed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id799df526-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsecs. (b)(7), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100A/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100A(2)</ref>, substituted “Bureau” for “Board”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s613/g">Pub. L. 96–221, § 613(g)</ref>, substituted “(b)(10)” for “(b)(11)” and “(a)(7)” for “(a)(8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s620/a">Pub. L. 96–221, § 620(a)</ref>, added par. (6) and redesignated former par. (6) as (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s620/b">Pub. L. 96–221, § 620(b)</ref>, inserted provisions respecting finance charges on amounts in dispute.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id799df527-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id799df528-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id799df529-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/221">Pub. L. 96–221</ref> effective on expiration of two years and six months after <date date="1980-03-31">Mar. 31, 1980</date>, with all regulations, forms, and clauses required to be prescribed to be promulgated at least one year prior to such effective date, and allowing any creditor to comply with any amendments, in accordance with the regulations, forms, and clauses prescribed by the Board prior to such effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/221/s625">section 625 of Pub. L. 96–221</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1602">section 1602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id799df52a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/495/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 93–495, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1517">88 Stat. 1517</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/495/tIII/s308">“This title [enacting this section and sections 1666a to 1666j of this title, amending sections 1601, 1602, 1610, 1631, 1632, and 1637 of this title, and enacting provision set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref>] takes effect upon the expiration of one year after the date of its enactment [<date date="1974-10-28">Oct. 28, 1974</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id799df52b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title III of <ref href="/us/pl/93/495">Pub. L. 93–495</ref>, which is classified principally to this part, is known as the “Fair Credit Billing Act”. For complete classification of Title III to the Code, see Short Title of 1974 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
