<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79b3781d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u"><num value="1681u">§ 1681u.</num><heading> Disclosures to FBI for counterintelligence purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3781e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Identity of financial institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681b">section 1681b of this title</ref> or any other provision of this subchapter, a consumer reporting agency shall furnish to the Federal Bureau of Investigation the names and addresses of all financial institutions (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3401">section 3401 of title 12</ref>) at which a consumer maintains or has maintained an account, to the extent that information is in the files of the agency, when presented with a written request for that information that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of that information, signed by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the Director’s designee in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office designated by the Director, which certifies compliance with this section. The Director or the Director’s designee may make such a certification only if the Director or the Director’s designee has determined in writing, that such information is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3781f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Identifying information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681b">section 1681b of this title</ref> or any other provision of this subchapter, a consumer reporting agency shall furnish identifying information respecting a consumer, limited to name, address, former addresses, places of employment, or former places of employment, to the Federal Bureau of Investigation when presented with a written request that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of that information, signed by the Director or the Director’s designee in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office designated by the Director, which certifies compliance with this subsection. The Director or the Director’s designee may make such a certification only if the Director or the Director’s designee has determined in writing that such information is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37820-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Court order for disclosure of consumer reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681b">section 1681b of this title</ref> or any other provision of this subchapter, if requested in writing by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or a designee of the Director in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge in a Bureau field office designated by the Director, a court may issue an order ex parte, which shall include a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of the information, directing a consumer reporting agency to furnish a consumer report to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, upon a showing in camera that the consumer report is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States. The terms of an order issued under this subsection shall not disclose that the order is issued for purposes of a counterintelligence investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37821-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition of certain disclosure</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37822-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37823-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a certification is issued under subparagraph (B) and notice of the right to judicial review under subsection (e) is provided, no consumer reporting agency that receives a request under subsection (a) or (b) or an order under subsection (c), or officer, employee, or agent thereof, shall disclose or specify in any consumer report, that the Federal Bureau of Investigation has sought or obtained access to information or records under subsection (a), (b), or (c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37824-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements of subparagraph (A) shall apply if the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or a designee of the Director whose rank shall be no lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office, certifies that the absence of a prohibition of disclosure under this subsection may result in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b37825-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a danger to the national security of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b37826-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> interference with a criminal, counterterrorism, or counterintelligence investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b37827-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> interference with diplomatic relations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b37828-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> danger to the life or physical safety of any person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37829-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3782a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A consumer reporting agency that receives a request under subsection (a) or (b) or an order under subsection (c), or officer, employee, or agent thereof, may disclose information otherwise subject to any applicable nondisclosure requirement to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b3782b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> those persons to whom disclosure is necessary in order to comply with the request;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b3782c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an attorney in order to obtain legal advice or assistance regarding the request; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79b3782d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> other persons as permitted by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the designee of the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3782e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person to whom disclosure is made under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the nondisclosure requirements applicable to a person to whom a request under subsection (a) or (b) or an order under subsection (c) is issued in the same manner as the person to whom the request is issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3782f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any recipient that discloses to a person described in subparagraph (A) information otherwise subject to a nondisclosure requirement shall inform the person of the applicable nondisclosure requirement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37830-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/d/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of disclosure recipients</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">At the request of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the designee of the Director, any person making or intending to make a disclosure under clause (i) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall identify to the Director or such designee the person to whom such disclosure will be made or to whom such disclosure was made prior to the request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37831-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37832-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A request under subsection (a) or (b) or an order under subsection (c) or a non-disclosure requirement imposed in connection with such request under subsection (d) shall be subject to judicial review under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3511">section 3511 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37833-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A request under subsection (a) or (b) or an order under subsection (c) shall include notice of the availability of judicial review described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37834-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, pay to the consumer reporting agency assembling or providing report or information in accordance with procedures established under this section a fee for reimbursement for such costs as are reasonably necessary and which have been directly incurred in searching, reproducing, or transporting books, papers, records, or other data required or requested to be produced under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37835-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limit on dissemination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Bureau of Investigation may not disseminate information obtained pursuant to this section outside of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, except to other Federal agencies as may be necessary for the approval or conduct of a foreign counterintelligence investigation, or, where the information concerns a person subject to the Uniform Code of Military Justice, to appropriate investigative authorities within the military department concerned as may be necessary for the conduct of a joint foreign counterintelligence investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37836-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit information from being furnished by the Federal Bureau of Investigation pursuant to a subpoena or court order, in connection with a judicial or administrative proceeding to enforce the provisions of this subchapter. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize or permit the withholding of information from the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37837-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b37838-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> On a semiannual basis, the Attorney General shall fully inform the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate concerning all requests made pursuant to subsections (a), (b), and (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79b37839-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of the semiannual reports required to be submitted under paragraph (1) to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the submittal dates for such reports shall be as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3106">section 3106 of title 50</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3783a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Damages</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any agency or department of the United States obtaining or disclosing any consumer reports, records, or information contained therein in violation of this section is liable to the consumer to whom such consumer reports, records, or information relate in an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b3783b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> $100, without regard to the volume of consumer reports, records, or information involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b3783c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any actual damages sustained by the consumer as a result of the disclosure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b3783d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if the violation is found to have been willful or intentional, such punitive damages as a court may allow; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79b3783e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the case of any successful action to enforce liability under this subsection, the costs of the action, together with reasonable attorney fees, as determined by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b3783f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Disciplinary actions for violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a court determines that any agency or department of the United States has violated any provision of this section and the court finds that the circumstances surrounding the violation raise questions of whether or not an officer or employee of the agency or department acted willfully or intentionally with respect to the violation, the agency or department shall promptly initiate a proceeding to determine whether or not disciplinary action is warranted against the officer or employee who was responsible for the violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37840-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Good-faith exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, any consumer reporting agency or agent or employee thereof making disclosure of consumer reports or identifying information pursuant to this subsection in good-faith reliance upon a certification of the Federal Bureau of Investigation pursuant to provisions of this section shall not be liable to any person for such disclosure under this subchapter, the constitution of any State, or any law or regulation of any State or any political subdivision of any State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37841-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation of remedies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the remedies and sanctions set forth in this section shall be the only judicial remedies and sanctions for violation of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79b37842-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1681u/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Injunctive relief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other remedy contained in this section, injunctive relief shall be available to require compliance with the procedures of this section. In the event of any successful action under this subsection, costs together with reasonable attorney fees, as determined by the court, may be recovered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79b37843-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tVI/s626">Pub. L. 90–321, title VI, § 626</ref>, formerly § 624, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/93/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 104–93, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/974">109 Stat. 974</ref>; renumbered § 625 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s358/g/1/A">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 358(g)(1)(A)</ref>, title V, § 505(c), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/327">115 Stat. 327</ref>, 366; <ref href="/us/pl/107/306/tVIII/s811/b/8/B">Pub. L. 107–306, title VIII, § 811(b)(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2426">116 Stat. 2426</ref>; renumbered § 626, <ref href="/us/pl/108/159/tII/s214/a/1">Pub. L. 108–159, title II, § 214(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-04">Dec. 4, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1980">117 Stat. 1980</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tI/s116/b">Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 116(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/214">120 Stat. 214</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/178/s4/c/1">Pub. L. 109–178, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/280">120 Stat. 280</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/tV">Pub. L. 114–23, title V</ref>, §§ 501(c), 502(c), 503(c), <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/282">129 Stat. 282</ref>, 285, 290.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79b37844-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79b37845-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79b37846-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (h), was in the original, “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/90/321">Pub. L. 90–321</ref>, known as the Fair Credit Reporting Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id79b37847-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s626">section 626 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref> was renumbered section 627 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681v">section 1681v of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79b37848-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s501/c/1">Pub. L. 114–23, § 501(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “that information that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of that information,” for “that information,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s501/c/2">Pub. L. 114–23, § 501(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “written request that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of that information,” for “written request,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s501/c/3">Pub. L. 114–23, § 501(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “, which shall include a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of the information,” after “issue an order ex parte”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s502/c">Pub. L. 114–23, § 502(c)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which related to confidentiality.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (n). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s503/c">Pub. L. 114–23, § 503(c)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and redesignated former subsecs. (e) to (m) as (f) to (n), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177">Pub. L. 109–177</ref> reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “No consumer reporting agency or officer, employee, or agent of a consumer reporting agency shall disclose to any person, other than those officers, employees, or agents of a consumer reporting agency necessary to fulfill the requirement to disclose information to the Federal Bureau of Investigation under this section, that the Federal Bureau of Investigation has sought or obtained the identity of financial institutions or a consumer report respecting any consumer under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section, and no consumer reporting agency or officer, employee, or agent of a consumer reporting agency shall include in any consumer report any information that would indicate that the Federal Bureau of Investigation has sought or obtained such information or a consumer report.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/178">Pub. L. 109–178</ref> amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “At the request of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the designee of the Director, any person making or intending to make a disclosure under this section shall identify to the Director or such designee the person to whom such disclosure will be made or to whom such disclosure was made prior to the request, but in no circumstance shall a person be required to inform the Director or such designee that the person intends to consult an attorney to obtain legal advice or legal assistance.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/107/306">Pub. L. 107–306</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—<ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s505/c">Pub. L. 107–56, § 505(c)</ref>, which directed amendment of section 624 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act, was executed by making the amendment to this section to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the renumbering of section 624 as 625 by <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s358/g/1/A">section 358(g)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 107–56</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s505/c/1">Pub. L. 107–56, § 505(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office designated by the Director” after “Investigation, or the Director’s designee” and substituted “in writing, that such information is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.” for pars. (1) and (2) requiring determination in writing that the information requested is necessary for the conduct of an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation and that there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the consumer is a foreign power or a person who is not a United States person and is an official of a foreign power, or that the consumer is an agent of a foreign power and is engaging or has engaged in an act of international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities that involve or may involve a violation of criminal statutes of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s505/c/2">Pub. L. 107–56, § 505(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge of a Bureau field office designated by the Director” after “signed by the Director or the Director’s designee” and substituted “in writing that such information is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.” for pars. (1) and (2) requiring determination in writing that the information requested is necessary to the conduct of an authorized counterintelligence investigation and that there is information giving reason to believe that the consumer has been, or is about to be, in contact with a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s505/c/3">Pub. L. 107–56, § 505(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “in a position not lower than Deputy Assistant Director at Bureau headquarters or a Special Agent in Charge in a Bureau field office designated by the Director” after “designee of the Director” and substituted “in camera that the consumer report is sought for the conduct of an authorized investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such an investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States.” for pars. (1) and (2) requiring a showing in camera that the consumer report is necessary for the conduct of an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation and there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the consumer whose consumer report is sought is an agent of a foreign power and is engaging or has engaged in an act of international terrorism or in clandestine intelligence activities that involve or may involve a violation of criminal statutes of the United States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79b37849-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id79b3784a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79b3784b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s358/g/1/A">section 358(g)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 107–56</ref> applicable with respect to reports filed or records maintained on, before, or after <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s358/h">section 358(h) of Pub. L. 107–56</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1829b">section 1829b of this Title</ref> 12, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
