<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79baa446-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p"><num value="1692p">§ 1692p.</num><heading> Exception for certain bad check enforcement programs operated by private entities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa447-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa448-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain private entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), a private entity shall be excluded from the definition of a debt collector, pursuant to the exception provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1692a/6">section 1692a(6) of this title</ref>, with respect to the operation by the entity of a program described in paragraph (2)(A) under a contract described in paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa449-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of applicability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79baa44a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a State or district attorney establishes, within the jurisdiction of such State or district attorney and with respect to alleged bad check violations that do not involve a check described in subsection (b), a pretrial diversion program for alleged bad check offenders who agree to participate voluntarily in such program to avoid criminal prosecution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79baa44b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a private entity, that is subject to an administrative support services contract with a State or district attorney and operates under the direction, supervision, and control of such State or district attorney, operates the pretrial diversion program described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79baa44c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> in the course of performing duties delegated to it by a State or district attorney under the contract, the private entity referred to in subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa44d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> complies with the penal laws of the State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa44e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> conforms with the terms of the contract and directives of the State or district attorney;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa44f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> does not exercise independent prosecutorial discretion;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa450-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> contacts any alleged offender referred to in subparagraph (A) for purposes of participating in a program referred to in such paragraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79baa451-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> only as a result of any determination by the State or district attorney that probable cause of a bad check violation under State penal law exists, and that contact with the alleged offender for purposes of participation in the program is appropriate; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79baa452-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the alleged offender has failed to pay the bad check after demand for payment, pursuant to State law, is made for payment of the check amount;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa453-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><chapeau> includes as part of an initial written communication with an alleged offender a clear and conspicuous statement that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79baa454-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/v/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the alleged offender may dispute the validity of any alleged bad check violation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79baa455-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/v/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> where the alleged offender knows, or has reasonable cause to believe, that the alleged bad check violation is the result of theft or forgery of the check, identity theft, or other fraud that is not the result of the conduct of the alleged offender, the alleged offender may file a crime report with the appropriate law enforcement agency; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id79baa456-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/v/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> if the alleged offender notifies the private entity or the district attorney in writing, not later than 30 days after being contacted for the first time pursuant to clause (iv), that there is a dispute pursuant to this subsection, before further restitution efforts are pursued, the district attorney or an employee of the district attorney authorized to make such a determination makes a determination that there is probable cause to believe that a crime has been committed; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79baa457-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/a/2/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> charges only fees in connection with services under the contract that have been authorized by the contract with the State or district attorney.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa458-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain checks excluded</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A check is described in this subsection if the check involves, or is subsequently found to involve—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa459-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a postdated check presented in connection with a payday loan, or other similar transaction, where the payee of the check knew that the issuer had insufficient funds at the time the check was made, drawn, or delivered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa45a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a stop payment order where the issuer acted in good faith and with reasonable cause in stopping payment on the check;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa45b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a check dishonored because of an adjustment to the issuer’s account by the financial institution holding such account without providing notice to the person at the time the check was made, drawn, or delivered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa45c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a check for partial payment of a debt where the payee had previously accepted partial payment for such debt;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa45d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a check issued by a person who was not competent, or was not of legal age, to enter into a legal contractual obligation at the time the check was made, drawn, or delivered; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79baa45e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a check issued to pay an obligation arising from a transaction that was illegal in the jurisdiction of the State or district attorney at the time the check was made, drawn, or delivered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa45f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa460-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> State or district attorney</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State or district attorney” means the chief elected or appointed prosecuting attorney in a district, county (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s2">section 2 of title 1</ref>), municipality, or comparable jurisdiction, including State attorneys general who act as chief elected or appointed prosecuting attorneys in a district, county (as so defined), municipality or comparable jurisdiction, who may be referred to by a variety of titles such as district attorneys, prosecuting attorneys, commonwealth’s attorneys, solicitors, county attorneys, and state’s attorneys, and who are responsible for the prosecution of State crimes and violations of jurisdiction-specific local ordinances.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa461-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Check</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “check” has the same meaning as in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5002/6">section 5002(6) of title 12</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79baa462-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1692p/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Bad check violation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “bad check violation” means a violation of the applicable State criminal law relating to the writing of dishonored checks.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79baa463-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tVIII/s818">Pub. L. 90–321, title VIII, § 818</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tVIII/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 109–351, title VIII, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2004">120 Stat. 2004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
