<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79bd15af-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o"><num value="1693o">§ 1693o.</num><heading> Administrative enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd15b0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcing agencies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5511">12 U.S.C. 5511</ref> et seq.], compliance with the requirements imposed under this subchapter shall be enforced under—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd15b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</ref>], by the appropriate Federal banking agency, as defined in section 3(q) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/q">12 U.S.C. 1813(q)</ref>), with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79bd15b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> national banks, Federal savings associations, and Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79bd15b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, and organizations operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s601">12 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq., 611 et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79bd15b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> banks and State savings associations insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System), and insured State branches of foreign banks;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd15b5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1751">12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.], by the Administrator of the National Credit Union Administration with respect to any Federal credit union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd15b6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> part A of subtitle VII of title 49, by the Secretary of Transportation, with respect to any air carrier or foreign air carrier subject to that part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd15b7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.], by the Securities and Exchange Commission, with respect to any broker or dealer subject to that Act and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002412">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002412"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “; and”.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd15b8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> subtitle E of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5561">12 U.S.C. 5561</ref> et seq.], by the Bureau, with respect to any person subject to this subchapter, except that the Bureau shall not have authority to enforce the requirements of section 1693<i>o</i>–2 of this title or any regulations prescribed by the Board under section 1693<i>o</i>–2 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The terms used in paragraph (1) that are not defined in this subchapter or otherwise defined in section 3(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/s">12 U.S.C. 1813(s)</ref>) shall have the meaning given to them in section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3101">12 U.S.C. 3101</ref>).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd15b9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations of subchapter deemed violations of pre-existing statutory requirements; additional powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of the exercise by any agency referred to in any of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) of its powers under any Act referred to in that subsection, a violation of any requirement imposed under this subchapter shall be deemed to be a violation of a requirement imposed under that Act. In addition to its powers under any provision of law specifically referred to in any of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a), each of the agencies referred to in that subsection may exercise, for the purpose of enforcing compliance with any requirement imposed under this subchapter, any other authority conferred on it by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd15ba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693o/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Overall enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except to the extent that enforcement of the requirements imposed under this subchapter is specifically committed to some other Government agency under any of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a), and subject to subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, the Federal Trade Commission shall be authorized to enforce such requirements. For the purpose of the exercise by the Federal Trade Commission of its functions and powers under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.], a violation of any requirement imposed under this subchapter shall be deemed a violation of a requirement imposed under that Act. All of the functions and powers of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act are available to the Federal Trade Commission to enforce compliance by any person subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission with the requirements imposed under this subchapter, irrespective of whether that person is engaged in commerce or meets any other jurisdictional tests under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79bd15bb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tIX/s918">Pub. L. 90–321, title IX, § 918</ref>, formerly § 917, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXX/s2001">Pub. L. 95–630, title XX, § 2001</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3739">92 Stat. 3739</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/73/tVII/s744">Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 744</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1989-08-09">Aug. 9, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/440">103 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/tII/s212/f">Pub. L. 102–242, title II, § 212(f)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2301">105 Stat. 2301</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s6/h">Pub. L. 104–287, § 6(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3399">110 Stat. 3399</ref>; renumbered § 918, <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/tIV/s401/1">Pub. L. 111–24, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1751">123 Stat. 1751</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1084/5">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1084(5)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2082">124 Stat. 2082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79bd15bc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79bd15bd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79bd15be-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is title X of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1955">124 Stat. 1955</ref>. Subtitles B (§§ 1021–1029A) and E (§§ 1051–1058) of the Act are classified generally to parts B (§ 5511 et seq.) and E (§ 5561 et seq.), respectively, of subchapter V of chapter 53 of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of subtitles B and E to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 25 and 25A of the Federal Reserve Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B), are classified to subchapters I (§ 601 et seq.) and II (§ 611 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 6 of Title 12, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Credit Union Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">act June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1216">48 Stat. 1216</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 14 (§ 1751 et seq.) of Title 12. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1751">section 1751 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79bd15bf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(3), “part A of subtitle VII of title 49” substituted for “the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 [49 App. U.S.C. 1301 et seq.]” and “that part” substituted for “that Act” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s6/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1378">108 Stat. 1378</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitles II, III, and V to X of Title 49, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id79bd15c0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s918">section 918 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref> was renumbered section 921 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693p">section 1693p of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79bd15c1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/5/A/i">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(5)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Subject to subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010, compliance” for “Compliance” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/5/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(5)(A)(ii)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, in the case of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) national banks, and Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks, by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, and organizations operating under section 25 or 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act, by the Board; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System) and insured State branches of foreign banks, by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/5/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(5)(A)(ii)</ref>–(vii), added par. (5), redesignated former pars. (3) to (5) as (2) to (4), respectively, and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, in the case of a savings association the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/5/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(5)(B)</ref>, inserted “any of paragraphs (1) through (4) of” before “subsection (a)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/5/C">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(5)(C)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Except to the extent that enforcement of the requirements imposed under this subchapter is specifically committed to some other Government agency under subsection (a) of this section, the Federal Trade Commission shall enforce such requirements. For the purpose of the exercise by the Federal Trade Commission of its functions and powers under the Federal Trade Commission Act, a violation of any requirement imposed under this subchapter shall be deemed a violation of a requirement imposed under that Act. All of the functions and powers of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act are available to the Commission to enforce compliance by any person subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission with the requirements imposed under this subchapter, irrespective of whether that person is engaged in commerce or meets any other jurisdictional tests in the Federal Trade Commission Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/287">Pub. L. 104–287</ref> substituted “Secretary of Transportation” for “Civil Aeronautics Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s212/f/2">Pub. L. 102–242, § 212(f)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “The terms used in paragraph (1) that are not defined in this subchapter or otherwise defined in section 3(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813/s">12 U.S.C. 1813(s)</ref>) shall have the meaning given to them in section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3101">12 U.S.C. 3101</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/242/s212/f/1">Pub. L. 102–242, § 212(f)(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, in the case of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) national banks, by the Comptroller of the Currency;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), by the Board;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System), by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “section 5(d) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, section 407 of the National Housing Act, and sections 6(i) and 17 of the Federal Home Loan Bank Act, by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board (acting directly or through the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation), in the case of any institution subject to any of those provisions;”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79bd15c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79bd15c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79bd15c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested in Administrator of National Credit Union Administration transferred and vested in National Credit Union Administration Board pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1752a">section 1752a of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
