<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79bd1586-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m"><num value="1693m">§ 1693m.</num><heading> Civil liability</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1587-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Individual or class action for damages; amount of award</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693h">section 1693h of this title</ref>, any person who fails to comply with any provision of this subchapter with respect to any consumer, except for an error resolved in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693f">section 1693f of this title</ref>, is liable to such consumer in an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd1588-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any actual damage sustained by such consumer as a result of such failure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd1589-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd158a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of an individual action, an amount not less than $100 nor greater than $1,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd158b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a class action, such amount as the court may allow, except that (i) as to each member of the class no minimum recovery shall be applicable, and (ii) the total recovery under this subparagraph in any class action or series of class actions arising out of the same failure to comply by the same person shall not be more than the lesser of $500,000 or 1 per centum of the net worth of the defendant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd158c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of any successful action to enforce the foregoing liability, the costs of the action, together with a reasonable attorney’s fee as determined by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd158d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors determining amount of award</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the amount of liability in any action under subsection (a), the court shall consider, among other relevant factors—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd158e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in any individual action under subsection (a)(2)(A), the frequency and persistence of noncompliance, the nature of such noncompliance, and the extent to which the noncompliance was intentional; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd158f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in any class action under subsection (a)(2)(B), the frequency and persistence of noncompliance, the nature of such noncompliance, the resources of the defendant, the number of persons adversely affected, and the extent to which the noncompliance was intentional.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1590-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Unintentional violations; bona fide error</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693h">section 1693h of this title</ref>, a person may not be held liable in any action brought under this section for a violation of this subchapter if the person shows by a preponderance of evidence that the violation was not intentional and resulted from a bona fide error notwithstanding the maintenance of procedures reasonably adapted to avoid any such error.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1591-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Good faith compliance with rule, regulation, or interpretation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision of this section or section 1693n <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002411">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002411"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title imposing any liability shall apply to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd1592-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any rule, regulation, or interpretation thereof by the Bureau or the Board or in conformity with any interpretation or approval by an official or employee of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection or the Federal Reserve System duly authorized by the Bureau or the Board to issue such interpretations or approvals under such procedures as the Bureau or the Board may prescribe therefor; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79bd1593-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any failure to make disclosure in proper form if a financial institution utilized an appropriate model clause issued by the Bureau or the Board,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">notwithstanding that after such act, omission, or failure has occurred, such rule, regulation, approval, or model clause is amended, rescinded, or determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1594-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification to consumer prior to action; adjustment of consumer’s account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person has no liability under this section for any failure to comply with any requirement under this subchapter if, prior to the institution of an action under this section, the person notifies the consumer concerned of the failure, complies with the requirements of this subchapter, and makes an appropriate adjustment to the consumer’s account and pays actual damages or, where applicable, damages in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693h">section 1693h of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1595-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Action in bad faith or for harassment; attorney’s fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On a finding by the court that an unsuccessful action under this section was brought in bad faith or for purposes of harassment, the court shall award to the defendant attorney’s fees reasonable in relation to the work expended and costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79bd1596-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1693m/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of courts; time for maintenance of action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Without regard to the amount in controversy, any action under this section may be brought in any United States district court, or in any other court of competent jurisdiction, within one year from the date of the occurrence of the violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79bd1597-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/321/tIX/s916">Pub. L. 90–321, title IX, § 916</ref>, formerly § 915, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tXX/s2001">Pub. L. 95–630, title XX, § 2001</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3737">92 Stat. 3737</ref>; renumbered § 916, <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/tIV/s401/1">Pub. L. 111–24, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1751">123 Stat. 1751</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1084/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1084(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2081">124 Stat. 2081</ref>, 2082.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79bd1598-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79bd1599-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79bd159a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693n">Section 1693n of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original a reference to <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s916">section 916 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref>, and was translated as meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s917">section 917 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref> to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the renumbering of <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s916">section 916 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref> as section 917 by <ref href="/us/pl/111/24/tIV/s401/1">Pub. L. 111–24, title IV, § 401(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1751">123 Stat. 1751</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id79bd159b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/321/s916">section 916 of Pub. L. 90–321</ref> was renumbered section 917 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1693n">section 1693n of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79bd159c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(1)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “Bureau” for “Board” wherever appearing in section, was not executed in subsec. (d), which was the only place such term appeared, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/4">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(4)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1084/4">Pub. L. 111–203, § 1084(4)</ref>, struck out “of Board or approval of duly authorized official or employee of Federal Reserve System” after “interpretation” in heading that had been supplied editorially and inserted “Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection or the” before “Federal Reserve System” in par. (1) and “Bureau or the” before “Board” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79bd159d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79bd159e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
