<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c44086-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1714"><num value="1714">§ 1714.</num><heading> Investigations, injunctions, and prosecution of offenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c44087-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1714/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent or temporary injunction or restraining order; jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever it shall appear to the Director that any person is engaged or about to engage in any acts or practices which constitute or will constitute a violation of the provisions of this chapter, or of any rule or regulation prescribed pursuant thereto, he may, in his discretion, bring an action in any district court of the United States, or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia to enjoin such acts or practices, and, upon a proper showing, a permanent or temporary injunction or restraining order shall be granted without bond. The Director may transmit such evidence as may be available concerning such acts or practices to the Attorney General who may, in his discretion, institute the appropriate criminal proceedings under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c44088-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1714/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigations; publication of information concerning violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may, in his discretion, make such investigations as he deems necessary to determine whether any person has violated or is about to violate any provision of this chapter or any rule or regulation prescribed pursuant thereto, and may require or permit any person to file with him a statement in writing, under oath or otherwise as the Director shall determine, as to all the facts and circumstances concerning the matter to be investigated. The Director is authorized, in his discretion, to publish information concerning any such violations, and to investigate any facts, conditions, practices, or matters which he may deem necessary or proper to aid in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, in the prescribing of rules and regulations thereunder, or in securing information to serve as a basis for recommending further legislation concerning the matters to which this chapter relates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c44089-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1714/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Oaths and affirmations; subpena power</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of any such investigation, or any other proceeding under this chapter; the Director, or any officer designated by him, is empowered to administer oaths and affirmations, subpena witnesses, compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memorandums, or other records which the Director deems relevant or material to the inquiry. Such attendance of witnesses and the production of any such records may be required from any place in the United States or any State at any designated place of hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c4408a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1714/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Contempt; court order requiring attendance and testimony of witnesses; jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena issued to, any person, the Director may invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which such investigation or proceeding is carried on, or where such person resides or carries on business, in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memorandums, and other records and documents. And such court may issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Director or any officer designated by the Director, there to produce records, if so ordered, or to give testimony touching the matter under investigation or in question; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof. All process in any such case may be served in the judicial district whereof such person is an inhabitant or wherever he may be found.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79c4408b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tXIV/s1415">Pub. L. 90–448, title XIV, § 1415</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/596">82 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tII/s220">Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/929">84 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tX/s1098A/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1098A(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2105">124 Stat. 2105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79c4408c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79c4408d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79c4408e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> substituted “Director” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref> struck out subsec. (e) which related to the immunity from prosecution of any individual compelled to testify or produce evidence, documentary or otherwise, after claiming his privilege against self-incrimination.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79c4408f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79c44090-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the designated transfer date, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s1100H">section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79c44091-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref>, and for amendment not to affect any immunity to which any individual is entitled under this section by reason of any testimony given before sixtieth day following <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/s260">section 260 of Pub. L. 91–452</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Savings Provision note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s6001">section 6001 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id79c44092-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of two hundred and seventy days after <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/s1423">section 1423 of Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
