<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c440f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1803"><num value="1803">§ 1803.</num><heading> Antitrust exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c440f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1803/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint operating arrangements entered into prior to <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall not be unlawful under any antitrust law for any person to perform, enforce, renew, or amend any joint newspaper operating arrangement entered into prior to <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, if at the time at which such arrangement was first entered into, regardless of ownership or affiliations, not more than one of the newspaper publications involved in the performance of such arrangement was likely to remain or become a financially sound publication: <i>Provided</i>, That the terms of a renewal or amendment to a joint operating arrangement must be filed with the Department of Justice and that the amendment does not add a newspaper publication or newspaper publications to such arrangement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c440f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1803/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Written consent for future joint operating arrangements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to enter into, perform, or enforce a joint operating arrangement, not already in effect, except with the prior written consent of the Attorney General of the United States. Prior to granting such approval, the Attorney General shall determine that not more than one of the newspaper publications involved in the arrangement is a publication other than a failing newspaper, and that approval of such arrangement would effectuate the policy and purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c440f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1803/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Predatory practices not exempt</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in the chapter shall be construed to exempt from any antitrust law any predatory pricing, any predatory practice, or any other conduct in the otherwise lawful operations of a joint newspaper operating arrangement which would be unlawful under any antitrust law if engaged in by a single entity. Except as provided in this chapter, no joint newspaper operating arrangement or any party thereto shall be exempt from any antitrust law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79c440f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/353/s4">Pub. L. 91–353, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-07-24">July 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/467">84 Stat. 467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
