<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c68b66-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s1841"><num value="1841">§ 1841.</num><heading> Emergency Loan Guarantee Board; establishment; membership; voting</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is created an Emergency Loan Guarantee Board (referred to in this chapter as the “Board”) composed of the Secretary of the Treasury, as Chairman, the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission. Decisions of the Board shall be made by majority vote.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id79c68b67-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/70/s2">Pub. L. 92–70, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-08-09">Aug. 9, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/178">85 Stat. 178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79c68b68-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79c68b69-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id79c68b6a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/70/s1">Pub. L. 92–70, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-08-09">Aug. 9, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/178">85 Stat. 178</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/70/s1">“This Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Emergency Loan Guarantee Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79c68b6b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Steel Loan Guarantees and Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/51">Pub. L. 106–51</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/252">113 Stat. 252</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tVII/s734">Pub. L. 106–102, title VII, § 734</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1478">113 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/63/tIII/s336/a">Pub. L. 107–63, title III, § 336(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-05">Nov. 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/472">115 Stat. 472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dB/tII/s211/a">Pub. L. 108–199, div. B, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/75">118 Stat. 75</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/108/tII/s205">Pub. L. 109–108, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2315">119 Stat. 2315</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dB/tI/s105">Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1892">121 Stat. 1892</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/117/dB/tI/s108">Pub. L. 111–117, div. B, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3122">123 Stat. 3122</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/117/dB/tI/s108">
<chapter style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="1">“CHAPTER 1</num><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="101">“Sec. 101.</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Program</inline>.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short Title</inline>.—</heading><content>This chapter may be cited as the ‘Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Act of 1999’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the United States steel industry has been severely harmed by a record surge of more than 40,000,000 tons of steel imports into the United States since 1998, caused by the world financial crisis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> this surge in imports resulted in the loss of more than 10,000 steel worker jobs since 1998, and was the imminent cause of three bankruptcies by medium-sized steel companies, Acme Steel, Laclede Steel, and Geneva Steel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> the crisis also forced almost all United States steel companies into—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> reduced volume, lower prices, and financial losses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an inability to obtain credit for continued operations and reinvestment in facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the crisis also has affected the willingness of private banks and investment institutions to make loans to the United States steel industry for continued operation and reinvestment in facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> these steel bankruptcies, job losses, and financial losses are also having serious negative effects on the tax base of cities, counties, and States, and on the essential health, education, and municipal services that these government entities provide to their citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> a strong steel industry is necessary to the adequate defense preparedness of the United States in order to have sufficient steel available to build the ships, tanks, planes, and armaments necessary for the national defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Board</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Board’ means the Loan Guarantee Board established under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Program’ means the Emergency Steel Guarantee Loan Program established under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified steel company</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified steel company’ means any company that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is incorporated under the laws of any State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is engaged in the production and manufacture of a product defined by the American Iron and Steel Institute as a basic steel mill product, including ingots, slab and billets, plates, flat-rolled steel, sections and structural products, bars, rail type products, pipe and tube, and wire rod; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> has experienced layoffs, production losses, or financial losses since the beginning of the steel import crisis in 1998, and thereafter, or that operates substantial assets of a company that meets these qualifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Emergency Steel Guarantee Loan Program</inline>.—</heading><content>There is established the Emergency Steel Guarantee Loan Program, to be administered by the Board, the purpose of which is to provide loan guarantees to qualified steel companies in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan Guarantee Board Membership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There is established a Loan Guarantee Board, which shall be composed of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, or a member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System designated by the Chairman, who shall serve as Chairman of the Board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission, or a commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission designated by the Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan Guarantee Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Program may guarantee loans provided to qualified steel companies by private banking and investment institutions in accordance with the procedures, rules, and regulations established by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total guarantee limit</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of loans guaranteed and outstanding at any one time under this section may not exceed $1,000,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individual guarantee limit</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of loans guaranteed under this section with respect to a single qualified steel company may not exceed $250,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timelines</inline>.—</heading><content>The Board shall approve or deny each application for a guarantee under this section as soon as possible after receipt of such application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional costs</inline>.—</heading><content>For the additional cost of the loans guaranteed under this subsection, including the costs of modifying the loans as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</ref>), there is appropriated $140,000,000 to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Loan Guarantees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A loan guarantee may be issued under this section upon application to the Board by a qualified steel company pursuant to an agreement to provide a loan to that qualified steel company by a private bank or investment company, if the Board determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> credit is not otherwise available to that company under reasonable terms or conditions sufficient to meet its financing needs, as reflected in the financial and business plans of that company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the prospective earning power of that company, together with the character and value of the security pledged, furnish reasonable assurance of repayment of the loan to be guaranteed in accordance with its terms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the loan to be guaranteed bears interest at a rate determined by the Board to be reasonable, taking into account the current average yield on outstanding obligations of the United States with remaining periods of maturity comparable to the maturity of such loan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the company has agreed to an audit by the Government Accountability Office prior to the issuance of the loan guarantee and annually thereafter while any such guaranteed loan is outstanding; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> in the case of a purchaser of substantial assets of a qualified steel company, the qualified steel company establishes that it is unable to reorganize itself.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions of Loan Guarantees.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan duration</inline>.—</heading><content>All loans guaranteed under this section shall be payable in full not later than <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>, and the terms and conditions of each such loan shall provide that the loan may not be amended, or any provision thereof waived, without the consent of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan security</inline>.—</heading><content>Any commitment to issue a loan guarantee under this section shall contain such affirmative and negative covenants and other protective provisions that the Board determines are appropriate. The Board shall require security for the loans to be guaranteed under this section at the time at which the commitment is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>A qualified steel company receiving a guarantee under this section shall pay a fee to the Department of the Treasury to cover costs of the program, but in no event shall such fee exceed an amount equal to 0.5 percent of the outstanding principal balance of the guaranteed loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee level.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), any loan guarantee provided under this section shall not exceed 85 percent of the amount of principal of the loan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Increased level one</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A loan guarantee may be provided under this section in excess of 85 percent, but not more than 90 percent, of the amount of principal of the loan, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the aggregate amount of loans guaranteed at such percentage and outstanding under this section at any one time does not exceed $100,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the aggregate amount of loans guaranteed at such percentage under this section with respect to a single qualified steel company does not exceed $50,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Increased level two</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A loan guarantee may be provided under this section in excess of 85 percent, but not more than 95 percent, of the amount of principal of the loan, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the aggregate amount of loans guaranteed at such percentage and outstanding under this section at any one time does not exceed $100,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the aggregate amount of loans guaranteed at such percentage under this section with respect to a single qualified steel company does not exceed $50,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to Congress a full report of the activities of the Board under this section during each of fiscal years 1999 and 2000, and annually thereafter, during such period as any loan guaranteed under this section is outstanding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Salaries and Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>For necessary expenses to administer the Program, $5,000,000 is appropriated to the Department of Commerce, to remain available until expended, which may be transferred to the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Trade Development of the International Trade Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Guarantee Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority of the Board to make commitments to guarantee any loan under this section shall terminate on <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="l">“(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulatory Action</inline>.—</heading><content>The Board shall issue such final procedures, rules, and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="m">“(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Iron Ore Companies.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the requirements of this subsection, an iron ore company incorporated under the laws of any State shall be treated as a qualified steel company for purposes of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total guarantee limit for iron ore company</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the aggregate amount of loans authorized to be guaranteed and outstanding at any one time under subsection (f)(2), an amount not to exceed $30,000,000 shall be loans with respect to iron ore companies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</chapter><level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“federal administrative and travel expenses</heading><level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“(rescissions)</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="102">“Sec. 102.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> Of the funds available in the nondefense category to the agencies of the Federal Government, $145,000,000 are hereby rescinded: <i>Provided</i>, That rescissions pursuant to this subsection shall be taken only from administrative and travel accounts: <i>Provided further</i>, That rescissions shall be taken on a pro rata basis from funds available to every Federal agency, department, and office in the executive branch, including the Office of the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Within 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>], the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a listing of the amounts by account of the reductions made pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="103">“SEC. 103.</num><heading> SALARIES AND ADMINISTRATIVE EXPENSES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> In addition to funds made available under section 101(j) of the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Act of 1999 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1841">15 U.S.C. 1841</ref> note), up to $1,000,000 in funds made available under section 101(f) of such Act may be used for salaries and administrative expenses to administer the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Funds made available for salaries and administrative expenses to administer the Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee Program shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level></level>
<chapter style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="2">“CHAPTER 2</num><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="201">“Sec. 201.</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Petroleum Development Management</inline>.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short Title</inline>.—</heading><content>This chapter may be cited as the ‘Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program Act’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> consumption of foreign oil in the United States is estimated to equal 56 percent of all oil consumed, and that percentage could reach 68 percent by 2010 if current prices prevail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the number of oil and gas rigs operating in the United States is at its lowest since 1944, when records of this tally began;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> if prices do not increase soon, the United States could lose at least half its marginal wells, which in aggregate produce as much oil as the United States imports from Saudi Arabia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> oil and gas prices are unlikely to increase for at least several years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> declining production, well abandonment, and greatly reduced exploration and development are shrinking the domestic oil and gas industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the world’s richest oil producing regions in the Middle East are experiencing increasingly greater political instability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> United Nations policy may make Iraq the swing oil producing nation, thereby granting Saddam Hussein tremendous power;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> reliance on foreign oil for more than 60 percent of our daily oil and gas consumption is a national security threat;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> the level of United States oil security is directly related to the level of domestic production of oil, natural gas liquids, and natural gas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> a national security policy should be developed that ensures that adequate supplies of oil are available at all times free of the threat of embargo or other foreign hostile acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Board</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Board’ means the Loan Guarantee Board established by subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Program’ means the Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program established by subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified oil and gas company</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘qualified oil and gas company’ means a company that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> an independent oil and gas company (within the meaning of section 57(a)(2)(B)(i) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s57/a/2/B/i">26 U.S.C. 57(a)(2)(B)(i)</ref>]); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a small business concern under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>) (or a company based in Alaska, including an Alaska Native Corporation created pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.)) that is an oil field service company whose main business is providing tools, products, personnel, and technical solutions on a contractual basis to exploration and production operators that drill, complete wells, and produce, transport, refine, and sell hydrocarbons and their byproducts as the main commercial business of the concern or company; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> has experienced layoffs, production losses, or financial losses since the beginning of the oil import crisis, after <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>There is established the Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program, the purpose of which shall be to provide loan guarantees to qualified oil and gas companies in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan guarantee board</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There is established to administer the Program a Loan Guarantee Board, to be composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, or a member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System designated by the Chairman, who shall serve as Chairman of the Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission, or a commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission designated by the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Program may guarantee loans provided to qualified oil and gas companies by private banking and investment institutions in accordance with procedures, rules, and regulations established by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total guarantee limit</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of loans guaranteed and outstanding at any one time under this section shall not exceed $500,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individual guarantee limit</inline>.—</heading><content>The aggregate amount of loans guaranteed under this section with respect to a single qualified oil and gas company shall not exceed $10,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expeditious action on applications</inline>.—</heading><content>The Board shall approve or deny an application for a guarantee under this section as soon as practicable after receipt of an application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional costs</inline>.—</heading><content>For the additional cost of the loans guaranteed under this subsection, including the costs of modifying the loans as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</ref>), there is appropriated $122,500,000 to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Loan Guarantees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Board may issue a loan guarantee on application by a qualified oil and gas company under an agreement by a private bank or investment company to provide a loan to the qualified oil and gas company, if the Board determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> credit is not otherwise available to the company under reasonable terms or conditions sufficient to meet its financing needs, as reflected in the financial and business plans of the company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the prospective earning power of the company, together with the character and value of the security pledged, provide a reasonable assurance of repayment of the loan to be guaranteed in accordance with its terms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the loan to be guaranteed bears interest at a rate determined by the Board to be reasonable, taking into account the current average yield on outstanding obligations of the United States with remaining periods of maturity comparable to the maturity of the loan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the company has agreed to an audit by the Government Accountability Office before issuance of the loan guarantee and annually while the guaranteed loan is outstanding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions of Loan Guarantees.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan duration</inline>.—</heading><content>All loans guaranteed under this section shall be repayable in full not later than <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, and the terms and conditions of each such loan shall provide that the loan agreement may not be amended, or any provision of the loan agreement waived, without the consent of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loan security</inline>.—</heading><content>A commitment to issue a loan guarantee under this section shall contain such affirmative and negative covenants and other protective provisions as the Board determines are appropriate. The Board shall require security for the loans to be guaranteed under this section at the time at which the commitment is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>A qualified oil and gas company receiving a loan guarantee under this section shall pay a fee to the Department of the Treasury to cover costs of the program, but in no event shall such fee exceed an amount equal to 0.5 percent of the outstanding principal balance of the guaranteed loan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee level</inline>.—</heading><content>No loan guarantee may be provided under this section if the guarantee exceeds 85 percent of the amount of principal of the loan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>During fiscal year 1999 and each fiscal year thereafter until each guaranteed loan has been repaid in full, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Salaries and Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>For necessary expenses to administer the Program, $2,500,000 is appropriated to the Department of Commerce, to remain available until expended, which may be transferred to the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Trade Development of the International Trade Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Guarantee Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority of the Board to make commitments to guarantee any loan under this section shall terminate on <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulatory Action</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>], the Board shall issue such final procedures, rules, and regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“federal administrative and travel expenses</heading><level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“(rescissions)</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="202">“Sec. 202.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> Of the funds available in the nondefense category to the agencies of the Federal Government, $125,000,000 are hereby rescinded: <i>Provided</i>, That rescissions pursuant to this subsection shall be taken only from administrative and travel accounts: <i>Provided further</i>, That rescissions shall be taken on a pro rata basis from funds available to every Federal agency, department, and office in the executive branch, including the Office of the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Within 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>], the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a listing of the amounts by account of the reductions made pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level></level>
</chapter><chapter style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="3">“CHAPTER 3</num><level style="-uslm-lc:I71"><heading>“GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="301">“Sec. 301.</num><content> No part of any appropriation contained in the Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Emergency Steel Loan Guarantee and Emergency Oil and Gas Guaranteed Loan Act of 1999’.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</level>
</chapter></quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dB/tI/s105/c">Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1893">121 Stat. 1893</ref>, which directed amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/106/51/s101/c/3/C">section 101(c)(3)(C) of Pub. L. 106–51</ref>, set out above, by substituting “in 1998, and thereafter,” for “, in 1998”, was executed by making the substitution for “, in January 1998” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.]</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/107/63/tIII/s336/b">Pub. L. 107–63, title III, § 336(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-05">Nov. 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/472">115 Stat. 472</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/63/tIII/s336/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/106/51/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 106–51</ref>, set out above] shall apply only with respect to any guarantee issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2001-11-05">Nov. 5, 2001</date>].”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
