<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79c8fc79-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053"><num value="2053">§ 2053.</num><heading> Consumer Product Safety Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc7a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An independent regulatory commission is hereby established, to be known as the Consumer Product Safety Commission, consisting of five Commissioners who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. In making such appointments, the President shall consider individuals who, by reason of their background and expertise in areas related to consumer products and protection of the public from risks to safety, are qualified to serve as members of the Commission. The Chairman shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among the members of the Commission. An individual may be appointed as a member of the Commission and as Chairman at the same time. Any member of the Commission may be removed by the President for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office but for no other cause.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc7b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Term; vacancies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc7c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), (A) the Commissioners first appointed under this section shall be appointed for terms ending three, four, five, six, and seven years, respectively, after <date date="1972-10-27">October 27, 1972</date>, the term of each to be designated by the President at the time of nomination; and (B) each of their successors shall be appointed for a term of seven years from the date of the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc7d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any Commissioner appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. A Commissioner may continue to serve after the expiration of this term until his successor has taken office, except that he may not so continue to serve more than one year after the date on which his term would otherwise expire under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc7e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on Commissioner’s outside activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not more than three of the Commissioners shall be affiliated with the same political party. No individual (1) in the employ of, or holding any official relation to, any person engaged in selling or manufacturing consumer products, or (2) owning stock or bonds of substantial value in a person so engaged, or (3) who is in any other manner pecuniarily interested in such a person, or in a substantial supplier of such a person, shall hold the office of Commissioner. A Commissioner may not engage in any other business, vocation, or employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc7f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Quorum; seal; Vice Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No vacancy in the Commission shall impair the right of the remaining Commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Commission, but three members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except that if there are only three members serving on the Commission because of vacancies in the Commission, two members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and if there are only two members serving on the Commission because of vacancies in the Commission, two members shall constitute a quorum for the six month period beginning on the date of the vacancy which caused the number of Commission members to decline to two. The Commission shall have an official seal of which judicial notice shall be taken. The Commission shall annually elect a Vice Chairman to act in the absence or disability of the Chairman or in case of a vacancy in the office of the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc80-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Offices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall maintain a principal office and such field offices as it deems necessary and may meet and exercise any of its powers at any other place.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc81-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of Chairman; request for appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc82-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Chairman of the Commission shall be the principal executive officer of the Commission, and he shall exercise all of the executive and administrative functions of the Commission, including functions of the Commission with respect to (A) the appointment and supervision of personnel employed under the Commission (other than personnel employed regularly and full time in the immediate offices of commissioners other than the Chairman), (B) the distribution of business among personnel appointed and supervised by the Chairman and among administrative units of the Commission, and (C) the use and expenditure of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc83-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In carrying out any of his functions under the provisions of this subsection the Chairman shall be governed by general policies of the Commission and by such regulatory decisions, findings, and determinations as the Commission may by law be authorized to make.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc84-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Requests or estimates for regular, supplemental, or deficiency appropriations on behalf of the Commission may not be submitted by the Chairman without the prior approval of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc85-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive Director; officers and employees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc86-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc87-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Chairman, subject to the approval of the Commission, shall appoint as officers of the Commission an Executive Director, a General Counsel, an Associate Executive Director for Engineering Sciences, an Associate Executive Director for Epidemiology, an Associate Executive Director for Compliance and Administrative Litigation, an Associate Executive Director for Health Sciences, an Associate Executive Director for Economic Analysis, an Associate Executive Director for Administration, an Associate Executive Director for Field Operations, a Director for Office of Program, Management, and Budget, and a Director for Office of Information and Public Affairs. Any other individual appointed to a position designated as an Associate Executive Director shall be appointed by the Chairman, subject to the approval of the Commission. The Chairman may only appoint an attorney to the position of Associate Executive Director of Compliance and Administrative Litigation except the position of acting Associate Executive Director of Compliance and Administrative Litigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc88-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc89-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> No individual may be appointed to such a position on an acting basis for a period longer than 90 days unless such appointment is approved by the Commission.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Chairman, with the approval of the Commission, may remove any individual serving in a position appointed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to prohibit appropriate reorganizations or changes in classification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Chairman, subject to subsection (f)(2), may employ such other officers and employees (including attorneys) as are necessary in the execution of the Commission’s functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to the number of positions authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108/a">section 5108(a) of title 5</ref>, the Chairman, subject to the approval of the Commission, and subject to the standards and procedures prescribed by chapter 51 of title 5, may place a total of twelve positions in grades GS–16, GS–17, and GS–18.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The appointment of any officer (other than a Commissioner) or employee of the Commission shall not be subject, directly or indirectly, to review or approval by any officer or entity within the Executive Office of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79c8fc8f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Chairman may provide to officers and employees of the Commission who are appointed or assigned by the Commission to serve abroad (as defined in section 102 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3902">22 U.S.C. 3902</ref>)) travel benefits similar to those authorized for members of the Foreign Service of the United Service under chapter 9 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002420">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002420"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4081">22 U.S.C. 4081</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc90-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79c8fc91-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil action against United States</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsections (a) and (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2680">section 2680 of title 28</ref> do not prohibit the bringing of a civil action on a claim against the United States which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79c8fc92-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> is based upon—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c8fc93-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> misrepresentation or deceit on the part of the Commission or any employee thereof, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79c8fc94-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any exercise or performance, or failure to exercise or perform, a discretionary function on the part of the Commission or any employee thereof, which exercise, performance, or failure was grossly negligent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79cb4585-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is not made with respect to any agency action (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551/13">section 551(13) of title 5</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of a civil action on a claim based upon the exercise or performance of, or failure to exercise or perform, a discretionary function, no judgment may be entered against the United States unless the court in which such action was brought determines (based upon consideration of all the relevant circumstances, including the statutory responsibility of the Commission and the public interest in encouraging rather than inhibiting the exercise of discretion) that such exercise, performance, or failure to exercise or perform was unreasonable.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cb4586-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2053/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Agenda and priorities; establishment and comments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At least 30 days before the beginning of each fiscal year, the Commission shall establish an agenda for Commission action under the Acts under its jurisdiction and, to the extent feasible, shall establish priorities for such actions. Before establishing such agenda and priorities, the Commission shall conduct a public hearing on the agenda and priorities and shall provide reasonable opportunity for the submission of comments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79cb4587-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s4">Pub. L. 92–573, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1210">86 Stat. 1210</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/284">Pub. L. 94–284</ref>, §§ 4, 5(a), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/504">90 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/631/s2">Pub. L. 95–631, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3742">92 Stat. 3742</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/373">Pub. L. 96–373</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1366">94 Stat. 1366</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/tI">Pub. L. 101–608, title I</ref>, §§ 102–105(a), <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3110">104 Stat. 3110</ref>, 3111; <ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dC/tV/s501">Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/907">125 Stat. 907</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79cb4588-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79cb4589-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79cb458a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (g)(5), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>. Chapter 9 of the Act probably means chapter 9 of title I of the Act which is classified generally to subchapter IX (§ 4081 et seq.) of chapter 52 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79cb458b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h) of this section amended sections 5314 and 5315 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79cb458c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/74">Pub. L. 112–74</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/s102">Pub. L. 101–608, § 102</ref>, inserted after first sentence “In making such appointments, the President shall consider individuals who, by reason of their background and expertise in areas related to consumer products and protection of the public from risks to safety, are qualified to serve as members of the Commission.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/s103">Pub. L. 101–608, § 103</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “, except that if there are only three members serving on the Commission because of vacancies in the Commission, two members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and if there are only two members serving on the Commission because of vacancies in the Commission, two members shall constitute a quorum for the six month period beginning on the date of the vacancy which caused the number of Commission members to decline to two”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/s104">Pub. L. 101–608, § 104</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The Chairman, subject to the approval of the Commission, shall appoint an Executive Director, a General Counsel, a Director of Engineering Sciences, a Director of Epidemiology, and a Director of Information. No individual so appointed may receive pay in excess of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/s105/a">Pub. L. 101–608, § 105(a)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/373">Pub. L. 96–373</ref> struck out prohibition against regular personnel acceptance of employment or compensation from manufacturer subject to this chapter for period of twelve months following termination of employment with Commission when compensated within preceding period of twelve months at rate in excess of annual rate of basic pay in effect for grade GS–14 of the General Schedule.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/631/s2/a">Pub. L. 95–631, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted “Senate. The Chairman shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among the members of the Commission. An individual may be appointed as a member of the Commission and as Chairman at the same time.” for “Senate, one of whom shall be designated by the President as Chairman. The Chairman, when so designated shall act as Chairman until the expiration of his term of office as Commissioner.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/631/s2/b">Pub. L. 95–631, § 2(b)</ref>, struck out “before <date date="1978-01-01">January 1, 1978</date>,” after “deceit” in cl. (A) and “before <date date="1978-01-01">January 1, 1978</date>” after “employee thereof” in cl. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/284/s4/a">Pub. L. 94–284, § 4(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/284/s4/b">Pub. L. 94–284, § 4(b)</ref>, substituted “regular” for “full-time” before “officer or employee of the Commission” and added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec (i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/284/s5">Pub. L. 94–284, § 5</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79cb458d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79cb458e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/608/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 101–608, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3111">104 Stat. 3111</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/608/tI/s105/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to fiscal years which begin more than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id79cb458f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s34/1">section 34(1) of Pub. L. 92–573</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79cb4590-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interim Quorum</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3039">122 Stat. 3039</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s202/a">“Notwithstanding section 4(d) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2053/d">15 U.S.C. 2053(d)</ref>), 2 members of the [Consumer Product Safety] Commission, if they are not affiliated with the same political party, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business for the 1 year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79cb4591-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Upgrade of Commission Information Technology Systems</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s212/b">Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 212(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3052">122 Stat. 3052</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s212/b">“The [Consumer Product Safety] Commission shall expedite efforts to upgrade and improve the information technology systems in use by the Commission on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79cb4592-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reduction in Number of Commissioners</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/389/tIII">Pub. L. 102–389, title III</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1596">106 Stat. 1596</ref>, provided in part that funds would not be available for the personnel compensation and benefits of more than three Commissioners of the Consumer Product Safety Commission for fiscal year 1993 and thereafter, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s202/b/1">Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3040">122 Stat. 3040</ref>.</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s202/b/2">Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3040">122 Stat. 3040</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s202/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [repealing provisions of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/102/389">Pub. L. 102–389</ref>, formerly set out above] shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>].”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79cb4593-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
