<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79cdb759-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a"><num value="2056a">§ 2056a.</num><heading> Standards and consumer registration of durable nursery products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb75a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Danny Keysar Child Product Safety Notification Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb75b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Safety standards</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb75c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb75d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in consultation with representatives of consumer groups, juvenile product manufacturers, and independent child product engineers and experts, examine and assess the effectiveness of any voluntary consumer product safety standards for durable infant or toddler products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb75e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, promulgate consumer product safety standards that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79cdb75f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are substantially the same as such voluntary standards; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79cdb760-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are more stringent than such voluntary standards, if the Commission determines that more stringent standards would further reduce the risk of injury associated with such products.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb761-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Timetable for rulemaking</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, the Commission shall commence the rulemaking required under paragraph (1) and shall promulgate standards for no fewer than 2 categories of durable infant or toddler products every 6 months thereafter, beginning with the product categories that the Commission determines to be of highest priority, until the Commission has promulgated standards for all such product categories. Thereafter, the Commission shall periodically review and revise the standards set forth under this subsection to ensure that such standards provide the highest level of safety for such products that is feasible.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb762-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person adversely affected by such standards may file a petition for review under the procedures set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2060/g">section 2060(g) of this title</ref>, as added by section 236 of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb763-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for considering subsequent revisions to voluntary standard</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb764-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of adoption of voluntary standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">When the Commission promulgates a consumer product safety standard under this subsection that is based, in whole or in part, on a voluntary standard, the Commission shall notify the organization that issued the voluntary standard of the Commission’s action and shall provide a copy of the consumer product safety standard to the organization.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb765-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission action on revised voluntary standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If an organization revises a standard that has been adopted, in whole or in part, as a consumer product safety standard under this subsection, it shall notify the Commission. The revised voluntary standard shall be considered to be a consumer product safety standard issued by the Commission under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2058">section 2058 of this title</ref>, effective 180 days after the date on which the organization notifies the Commission (or such later date specified by the Commission in the Federal Register) unless, within 90 days after receiving that notice, the Commission notifies the organization that it has determined that the proposed revision does not improve the safety of the consumer product covered by the standard and that the Commission is retaining the existing consumer product safety standard.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb766-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cribs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb767-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It shall be a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2068/a/1">section 2068(a)(1) of this title</ref> for any person to which this subsection applies to manufacture, sell, contract to sell or resell, lease, sublet, offer, provide for use, or otherwise place in the stream of commerce a crib that is not in compliance with a standard promulgated under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb768-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons to which subsection applies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection applies to any person that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb769-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> manufactures, distributes in commerce, or contracts to sell cribs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb76a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> based on the person’s occupation, holds itself out as having knowledge or skill peculiar to cribs, including child care facilities and family child care homes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb76b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is in the business of contracting to sell or resell, lease, sublet, or otherwise place cribs in the stream of commerce; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb76c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> owns or operates a place of public accommodation affecting commerce (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2203">section 2203 of this title</ref> applied without regard to the phrase “not owned by the Federal Government”).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb76d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of any revision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to any revision of the standard promulgated under subsection (b)(1)(B) subsequent to the initial promulgation of a standard under such subsection, paragraph (1) shall apply only to a person that manufactures or imports cribs, unless the Commission determines that application to any other person described in paragraph (2) is necessary to protect against an unreasonable risk to health or safety. If the Commission determines that application to a person described in paragraph (2) is necessary, it shall provide not less than 12 months for such person to come into compliance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb76e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Crib defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “crib” includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb76f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> new and used cribs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb770-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> full-sized or nonfull-sized cribs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb771-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> portable cribs and crib-pens.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb772-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumer registration requirement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb773-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 6 of title 5 or the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.), not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, the Commission shall, pursuant to its authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2065/b">section 2065(b) of this title</ref>, promulgate a final consumer product safety rule to require each manufacturer of a durable infant or toddler product—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb774-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to provide consumers with a postage-paid consumer registration form with each such product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb775-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to maintain a record of the names, addresses, e-mail addresses, and other contact information of consumers who register their ownership of such products with the manufacturer in order to improve the effectiveness of manufacturer campaigns to recall such products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb776-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to permanently place the manufacturer name and contact information, model name and number, and the date of manufacture on each durable infant or toddler product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb777-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for registration form</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The registration form required to be provided to consumers under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb778-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include spaces for a consumer to provide the consumer’s name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb779-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include space sufficiently large to permit easy, legible recording of all desired information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb77a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> be attached to the surface of each durable infant or toddler product so that, as a practical matter, the consumer must notice and handle the form after purchasing the product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb77b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> include the manufacturer’s name, model name and number for the product, and the date of manufacture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb77c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> include a message explaining the purpose of the registration and designed to encourage consumers to complete the registration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb77d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> include an option for consumers to register through the Internet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb77e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> include a statement that information provided by the consumer shall not be used for any purpose other than to facilitate a recall of or safety alert regarding that product.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In issuing regulations under this section, the Commission may prescribe the exact text and format of the required registration form.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb77f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Record keeping and notification requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The rules required under this section shall require each manufacturer of a durable infant or toddler product to maintain a record of registrants for each product manufactured that includes all of the information provided by each consumer registered, and to use such information to notify such consumers in the event of a voluntary or involuntary recall of or safety alert regarding such product. Each manufacturer shall maintain such a record for a period of not less than 6 years after the date of manufacture of the product. Consumer information collected by a manufacturer under this Act may not be used by the manufacturer, nor disseminated by such manufacturer to any other party, for any purpose other than notification to such consumer in the event of a product recall or safety alert.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb780-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall conduct a study at such time as it considers appropriate on the effectiveness of the consumer registration forms required by this section in facilitating product recalls and whether such registration forms should be required for other children’s products. Not later than 4 years after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, the Commission shall report its findings to the appropriate Congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb781-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of alternative recall notification technology</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb782-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Technology assessment and report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb783-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> beginning 2 years after a rule is promulgated under subsection (d), regularly review recall notification technology and assess the effectiveness of such technology in facilitating recalls of durable infant or toddler products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb784-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than 3 years after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, and periodically thereafter as the Commission considers appropriate, transmit a report on such assessments to the appropriate Congressional committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb785-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, based on the assessment required by paragraph (1), the Commission determines by rule that a recall notification technology is likely to be as effective or more effective in facilitating recalls of durable infant or toddler products as the registration forms required by subsection (d), the Commission—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb786-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall submit to the appropriate Congressional committees a report on such determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb787-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall permit a manufacturer of durable infant or toddler products to use such technology in lieu of such registration forms to facilitate recalls of durable infant or toddler products.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79cdb788-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of durable infant or toddler product</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “durable infant or toddler product”—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79cdb789-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> means a durable product intended for use, or that may be reasonably expected to be used, by children under the age of 5 years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79cdb78a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb78b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> full-size cribs and nonfull-size cribs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb78c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> toddler beds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb78d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> high chairs, booster chairs, and hook-on chairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb78e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> bath seats;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb78f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> gates and other enclosures for confining a child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb790-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> play yards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb791-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> stationary activity centers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb792-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> infant carriers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb793-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> strollers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb794-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> walkers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb795-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> swings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79cdb796-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2056a/f/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> bassinets and cradles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79cdb797-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tI/s104">Pub. L. 110–314, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3028">122 Stat. 3028</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/28/s3">Pub. L. 112–28, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-08-12">Aug. 12, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/279">125 Stat. 279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79cdb798-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79cdb799-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79cdb79a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2060/g">Section 2060(g) of this title</ref>, as added by section 236 of this Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2060/g">section 2060(g) of this title</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s236">section 236 of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/511">Pub. L. 96–511</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2812">94 Stat. 2812</ref>, which was classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 3501 et seq.) of Title 44, Public Printing and Documents, prior to the general amendment of that chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/104/13/s2">Pub. L. 104–13, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-05-22">May 22, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/163">109 Stat. 163</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1980 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s101">section 101 of Title 44</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/110/314">Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3016">122 Stat. 3016</ref>, known as the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2008 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79cdb79b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008, and not as part of the Consumer Product Safety Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79cdb79c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/28/s3/a">Pub. L. 112–28, § 3(a)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/28/s3/b">Pub. L. 112–28, § 3(b)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79cdb79d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id79cdb79e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of “Commission” and “appropriate Congressional committees” used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s2/a">section 2(a) of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
