<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79d4e2e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066"><num value="2066">§ 2066.</num><heading> Imported products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Refusal of admission</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any consumer product offered for importation into the customs territory of the United States (as defined in general note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States) shall be refused admission into such customs territory if such product—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79d4e2e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> fails to comply with an applicable consumer product safety rule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79d4e2e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is not accompanied by a certificate required by this chapter or any other Act enforced by the Commission, or is accompanied by a false certificate, if the manufacturer in the exercise of due care has reason to know that the certificate is false or misleading in any material respect, or is not accompanied by any label or certificate (including tracking labels) required under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2063">section 2063 of this title</ref> or any rule or regulation under such section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79d4e2e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is or has been determined to be an imminently hazardous consumer product in a proceeding brought under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2061">section 2061 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79d4e2ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> has a product defect which constitutes a substantial product hazard (within the meaning of section 2064(a)(2)) of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79d4e2eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> is a product which was manufactured by a person who the Commission has informed the Secretary of the Treasury is in violation of subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2ec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Samples</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall obtain without charge and deliver to the Commission, upon the latter’s request, a reasonable number of samples of consumer products being offered for import. Except for those owners or consignees who are or have been afforded an opportunity for a hearing in a proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2061">section 2061 of this title</ref> with respect to an imminently hazardous product, the owner or consignee of the product shall be afforded an opportunity by the Commission for a hearing in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref> with respect to the importation of such products into the customs territory of the United States. If it appears from examination of such samples or otherwise that a product must be refused admission under the terms of subsection (a), such product shall be refused admission, unless subsection (c) of this section applies and is complied with.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2ed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If it appears to the Commission that any consumer product which may be refused admission pursuant to subsection (a) of this section can be so modified that it need not (under the terms of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a)) be refused admission, the Commission may defer final determination as to the admission of such product and, in accordance with such regulations as the Commission and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly agree to, permit such product to be delivered from customs custody under bond for the purpose of permitting the owner or consignee an opportunity to so modify such product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2ee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Supervision of modifications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All actions taken by an owner or consignee to modify such product under subsection (c) shall be subject to the supervision of an officer or employee of the Commission and of the Department of the Treasury. If it appears to the Commission that the product cannot be so modified or that the owner or consignee is not proceeding satisfactorily to modify such product, it shall be refused admission into the customs territory of the United States, and the Commission may direct the Secretary to demand redelivery of the product into customs custody, and to seize the product in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2071/b">section 2071(b) of this title</ref> if it is not so redelivered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2ef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Product destruction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Products refused admission into the customs territory of the United States shall be destroyed unless, upon application by the owner, consignee, or importer of record, the Secretary of the Treasury permits the export of the product in lieu of destruction. If the owner, consignee, or importer of record does not export the product within 90 days of approval to export, such product shall be destroyed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2f0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of expenses occasioned by refusal of admission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All expenses (including travel, per diem or subsistence, and salaries of officers or employees of the United States) in connection with the destruction provided for in this section (the amount of such expenses to be determined in accordance with regulations of the Secretary of the Treasury) and all expenses in connection with the storage, cartage, or labor with respect to any consumer product refused admission under this section, shall be paid by the owner or consignee and, in default of such payment, shall constitute a lien against any future importations made by such owner or consignee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2f1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspection and recordkeeping requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Manufacturers of imported products shall be in compliance with all inspection and recordkeeping requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2065">section 2065 of this title</ref> applicable to such products, and the Commission shall advise the Secretary of the Treasury of any manufacturer who is not in compliance with all inspection and recordkeeping requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2065">section 2065 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79d4e2f2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Product surveillance program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79d4e2f3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall establish and maintain a permanent product surveillance program, in cooperation with other appropriate Federal agencies, for the purpose of carrying out the Commission’s responsibilities under this chapter and the other Acts administered by the Commission and preventing the entry of unsafe consumer products into the commerce of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79d4e2f4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commission may provide to the agencies with which it is cooperating under paragraph (1) such information, data, violator lists, test results, and other support, guidance, and documents as may be necessary or helpful for such agencies to cooperate with the Commission to carry out the product surveillance program under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79d4e2f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2066/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Commission shall periodically report to the appropriate Congressional committees the results of the surveillance program under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79d4e2f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s17">Pub. L. 92–573, § 17</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1223">86 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1214/d">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1156">102 Stat. 1156</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/608/tI/s114">Pub. L. 101–608, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3118">104 Stat. 3118</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII">Pub. L. 110–314, title II</ref>, §§ 216(b), 223(b), (c)(1), 235(c)(6), <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3058">122 Stat. 3058</ref>, 3068, 3069, 3075.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79d753f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79d753f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79d753f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, referred to in subsec. (a), is not set out in the Code. See Publication of Harmonized Tariff Schedule note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79d753fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s216/b">Pub. L. 110–314, § 216(b)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “is not accompanied by a certificate required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2063">section 2063 of this title</ref>, or is not labeled in accordance with regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2063/c">section 2063(c) of this title</ref>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s223/b">Pub. L. 110–314, § 223(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Products refused admission into the customs territory of the United States under this section must be exported, except that upon application, the Secretary of the Treasury may permit the destruction of the product in lieu of exportation. If the owner or consignee does not export the product within a reasonable time, the Department of the Treasury may destroy the product.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s223/c/1">Pub. L. 110–314, § 223(c)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Commission may, by rule, condition the importation of a consumer product on the manufacturer’s compliance with the inspection and recordkeeping requirements of this chapter and the Commission’s rules with respect to such requirements.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s235/c/6">Pub. L. 110–314, § 235(c)(6)</ref>, substituted “the appropriate Congressional committees” for “the Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/608">Pub. L. 101–608</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “general note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States” for “general headnote 2 to the Tariff Schedules of the United States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79d753fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79d753fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 216(b) and 223(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/110/314">Pub. L. 110–314</ref> effective on the date that is 30 days after <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s239/a">section 239(a) of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79d753fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, and applicable with respect to articles entered on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1217/b/1">section 1217(b)(1) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3001">section 3001 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id79d753fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the sixtieth day following <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/573/s34">section 34 of Pub. L. 92–573</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79d753ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funding for Consumer Product Safety Fund To Protect Consumers From Potentially Dangerous Products Related to COVID–19</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tVII/s7401">Pub. L. 117–2, title VII, § 7401</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/108">135 Stat. 108</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/2/tVII/s7401">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriation</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Consumer Product Safety Commission for fiscal year 2021, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $50,000,000, to remain available until <date date="2026-09-30">September 30, 2026</date>, for the purposes described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The funds made available in subsection (a) shall only be used for purposes of the Consumer Product Safety Commission to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> carry out the requirements in title XX of division FF of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) [consisting only of section 2001, set out as a note below];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> enhance targeting, surveillance, and screening of consumer products, particularly COVID–19 products, entering the United States at ports of entry, including ports of entry for de minimis shipments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> enhance monitoring of internet websites for the offering for sale of new and used violative consumer products, particularly COVID–19 products, and coordination with retail and resale websites to improve identification and elimination of listings of such products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> increase awareness and communication particularly of COVID–19 product related risks and other consumer product safety information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> improve the Commission’s data collection and analysis system especially with a focus on consumer product safety risks resulting from the COVID–19 pandemic to socially disadvantaged individuals and other vulnerable populations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Commission’ means the Consumer Product Safety Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘violative consumer products’ means consumer products in violation of an applicable consumer product safety standard under the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">15 U.S.C. 2051</ref> et seq.) or any similar rule, regulation, standard, or ban under any other Act enforced by the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘COVID–19 emergency period’ means the period during which a public health emergency declared pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</ref>) with respect to the 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID–19), including under any renewal of such declaration, is in effect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the term ‘COVID–19 products’ means consumer products, as defined by section 3(a)(5) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2052/a/5">15 U.S.C. 2052(a)(5)</ref>), whose risks have been significantly affected by COVID–19 or whose sales have materially increased during the COVID–19 emergency period as a result of the COVID–19 pandemic.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79d75400-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Port Surveillance During the COVID–19 Pandemic</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tXX/s2001">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title XX, § 2001</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3301">134 Stat. 3301</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tXX/s2001">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">CPSC Surveillance Personnel During the COVID–</inline>19<inline class="small-caps"> Pandemic</inline>.—</heading><content>For the duration of a public health emergency declared pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</ref>) as a result of confirmed cases of 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID–19), including any renewal thereof, the Commission shall ensure, to the maximum extent feasible, that investigators are stationed at ports of entry to protect the public against unreasonable risk of injury from consumer products, with the goal of covering no fewer than 90 percent of all consumer products entering the United States that are risk-scored in the Risk Assessment Methodology system. The Commission shall consult with United States Customs and Border Protection, and other relevant agencies, including health and safety agencies, on methods to safely staff ports during the pandemic.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional CPSC Surveillance Personnel at Key Ports of Entry</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission shall hire, train, and assign not fewer than 16 additional full-time equivalent personnel to be stationed at or supporting efforts at ports of entry, including ports of entry for de minimis shipments, for the purpose of identifying, assessing, and addressing shipments of violative consumer products. Such hiring shall continue during each fiscal year until the total number of full-time equivalent personnel equals and sustains the staffing requirements identified in the report to Congress required under subsection (c)(2)(F).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>], the Commission shall transmit to Congress, and make publicly available, a study and report assessing the risk to consumers associated with the reduction in Commission port inspection activity during the COVID–19 pandemic and the targeting and screening of de minimis shipments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the study and report, the Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> identify—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the risks associated with the reduction in Commission port inspection activity during the COVID–19 pandemic;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the extent to which the reduction in port inspection activity is linked to inadequate Commission resources or due to shortages of trained Commission staff due to the COVID–19 pandemic; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the steps the Commission has taken and plans to take to mitigate those risks, such as recalls, inspections of product inventory, consumer warnings, and other appropriate measures;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> examine a sampling of de minimis shipments at a sufficient and representative sample of all types of ports of entry where de minimis shipments are processed, including express consignment carrier facilities, international mail facilities, and air cargo facilities to assess the extent to which such shipments include violative consumer products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> examine a sampling of shipments coming from countries identified as high-risk for exporting violative consumer products to identify trends associated with the shipment of products containing both intellectual property rights infringements and consumer product safety violations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> detail plans and timelines to effectively address targeting and screening of de minimis shipments to prevent the entry of violative consumer products entering into the commerce of the United States taking into consideration projected growth in e-commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> establish metrics by which to evaluate the effectiveness of the Commission efforts to reduce the number of de minimis shipments containing violative consumer products from entering into the commerce of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> assess projected technology and resources, including staffing requirements necessary to implement such plans based on available and needed Commission resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Commission’ means the Consumer Product Safety Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘de minimis shipments’ means articles containing consumer products entering the United States under the de minimis value exemption in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1321/a/2/C">19 U.S.C. 1321(a)(2)(C)</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘ports of entry for de minimis shipments’ means environments where de minimis shipments are processed, including express consignment carrier facilities, international mail facilities, and air cargo facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the term ‘violative consumer products’ means consumer products in violation of an applicable consumer product safety rule under the Consumer Product Safety Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">15 U.S.C. 2051</ref> et seq.] or any similar rule, regulation, standard, or ban under any other Act enforced by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Clause</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit, affect, or conflict with any other authority of the Commission or any other statutory requirements governing the Commission.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79d75401-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Import Safety Management and Interagency Cooperation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s222">Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3066">122 Stat. 3066</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/314/tII/s222">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Risk Assessment Methodology</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>], the Commission shall develop a risk assessment methodology for the identification of shipments of consumer products that are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> intended for import into the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> likely to include consumer products in violation of section 17(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of International Trade Data System and Other Databases</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing the methodology required under subsection (a), the Commission shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> provide for the use of the International Trade Data System, insofar as is practicable, established under section 411(d) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1411/d">19 U.S.C. 1411(d)</ref>) to evaluate and assess information about shipments of consumer products intended for import into the customs territory of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> incorporate the risk assessment methodology required under this section into its information technology modernization plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> examine, in consultation with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, how to share information collected and retained by the Commission, including information in the database required under section 6A of the Consumer Product Safety Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2055a">15 U.S.C. 2055a</ref>], for the purpose of identifying shipments of consumer products in violation of section 17(a) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> examine, in consultation with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, how to share information required by section 15(j) of the CPSA [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2064/j">15 U.S.C. 2064(j)</ref>] as added by section 223 of this Act for the purpose of identifying shipments of consumer products in violation of section 17(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With U.S. Customs and Border Protection</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>], the Commission shall develop a plan for sharing information and coordinating with U.S. Customs and Border Protection that considers, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The number of full-time equivalent personnel employed by the Commission that should be stationed at U.S. ports of entry for the purpose of identifying shipments of consumer products that are in violation of section 17(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The extent and nature of cooperation between the Commission and U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel stationed at ports of entry in the identification of shipments of consumer product that are in violation of section 17(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission under this Act [see Short Title of 2008 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>] or any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The number of full-time equivalent personnel employed by the Commission that should be stationed at the National Targeting Center (or its equivalent) of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the extent and nature of cooperation between Commission and U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel stationed at the National Targeting Center (or its equivalent), as well as at United States ports of entry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the responsibilities of Commission personnel assigned to the National Targeting Center (or its equivalent) under subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> whether the information available at the National Targeting Center (or its equivalent) would be useful to the Commission or U.S. Customs and Border Protection in identifying the consumer products described in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The development of rule sets for the Automated Targeting System and expedited access for the Commission to the Automated Targeting System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The information and resources necessary for the development, updating, and effective implementation of the risk assessment methodology required in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after completion of the risk assessment methodology required under this section, the Commission shall submit a report to the appropriate Congressional committees concerning, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Commission’s plan for implementing the risk assessment methodology required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The changes made or necessary to be made to the Commission’s memorandum of understanding with U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The status of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the development of the Automated Targeting System rule set required under subsection (c)(4) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Commission’s access to the Automated Targeting System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the effectiveness of the International Trade Data System in enhancing cooperation between the Commission and U.S. Customs and Border Protection for the purpose of identifying shipments of consumer products in violation of section 17(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2066/a">15 U.S.C. 2066(a)</ref>) or other import provisions enforced by the Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Whether the Commission requires additional statutory authority under the Consumer Product Safety Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">15 U.S.C. 2051</ref> et seq.], the Federal Hazardous Substances Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1261">15 U.S.C. 1261</ref> et seq.], the Flammable Fabrics Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1191">15 U.S.C. 1191</ref> et seq.], or the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1471">15 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.] in order to implement the risk assessment methodology required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The level of appropriations necessary to implement the risk assessment methodology required under this section.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “Commission” and “appropriate Congressional committees” used in <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s222">section 222 of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/314/s2/a">section 2(a) of Pub. L. 110–314</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
