<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77b9f21c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s21a"><num value="21a">§ 21a.</num><heading> Actions and proceedings pending prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>; additional and continuing violations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing herein contained shall affect rights of action arising, or litigation pending, or orders of the Federal Trade Commission issued and in effect or pending on review, based on <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That where, prior to <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, the Federal Trade Commission has issued an order requiring any person to cease and desist from a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, and such order is pending on review or is in effect, either as issued or as affirmed or modified by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the Commission shall have reason to believe that such person has committed, used or carried on, since <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, or is committing, using or carrying on, any act, practice or method in violation of any of the provisions of said <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, it may reopen such original proceedings and may issue and serve upon such person its complaint, supplementary to the original complaint, stating its charges in that respect. Thereupon the same proceedings shall be had upon such supplementary complaint as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s21">section 21 of this title</ref>. If upon such hearing the Commission shall be of the opinion that any act, practice, or method charged in said supplementary complaint has been committed, used, or carried on since <date date="1936-06-19">June 19, 1936</date>, or is being committed, used or carried on, in violation of said <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, it shall make a report in writing in which it shall state its findings as to the facts and shall issue and serve upon such person its order modifying or amending its original order to include any additional violations of law so found. Thereafter the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s21">section 21 of this title</ref>, as to review and enforcement of orders of the Commission shall in all things apply to such modified or amended order. If upon review as provided in said <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s21">section 21 of this title</ref> the court shall set aside such modified or amended order, the original order shall not be affected thereby, but it shall be and remain in force and effect as fully and to the same extent as if such supplementary proceedings had not been taken.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77b9f21d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-19/ch592/s2">June 19, 1936, ch. 592, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1527">49 Stat. 1527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77b9f21e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77b9f21f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77b9f220-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing herein contained, referred to in text, probably means nothing contained in <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-19/ch592">act June 19, 1936, ch. 592</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1526">49 Stat. 1526</ref>, popularly known as the Robinson-Patman Antidiscrimination Act and also as the Robinson-Patman Price Discrimination Act, which enacted sections 13a, 13b, and 21a of this title and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s13">section 13 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77b9f221-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77b9f222-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 8 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1264">64 Stat. 1264</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
