<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79e0c9af-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2202"><num value="2202">§ 2202.</num><heading> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is declared to be the purpose of Congress in this chapter to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e0c9b0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2202/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reduce the Nation’s losses caused by fire through better fire prevention and control;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e0c9b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2202/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> supplement existing programs of research, training, and education, and to encourage new and improved programs and activities by State and local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e0c9b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2202/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish the United States Fire Administration and the Fire Research Center within the Department of Commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e0c9b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2202/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> establish an intensified program of research into the treatment of burn and smoke injuries and the rehabilitation of victims of fires within the National Institutes of Health.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id79e0c9b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/498/s3">Pub. L. 93–498, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1536">88 Stat. 1536</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/422/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 95–422, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-05">Oct. 5, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/932">92 Stat. 932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79e0c9b5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79e0c9b6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79e0c9b7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/498">Pub. L. 93–498</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1535">88 Stat. 1535</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79e0c9b8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/422">Pub. L. 95–422</ref> substituted “United States Fire Administration” for “National Fire Prevention and Control Administration”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79e0c9b9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79e0c9ba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79e0c9bb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79e0c9bc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Fire Prevention and Control Administration [now United States Fire Administration] and the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control and the positions of Administrator of the Administration and Superintendent of the Academy were transferred to an independent agency in the Executive Branch, to be known as the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and all functions vested in the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator and Deputy Administrator of the National Fire Prevention and Control Administration, and the Superintendent of the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, with the exception of those functions under sections 2220 and 2221 of this title which remain vested in the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, were transferred to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1978, §§ 201, 301, <date date="1978-06-19">June 19, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 41944, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3788">92 Stat. 3788</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>, effective <date date="1979-04-01">Apr. 1, 1979</date>, pursuant to Ex. Ord. No. 12127, §§ 1–101, 1–103(a), <date date="1979-03-31">Mar. 31, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 19367.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
