<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79e33ace-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214"><num value="2214">§ 2214.</num><heading> Public safety awards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e33acf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established an honorary award for the recognition of outstanding and distinguished service by public safety officers to be known as the Administrator’s Award For Distinguished Public Safety Service (“Administrator’s Award”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e33ad0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Description</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> The Administrator’s Award shall be presented by the Administrator of FEMA or by the Attorney General to public safety officers for distinguished service in the field of public safety.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e33ad1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Award</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Administrator’s Award shall consist of an appropriate citation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e33ad2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of FEMA and the Attorney General are authorized and directed to issue jointly such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79e33ad3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “Public safety officer” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “public safety officer” means a person serving a public agency, with or without compensation, as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e33ad4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a firefighter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e33ad5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a law enforcement officer, including a corrections or court officer; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79e33ad6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2214/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a civil defense officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79e33ad7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/498/s15">Pub. L. 93–498, § 15</ref>, <date date="1974-10-29">Oct. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1544">88 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/241/tII/s202">Pub. L. 98–241, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1984-03-22">Mar. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/96">98 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/tI/s110/a/2/B/iv">Pub. L. 106–503, title I, § 110(a)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, (v), (C), <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2302">114 Stat. 2302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8</ref>, <date date="2001-05-30">May 30, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/22">115 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVIII/s1802/b">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2100">126 Stat. 2100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79e33ad8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79e33ad9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79e33ada-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—<ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1802/b/2">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1802(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Administrator’s Award” for “Director’s Award” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1802/b/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1802(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of FEMA” for “Director” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/1">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (a). Text read as follows: “There are hereby established two classes of honorary awards for the recognition of outstanding and distinguished service by public safety officers—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the President’s Award For Outstanding Public Safety Service (‘President’s Award’); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the Director’s Award For Distinguished Public Safety Service (‘Director’s Award’).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/2">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(2)</ref>, struck out pars. (1) and (2) designations and text of par. (1) which read as follows: “The President’s Award shall be presented by the President of the United States to public safety officers for extraordinary valor in the line of duty or for outstanding contribution to public safety.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/3">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and struck out pars. (1) and (2) designations and text of par. (1), which read as follows: “Each President’s Award shall consist of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) a medal suitably inscribed, bearing such devices and emblems, and struck from such material as the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Director and the Attorney General deems appropriate. The Secretary of the Treasury shall cause the medal to be struck and furnished to the President; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) an appropriate citation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Former subsec. (c) was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/3">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(3)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “The Director and the Attorney General shall advise and assist the President in the selection of individuals to whom the President’s Award shall be tendered and in the course of performing such duties they shall seek and review nominations for such awards which are submitted to them by Federal, State, county, and local government officials. They shall annually transmit to the President the names of those individuals determined by them to merit the award, together with the reasons therefor. Recipients of the President’s Award shall be selected by the President.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/3">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (d) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (d). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) There shall not be presented in any one calendar year in excess of twelve President’s Awards.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) There shall be no limitation on the number of Director’s Awards presented.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/12/s8/3">Pub. L. 107–12, § 8(3)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (e) to (g) as (c) to (e), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/C">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “Director’s” for “Secretary’s” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/B/iv">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, (C), substituted “Director’s” for “Secretary’s” and “Director” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/B/iv">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, substituted “Director” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/C">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “Director’s” for “Secretary’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/B/v">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(B)(v)</ref>, substituted “with the Director” for “with the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/C">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “Director’s” for “Secretary’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/106/503/s110/a/2/B/iv">Pub. L. 106–503, § 110(a)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, substituted “Director” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsecs. (b)(2), (c), (e)(1)(A), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/241">Pub. L. 98–241</ref> struck out “, the Secretary of Defense,” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79e33adb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79e33adc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79e33add-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79e33ade-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of National Fire Prevention and Control Administration [now United States Fire Administration] and National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control generally transferred to Federal Emergency Management Agency. For further details see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2202">section 2202 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id79e33adf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13161. Establishment of the Presidential Medal of Valor for Public Safety Officers</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13161, <date date="2000-06-29">June 29, 2000</date>, 65 F.R. 41543, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The Presidential Medal of Valor for Public Safety Officers (Medal) is established for the purpose of recognizing those public safety officers adjudged to have shown extraordinary valor above and beyond the call of duty in the exercise of their official duties. As used in this section, the term “public safety officer” means a person serving a public agency with or without compensation:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) as a law enforcement officer, including police, correctional, probation, or parole officers;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) as a firefighter or emergency responder; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) who is employed by the Government of the United States, any State of the United States, any officially recognized elective body within a State of the United States, or any Federally recognized tribal organization.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. Eligible recipients generally will be recommended to the President by the Attorney General by April 1 of each year. Pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t36/s136–137">36 U.S.C. 136–137</ref>, the President designates May 15 of each year as “Peace Officers Memorial Day” and the week in which it falls as “Police Week.” Presentation of the Medal shall occur at an appropriate time during the commemoration of Police Week, as far as is practicable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The President may select for the Medal up to ten persons annually from among those persons recommended to the President by the Attorney General. In submitting recommendations to the President, the Attorney General may consult with experts representing all segments of the public safety sector, including representatives from law enforcement, firefighters, and emergency services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. Those chosen for recognition shall receive a medal and a certificate, the designs of which shall be submitted by the Attorney General for the President’s approval no later than <date date="2000-12-01">December 1, 2000</date>. The medal and certificate shall be prepared by the Department of Justice.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. The Medal may be given posthumously.</p>
<signature>
<name>William J. Clinton.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
