<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79ea4002-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a"><num value="2229a">§ 2229a.</num><heading> Staffing for adequate fire and emergency response</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4003-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Expanded authority to make grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4004-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Hiring grants</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4005-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator of FEMA shall make grants directly to career fire departments, combination fire departments, and volunteer fire departments, in consultation with the chief executive of the State in which the applicant is located, for the purpose of increasing the number of firefighters to help communities meet industry minimum standards and attain 24-hour staffing to provide adequate protection from fire and fire-related hazards, and to fulfill traditional missions of fire departments that antedate the creation of the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4006-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Grants made under this paragraph shall be for 3 years and be used for programs to hire new, additional firefighters or to change the status of part-time or paid-on-call (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2229/a">section 2229(a) of this title</ref>) firefighters to full-time firefighters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4007-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In awarding grants under this subsection, the Administrator of FEMA may give preferential consideration to applications that involve a non-Federal contribution exceeding the minimums under subparagraph (E).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4008-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Administrator of FEMA may provide technical assistance to States, units of local government, Indian tribal governments, and to other public entities, in furtherance of the purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4009-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The portion of the costs of hiring firefighters provided by a grant under this paragraph may not exceed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea400a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 75 percent in the first year of the grant;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea400b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 75 percent in the second year of the grant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea400c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> 35 percent in the third year of the grant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea400d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any firefighter hired with funds provided under this subsection shall not be discriminated against for, or be prohibited from, engaging in volunteer activities in another jurisdiction during off-duty hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea400e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> All grants made pursuant to this subsection shall be awarded on a competitive basis through a neutral peer review process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea400f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> At the beginning of the fiscal year, the Administrator of FEMA shall set aside 10 percent of the funds appropriated for carrying out this paragraph for departments with majority volunteer or all volunteer personnel. After awards have been made, if less than 10 percent of the funds appropriated for carrying out this paragraph are not awarded to departments with majority volunteer or all volunteer personnel, the Administrator of FEMA shall transfer from funds appropriated for carrying out this paragraph to funds available for carrying out paragraph (2) an amount equal to the difference between the amount that is provided to such fire departments and 10 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4010-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Recruitment and retention grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to any amounts transferred under paragraph (1)(H), the Administrator of FEMA shall direct at least 10 percent of the total amount of funds appropriated pursuant to this section annually to a competitive grant program for the recruitment and retention of volunteer firefighters who are involved with or trained in the operations of firefighting and emergency response. Eligible entities shall include volunteer or combination fire departments, and national, State, local, or tribal organizations that represent the interests of volunteer firefighters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4011-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea4012-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No grant may be made under this section unless an application has been submitted to, and approved by, the Administrator of FEMA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea4013-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An application for a grant under this section shall be submitted in such form, and contain such information, as the Administrator of FEMA may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea4014-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> At a minimum, each application for a grant under this section shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4015-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> explain the applicant’s inability to address the need without Federal assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4016-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a grant under subsection (a)(1), explain how the applicant plans to meet the requirements of subsection (a)(1)(F);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4017-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> specify long-term plans for retaining firefighters following the conclusion of Federal support provided under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4018-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> provide assurances that the applicant will, to the extent practicable, seek, recruit, and hire members of racial and ethnic minority groups and women in order to increase their ranks within firefighting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4019-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea401a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Funds made available under this section to fire departments for salaries and benefits to hire new, additional firefighters shall not be used to supplant State or local funds, or, in the case of Indian tribal governments, funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, but shall be used to increase the amount of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds received under this section, be made available from State or local sources, or in the case of Indian tribal governments, from funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea401b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No grant shall be awarded pursuant to this section to a municipality or other recipient whose annual budget at the time of the application for fire-related programs and emergency response has been reduced below 80 percent of the average funding level in the 3 years prior to the date of the application for the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea401c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Funds appropriated by the Congress for the activities of any agency of an Indian tribal government or the Bureau of Indian Affairs performing firefighting functions on any Indian lands may be used to provide the non-Federal share of the cost of programs or projects funded under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea401d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The amount of funding provided under this section to a recipient fire department for hiring a firefighter in any fiscal year may not exceed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea401e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the first year of the grant, 75 percent of the usual annual cost of a first-year firefighter in that department at the time the grant application was submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea401f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the second year of the grant, 75 percent of the usual annual cost of a first-year firefighter in that department at the time the grant application was submitted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4020-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the third year of the grant, 35 percent of the usual annual cost of a first-year firefighter in that department at the time the grant application was submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4021-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4022-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In a case of demonstrated economic hardship, the Administrator of FEMA may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4023-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> waive the requirements of subsection (c)(1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4024-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> waive or reduce the requirements in subsection (a)(1)(E), (c)(2), or (c)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4025-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4026-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator of FEMA shall establish and publish guidelines for determining what constitutes economic hardship for purposes of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4027-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In developing guidelines under subparagraph (A), the Administrator of FEMA shall consult with individuals who are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea4028-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> recognized for expertise in firefighting, emergency medical services provided by fire services, or the economic affairs of State and local governments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea4029-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> members of national fire service organizations or national organizations representing the interests of State and local governments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea402a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In developing guidelines under subparagraph (A), the Administrator of FEMA shall consider, with respect to relevant communities, the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea402b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Changes in rates of unemployment from previous years.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea402c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Whether the rates of unemployment of the relevant communities are currently and have consistently exceeded <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002451">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002451"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “are currently exceeding and have consistently exceeded”.</note> the annual national average rates of unemployment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea402d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Changes in percentages of individuals eligible to receive food stamps from previous years.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id79ea402e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/d/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Such other factors as the Administrator of FEMA considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea402f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance evaluation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4030-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator of FEMA shall establish a performance assessment system, including quantifiable performance metrics, to evaluate the extent to which grants awarded under this section are furthering the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4031-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submittal of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator of FEMA may require a grant recipient to submit any information the Administrator of FEMA considers reasonably necessary to evaluate the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4032-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>, the Administrator of FEMA shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the experience with, and effectiveness of, such grants in meeting the objectives of this section. The report may include any recommendations the Administrator of FEMA may have for amendments to this section and related provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4033-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation or suspension of funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Administrator of FEMA determines that a grant recipient under this section is not in substantial compliance with the terms and requirements of an approved grant application submitted under this section, the Administrator of FEMA may revoke or suspend funding of that grant, in whole or in part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4034-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to documents</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea4035-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator of FEMA shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any pertinent books, documents, papers, or records of a grant recipient under this section and to the pertinent books, documents, papers, or records of State and local governments, persons, businesses, and other entities that are involved in programs, projects, or activities for which assistance is provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ea4036-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to audits and examinations conducted by the Comptroller General of the United States or by an authorized representative of the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4037-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4038-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “firefighter” has the meaning given the term “employee in fire protection activities” under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s203/y">section 203(y) of title 29</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002452">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002452"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ea4039-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The terms “Administrator of FEMA”, “career fire department”, “combination fire department”, and “volunteer fire department” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2229/a">section 2229(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea403a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea403b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of carrying out this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea403c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2004;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea403d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> $1,030,000,000 for fiscal year 2005;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea403e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> $1,061,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea403f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> $1,093,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4040-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> $1,126,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4041-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> $1,159,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4042-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> $1,194,000,000 for fiscal year 2010; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79ea4043-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> $750,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4044-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Administrator of FEMA may use not more than 5 percent of such amounts to cover salaries and expenses and other administrative costs incurred by the Administrator of FEMA to make grants and provide assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4045-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressionally directed spending</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Consistent with the requirement in subsection (a) that grants under this section be awarded on a competitive basis, none of the funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection may be used for any congressionally direct spending item (as defined under the rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ea4046-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2229a/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset of authorities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority to award assistance and grants under this section shall expire on <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79ea4047-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/498/s34">Pub. L. 93–498, § 34</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tX/s1057">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1057</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1616">117 Stat. 1616</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVIII/s1804">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVIII, § 1804</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2111">126 Stat. 2111</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1091/b/9">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1091(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/876">127 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tXIV/s14001/c">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title XIV, § 14001(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1288">130 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-01-03">Jan. 3, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2240">131 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/dA/s4">Pub. L. 118–67, div. A, § 4</ref>, <date date="2024-07-09">July 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1447">138 Stat. 1447</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79ea4048-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79ea4049-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79ea404a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s203/y">Section 203(y) of title 29</ref>, referred to in subsec. (i)(1), was in the original “section 3(y) of the Fair Labor Standards Act” and has been translated as reading “section 3(y) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id79ea404b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/498/s34">section 34 of Pub. L. 93–498</ref> was renumbered section 36 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2231">section 2231 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79ea404c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (j)(1)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 118–67, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028.” for “fiscal year 2013; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 118–67, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (3), struck out subpar. (I) which read as follows: “for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023, an amount equal to the amount authorized for the previous fiscal year increased by the percentage by which—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the Consumer Price Index (all items, United States city average) for the previous fiscal year, exceeds</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the Consumer Price Index for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year described in subparagraph (A).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s4/a">Pub. L. 118–67, § 4(a)</ref>, substituted “2030” for “2024”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/f">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(f)</ref>, substituted “firefighters or to change the status of part-time or paid-on-call (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2229/a">section 2229(a) of this title</ref>) firefighters to full-time firefighters” for “firefighters and to provide specialized training to paramedics, emergency medical services workers, and other first responders to recognize individuals who have mental illness and how to properly intervene with individuals with mental illness, including strategies for verbal de-escalation of crises”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/c">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(c)</ref>, substituted “of subsection (a)(1)(F)” for “of subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) and (F)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/d">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(d)</ref>, substituted “prior to the date of the application for the grant” for “prior to <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/e">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(e)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a)(1)(E), (c)(2), or (c)(4)” for “subsection (a)(1)(E) or subsection (c)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/b">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(b)</ref>, substituted “2023” for “2017” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/115/98/s4/a">Pub. L. 115–98, § 4(a)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>” for “the date that is 5 years after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255">Pub. L. 114–255</ref> inserted before period at end “and to provide specialized training to paramedics, emergency medical services workers, and other first responders to recognize individuals who have mental illness and how to properly intervene with individuals with mental illness, including strategies for verbal de-escalation of crises”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—<ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/j">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(j)</ref>, substituted “Staffing for adequate fire and emergency response” for “Expansion of pre-<date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, fire grant program” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/i">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(i)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1091/b/9/B">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1091(b)(9)(B)</ref>, substituted “Administrator of FEMA” for “Administrator” wherever appearing, except in those places in which “Administrator of FEMA” already appeared.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/g/2">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “career fire departments, combination fire departments, and volunteer fire departments” for “career, volunteer, and combination fire departments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/a/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(a)(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B)(i) Grants made under this paragraph shall be for 4 years and be used for programs to hire new, additional firefighters.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(ii) Grantees are required to commit to retaining for at least 1 year beyond the termination of their grants those firefighters hired under this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/a/2">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(a)(2)</ref>, amended subpar. (E) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (E) read as follows: “The portion of the costs of hiring firefighters provided by a grant under this paragraph may not exceed—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) 90 percent in the first year of the grant;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) 80 percent in the second year of the grant;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) 50 percent in the third year of the grant; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iv) 30 percent in the fourth year of the grant.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/b">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(b)</ref>, substituted “national, State, local, or tribal organizations” for “organizations on a local or statewide basis”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/c">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(c)</ref>, amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4)(A) Total funding provided under this section over 4 years for hiring a firefighter may not exceed $100,000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) The $100,000 cap shall be adjusted annually for inflation beginning in fiscal year 2005.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/2">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/e">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(e)</ref>, added par. (1) and designated existing provisions as par. (2) and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/f">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(f)</ref>, substituted “Report” for “Sunset and reports” in heading and “Not later than <date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>, the Administrator of FEMA shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Science and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on” for “The authority under this section to make grants shall lapse at the conclusion of 10 years from <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>. Not later than 6 years after <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>, the Administrator shall submit a report to Congress concerning” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (g) and (h), respectively. Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/g/1/A">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(g)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “In this section:” for “In this section, the term—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/g/1/B">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(g)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “The term” before “ ‘firefighter’ has” and substituted period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/g/1/C">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(g)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “ ‘Indian tribe’ means a tribe, band, pueblo, nation, or other organized group or community of Indians, including an Alaska Native village (as defined in or established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.)), that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/h/2">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(h)(2)</ref>, (3), designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, redesignated former pars. (1) to (9) as subpars. (A) to (I), respectively, of par. (1), redesignated subpars. (A) and (B) of former par. (9) as cls. (i) and (ii) of subpar. (I), and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/d/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/h/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(h)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1091/b/9/A">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1091(b)(9)(A)</ref>, added pars. (8) and (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1804/k">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1804(k)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79ea404d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id79ea404e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1091/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1091(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/876">127 Stat. 876</ref>, provided in part that the amendment made by section 1091(b)(9) is effective as of <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
