<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78897728-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s236"><num value="236">§ 236.</num><heading> Variations from standard permitted; prosecutions; law not applicable to certain barrels</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Reasonable variations shall be permitted and tolerance shall be established by rules and regulations made by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and approved by the Secretary of Commerce. Prosecutions for offenses under this section or sections 234 or 235 of this title may be begun upon complaint of local sealers of weights and measures or other officers of the several States and Territories appointed to enforce the laws of the said States or Territories, respectively, relating to weights and measures: <i>Provided, however</i>, That nothing in this section or sections 234 and 235 of this title shall apply to barrels used in packing or shipping commodities sold exclusively by weight or numerical count.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78897729-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1915-03-04/ch158/s3">Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 158, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/1187">38 Stat. 1187</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7889772a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7889772b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7889772c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7889772d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7889772e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all other officers of Department of Commerce and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department, with a few exceptions, transferred to Secretary of Commerce, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 5 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
