<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79ecb16e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412"><num value="2412">§ 2412.</num><heading> Board of Directors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ecb16f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Center shall have a Board of Directors, to be comprised of not more than twenty-seven members, as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb170-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a Chairman, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb171-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary of the Treasury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb172-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb173-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb174-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb175-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the Executive Director of the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb176-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> not less than five members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among qualified private individuals in manufacturing and service industries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb177-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> not less than five members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among qualified private individuals from labor organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb178-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> not less than two members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among qualified individuals in State or local governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb179-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> not less than one member who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among the general public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb17a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> not less than one member who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among qualified individuals associated with leading institutions of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ecb17b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> such other qualified members from the public or private sectors whom the President may deem appropriate who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">When unable to attend a meeting of the Board, a member appointed under clauses (2), (3), (4), and (5) shall appoint an appropriate alternate from such member’s Department or agency to represent such member at that meeting.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ecb17c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Term</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb17d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The members of the Board appointed under clauses (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), and any private sector members appointed pursuant to clause (12) of subsection (a) shall be appointed for a four-year term coterminous with the term of the President. Members other than members appointed under such clauses, with the exception of the Chairman, shall serve as long as such member is head of the department or agency represented on the Board. No person shall serve as an acting or temporary member in positions requiring Senate confirmation including that of Chairman, for a period in excess of three months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb17e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The President shall appoint a Chairman for a term of four years coterminous with the term of the President. In appointing a Chairman, the President may appoint an individual who is an officer of the United States. If that officer has been appointed to his current position, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, or if such individual is the Vice President of the United States, such individual may be appointed chairman by the President without the requirement of confirmation by the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ecb17f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ecb180-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation, travel, subsistence, and other expense items</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb181-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each member of the Board appointed under clauses (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), and any private sector members appointed pursuant to clause (12) of subsection (a) may be compensated at the daily rate provided for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, including traveltime, for each day such member is engaged in the performance of his duties as a member of the Board and shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in carrying out the functions of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb182-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Other members of the Board, with the exception of the Chairman, and the Executive Director of the Center shall serve without additional compensation but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in carrying out the functions of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb183-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Chairman shall be compensated as set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, except if the Chairman holds some other position in the Federal Government such individual shall be compensated as set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79ecb184-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive Committee of the Board</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb185-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Chairman shall appoint an Executive Committee of the Board, not to exceed seven members, including the Executive Director of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79ecb186-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2412/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Executive Committee of the Board shall meet at the call of the Chairman, but in no case less frequently than once every ninety days.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79ecb187-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/136/tII/s202">Pub. L. 94–136, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/735">89 Stat. 735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79ecb188-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79ecb189-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79ecb18a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
