<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79ef21ae-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415"><num value="2415">§ 2415.</num><heading> Powers of the Center</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out its functions, the Center is authorized—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ef21af-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to enter into contracts or other funding arrangements, or modifications thereof, in order to carry out the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ef21b0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to organize and conduct, directly by contract or other funding arrangements with other public agencies or private organizations, conferences, meetings, seminars, workshops, or other forums for the presentation and dissemination of relevant information generated or collected pursuant to the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ef21b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to make such studies and recommendations to the President and to Congress as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ef21b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to implement a program and secure necessary facilities for the collection, collation, analysis, and interpretation of data and information as required in order to carry out the public information functions under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79ef21b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2415/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to undertake such other studies, reviews, activities, and to make such recommendations and reports as may be required to carry out the functions of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id79ef21b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/136/tII/s205">Pub. L. 94–136, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/739">89 Stat. 739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
