<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79f16b95-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512"><num value="2512">§ 2512.</num><heading> Studies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f16b96-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Bias of surface transportation systems; submission of report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study to determine the existence of any tax, regulatory, traffic, urban design, rural electrical, or other institutional factor which tends or may tend to bias surface transportation systems toward vehicles of particular characteristics. The Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings and conclusions of such study, within 1 year after <date date="1976-09-17">September 17, 1976</date>. The report shall include any legislative or other recommendations of the Secretary of Energy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f16b97-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Material demand and pollution effect; impact statement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a continuing assessment of the long-range material demand and pollution effects which may result from or in connection with the electrification of urban traffic. Such assessment shall include a statement of the Secretary of Energy’s current findings in each report submitted under section 2513 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002454">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002454"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title. Any environmental impact statement which may be filed under a Federal law with respect to research, development, or demonstration activities under this chapter shall include reference to the matters which are subject to assessment under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f16b98-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Incentives to encourage utilization; inclusion of electric vehicles in calculation of average fuel economy; evaluation program; annual report; final report and recommendations to Congress on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date></heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall perform, or cause to be performed, studies and research on incentives to promote broader utilization and consumer acceptance of electric and hybrid vehicle technologies. A description and a statement of the findings of such studies and research activities shall be included in each report submitted under section 2513 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16b99-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency is authorized and directed to conduct a seven-year evaluation program of the inclusion of electric vehicles, as defined in section 512(b)(2) <sup>1</sup> of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2012/b/2">15 U.S.C. 2012(b)(2)</ref>), in the calculation of average fuel economy pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32904/a/1">section 32904(a)(1) of title 49</ref> to determine the value and implications of such inclusion as an incentive for the early initiation of industrial engineering development and initial commercialization of electric vehicles in the United States. The evaluation program shall be conducted in parallel with the research and development activities of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2505">section 2505 of this title</ref> and demonstration activities of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2506">section 2506 of this title</ref> to provide all necessary information no later than <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, for the private sector and Federal, State and local officials to make required decisions for the full commercialization of electric vehicles in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16b9a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Transportation, shall implement immediately the evaluation program by promulgating, within sixty days of <date date="1980-01-07">January 7, 1980</date>, regulations to include electric vehicles in average fuel economy calculations under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32904/a/1">section 32904(a)(1) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16b9b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall include a full discussion of this evaluation program in the annual report required by section 2513 <sup>1</sup> of this title in each year after promulgation of the regulations under paragraph (2). The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall submit to the Congress on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, a final report on the results of the evaluation program and any recommendations regarding the continued inclusion of electric vehicles in the average fuel economy calculations under part C of subtitle VI of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f16b9c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Safety standards and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall conduct a study of the current and future applicability of safety standards and regulations to electric and hybrid vehicles. The Secretary of Transportation shall report the results of such study to the Secretary of Energy and the Congress within 1 year after <date date="1976-09-17">September 17, 1976</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79f16b9d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regenerative braking systems</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study to determine the overall effectiveness and feasibility of including regenerative braking systems on electric and other automobiles in order to recover energy. In such study the Secretary of Energy shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16b9e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> review the history of regenerative braking devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16b9f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> describe relevant experimental test data and theoretical calculations with respect to such devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16ba0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assess the net energy impacts and cost effectiveness of such devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16ba1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> examine present patents and patent policy regarding such devices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79f16ba2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2512/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> determine whether regenerative braking should be used on some of the advanced electric or hybrid vehicles to be purchased or leased pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2506/c/2">section 2506(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings and conclusions of such study within 1 year after <date date="1976-09-17">September 17, 1976</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79f16ba3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/413/s13">Pub. L. 94–413, § 13</ref>, <date date="1976-09-17">Sept. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1269">90 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/185/s18">Pub. L. 96–185, § 18</ref>, <date date="1980-01-07">Jan. 7, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1336">93 Stat. 1336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79f16ba4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79f16ba5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79f16ba6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2513">Section 2513 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (c), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1051">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1051</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/717">109 Stat. 717</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 512(b)(2) of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2012/b/2">15 U.S.C. 2012(b)(2)</ref>), referred to in subsec. (c)(1), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s7/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1379">108 Stat. 1379</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitles II, III, and V to X of Title 49, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79f16ba7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c), “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32904/a/1">section 32904(a)(1) of title 49</ref>” substituted for “section 503(a)(1) and (2) of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2003/a/1">15 U.S.C. 2003(a)(1)</ref> and (2))” and “section 503(a)(1) and (2) of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act”, and “part C of subtitle VI of title 49” substituted for “the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1901">15 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s6/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1378">108 Stat. 1378</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitles II, III, and V to X of Title 49, Transportation, and on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/103/429/s10/b">Pub. L. 103–429, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4391">108 Stat. 4391</ref>, section 6(43)(B) of which enacted section 32918 as part of part C of subtitle VI of Title 49.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1980-01-07">January 7, 1980</date>, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), was in the original “enactment of the Act” which has been translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/96/185">Pub. L. 96–185</ref> as the probable intent of Congress in view of the fact that <ref href="/us/pl/96/185/s18">section 18 of Pub. L. 96–185</ref> enacted subsec. (c)(1) to (3) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A part of par. (2) of section 2512(c) of the Electric and Hybrid Vehicle Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1976, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/96/185">Pub. L. 96–185</ref>, has not been included in the text of subsec. (c)(2) of this section. The omitted provision consists of directory language for an amendment of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2003">section 2003 of this title</ref> and the indicated amendment has been executed to the text of that section as directed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “Secretary of Transportation” substituted for “Secretary” in two places for clarity, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2502">section 2502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79f16ba8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c)(1) to (3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/185">Pub. L. 96–185</ref> added pars. (1) to (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79f16ba9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79f16baa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted for “Administrator” in subsecs. (a), (b), (d), and (e) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/s301/a">section 301(a) of Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, see Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2502">section 2502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id79f16bab-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Electric Vehicles</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s7">Pub. L. 100–494, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2452">102 Stat. 2452</ref>, directed Secretary of Transportation to study whether regulations should be amended or promulgated to stimulate production and introduction of electric and solar-powered vehicles into commerce and to report to Congress on results of study, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s7/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1379">108 Stat. 1379</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
