<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77bc6339-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s26"><num value="26">§ 26.</num><heading> Injunctive relief for private parties; exception; costs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person, firm, corporation, or association shall be entitled to sue for and have injunctive relief, in any court of the United States having jurisdiction over the parties, against threatened loss or damage by a violation of the antitrust laws, including sections 13, 14, 18, and 19 of this title, when and under the same conditions and principles as injunctive relief against threatened conduct that will cause loss or damage is granted by courts of equity, under the rules governing such proceedings, and upon the execution of proper bond against damages for an injunction improvidently granted and a showing that the danger of irreparable loss or damage is immediate, a preliminary injunction may issue: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein contained shall be construed to entitle any person, firm, corporation, or association, except the United States, to bring suit for injunctive relief against any common carrier subject to the jurisdiction of the Surface Transportation Board under subtitle IV of title 49. In any action under this section in which the plaintiff substantially prevails, the court shall award the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, to such plaintiff.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id77bc633a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323/s16">Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/737">38 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/435/tIII/s302/3">Pub. L. 94–435, title III, § 302(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1396">90 Stat. 1396</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tIII/s318/3">Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 318(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/949">109 Stat. 949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77bc633b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77bc633c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77bc633d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The antitrust laws, referred to in text, are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77bc633e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref> substituted “for injunctive relief against any common carrier subject to the jurisdiction of the Surface Transportation Board under subtitle IV of title 49” for “in equity for injunctive relief against any common carrier subject to the provisions of the Act to regulate commerce, approved February fourth, eighteen hundred and eighty-seven, in respect of any matter subject to the regulation, supervision, or other jurisdiction of the Interstate Commerce Commission.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/435">Pub. L. 94–435</ref> inserted provision authorizing court to award costs, including attorneys’ fees, to a successful plaintiff.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77bc633f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77bc6340-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref> effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
