<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79fd7975-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616"><num value="2616">§ 2616.</num><heading> Specific enforcement and seizure</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79fd7976-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79fd7977-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over civil actions to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd7978-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> restrain any violation of section 2614 or 2689 of this title,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd7979-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> restrain any person from taking any action prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, 2605 of this title, or subchapter IV, or by a rule or order under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, 2605 of this title, or subchapter IV,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd797a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> compel the taking of any action required by or under this chapter, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd797b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> direct any manufacturer or processor of a chemical substance, mixture, or product subject to subchapter IV manufactured or processed in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, 2605 of this title, or subchapter IV, or a rule or order under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, 2605 of this title, or subchapter IV, and distributed in commerce, (i) to give notice of such fact to distributors in commerce of such substance, mixture, or product and, to the extent reasonably ascertainable, to other persons in possession of such substance, mixture, or product or exposed to such substance, mixture, or product, (ii) to give public notice of such risk of injury, and (iii) to either replace or repurchase such substance, mixture, or product, whichever the person to which the requirement is directed elects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79fd797c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A civil action described in paragraph (1) may be brought—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd797d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a civil action described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph, in the United States district court for the judicial district wherein any act, omission, or transaction constituting a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2614">section 2614 of this title</ref> occurred or wherein the defendant is found or transacts business, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79fd797e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of any other civil action described in such paragraph, in the United States district court for the judicial district wherein the defendant is found or transacts business.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In any such civil action process may be served on a defendant in any judicial district in which a defendant resides or may be found. Subpoenas requiring attendance of witnesses in any such action may be served in any judicial district.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79fd797f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2616/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Seizure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any chemical substance, mixture, or product subject to subchapter IV which was manufactured, processed, or distributed in commerce in violation of this chapter or any rule promulgated or order issued under this chapter or any article containing such a substance or mixture shall be liable to be proceeded against, by process of libel, for the seizure and condemnation of such substance, mixture, product, or article, in any district court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which such substance, mixture, product, or article is found. Such proceedings shall conform as nearly as possible to proceedings in rem in admiralty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79fd7980-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/469/tI/s17">Pub. L. 94–469, title I, § 17</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2037">90 Stat. 2037</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/99/519/s3/c/1">Pub. L. 99–519, § 3(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2989">100 Stat. 2989</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tX/s1021/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, title X, § 1021(b)(6)</ref>, (7), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3923">106 Stat. 3923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79fd7981-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79fd7982-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79fd7983-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1021/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 1021(b)(6)</ref>, which directed that subsec. (a) be amended “to read as follows” and then set out the subsec. (a) designation and heading, followed by the par. (1) designation and text, without any restatement of par. (2), was executed as a general amendment of par. (1) only, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over civil actions to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) restrain any violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2614">section 2614 of this title</ref>,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) restrain any person from taking any action prohibited by section 2604 or 2605 of this title or by a rule or order under section 2604 or 2605 of this title,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) compel the taking of any action required by or under this chapter, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) direct any manufacturer or processor of a chemical substance or mixture manufactured or processed in violation of section 2604 or 2605 of this title or a rule or order under section 2604 or 2605 of this title and distributed in commerce, (i) to give notice of such fact to distributors in commerce of such substance or mixture and, to the extent reasonably ascertainable, to other persons in possession of such substance or mixture or exposed to such substance or mixture, (ii) to give public notice of such risk of injury, and (iii) to either replace or repurchase such substance or mixture, whichever the person to which the requirement is directed elects.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s1021/b/7">Pub. L. 102–550, § 1021(b)(7)</ref>, in first sentence substituted “substance, mixture, or product subject to subchapter IV” for “substance or mixture” and inserted “product,” before “or article” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id79fd7984-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id79fd7985-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/469/s31">section 31 of Pub. L. 94–469</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">section 2601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
