<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id788bc179-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s263"><num value="263">§ 263.</num><heading> Designation of zone standard times</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The standard time of the first zone shall be known and designated as Atlantic standard time; that of the second zone shall be known and designated as eastern standard time; that of the third zone shall be known and designated as central standard time; that of the fourth zone shall be known and designated as mountain standard time; that of the fifth zone shall be known and designated as Pacific standard time; that of the sixth zone shall be known and designated as Alaska standard time; that of the seventh zone shall be known and designated as Hawaii-Aleutian standard time; that of the eighth zone shall be known and designated as Samoa standard time; and that of the ninth zone shall be known as Chamorro standard time.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id788bc17a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1918-03-19/ch24/s4">Mar. 19, 1918, ch. 24, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/451">40 Stat. 451</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/387/s4/c">Pub. L. 89–387, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-04-13">Apr. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/108">80 Stat. 108</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tII/s2003/a">Pub. L. 98–181, title II, § 2003(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1297">97 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/564/s1/b">Pub. L. 106–564, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-23">Dec. 23, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2811">114 Stat. 2811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id788bc17b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id788bc17c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id788bc17d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/564">Pub. L. 106–564</ref> struck out “and” before “that of the eighth” and inserted before period at end “; and that of the ninth zone shall be known as Chamorro standard time”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “Alaska” for “Yukon”, “Hawaii-Aleutian” for “Alaska-Hawaii”, and “Samoa” for “Bering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/387">Pub. L. 89–387</ref> added Atlantic standard time as first zone designation; redesignated as eastern standard time, central standard time, mountain standard time and Pacific standard time for second through fifth zones former designation of United States standard eastern time, United States standard central time, United States standard mountain time and United States standard Pacific time for former zones one through four; added Yukon standard time as sixth zone designation; redesignated as Alaska-Hawaii standard time for seventh zone former designation of United States standard Alaska time for fifth zone; and added Bering standard time as eighth zone designation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id788bc17e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id788bc17f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conforming Changes in Time Zone Designations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tII/s2003/b">Pub. L. 98–181, title II, § 2003(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1297">97 Stat. 1297</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/181/tII/s2003/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Any reference to Yukon standard time in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be held and considered to be a reference to Alaska standard time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any reference to Alaska-Hawaii standard time in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be held and considered to be a reference to Hawaii-Aleutian standard time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any reference to Bering standard time in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be held and considered to be a reference to Samoa standard time.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
