<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id788bc188-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s265"><num value="265">§ 265.</num><heading> Transfer of certain territory to standard central-time zone</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Panhandle and Plains sections of Texas and Oklahoma are transferred to and placed within the United States standard central-time zone.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation is authorized and directed to issue an order placing the western boundary line of the United States standard central-time zone insofar as the same affect Texas and Oklahoma as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning at a point where such western boundary time zone line crosses the State boundary line between Kansas and Oklahoma; thence westerly along said State boundary line to the northwest corner of the State of Oklahoma; thence in a southerly direction along the west State boundary line of Oklahoma and the west State boundary line of Texas to the southeastern corner of the State of New Mexico; thence in a westerly direction along the State boundary line between the States of Texas and New Mexico to the Rio Grande River; thence down the Rio Grande River as the boundary line between the United States and Mexico: <i>Provided</i>, That the Chicago, Rock Island and Gulf Railway Company and the Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway Company may use Tucumcari, New Mexico, as the point at which they change from central to mountain time and vice versa; the Colorado Southern and Fort Worth and Denver City Railway Companies may use Sixela, New Mexico, as such changing point; the Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company and other branches of the Santa Fe system may use Clovis, New Mexico, as such changing point, and those railways running into or through El Paso may use El Paso as such point: <i>Provided further</i>, That this section shall not, except as herein provided, interfere with the adjustment of time zones as established by the Secretary of Transportation.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id788bc189-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1921-03-04/ch173/s1">Mar. 4, 1921, ch. 173, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1446">41 Stat. 1446</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/449/s2/c">Pub. L. 97–449, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2439">96 Stat. 2439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id788bc18a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id788bc18b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id788bc18c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/449">Pub. L. 97–449</ref> substituted “Secretary of Transportation” for “Interstate Commerce Commission”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id788bc18d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id788bc18e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2 of act <date date="1921-03-04">Mar. 4, 1921</date>, repealed all conflicting laws and parts of laws.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id788bc18f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of El Paso and Hudspeth Counties, Texas, to Mountain Standard Time Zone</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/228">Pub. L. 91–228</ref>, <date date="1970-04-10">Apr. 10, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/119">84 Stat. 119</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/228">“That, notwithstanding the first section of the Act of <date date="1921-03-04">March 4, 1921</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s265">15 U.S.C. 265</ref>), the Secretary of Transportation may, upon the written request of the County Commissioners Court of El Paso County, Texas, change the boundary line between the central standard time zone and the mountain standard time zone, so as to place El Paso County in the mountain standard time zone, in the manner prescribed in <ref href="/us/act/1918-03-19/s1">section 1 of the Act of March 19, 1918</ref>, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s261">15 U.S.C. 261</ref>), and <ref href="/us/act/1966-04-13/s5">section 5 of the Act of April 13, 1966</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s266">15 U.S.C. 266</ref>). In the same manner, the Secretary of Transportation may also place Hudspeth County, Texas, in the mountain standard time zone, if the Hudspeth County Commissioners Court so requests in writing and if El Paso County is to be placed in that time zone.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
