<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id788e321d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s272a"><num value="272a">§ 272a.</num><heading> Technology services</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to such other technology services and technology extension activities which may be mandated or authorized by law, and in order to help improve the use of technology by small and medium-sized industrial firms within the United States, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, as appropriate, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id788e321e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s272a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> work directly with States, local governments, and other appropriate organizations to provide for extended distribution of Standard Reference Materials, Standard Reference Data, calibrations, and related technical services and to help transfer other expertise and technology to the States and to small businesses and other businesses within the States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id788e321f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s272a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> evaluate those inventions from small businesses or individuals which have a significant potential for improving competitiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id788e3220-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s272a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide support for workshops on technical and entrepreneurial topics and share information developed through the Malcolm Baldrige Quality Award Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id788e3221-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s272a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> work with other Federal agencies to provide technical and related assistance to the States and businesses within the States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id788e3222-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/519/tI/s109">Pub. L. 100–519, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2591">102 Stat. 2591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id788e3223-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id788e3224-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id788e3225-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1989, and not as part of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
