<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a0e1c60-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841"><num value="2841">§ 2841.</num><heading> Study by Secretary of Energy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a0e1c61-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with Chairman of Federal Trade Commission, Attorney General, and other agencies deemed appropriate by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission and the Attorney General and other agencies as the Secretary deems appropriate, shall conduct a study of the extent to which producers, refiners, and other suppliers of motor fuel subsidize the sale of such motor fuel at retail or wholesale with profits obtained from other operations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a0e1c62-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such study shall examine—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a0e1c63-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the role of vertically integrated operations in facilitating subsidization of sales of motor fuel at wholesale or retail;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a0e1c64-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the extent to which such subsidization is predatory and presents a threat to competition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a0e1c65-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the profitability of various segments of the petroleum industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a0e1c66-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the impact of prohibiting such subsidization on the competitive viability of various segments of the petroleum industry, on prices of motor fuel to consumers and on the health and structure of the petroleum industry as a whole; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a0e1c67-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a0e1c68-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to interested parties and opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conducting the study required by this section, the Secretary shall give appropriate notice and afford interested persons an opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments concerning such study.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a0e1c69-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress; contents and time for submission; Presidential promulgation of rules establishing interim measures; submission date and duration of interim measures; Congressional approval of interim measures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a0e1c6a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall report the results of the study required by this section, together with such recommendations for legislative action and such statistical evidence as he deems appropriate to the Congress on or before the expiration of the eighteenth month after <date date="1978-06-19">June 19, 1978</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a0e1c6b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the President determines that interim measures are necessary and appropriate to maintain the competitive viability of the marketing sector of the petroleum industry during Congressional consideration of the recommendations contained in the report submitted under paragraph (1), he shall prescribe, by rule, in accordance with the procedures set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6393/a">section 6393(a) of title 42</ref> such interim measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a0e1c6c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No interim measure proposed by the President under this section may be submitted after <date date="1980-01-01">January 1, 1980</date>, and the effect of such measure if approved by the Congress under paragraph (4) may not extend beyond 18 months after such Congressional approval.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a0e1c6d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Such interim measure shall not take effect unless approved by both Houses of Congress as if it were a contingency plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6422">section 6422 of title 42</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That the 60-day period referred to in such section shall be extended to 90 days for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a0e1c6e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2841/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a0e1c6f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/297/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 95–297, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1978-06-19">June 19, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/337">92 Stat. 337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
