<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77bc637b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s29"><num value="29">§ 29.</num><heading> Appeals</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77bc637c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s29/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Court of appeals; review by Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise expressly provided by this section, in every civil action brought in any district court of the United States under the Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies”, approved <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, or any other Acts having like purpose that have been or hereafter may be enacted, in which the United States is the complainant and equitable relief is sought, any appeal from a final judgement entered in any such action shall be taken to the court of appeals pursuant to sections 1291 and 2107 of title 28. Any appeal from an interlocutory order entered in any such action shall be taken to the court of appeals pursuant to sections 1292(a)(1) and 2107 of title 28 but not otherwise. Any judgment entered by the court of appeals in any such action shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court upon a writ of certiorari as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254/1">section 1254(1) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77bc637d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s29/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct appeals to Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An appeal from a final judgment pursuant to subsection (a) shall lie directly to the Supreme Court, if, upon application of a party filed within fifteen days of the filing of a notice of appeal, the district judge who adjudicated the case enters an order stating that immediate consideration of the appeal by the Supreme Court is of general public importance in the administration of justice. Such order shall be filed within thirty days after the filing of a notice of appeal. When such an order is filed, the appeal and any cross appeal shall be docketed in the time and manner prescribed by the rules of the Supreme Court. The Supreme Court shall thereupon either (1) dispose of the appeal and any cross appeal in the same manner as any other direct appeal authorized by law, or (2) in its discretion, deny the direct appeal and remand the case to the court of appeals, which shall then have jurisdiction to hear and determine the same as if the appeal and any cross appeal therein had been docketed in the court of appeals in the first instance pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77bc637e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1903-02-11/ch544/s2">Feb. 11, 1903, ch. 544, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/823">32 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s291">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 291</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1167">36 Stat. 1167</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1944-06-09/ch239">June 9, 1944, ch. 239</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/272">58 Stat. 272</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s17">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 17</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/989">62 Stat. 989</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/528/s5">Pub. L. 93–528, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1709">88 Stat. 1709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77bc637f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77bc6380-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77bc6381-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to protect trade and commerce against unlawful restraints and monopolies”, approved <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is known as the Sherman Act, and is classified to sections 1 to 7 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77bc6382-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was previously set out in both this section and in section 45 of former Title 49, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77bc6383-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/528">Pub. L. 93–528</ref> substituted provisions for appeals to the court of appeals from civil actions in district courts where equitable relief is sought, review by the Supreme Court of judgments of courts of appeals, and for direct appeals to the Supreme Court of cases involving general public importance, for provisions that appeals from final judgments of district courts lie to the Supreme Court only.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, amended section generally to strike out provisions relating to time for appeal, procedure, etc. See sections 2101 and 2109 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1944—Act <date date="1944-06-09">June 9, 1944</date>, provided for certification of case to circuit court of appeals when there was no quorum of Justices of the Supreme Court qualified to participate in the consideration of the case and for designation of circuit judges in the event of disqualification from hearing the case.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77bc6384-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id77bc6385-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1911-03-03">Mar. 3, 1911</date>, which transferred the powers and duties of the circuit courts to the district courts, substituted “district court” for “circuit court”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77bc6386-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/528/s7">Pub. L. 93–528, § 7</ref>, <date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1710">88 Stat. 1710</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/528/s7">“The amendment made by section 5 of this Act [amending this section] shall not apply to an action in which a notice of appeal to the Supreme Court has been filed on or before the fifteenth day following the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1974-12-21">Dec. 21, 1974</date>]. Appeal in any such action shall be taken pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/act/1903-02-11/s2">section 2 of the Act of February 11, 1903</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/32/823">32 Stat. 823</ref>), as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s29">15 U.S.C. 29</ref>; [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s45">49 U.S.C. 45</ref>) which were in effect on the day preceding the date of enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77bc6387-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1948 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 38 of act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, provided that the amendment made by that act is effective <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77bc6388-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1944 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1944-06-09/ch239">Act June 9, 1944, ch. 239</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/272">58 Stat. 272</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1944-06-09/ch239">“This Act [this section] shall apply to every case pending before the Supreme Court of the United States on the date of its enactment [<date date="1944-06-09">June 9, 1944</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id77bc6389-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1903-02-11">Feb. 11, 1903</date>, which enacted sections 28 and 29 of this title, is commonly known as the “Expediting Act”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
