<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a108ce1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931"><num value="2931">§ 2931.</num><heading> Findings and purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a108ce2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Industrial, agricultural, and other human activities, coupled with an expanding world population, are contributing to processes of global change that may significantly alter the Earth habitat within a few human generations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such human-induced changes, in conjunction with natural fluctuations, may lead to significant global warming and thus alter world climate patterns and increase global sea levels. Over the next century, these consequences could adversely affect world agricultural and marine production, coastal habitability, biological diversity, human health, and global economic and social well-being.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The release of chlorofluorocarbons and other stratospheric ozone-depleting substances is rapidly reducing the ability of the atmosphere to screen out harmful ultraviolet radiation, which could adversely affect human health and ecological systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Development of effective policies to abate, mitigate, and cope with global change will rely on greatly improved scientific understanding of global environmental processes and on our ability to distinguish human-induced from natural global change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> New developments in interdisciplinary Earth sciences, global observing systems, and computing technology make possible significant advances in the scientific understanding and prediction of these global changes and their effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108ce8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Although significant Federal global change research efforts are underway, an effective Federal research program will require efficient interagency coordination, and coordination with the research activities of State, private, and international entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a108ce9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2931/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purpose of this subchapter is to provide for development and coordination of a comprehensive and integrated United States research program which will assist the Nation and the world to understand, assess, predict, and respond to human-induced and natural processes of global change.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a108cea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/606/tI/s101">Pub. L. 101–606, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3096">104 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
