<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id789c89f3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s294"><num value="294">§ 294.</num><heading> Importation or transportation of falsely marked gold or silver ware prohibited</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, corporation, or association, being a manufacturer of or wholesale or retail dealer in gold or silver jewelry or gold ware, silver goods or silverware, or for any officer, manager, director, or agent of such firm, corporation, or association to import or export or cause to be imported into or exported from the United States for the purpose of selling or disposing of the same, or to deposit or cause to be deposited in the United States mails for transmission thereby, or to deliver or cause to be delivered to any common carrier for transportation from one State, Territory, or possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, to any other State, Territory, or possession of the United States, or to said District, in interstate commerce, or to transport or cause to be transported from one State, Territory, or possession of the United States, or from the District of Columbia, to any other State, Territory, or possession of the United States, or to said District, in interstate commerce, any article of merchandise manufactured after <date date="1907-06-13">June 13, 1907</date>, and made in whole or in part of gold or silver, or any alloy of either of said metals, and having stamped, branded, engraved, or printed thereon, or upon any tag, card, or label attached thereto, or upon any box, package, cover, or wrapper in which said article is incased or inclosed, any mark or word indicating or designed or intended to indicate that the gold or silver or alloy of either of said metals in such article is of a greater degree of fineness than the actual fineness or quality of such gold, silver, or alloy, according to the standards and subject to the qualifications set forth in sections 295 and 296 of this title.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id789c89f4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1906-06-13/ch3289/s1">June 13, 1906, ch. 3289, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/260">34 Stat. 260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id789c89f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id789c89f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id789c89f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/450/s1">Pub. L. 94–450, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1501">90 Stat. 1501</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/450/s1">“That this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s295">section 295 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s295">section 295 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Gold Labeling Act of 1976’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id789c89f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1906-06-13/ch3289">Act June 13, 1906, ch. 3289</ref>, which enacted this section and sections 295 to 300 of this title, is popularly known as the “Jewelers’ Liability Act (Gold and Silver Articles)” and also as the “National Gold and Silver Stamping Act of 1906”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
