<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a108d54-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952"><num value="2952">§ 2952.</num><heading> International discussions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a108d55-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Global change research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President should direct the Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Committee, to initiate discussions with other nations leading toward international protocols and other agreements to coordinate global change research activities. Such discussions should include the following issues:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d56-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Allocation of costs in global change research programs, especially with respect to major capital projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d57-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Coordination of global change research plans with those developed by international organizations such as the International Council on Scientific Unions, the World Meteorological Organization, and the United Nations Environment Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d58-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Establishment of global change research centers and training programs for scientists, especially those from developing nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d59-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Development of innovative methods for management of international global change research, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a108d5a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> use of new or existing intergovernmental organizations for the coordination or funding of global change research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a108d5b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> creation of a limited foundation for global change research.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d5c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The prompt establishment of international projects to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a108d5d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> create globally accessible formats for data collected by various international sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a108d5e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> combine and interpret data from various sources to produce information readily usable by policymakers attempting to formulate effective strategies for preventing, mitigating, and adapting to possible adverse effects of global change.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d5f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Establishment of international offices to disseminate information useful in identifying, preventing, mitigating, or adapting to the possible effects of global change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a108d60-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Energy research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President should direct the Secretary of State (in cooperation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, the United States Trade Representative, and other appropriate members of the Committee) to initiate discussions with other nations leading toward an international research protocol for cooperation on the development of energy technologies which have minimally adverse effects on the environment. Such discussions should include, but not be limited to, the following issues:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d61-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Creation of an international cooperative program to fund research related to energy efficiency, solar and other renewable energy sources, and passively safe and diversion-resistant nuclear reactors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d62-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Creation of an international cooperative program to develop low cost energy technologies which are appropriate to the environmental, economic, and social needs of developing nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a108d63-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s2952/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Exchange of information concerning environmentally safe energy technologies and practices, including those described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a108d64-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/606/tII/s203">Pub. L. 101–606, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3102">104 Stat. 3102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
