<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a15479c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3113"><num value="3113">§ 3113.</num><heading> Economic activity coordination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a15479d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3113/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal, regional, State, local, and private sector</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As an integral part of any countercyclical employment policies undertaken in accord with <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3112">section 3112 of this title</ref>, the President shall, to the extent the President deems necessary, set forth programs and policies, including recommended legislation where needed, to coordinate economic action among the Federal Government, regions, States and localities, and the private sector to promote achievement of the purposes of this chapter and the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">15 U.S.C. 1021</ref> et seq.] and an economic environment in which State and local governments and private sector economic activity and employment will prosper. In considering programs and policies related to the private sector, full consideration shall be given to promoting the growth and well-being of small businesses and employment training programs through private sector incentives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a15479e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3113/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fiscal needs and budget conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any efforts under this section, the President shall endeavor to meet criteria that establish programs which are funded to take account of the fiscal needs and budget conditions of the respective States and localities and their own efforts, with special attention to the rates of unemployment in such States and localities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a15479f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/523/tII/s203">Pub. L. 95–523, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1900">92 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a1547a0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a1547a1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a1547a2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “this chapter”, referred to in subsec. (a), see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3102">section 3102 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employment Act of 1946, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-02-20/ch33">act Feb. 20, 1946, ch. 33</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/23">60 Stat. 23</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 21 (§ 1021 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7a1547a3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7a1547a4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 12329</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12329, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 50919, which established the President’s Task Force on Private Sector Initiatives and provided for its membership, functions, etc., was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12399, § 4(i), <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, 48 F.R. 380, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
