<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a1790d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3132"><num value="3132">§ 3132.</num><heading> Committee review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a1790da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3132/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short-term and medium-term goals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conjunction with its review of the Economic Report, and the holding of hearings on the Economic Report under the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">15 U.S.C. 1021</ref> et seq.], the Joint Economic Committee shall review and analyze the short-term and medium-term goals set forth in the Economic Report pursuant to section 3(a)(2) and 4(b) of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/2">15 U.S.C. 1022(a)(2)</ref>, 1022a(b)].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a1790db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3132/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Joint Economic Committee shall hold hearings on the Economic Report for the purpose of receiving testimony from Members of the Congress, and such appropriate representatives of Federal departments and agencies, the general public, and interested groups as the joint committee deems advisable. The joint committee shall also consider the comments and views on the Economic Report which are received from State and local officials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a1790dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3132/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report of standing and joint committees and committees with legislative jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within thirty days after receipt by the Congress of the Economic Report, each standing committee of the Senate and the House of Representatives, each other committee of the Senate and the House of Representatives which has legislative jurisdiction, and each joint committee of the Congress may submit to the Joint Economic Committee, for use by the Joint Economic Committee in conducting its review and analysis under subsection (a), a report containing the views and recommendations of the submitting committee with respect to aspects of the Economic Report which relate to its jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a1790dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3132/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report of Joint Economic Committee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On or before March 15 of each year, a majority of the members of the Joint Economic Committee shall submit a report to the Committees on the Budget of the Senate and the House of Representatives. Such report shall include findings, recommendations, and any appropriate analyses with respect and in direct comparison to each of the short-term and medium-term goals set forth in the Economic Report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a1790de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/523/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 95–523, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1904">92 Stat. 1904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a1790df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a1790e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a1790e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employment Act of 1946, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-02-20/ch33">act Feb. 20, 1946, ch. 33</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/23">60 Stat. 23</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 21 (§ 1021 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">section 1021 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
