<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78a1445d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c"><num value="313c">§ 313c.</num><heading> Authorized activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, through the United States Weather Research Program, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a1445e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> improve the capability to accurately forecast inland flooding (including inland flooding influenced by coastal and ocean storms) through research and modeling;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a1445f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop, test, and deploy a new flood warning index that will give the public and emergency management officials fuller, clearer, and more accurate information about the risks and dangers posed by expected floods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a14460-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> train emergency management officials, National Weather Service personnel, meteorologists, and others as appropriate regarding improved forecasting techniques for inland flooding, risk management techniques, and use of the inland flood warning index developed under paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a14461-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> conduct outreach and education activities for local meteorologists and the public regarding the dangers and risks associated with inland flooding and the use and understanding of the inland flood warning index developed under paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78a14462-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> assess, through research and analysis of previous trends, among other activities—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78a14463-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the long-term trends in frequency and severity of inland flooding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78a14464-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s313c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> how shifts in climate, development, and erosion patterns might make certain regions vulnerable to more continual or escalating flood damage in the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id78a14465-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/253/s2">Pub. L. 107–253, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1731">116 Stat. 1731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78a14466-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78a14467-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78a14468-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization of Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/253/s3">Pub. L. 107–253, § 3</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1731">116 Stat. 1731</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/253/s3">“There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for carrying out this Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s311">section 311 of this title</ref>] $1,250,000 for each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2005, of which $100,000 for each fiscal year shall be available for competitive merit-reviewed grants to institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>)) to carry out the activities described in section 2(5) [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s313c/5">15 U.S.C. 313c(5)</ref>], and $1,150,000 for each of the fiscal years 2006 and 2007. Of the amounts authorized under this section, $250,000 for each fiscal year shall be available for competitive merit-reviewed grants to institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>)) to develop models that can improve the ability to forecast the coastal and estuary-inland flooding that is influenced by tropical cyclones. The models should incorporate the interaction of such factors as storm surges, soil saturation, and other relevant phenomena.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78a14469-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/253/s4">Pub. L. 107–253, § 4</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1732">116 Stat. 1732</ref>, required the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to provide Congress with annual reports through fiscal year 2007 on its activities under <ref href="/us/pl/107/253">Pub. L. 107–253</ref> (see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s311">section 311 of this title</ref>) and the success and acceptance of the inland flood warning index developed under par. (2) of this section and also to report by <date date="2006-01-01">Jan. 1, 2006</date>, on the likely long-term trends in inland flooding for use in outreach activities conducted under par. (4) of this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
