<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a179120-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203"><num value="3203">§ 3203.</num><heading> Adoption of certain standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179121-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Adoption of standards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date> (or after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, in the case of standards under paragraphs (3),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002485">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002485"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> and (4) of subsection (b)), each State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated gas utility shall provide public notice and conduct a hearing respecting the standards established by subsection (b), and, on the basis of such hearing, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a179122-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> adopt the standard established by subsection (b)(1), if, and to the extent, such authority or nonregulated utility determines that such adoption is appropriate and is consistent with otherwise applicable State law, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a179123-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> adopt the standards established by paragraphs (2), (3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002486">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002486"><num>2</num> So in original. A comma probably should appear.</note> (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (b), if, and to the extent, such authority or nonregulated utility determines that such adoption is appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter, is otherwise appropriate, and is consistent with otherwise applicable State law.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of any determination under paragraphs (1) and (2) and any review of such determination in any court under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3207">section 3207 of this title</ref>, the purposes of this chapter supplement State law. Nothing in this subsection prohibits any State regulatory authority or non­regulated utility from making any determination that it is not appropriate to implement any such standard, pursuant to its authority under otherwise applicable State law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179124-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following Federal standards are hereby established:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179125-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for termination of natural gas service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No gas utility may terminate natural gas service to any gas consumer except pursuant to procedures described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3204/a">section 3204(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179126-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No gas utility may recover from any person other than the shareholders (or other owners) of such utility any direct or indirect expenditure by such utility for promotional or political advertising as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3204/b">section 3204(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179127-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Integrated resource planning</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each gas utility shall employ, in order to provide adequate and reliable service to its gas customers at the lowest system cost. All plans or filings of a State regulated gas utility before a State regulatory authority to meet the requirements of this paragraph shall (A) be updated on a regular basis, (B) provide the opportunity for public participation and comment, (C) provide for methods of validating predicted performance, and (D) contain a requirement that the plan be implemented after approval of the State regulatory authority. Subsection (c) shall not apply to this paragraph to the extent that it could be construed to require the State regulatory authority to extend the record of a State proceeding in submitting reports to the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179128-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Investments in conservation and demand management</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The rates charged by any State regulated gas utility shall be such that the utility’s prudent investments in, and expenditures for, energy conservation and load shifting programs and for other demand-side management measures which are consistent with the findings and purposes of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 are at least as profitable (taking into account the income lost due to reduced sales resulting from such programs) as prudent investments in, and expenditures for, the acquisition or construction of supplies and facilities. This objective requires that (A) regulators link the utility’s net revenues, at least in part, to the utility’s performance in implementing cost-effective programs promoted by this section; and (B) regulators ensure that, for purposes of recovering fixed costs, including its authorized return, the utility’s performance is not affected by reductions in its retail sales volumes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179129-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Energy efficiency</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each natural gas utility shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a17912a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> integrate energy efficiency resources into the plans and planning processes of the natural gas utility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a17912b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> adopt policies that establish energy efficiency as a priority resource in the plans and planning processes of the natural gas utility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a17912c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Rate design modifications to promote energy efficiency investments</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a17912d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The rates allowed to be charged by a natural gas utility shall align utility incentives with the deployment of cost-effective energy efficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a17912e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy options</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In complying with subparagraph (A), each State regulatory authority and each nonregulated utility shall consider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a17912f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> separating fixed-cost revenue recovery from the volume of transportation or sales service provided to the customer;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a179130-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> providing to utilities incentives for the successful management of energy efficiency programs, such as allowing utilities to retain a portion of the cost-reducing benefits accruing from the programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a179131-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> promoting the impact on adoption of energy efficiency as 1 of the goals of retail rate design, recognizing that energy efficiency must be balanced with other objectives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a179132-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> adopting rate designs that encourage energy efficiency for each customer class.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of applying the provisions of this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002487">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002487"><num>3</num> See Codification note below.</note> to this paragraph, any reference in this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002487">3</ref> to <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, shall be treated as a reference to <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179133-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State regulatory authority (with respect to each gas utility for which it has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated gas utility, within the 2-year period specified in subsection (a), shall adopt, pursuant to subsection (a), each of the standards established by subsection (b), or, with respect to any such standard which is not adopted, such authority or nonregulated gas utility shall state in writing that it has determined not to adopt such standard, together with the reasons for such determination. Such statement of reasons shall be available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a179134-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Small business impacts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a State regulatory authority implements a standard established by subsection (b)(3) or (4), such authority shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a179135-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consider the impact that implementation of such standard would have on small businesses engaged in the design, sale, supply, installation, or servicing of energy conservation, energy efficiency, or other demand-side management measures, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a179136-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3203/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> implement such standard so as to assure that utility actions would not provide such utilities with unfair competitive advantages over such small businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a179137-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/617/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 95–617, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3150">92 Stat. 3150</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s115/b">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 115(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2803">106 Stat. 2803</ref>, 2804; <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tV/s532/b">Pub. L. 110–140, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1666">121 Stat. 1666</ref>, 1667.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a179138-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a179139-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a17913a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Policy Act of 1992, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2776">106 Stat. 2776</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13201">section 13201 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7a17913b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(6), was in the original “this subtitle”, which was translated as meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/95/617">Pub. L. 95–617</ref> to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a17913c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s532/c">Pub. L. 110–140, § 532(c)</ref>, which directed substitution of “(4), (5), and (6)” for “and (4)” in subsec. (a), was executed by making the substitution in subsec. (a)(2) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s532/b">Pub. L. 110–140, § 532(b)</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s115/d">Pub. L. 102–486, § 115(d)</ref>, in introductory provisions inserted “(or after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, in the case of standards under paragraphs (3), and (4) of subsection (b))” and in par. (2) substituted “standards established by paragraphs (2), (3) and (4) of subsection (b)” for “standard established by subsection (b)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s115/b">Pub. L. 102–486, § 115(b)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s115/c">Pub. L. 102–486, § 115(c)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a17913d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7a17913e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> effective on the date that is 1 day after <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s1601">section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1824">section 1824 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7a17913f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to President and Congress on Encouragement of Integrated Resource Planning and Investments in Conservation and Energy Efficiency by Electric Utilities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s115/e">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 115(e)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2804">106 Stat. 2804</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s115/e">“The report under section 111(e) of this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2621">16 U.S.C. 2621</ref> note] transmitted by the Secretary of Energy to the President and to the Congress shall contain a survey of all State laws, regulations, practices, and policies under which State regulatory authorities implement the provisions of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 303(b) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3203/b/3">15 U.S.C. 3203(b)(3)</ref> and (4)]. The report shall include an analysis, prepared in conjunction with the Federal Trade Commission, of the competitive impact of implementation of energy conservation, energy efficiency, and other demand side management programs by gas utilities on small businesses engaged in the design, sale, supply, installation, or servicing of similar energy conservation, energy efficiency, or other demand-side management measures and whether any unfair, deceptive, or predatory acts or practices exist, or are likely to exist, from implementation of such programs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id7a179140-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions of State and system cost in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s2602">section 2602 of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, apply to this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
