<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a1c72e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3375"><num value="3375">§ 3375.</num><heading> Filing of contracts and agreements</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may, by rule or order, require any first sale purchaser of natural gas under a new contract, a successor to an existing contract, or a rollover contract to file with the Commission a copy of such contract, together with all ancillary agreements and any existing contract applicable to such natural gas.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7a1c72e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/621/tIII/s315">Pub. L. 95–621, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3393">92 Stat. 3393</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/439">Pub. L. 100–439</ref>, §§ 1, 2(a), (b)(1), <date date="1988-09-22">Sept. 22, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1720">102 Stat. 1720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/60/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 101–60, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-07-26">July 26, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/158">103 Stat. 158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a1c72e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a1c72ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a1c72eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/60">Pub. L. 101–60</ref>, in section catchline, substituted “Filing of contracts and agreements” for “Contract duration; filing of contracts and agreements”, and in text, struck out subsec. (a) designation, heading “Contract duration”, and text relating to power of Commissioner to specify minimum duration of contracts for purchase of natural gas and requiring nondiscriminatory exercise of such authority, and struck out subsec. (b) designation and heading “Filing of contracts and ancillary agreements”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/439/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 100–439, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “right of first refusal;” after “Contract duration;” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/439/s1">Pub. L. 100–439, § 1</ref>, struck out last sentence which directed that provisions of par. (1) did not apply to contracts of natural gas subject to requirements of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/439/s1">Pub. L. 100–439, § 1</ref>, struck out par. (3) which related to contracts for purchase of natural gas produced from reservoirs on Outer Continental Shelf.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/439/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–439, § 2(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which related to certain rights of first refusal with respect to certain natural gas committed or dedicated to interstate commerce on <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
