<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a212eb0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a"><num value="3704a">§ 3704a.</num><heading> Clearinghouse for State and Local Initiatives on Productivity, Technology, and Innovation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a212eb1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established within the Office of Productivity, Technology, and Innovation a Clearinghouse for State and Local Initiatives on Productivity, Technology, and Innovation. The Clearinghouse shall serve as a central repository of information on initiatives by State and local governments to enhance the competitiveness of American business through the stimulation of productivity, technology, and innovation and Federal efforts to assist State and local governments to enhance competitiveness.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a212eb2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Clearinghouse may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish relationships with State and local governments, and regional and multistate organizations of such governments, which carry out such initiatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collect information on the nature, extent, and effects of such initiatives, particularly information useful to the Congress, Federal agencies, State and local governments, regional and multistate organizations of such governments, businesses, and the public throughout the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> disseminate information collected under paragraph (2) through reports, directories, handbooks, conferences, and seminars;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide technical assistance and advice to such governments with respect to such initiatives, including assistance in determining sources of assistance from Federal agencies which may be available to support such initiatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> study ways in which Federal agencies, including Federal laboratories, are able to use their existing policies and programs to assist State and local governments, and regional and multistate organizations of such governments, to enhance the competitiveness of American business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> make periodic recommendations to the Secretary, and to other Federal agencies upon their request, concerning modifications in Federal policies and programs which would improve Federal assistance to State and local technology and business assistance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eb9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> develop methodologies to evaluate State and local programs, and, when requested, advise State and local governments, and regional and multistate organizations of such governments, as to which programs are most effective in enhancing the competitiveness of American business through the stimulation of productivity, technology, and innovation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a212eba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> make use of, and disseminate, the nationwide study of State industrial extension programs conducted by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a212ebb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3704a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary may enter into contracts for the purpose of collecting information on the nature, extent, and effects of initiatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a212ebc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/480/s6">Pub. L. 96–480, § 6</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5122/a/2">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5122(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1438">102 Stat. 1438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a212ebd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a212ebe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7a212ebf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d) of this section, which required the Secretary to prepare and transmit a triennial report to Congress, including recommendations to the President, Congress, and Federal agencies, on initiatives by State and local governments to enhance the competitiveness of American businesses through the stimulation of productivity, technology, and innovation, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 50 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
