<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a285a0e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a"><num value="3711a">§ 3711a.</num><heading> Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a0f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award, which shall be evidenced by a medal bearing the inscriptions “Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award” and “The Quest for Excellence”. The medal shall be of such design and materials and bear such additional inscriptions as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a10-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Making and presentation of award</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President (on the basis of recommendations received from the Secretary), or the Secretary, shall periodically make the award to companies and other organizations which in the judgment of the President or the Secretary have substantially benefited the economic or social well-being of the United States through improvements in the quality of their goods or services resulting from the effective practice of quality management, and which as a consequence are deserving of special recognition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The presentation of the award shall be made by the President or the Secretary with such ceremonies as the President or the Secretary may deem proper.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a13-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An organization to which an award is made under this section, and which agrees to help other American organizations improve their quality management, may publicize its receipt of such award and use the award in its advertising, but it shall be ineligible to receive another such award in the same category for a period of 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a14-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Categories in which award may be given</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a15-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), separate awards shall be made to qualifying organizations in each of the following categories—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a16-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Small businesses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a17-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Companies or their subsidiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a18-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Companies which primarily provide services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a19-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Health care providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a1a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Education providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a1b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Nonprofit organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a1c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a1d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may at any time expand, subdivide, or otherwise modify the list of categories within which awards may be made as initially in effect under paragraph (1), and may establish separate awards for other organizations including units of government, upon a determination that the objectives of this section would be better served thereby; except that any such expansion, subdivision, modification, or establishment shall not be effective unless and until the Secretary has submitted a detailed description thereof to the Congress and a period of 30 days has elapsed since that submission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a1e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In any year, not more than 18 awards may be made under this section to recipients who have not previously received an award under this section, and no award shall be made within any category described in paragraph (1) if there are no qualifying enterprises in that category.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a1f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria for qualification</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a20-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An organization may qualify for an award under this section only if it—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a21-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> applies to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology in writing, for the award,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a22-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> permits a rigorous evaluation of the way in which its business and other operations have contributed to improvements in the quality of goods and services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a285a23-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> meets such requirements and specifications as the Secretary, after receiving recommendations from the Board of Overseers established under paragraph (2)(B) and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, determines to be appropriate to achieve the objectives of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In applying the provisions of subparagraph (C) with respect to any organization, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall rely upon an intensive evaluation by a competent board of examiners which shall review the evidence submitted by the organization and, through a site visit, verify the accuracy of the quality improvements claimed. The examination should encompass all aspects of the organization’s current practice of quality management, as well as the organization’s provision for quality management in its future goals. The award shall be given only to organizations which have made outstanding improvements in the quality of their goods or services (or both) and which demonstrate effective quality management through the training and involvement of all levels of personnel in quality improvement.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a24-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a25-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall, under appropriate contractual arrangements, carry out the Director’s responsibilities under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) through one or more broad-based nonprofit entities which are leaders in the field of quality management and which have a history of service to society.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a285a26-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall appoint a board of overseers for the award, consisting of at least five persons selected for their preeminence in the field of quality management. This board shall meet annually to review the work of the contractor or contractors and make such suggestions for the improvement of the award process as they deem necessary. The board shall report the results of the award activities to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology each year, along with its recommendations for improvement of the process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a27-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Information and technology transfer program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall ensure that all program participants receive the complete results of their audits as well as detailed explanations of all suggestions for improvements. The Director shall also provide information about the awards and the successful quality improvement strategies and programs of the award-winning participants to all participants and other appropriate groups.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a28-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to seek and accept gifts from public and private sources to carry out the program under this section. If additional sums are needed to cover the full cost of the program, the Secretary shall impose fees upon the organizations applying for the award in amounts sufficient to provide such additional sums. The Director is authorized to use appropriated funds to carry out responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a285a29-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s3711a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare and submit to the President and the Congress, within 3 years after <date date="1987-08-20">August 20, 1987</date>, a report on the progress, findings, and conclusions of activities conducted pursuant to this section along with recommendations for possible modifications thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a285a2a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/480/s17">Pub. L. 96–480, § 17</ref>, formerly § 16, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/107/s3/a">Pub. L. 100–107, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-08-20">Aug. 20, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/725">101 Stat. 725</ref>; renumbered § 17 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV">Pub. L. 100–418, title V</ref>, §§ 5115(b)(2)(A), 5122(a)(1), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>, 1438; <ref href="/us/pl/102/245/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 102–245, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1992-02-14">Feb. 14, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/20">106 Stat. 20</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/309/s3">Pub. L. 105–309, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2935">112 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/320/s1">Pub. L. 108–320, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-10-05">Oct. 5, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1213">118 Stat. 1213</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/69/tIII/s3010">Pub. L. 110–69, title III, § 3010</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/592">121 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tII/s10246/b/1">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title II, § 10246(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1492">136 Stat. 1492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a285a2b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a285a2c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a285a2d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(1)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10246/b/1/A">Pub. L. 117–167, § 10246(b)(1)(A)</ref>, realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10246/b/1/B">Pub. L. 117–167, § 10246(b)(1)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/69">Pub. L. 110–69</ref> amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “Not more than two awards may be made within any subcategory in any year, unless the Secretary determines that a third award is merited and can be given at no additional cost to the Federal Government (and no award shall be made within any category or subcategory if there are no qualifying enterprises in that category or subcategory).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/108/320">Pub. L. 108–320</ref> added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (c)(1)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/105/309/s3/b">Pub. L. 105–309, § 3(b)</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/309/s3/a">Pub. L. 105–309, § 3(a)</ref>, inserted “, unless the Secretary determines that a third award is merited and can be given at no additional cost to the Federal Government” after “in any year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/245">Pub. L. 102–245</ref> inserted at end “The Director is authorized to use appropriated funds to carry out responsibilities under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s5115/b/2/A">Pub. L. 100–418, § 5115(b)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a285a2e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7a285a2f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings and Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/107/s2">Pub. L. 100–107, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-08-20">Aug. 20, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/724">101 Stat. 724</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/107/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the leadership of the United States in product and process quality has been challenged strongly (and sometimes successfully) by foreign competition, and our Nation’s productivity growth has improved less than our competitors over the last two decades;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> American business and industry are beginning to understand that poor quality costs companies as much as 20 percent of sales revenues nationally, and that improved quality of goods and services goes hand in hand with improved productivity, lower costs, and increased profitability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> strategic planning for quality and quality improvement programs, through a commitment to excellence in manufacturing and services, are becoming more and more essential to the well-being of our Nation’s economy and our ability to compete effectively in the global marketplace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> improved management understanding of the factory floor, worker involvement in quality, and greater emphasis on statistical process control can lead to dramatic improvements in the cost and quality of manufactured products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the concept of quality improvement is directly applicable to small companies as well as large, to service industries as well as manufacturing, and to the public sector as well as private enterprise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> in order to be successful, quality improvement programs must be management-led and customer-oriented and this may require fundamental changes in the way companies and agencies do business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> several major industrial nations have successfully coupled rigorous private sector quality audits with national awards giving special recognition to those enterprises the audits identify as the very best; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><chapeau> a national quality award program of this kind in the United States would help improve quality and productivity by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> helping to stimulate American companies to improve quality and productivity for the pride of recognition while obtaining a competitive edge through increased profits,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> recognizing the achievements of those companies which improve the quality of their goods and services and providing an example to others,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> establishing guidelines and criteria that can be used by business, industrial, governmental, and other organizations in evaluating their own quality improvement efforts, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> providing specific guidance for other American organizations that wish to learn how to manage for high quality by making available detailed information on how winning organizations were able to change their cultures and achieve eminence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the purpose of this Act [enacting this section, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3708">section 3708 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">section 3701 of this title</ref>] to provide for the establishment and conduct of a national quality improvement program under which (1) awards are given to selected companies and other organizations in the United States that practice effective quality management and as a result make significant improvements in the quality of their goods and services, and (2) information is disseminated about the successful strategies and programs.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
