<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a31d073-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013"><num value="4013">§ 4013.</num><heading> Issuance of certificate</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d074-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A certificate of review shall be issued to any applicant that establishes that its specified export trade, export trade activities, and methods of operation will—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d075-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> result in neither a substantial lessening of competition or restraint of trade within the United States nor a substantial restraint of the export trade of any competitor of the applicant,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d076-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not unreasonably enhance, stabilize, or depress prices within the United States of the goods, wares, merchandise, or services of the class exported by the applicant,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d077-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> not constitute unfair methods of competition against competitors engaged in the export of goods, wares, merchandise, or services of the class exported by the applicant, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d078-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> not include any act that may reasonably be expected to result in the sale for consumption or resale within the United States of the goods, wares, merchandise, or services exported by the applicant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d079-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for determination; specification in certificate</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within ninety days after the Secretary receives an application for a certificate of review, the Secretary shall determine whether the applicant’s export trade, export trade activities, and methods of operation meet the standards of subsection (a). If the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Attorney General, determines that such standards are met, the Secretary shall issue to the applicant a certificate of review. The certificate of review shall specify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d07a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the export trade, export trade activities, and methods of operation to which the certificate applies,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d07b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the person to whom the certificate of review is issued, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a31d07c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any terms and conditions the Secretary or the Attorney General deems necessary to assure compliance with the standards of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d07d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the applicant indicates a special need for prompt disposition, the Secretary and the Attorney General may expedite action on the application, except that no certificate of review may be issued within thirty days of publication of notice in the Federal Register under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4012/b/1">section 4012(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d07e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of denial; request for reconsideration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a31d07f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Secretary denies in whole or in part an application for a certificate, he shall notify the applicant of his determination and the reasons for it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a31d080-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An applicant may, within thirty days of receipt of notification that the application has been denied in whole or in part, request the Secretary to reconsider the determination. The Secretary, with the concurrence of the Attorney General, shall notify the applicant of the determination upon reconsideration within thirty days of receipt of the request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d081-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Return of documents upon request after denial</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary denies an application for the issuance of a certificate of review and thereafter receives from the applicant a request for the return of documents submitted by the applicant in connection with the application for the certificate, the Secretary and the Attorney General shall return to the applicant, not later than thirty days after receipt of the request, the documents and all copies of the documents available to the Secretary and the Attorney General, except to the extent that the information contained in a document has been made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a31d082-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4013/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Fraudulent procurement of certificate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A certificate shall be void ab initio with respect to any export trade, export trade activities, or methods of operation for which a certificate was procured by fraud.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a31d083-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/290/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 97–290, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1982-10-08">Oct. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1241">96 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a31d084-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a31d085-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id7a31d086-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after effective date of rules and regulations first promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4020">section 4020 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/290/s312/b">section 312(b) of Pub. L. 97–290</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4011">section 4011 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
