<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a36b259-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104"><num value="4104">§ 4104.</num><heading> Cooperation with Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a36b25a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of information from Federal agencies; withholding authorization</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a36b25b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission may acquire from the head of any Federal agency unclassified data, reports, and other nonproprietary information with respect to Arctic research in the possession of the agency which the Commission considers useful in the discharge of its duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a36b25c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each agency shall cooperate with the Commission and furnish all data, reports, and other information requested by the Commission to the extent permitted by law; except that no agency need furnish any information which it is permitted to withhold under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a36b25d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of facilities and services; reimbursement; avoidance of duplication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With the consent of the appropriate agency head, the Commission may utilize the facilities and services of any Federal agency to the extent that the facilities and services are needed for the establishment and development of an Arctic research policy, upon reimbursement to be agreed upon by the Commission and the agency head and taking every feasible step to avoid duplication of effort.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a36b25e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultations with Commission prior to major Federal actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All Federal agencies shall consult with the Commission before undertaking major Federal actions relating to Arctic research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a36b25f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/373/tI/s105">Pub. L. 98–373, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1984-07-31">July 31, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1245">98 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
