<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a38fd11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504"><num value="4504">§ 4504.</num><heading> Statute of limitation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a38fd12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a38fd13-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), the commencement of a civil enforcement action shall be barred unless such action is commenced before the later of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a38fd14-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a38fd15-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> six years after the date of the violation upon which the action is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a38fd16-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “commencement of a civil enforcement action” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a38fd17-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the signing and issuance of a proposed remedial order against any person for filing with the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of Energy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a38fd18-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the filing of a complaint with the appropriate district court of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a38fd19-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the term “civil enforcement action” means an administrative or judicial civil action by the Secretary under the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s751">15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970 (or the regulations issued thereunder) for the enforcement of any violation of such Acts or regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d1a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d1b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In computing the periods established in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1), there shall be excluded any period—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d1c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> during which any person who is or may become the subject of a civil enforcement action is outside the United States, has absconded or concealed himself, or is not subject to legal process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d1d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> during which facts material to the establishment and maintenance of a civil enforcement action could not be known;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d1e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> occurring before full compliance with any subpoena or special report order issued to any person under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s772">section 772 of this title</ref>, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) after such compliance for the Secretary to consider the results thereof and commence a civil enforcement action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d1f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> during the pendency of any relevant criminal action under the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) during which a civil enforcement action is held in abeyance as a result of prosecutorial discretion and with or without a stay, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) after a final judicial order or dismissal of such criminal action to commence a civil enforcement action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d20-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> before the issuance of an order that constitutes final agency action on a request for adjustment from any rule, regulation, or order under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7194">section 7194 of title 42</ref>, and such additional period (not to exceed 12 calendar months) to commence a civil enforcement action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d21-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> of extension, to which the Secretary and the defendant have consented in writing, before the expiration of the time periods prescribed in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d22-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The provisions of subsection (a) shall not affect or apply to any civil enforcement action commenced before, on, or after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and remanded by the Office of Hearings and Appeals, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, or the court for further action of any kind.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d23-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to any agency orders issued under the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) or to regulations issued under this chapter, other than a proposed remedial order subject to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d24-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Expression of intent</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d25-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> It is the intent of the Congress that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d26-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary and the Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall, to the greatest extent possible and within the time frames specified on <date date="1986-09-12">September 12, 1986</date>, by such Administrator to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, commence civil enforcement actions with respect to all cases known by such Administrator as of <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, and designated by such Administrator as “prelitigation cases”, unless such an action is found not to be warranted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d27-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary and such Administrator not delay civil enforcement actions so as to cause the limitation in subsection (a)(1) to apply to any such case;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d28-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any negotiations for the purpose of settlement of alleged violations not delay the commencement of a civil enforcement action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d29-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the Department of Justice cooperate in ensuring that activities necessary, including the enforcement of subpoenas, to commence civil enforcement actions are carried out in a timely manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d2a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any failure to comply with the time frames described in paragraph (1)(A) shall not be considered for any purpose in any administrative or judicial proceeding subsequently commenced.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d2b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> End of investigations and audits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not initiate, after <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, any audit or investigation of alleged civil violations of the Acts or regulations described in subsection (a)(1) for the purpose of commencement of any civil enforcement action. Nothing in this subsection shall affect or apply to any audit or investigation conducted with respect to any civil enforcement action commenced (within the limitation established by subsection (a)(1)) before, on, or after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>. Nothing in this subsection shall limit the authority of the Secretary to continue any audit or investigation initiated before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d2c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any review of a final agency action determined under section 7193 or 7194 of title 42 may not be initiated in any court by any person subject to such action after—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d2d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 60 days after the effective date of that action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d2e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 90 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever occurs later.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d2f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d30-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In order to ensure the expeditious, effective, and efficient resolution of all civil enforcement actions (whether or not in administrative or judicial litigation) and all cases pending at the Office of Hearings and Appeals under subpart V regulations, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d31-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> maintain a personnel level for the compliance program of the Economic Regulatory Administration of 170 full-time equivalents for fiscal year 1987, subject to normal attrition and subject to the provisions of any appropriation Act enacted for such fiscal year concerning such program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d32-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> maintain for the remainder of the program an adequate mix of lawyers, auditors, technical, clerical, and administrative personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d33-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> By <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>, and by July 1 of each year thereafter, the Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall provide to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the full-time equivalent level necessary for such compliance program for the next fiscal year and the basis for that level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d34-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall, in any fiscal year, provide a notice of at least 30 days to such Committees before initiating any reduction of force at the Economic Regulatory Administration. Such notice shall provide at least—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d35-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the reasons for such reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d36-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the impact on the mix of personnel and on all cases, whether or not in litigation, including the subpart V regulation proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d37-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the expected costs and savings for the applicable fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a3b6d38-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4504/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Administrator of the Economic Regulatory Administration shall keep such Committees fully and currently informed about the status (including delays, settlement negotiations, and other pertinent matters) of all enforcement cases (whether or not in litigation) and subpart V regulation proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a3b6d39-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIII/s3005">Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3005</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1884">100 Stat. 1884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a3b6d3a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a3b6d3b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a3b6d3c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/159">Pub. L. 93–159</ref>, <date date="1973-11-27">Nov. 27, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/628">87 Stat. 628</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 16A (§ 751 et seq.) of this title, was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s760g">section 760g of this title</ref>, which provided for the expiration of the President’s authority under that chapter on <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/379">Pub. L. 91–379</ref>, <date date="1970-08-15">Aug. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/799">84 Stat. 799</ref>, formerly set out as an Economic Stabilization Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1904">section 1904 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was in the original “this Act”, which was translated as meaning this subtitle, which enacted this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a3b6d3d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7a3b6d3e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
