<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a3b6d3f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505"><num value="4505">§ 4505.</num><heading> Reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d40-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on receipts and disbursements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit, not later than 60 days after <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, a report to the committees referred to in subsection (d) containing a clear and complete statement of all receipts, disbursements, and commitments of restitutionary amounts, as of <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, by the Secretary pursuant to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d41-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any judicial or administrative proceeding (including any settlement agreement or declaratory judgment) instituted at any time by the Secretary to enforce the crude oil and petroleum product pricing and allocation regulations issued under the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s751">15 U.S.C. 751</ref> et seq.] or the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6d42-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> <ref href="/us/pl/97/377/s155">section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d43-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on collection of certain deficiency funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit a report each fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 1987, to such committees on the status of collections by the Secretary of deficiency funds to be deposited into the M.D.L. No. 378 escrow account established by the United States District Court for the District of Kansas until all such deficiency funds have been paid. The Secretary shall, in a manner substantially similar to that required by <ref href="/us/pl/97/377/s155">section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref> with respect to amounts disbursed under such section, monitor the disposition by the States of any funds disbursed to the States by the court pursuant to the opinion and order of such District Court, dated <date date="1986-07-07">July 7, 1986</date>, with respect to In Re: the Department of Energy Stripper Well Exemption Litigation, M.D.L. No. 378, including the use of such funds for administrative costs and attorneys fees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d44-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on amount estimated to be available for indirect restitution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall transmit, on March 1 of each year beginning with 1987 and continuing until all the restitutionary amounts to which <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4501/a">section 4501(a) of this title</ref> applies have been collected and disbursed as provided in this chapter, a report to such committees containing an estimate of the amount that will be determined under section 4502(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002516">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002516"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title to be the excess amount for purposes of section 4502(d)(1)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002516">1</ref> of this title for the fiscal year beginning the next October 1.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a3b6d45-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4505/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Receipt by committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The reports required by this chapter shall be transmitted to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a3b6d46-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIII/s3006">Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3006</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1886">100 Stat. 1886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a3b6d47-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a3b6d48-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a3b6d49-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/159">Pub. L. 93–159</ref>, <date date="1973-11-27">Nov. 27, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/628">87 Stat. 628</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 16A (§ 751 et seq.) of this title, was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s760g">section 760g of this title</ref>, which provided for the expiration of the President’s authority under that chapter on <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/379">Pub. L. 91–379</ref>, <date date="1970-08-15">Aug. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/799">84 Stat. 799</ref>, formerly set out as an Economic Stabilization Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1904">section 1904 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/377/s155">Section 155 of Public Law 97–377</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2), (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/97/377/s155">section 155 of Pub. L. 97–377</ref>, title I, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1919">96 Stat. 1919</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4502(c) and (d) of this title, referred to in subsec. (c), was repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4502/e">section 4502(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a3b6d4a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7a3b6d4b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
