<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a3b6dd1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621"><num value="4621">§ 4621.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Semiconductors and related microelectronic devices are key components in computers, telecommunications equipment, advanced defense systems, and other equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Aggregate sales of such equipment, in excess of $230,000,000,000 annually, comprise a significant portion of the gross national product of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The leadership position of the United States in advanced technology is threatened by (A) competition from foreign businesses which is promoted and facilitated by the increasingly active involvement of foreign governments, and (B) other changes in the nature of foreign competition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The principal cause of the relative shift in strength of the United States and its semiconductor competitors is the establishment of a long-term goal by a major foreign competitor to achieve world superiority in semiconductor research and manufacturing technology and the pursuit of such goal by that competitor by effectively marshalling all of the government, industry, and academic resources needed to achieve that goal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Although the United States semiconductor industry leads all other principal United States industries in terms of its reinvestment in research and development, that has been insufficient by worldwide standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Electronic equipment is essential to protect the national security of the United States, as is evidenced by the allocation of approximately 35 percent of the total research, development, and procurement budgets of the Department of Defense to electronics research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The Armed Forces of the United States will eventually depend extensively on foreign semiconductor technology unless significant steps are taken, and taken at an early date, to retain United States leadership in semiconductor technology research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dd9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> It is in the interests of the national security and national economy of the United States for the United States to regain its traditional world leadership in the field of semiconductors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6dda-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The most effective means of regaining that leadership is through a joint research effort of the Federal Government and private industry of the United States to improve semiconductor manufacturing technology and to develop practical uses for such technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6ddb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> In order to meet the national defense needs of the United States and to insure the continued vitality of a commercial manufacturing base in the United States, it is essential that priority be given to the development, demonstration, and advancement of the semiconductor technology base in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a3b6ddc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4621/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The national laboratories of the Department of Energy are a major national research resource, and the extensive involvement of such laboratories in the semiconductor research initiatives of the Federal Government and private industry would be an effective use of such laboratories and would help insure the success of such initiatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7a3b6ddd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dC/tI/s3141">Pub. L. 100–180, div. C, title I, § 3141</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1241">101 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
