<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a42994a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721"><num value="4721">§ 4721.</num><heading> United States and Foreign Commercial Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42994b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42994c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Commerce shall establish, within the International Trade Administration, the United States and Foreign Commercial Service. The Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, transfer to the Commercial Service the functions and personnel of the United States and Foreign Commercial Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42994d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General; other personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The head of the Commercial Service shall be the Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the Commercial Service, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the Commercial Service may appoint Commercial Service Officers and such other personnel as may be necessary to carry out the activities of the Commercial Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42994e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with foreign policy objectives</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall take the necessary steps to ensure that the activities of the Commercial Service are carried out in a manner consistent with United States foreign policy objectives, and the Secretary shall consult regularly with the Secretary of State in order to comply with this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42994f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of chief of mission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All activities of the Commercial Service shall be subject to section 207 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3927">22 U.S.C. 3927</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429950-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commercial Service shall place primary emphasis on the promotion of exports of goods and services from the United States, particularly by small businesses and medium-sized businesses, and on the protection of United States business interests abroad by carrying out activities such as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429951-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identifying United States businesses with the potential to export goods and services and providing such businesses with advice and information on establishing export businesses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429952-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing United States exporters with information on economic conditions, market opportunities, the status of the intellectual property system in such country, and the legal and regulatory environment within foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429953-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> providing United States exporters with information and advice on the necessary adaptation of product design and marketing strategy to meet the differing cultural and technical requirements of foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429954-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> providing United States exporters with actual leads and an introduction to contacts within foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429955-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> assisting United States exporters in locating reliable sources of business services in foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429956-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> assisting United States exporters in their dealings with foreign governments and enterprises owned by foreign governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429957-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> assisting the coordination of the efforts of State and local agencies and private organizations which seek to promote United States business interests abroad so as to maximize their effectiveness and minimize the duplication of efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429958-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> utilizing district and foreign offices as one-stop shops for United States exporters by providing exporters with information on all export promotion and export finance activities of the Federal Government, assisting exporters in identifying which Federal programs may be of greatest assistance, and assisting exporters in making contact with the Federal programs identified; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429959-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> providing United States exporters and export finance institutions with information on all financing and insurance programs of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Trade and Development Program, and the Small Business Administration, including providing assistance in completing applications for such programs and working with exporters and export finance institutions to address any deficiencies in such applications that have been submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42995a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Offices</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42995b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commercial Service shall conduct its activities at a headquarters office, district offices located in major United States cities, and foreign offices located in major foreign cities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42995c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Headquarters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The headquarters of the Commercial Service shall provide such managerial, administrative, research, and other services as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out the purposes of the Commercial Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42995d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> District offices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish district offices of the Commercial Service in any United States city in a region in which the Secretary determines that there is a need for Federal Government export assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42995e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreign offices</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42995f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary may, after consultation with the Secretary of State, establish foreign offices of the Commercial Service. These offices shall be located in foreign cities in regions in which the Secretary determines there are significant business opportunities for United States exporters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429960-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may, in consultation with the Secretary of State, assign to the foreign offices Commercial Service Officers and such other personnel as the Secretary considers necessary. In employing Commercial Service Officers and such other personnel, the Secretary shall use the Foreign Service personnel system in accordance with the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.]. The Secretary shall designate a Commercial Officer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002531">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002531"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Commercial Service Officer”.</note> as head of each foreign office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429961-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of State shall attach the Commercial Service Officers and other employees of each foreign office to the diplomatic mission of the United States in the country in which that foreign office is located, and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by Foreign Service personnel of comparable rank and salary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429962-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> For purposes of official representation, the senior Commercial Service Officer in each country shall be considered to be the senior commercial representative of the United States in that country, and the United States chief of mission in that country shall accord that officer all privileges and responsibilities appropriate to the position of senior commercial representative of other countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429963-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The Secretary of State is authorized, upon the request of the Secretary, to provide office space, equipment, facilities, and such other administrative and clerical services as may be required for the operation of the foreign offices. The Secretary is authorized to reimburse or advance funds to the Secretary of State for such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429964-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/c/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The authority of the Secretary under this paragraph shall be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4802">section 4802 of title 22</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429965-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rank of Commercial Service Officers in foreign missions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429966-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Minister-Counselor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to designate up to 16 United States missions abroad at which the senior Commercial Service Officer will be able to use the diplomatic title of Minister-Counselor. The Secretary of State shall accord the diplomatic title of Minister-Counselor to the senior Commercial Service Officer assigned to a United States mission so designated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429967-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consul General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any United States consulate in which a vacancy occurs in the position of Consul General, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, shall consider filling that vacancy with a Commercial Service Officer if the primary functions of the consulate are of a commercial nature and if there are significant business opportunities for United States exporters in the region in which the consulate is located.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429968-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Information dissemination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out subsection (b)(7), to lessen the cost of distribution of information produced by the Commercial Service, and to make that information more readily available, the Secretary should establish a system for distributing that information in those areas where no district offices of the Commercial Service are located. Distributors of the information should be State export promotion agencies or private export and trade promotion associations. The distribution system should be consistent with cost recovery objectives of the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429969-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation in Federal financing and insurance programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To assist the Commercial Service in carrying out subsection (b)(9), and consistent with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635i–7">section 635i–7 of title 12</ref>, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Trade and Development Program, and the Small Business Administration shall each—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42996a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide to the Commercial Service complete and current information on all of its programs and financing practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42996b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> undertake a training program regarding such programs and practices for Commercial Service Officers who are designated by the Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the Commercial Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a42996c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Audits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Inspector General of the Department of Commerce shall perform periodic audits of the operations of the Commercial Service, but at least once every 3 years. The Inspector General shall report to the Congress the results of each such audit. In addition to an overview of the activities and effectiveness of Commercial Service operations, the audit shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42996d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an evaluation of the current placement of domestic personnel and recommendations for transferring personnel among district offices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42996e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an evaluation of the current placement of foreign-based personnel and recommendations for transferring such personnel in response to newly emerging business opportunities for United States exporters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42996f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an evaluation of the personnel system and its management, including the recruitment, assignment, promotion, and performance appraisal of personnel, the use of limited appointees, and the “time-in-class” system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429970-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Report by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the feasibility and desirability, the progress to date, the present status, and the 5-year outlook, of the comprehensive integration of the functions and personnel of the foreign and domestic export promotion operations within the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429971-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a429972-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429973-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429974-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “Commercial Service” means the United States and Foreign Commercial Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429975-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the term “United States exporter” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a429976-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a United States citizen;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a429977-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a corporation, partnership, or other association created under the laws of the United States or of any State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a429978-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a foreign corporation, partnership, or other association, more than 95 percent of which is owned by persons described in subparagraphs (A) and (B),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">that exports, or seeks to export, goods or services produced in the United States;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a429979-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “small business” means any small business concern as defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">section 632 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42997a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a42997b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s4721/j/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “United States” means the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a42997c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tII/s2301">Pub. L. 100–418, title II, § 2301</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1338">102 Stat. 1338</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/tII">Pub. L. 102–429, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 203, 205, <date date="1992-10-21">Oct. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2201">106 Stat. 2201</ref>, 2204; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dF/tVI/s1470/d">Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3516">132 Stat. 3516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a42997d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a42997e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a42997f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (c)(4)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 52 (§ 3901 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7a429980-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s2301">section 2301 of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>. Subsec. (i) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s2301">section 2301 of Pub. L. 100–418</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a429981-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> substituted “United States International Development Finance Corporation” for “Overseas Private Investment Corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> substituted “United States International Development Finance Corporation” for “Overseas Private Investment Corporation” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429">Pub. L. 102–429</ref>, §§ 202, 203(a), added pars. (8) and (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s205">Pub. L. 102–429, § 205</ref>, substituted “16” for “8”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/429/s203/b">Pub. L. 102–429, § 203(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and redesignated former subsecs. (f) to (i) as (g) to (j), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a429982-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7a429983-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> effective at the end of the transition period, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9681">section 9681 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1470/w">section 1470(w) of Pub. L. 115–254</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s905">section 905 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7a429984-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (g) of this section relating to reporting results of audits to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 53 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
