<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a49c54b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s5110"><num value="5110">§ 5110.</num><heading> Drug-free workplace</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a49c54c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s5110/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> No department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States receiving funds authorized to be appropriated under this chapter for fiscal year 1989, fiscal year 1990, fiscal year 1991, fiscal year 1992, fiscal year 1993, fiscal year 1994, fiscal year 1995, fiscal year 1996, and fiscal year 1997, or under any other Act authorizing appropriations for fiscal year 1989, fiscal year 1990, fiscal year 1991, fiscal year 1992, fiscal year 1993, fiscal year 1994, fiscal year 1995, fiscal year 1996, and fiscal year 1997, shall obligate or spend any such funds, unless such department, agency, or instrumentality has in place, and will continue to administer in good faith, a written policy designed to ensure that all of its work places are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.]) by the officers and employees of such department, agency, or instrumentality.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7a49c54d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s5110/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> No funds so authorized to be appropriated to any such department, agency, or instrumentality shall be available for payment in connection with any grant, contract, or other agreement, unless the recipient of such grant, contract, or party to such agreement, as the case may be, has in place and will continue to administer in good faith a written policy, adopted by such recipient, contractor, or party’s board of directors or other governing authority, satisfactory to the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality making such payment, designed to ensure that all of the workplace of such recipient, contractor, or party are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.]) by the officers and employees of such recipient, contractor, or party.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a49c54e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/680/s11">Pub. L. 100–680, § 11</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4077">102 Stat. 4077</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXI/s2106/a/5">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3070">106 Stat. 3070</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a49c54f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a49c550-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a49c551-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in text, is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 801 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a49c552-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> substituted “fiscal year 1991, fiscal year 1992, fiscal year 1993, fiscal year 1994, fiscal year 1995, fiscal year 1996, and fiscal year 1997” for “or fiscal year 1991” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a49c553-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id7a49c554-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/685/tII/s215">Pub. L. 100–685, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4093">102 Stat. 4093</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/685/tII/s215">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> No funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act, or under any other Act authorizing appropriations for fiscal year 1989 through 1993 for the [National Aeronautics and Space] Administration, shall be obligated or expended unless the Administration has in place, and will continue to administer in good faith, a written policy designed to ensure that all of its workplaces are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.]) by the officers and employees of the Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> No funds authorized to be appropriated to the Administration for fiscal years 1989 through 1993 shall be available for payment in connection with any grant, contract, or other agreement, unless the recipient of such grant, contractor, or party to such agreement, as the case may be, has in place and will continue to administer in good faith a written policy, adopted by the board of directors or other government authority of such recipient, contractor, or party, satisfactory to the Administrator of the [National Aeronautics and Space] Administration, designed to ensure that all of the workplaces of such recipient, contractor, or party are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defined in the Controlled Substances Act) by the officers and employees of such recipient, contractor, or party.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The provisions of this section, and the provisions of the Steel and Aluminum Energy Conservation and Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s5101">15 U.S.C. 5101</ref> et seq.], the National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1989 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/519/tI">Pub. L. 100–519, title I</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2589">102 Stat. 2589</ref>], the National Science Foundation Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1989 and 1990 [probably means <ref href="/us/pl/100/570">Pub. L. 100–570</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2865">102 Stat. 2865</ref>], and the National Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research Act of 1988 [probably means S. 1081, One Hundredth Congress, which was pocket vetoed], relating to a drug-free workplace, shall not be effective until <date date="1989-01-16">January 16, 1989</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
