<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a49c579-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s5203"><num value="5203">§ 5203.</num><heading> Department of Energy</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a program in superconductivity research and development. Within 180 days after <date date="1988-11-19">November 19, 1988</date>, and for the two succeeding years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit annual reports on the implementation of technology transfer activities under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.] and related legislation with respect to superconductivity research and development to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate. Such report shall include recommendations for improvements in the technology transfer between government and industry, and in the management of property developed or made at the National Laboratories.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7a49c57a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/697/s4">Pub. L. 100–697, § 4</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4615">102 Stat. 4615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a49c57b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a49c57c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a49c57d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/480">Pub. L. 96–480</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2311">94 Stat. 2311</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 63 (§ 3701 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">section 3701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
