<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78a60054-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s521"><num value="521">§ 521.</num><heading> Fishing industry; associations authorized; “aquatic products” defined; marketing agencies; requirements</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Persons engaged in the fishery industry, as fishermen, catching, collecting, or cultivating aquatic products, or as planters of aquatic products on public or private beds, may act together in associations, corporate or otherwise, with or without capital stock, in collectively catching, producing, preparing for market, processing, handling, and marketing in interstate and foreign commerce, such products of said persons so engaged.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “aquatic products” includes all commercial products of aquatic life in both fresh and salt water, as carried on in the several States, the District of Columbia, the several Territories of the United States, the insular possessions, or other places under the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such associations may have marketing agencies in common, and such associations and their members may make the necessary contracts and agreements to effect such purposes: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such associations are operated for the mutual benefit of the members thereof, and conform to one or both of the following requirements:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">First. That no member of the association is allowed more than one vote because of the amount of stock or membership capital he may own therein; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Second. That the association does not pay dividends on stock or membership capital in excess of 8 per centum per annum.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and in any case to the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Third. That the association shall not deal in the products of nonmembers to an amount greater in value than such as are handled by it for members.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id78a60055-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-25/ch742/s1">June 25, 1934, ch. 742, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1213">48 Stat. 1213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
