<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77c849c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53"><num value="53">§ 53.</num><heading> False advertisements; injunctions and restraining orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c849c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Power of Commission; jurisdiction of courts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Commission has reason to believe—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77c849c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that any person, partnership, or corporation is engaged in, or is about to engage in, the dissemination or the causing of the dissemination of any advertisement in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s52">section 52 of this title</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77c849c5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that the enjoining thereof pending the issuance of a complaint by the Commission under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">section 45 of this title</ref>, and until such complaint is dismissed by the Commission or set aside by the court on review, or the order of the Commission to cease and desist made thereon has become final within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">section 45 of this title</ref>, would be to the interest of the public,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commission by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose may bring suit in a district court of the United States or in the United States court of any Territory, to enjoin the dissemination or the causing of the dissemination of such advertisement. Upon proper showing a temporary injunction or restraining order shall be granted without bond. Any suit may be brought where such person, partnership, or corporation resides or transacts business, or wherever venue is proper under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1391">section 1391 of title 28</ref>. In addition, the court may, if the court determines that the interests of justice require that any other person, partnership, or corporation should be a party in such suit, cause such other person, partnership, or corporation to be added as a party without regard to whether venue is otherwise proper in the district in which the suit is brought. In any suit under this section, process may be served on any person, partnership, or corporation wherever it may be found.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77c849c6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary restraining orders; preliminary injunctions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Commission has reason to believe—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77c849c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that any person, partnership, or corporation is violating, or is about to violate, any provision of law enforced by the Federal Trade Commission, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77c849c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that the enjoining thereof pending the issuance of a complaint by the Commission and until such complaint is dismissed by the Commission or set aside by the court on review, or until the order of the Commission made thereon has become final, would be in the interest of the public—</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commission by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose may bring suit in a district court of the United States to enjoin any such act or practice. Upon a proper showing that, weighing the equities and considering the Commission’s likelihood of ultimate success, such action would be in the public interest, and after notice to the defendant, a temporary restraining order or a preliminary injunction may be granted without bond: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if a complaint is not filed within such period (not exceeding 20 days) as may be specified by the court after issuance of the temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction, the order or injunction shall be dissolved by the court and be of no further force and effect: <i>Provided further</i>, That in proper cases the Commission may seek, and after proper proof, the court may issue, a permanent injunction. Any suit may be brought where such person, partnership, or corporation resides or transacts business, or wherever venue is proper under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1391">section 1391 of title 28</ref>. In addition, the court may, if the court determines that the interests of justice require that any other person, partnership, or corporation should be a party in such suit, cause such other person, partnership, or corporation to be added as a party without regard to whether venue is otherwise proper in the district in which the suit is brought. In any suit under this section, process may be served on any person, partnership, or corporation wherever it may be found.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cabac9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Service of process; proof of service</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any process of the Commission under this section may be served by any person duly authorized by the Commission—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cabaca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by delivering a copy of such process to the person to be served, to a member of the partnership to be served, or to the president, secretary, or other executive officer or a director of the corporation to be served;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cabacb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> by leaving a copy of such process at the residence or the principal office or place of business of such person, partnership, or corporation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cabacc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> by mailing a copy of such process by registered mail or certified mail addressed to such person, partnership, or corporation at his, or her, or its residence, principal office, or principal place or business.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The verified return by the person serving such process setting forth the manner of such service shall be proof of the same.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cabacd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception of periodical publications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever it appears to the satisfaction of the court in the case of a newspaper, magazine, periodical, or other publication, published at regular intervals—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cabace-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that restraining the dissemination of a false advertisement in any particular issue of such publication would delay the delivery of such issue after the regular time therefor, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77cabacf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s53/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that such delay would be due to the method by which the manufacture and distribution of such publication is customarily conducted by the publisher in accordance with sound business practice, and not to any method or device adopted for the evasion of this section or to prevent or delay the issuance of an injunction or restraining order with respect to such false advertisement or any other advertisement,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the court shall exclude such issue from the operation of the restraining order or injunction.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77cabad0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311/s13">Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, § 13</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1938-03-21/ch49/s4">Mar. 21, 1938, ch. 49, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/114">52 Stat. 114</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/153/tIV/s408/f">Pub. L. 93–153, title IV, § 408(f)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/592">87 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/312/s10">Pub. L. 103–312, § 10</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1695">108 Stat. 1695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77cabad1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77cabad2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77cabad3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/312/s10/a">Pub. L. 103–312, § 10(a)</ref>, in concluding provisions, substituted “Any suit may be brought where such person, partnership, or corporation resides or transacts business, or wherever venue is proper under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1391">section 1391 of title 28</ref>. In addition, the court may, if the court determines that the interests of justice require that any other person, partnership, or corporation should be a party in such suit, cause such other person, partnership, or corporation to be added as a party without regard to whether venue is otherwise proper in the district in which the suit is brought. In any suit under this section, process may be served on any person, partnership, or corporation wherever it may be found.” for “Any such suit shall be brought in the district in which such person, partnership, or corporation resides or transacts business.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/312/s10/b">Pub. L. 103–312, § 10(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/153">Pub. L. 93–153</ref> added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77cabad4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77cabad5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 8 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1264">64 Stat. 1264</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
