<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77cd0569-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b"><num value="57b">§ 57b.</num><heading> Civil actions for violations of rules and cease and desist orders respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cd056a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Suits by Commission against persons, partnerships, or corporations; jurisdiction; relief for dishonest or fraudulent acts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cd056b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If any person, partnership, or corporation violates any rule under this subchapter respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices (other than an interpretive rule, or a rule violation of which the Commission has provided is not an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/a">section 45(a) of this title</ref>), then the Commission may commence a civil action against such person, partnership, or corporation for relief under subsection (b) in a United States district court or in any court of competent jurisdiction of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cd056c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If any person, partnership, or corporation engages in any unfair or deceptive act or practice (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/a/1">section 45(a)(1) of this title</ref>) with respect to which the Commission has issued a final cease and desist order which is applicable to such person, partnership, or corporation, then the Commission may commence a civil action against such person, partnership, or corporation in a United States district court or in any court of competent jurisdiction of a State. If the Commission satisfies the court that the act or practice to which the cease and desist order relates is one which a reasonable man would have known under the circumstances was dishonest or fraudulent, the court may grant relief under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cd056d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Nature of relief available</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The court in an action under subsection (a) shall have jurisdiction to grant such relief as the court finds necessary to redress injury to consumers or other persons, partnerships, and corporations resulting from the rule violation or the unfair or deceptive act or practice, as the case may be. Such relief may include, but shall not be limited to, rescission or reformation of contracts, the refund of money or return of property, the payment of damages, and public notification respecting the rule violation or the unfair or deceptive act or practice, as the case may be; except that nothing in this subsection is intended to authorize the imposition of any exemplary or punitive damages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cd056e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conclusiveness of findings of Commission in cease and desist proceedings; notice of judicial proceedings to injured persons, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cd056f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If (A) a cease and desist order issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/b">section 45(b) of this title</ref> has become final under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/g">section 45(g) of this title</ref> with respect to any person’s, partnership’s, or corporation’s rule violation or unfair or deceptive act or practice, and (B) an action under this section is brought with respect to such person’s, partnership’s, or corporation’s rule violation or act or practice, then the findings of the Commission as to the material facts in the proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/b">section 45(b) of this title</ref> with respect to such person’s, partnership’s, or corporation’s rule violation or act or practice, shall be conclusive unless (i) the terms of such cease and desist order expressly provide that the Commission’s findings shall not be conclusive, or (ii) the order became final by reason of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/g/1">section 45(g)(1) of this title</ref>, in which case such finding shall be conclusive if supported by evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77cd0570-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The court shall cause notice of an action under this section to be given in a manner which is reasonably calculated, under all of the circumstances, to apprise the persons, partnerships, and corporations allegedly injured by the defendant’s rule violation or act or practice of the pendency of such action. Such notice may, in the discretion of the court, be given by publication.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cd0571-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for bringing of actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No action may be brought by the Commission under this section more than 3 years after the rule violation to which an action under subsection (a)(1) relates, or the unfair or deceptive act or practice to which an action under subsection (a)(2) relates; except that if a cease and desist order with respect to any person’s, partnership’s, or corporation’s rule violation or unfair or deceptive act or practice has become final and such order was issued in a proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45/b">section 45(b) of this title</ref> which was commenced not later than 3 years after the rule violation or act or practice occurred, a civil action may be commenced under this section against such person, partnership, or corporation at any time before the expiration of one year after such order becomes final.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77cd0572-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s57b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of additional Federal or State remedies; other authority of Commission unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Remedies provided in this section are in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other remedy or right of action provided by State or Federal law. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77cd0573-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311/s19">Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, § 19</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/637/tII/s206/a">Pub. L. 93–637, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2201">88 Stat. 2201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77cd0574-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77cd0575-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id77cd0576-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/637/tII/s206/b">Pub. L. 93–637, title II, § 206(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2202">88 Stat. 2202</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/637/tII/s206/b">
<inline>“The amendment made by subsection (a) of this section [enacting this section] shall not apply to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any violation of a rule to the extent that such violation occurred before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>], or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any act or practice with respect to which the Commission issues a cease-and-desist order, to the extent that such act or practice occurred before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>], unless such order was issued after such date and the person, partnership or corporation against whom such an order was issued had been notified in the complaint, or in the notice or order attached thereto, that consumer redress may be sought.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
