<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78c03eea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b"><num value="634b">§ 634b.</num><heading> Primary functions of Office of Advocacy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The primary functions of the Office of Advocacy shall be to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03eeb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> examine the role of small business in the American economy and the contribution which small business can make in improving competition, encouraging economic and social mobility for all citizens, restraining inflation, spurring production, expanding employment opportunities, increasing productivity, promoting exports, stimulating innovation and entrepreneurship, and providing an avenue through which new and untested products and services can be brought to the marketplace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03eec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assess the effectiveness of existing Federal subsidy and assistance programs for small business and the desirability of reducing the emphasis on such existing programs and increasing the emphasis on general assistance programs designed to benefit all small businesses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03eed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> measure the direct costs and other effects of government regulation on small businesses; and make legislative and nonlegislative proposals for eliminating excessive or unnecessary regulations of small businesses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03eee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> determine the impact of the tax structure on small businesses and make legislative and other proposals for altering the tax structure to enable all small businesses to realize their potential for contributing to the improvement of the Nation’s economic well-being;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03eef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> study the ability of financial markets and institutions to meet small business credit needs and determine the impact of government demands for credit on small businesses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> determine financial resource availability and to recommend methods for delivery of financial assistance to minority enterprises, including methods for securing equity capital, for generating markets for goods and services, for providing effective business education, more effective management and technical assistance, and training, and for assistance in complying with Federal, State, and local law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> evaluate the efforts of Federal agencies, business and industry to assist minority enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> make such other recommendations as may be appropriate to assist the development and strengthening of minority and other small business enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> recommend specific measures for creating an environment in which all businesses will have the opportunity to complete <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002177">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002177"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “compete”.</note> effectively and expand to their full potential, and to ascertain the common reasons, if any, for small business successes and failures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> determine the desirability of developing a set of rational, objective criteria to be used to define small business, and to develop such criteria, if appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> advise, cooperate with, and consult with, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States with respect to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s504/e">section 504(e) of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78c03ef6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s634b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> evaluate the efforts of each department and agency of the United States, and of private industry, to assist small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/q">section 632(q) of this title</ref>, and small business concerns owned and controlled by serviced-disabled <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002178">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002178"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> veterans, as defined in such <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/q">section 632(q) of this title</ref>, and to provide statistical information on the utilization of such programs by such small business concerns, and to make appropriate recommendations to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and to the Congress in order to promote the establishment and growth of those small business concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id78c03ef7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/305/tII/s202">Pub. L. 94–305, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1976-06-04">June 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/668">90 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/481/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 96–481, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2327">94 Stat. 2327</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/50/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 106–50, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/250">113 Stat. 250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78c03ef8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78c03ef9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id78c03efa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Small Business Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78c03efb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Par. (12). <ref href="/us/pl/106/50">Pub. L. 106–50</ref> added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/96/481">Pub. L. 96–481</ref> added par. (11).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78c03efc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78c03efd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/481">Pub. L. 96–481</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, and applicable to adversary adjudication as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s504/b/1/C">section 504(b)(1)(C) of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and to civil actions and adversary adjudications described in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2412">section 2412 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, which are pending on, or commenced on or after <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/481/s208">section 208 of Pub. L. 96–481</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s504">section 504 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78c03efe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Administrative Conference of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Administrative Conference of United States, see provision of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/104/52">Pub. L. 104–52</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s591">section 591 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78c03eff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Advocacy Study of Paperwork and Tax Impact</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/403/tVI/s613">Pub. L. 103–403, title VI, § 613</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4205">108 Stat. 4205</ref>, directed Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to conduct a study of the impact of all Federal regulatory, paperwork, and tax requirements upon small business, and report its findings to Congress not later than 1 year after <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
