<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7900a29a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s640"><num value="640">§ 640.</num><heading> Voluntary agreements among small-business concerns</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7900a29b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s640/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with President</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to consult with representatives of small-business concerns with a view to encouraging the making by such persons with the approval of the President of voluntary agreements and programs to further the objectives of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7900a29c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s640/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from certain laws; findings and requests; filing and publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No act or omission to act pursuant to this chapter which occurs while this chapter is in effect, if requested by the President pursuant to a voluntary agreement or program approved under subsection (a) of this section and found by the President to be in the public interest as contributing to the national defense, shall be construed to be within the prohibitions of the antitrust laws or the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] of the United States. A copy of each such request intended to be within the coverage of this section, and any modification or withdrawal thereof, shall be furnished to the Attorney General and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission when made, and it shall be published in the Federal Register unless publication thereof would, in the opinion of the President, endanger the national security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7900a29d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s640/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority; consultation; approval of requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority granted in subsection (b) of this section shall be delegated only (1) to an official who shall for the purpose of such delegation be required to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, (2) upon the condition that such official consult with the Attorney General and the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission not less than ten days before making any request or finding thereunder, and (3) upon the condition that such official obtain the approval of the Attorney General to any request thereunder before making the request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7900a29e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s640/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of section when request or finding withdrawn</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon withdrawal of any request or finding hereunder, or upon withdrawal by the Attorney General of his approval of the voluntary agreement or program on which the request or finding is based, the provisions of this section shall not apply to any subsequent act, or omission to act, by reason of such finding or request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7900a29f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/536/s2/s11">Pub. L. 85–536, § 2[11]</ref>, <date date="1958-07-18">July 18, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/394">72 Stat. 394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7900a2a0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7900a2a1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7900a2a2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id7900a2a3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior similar provisions were contained in section 217 of <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-30/ch282/tII">act July 30, 1953, ch. 282, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/239">67 Stat. 239</ref>, which was previously classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s646">section 646 of this title</ref>. The provisions of section 211 of act <date date="1953-07-30">July 30, 1953</date>, formerly classified to this section, were transferred to section 2[10] of <ref href="/us/pl/85/536">Pub. L. 85–536</ref>, and are classified to section 639(d), (f) of this title. See Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7900a2a4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7900a2a5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10493. Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10493, <date date="1953-10-14">Oct. 14, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 6583, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The functions conferred upon the President by section 217 of the Small Business Act of 1953 [covered by this section] are hereby delegated to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and shall be carried out as provided in the said section 217.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. There is hereby delegated to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration so much of the functions conferred upon the President by section 708 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4558">50 U.S.C. 4558</ref>], as necessary to effect changes in the composition of, or to take other action respecting voluntary agreements and programs relating to, small-business production pools approved prior to <date date="1953-07-31">July 31, 1953</date>, pursuant to the said section 708 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4558">50 U.S.C. 4558</ref>]: <i>Provided</i>, That this section shall not be construed as limiting the authority of the Director of the Office of Defense Mobilization under Executive Order No. 10480 of <date date="1953-08-14">August 14, 1953</date> (18 F.R. 4939) [formerly set out as a note under section 2153 of the former Appendix to Title 50]. The functions delegated to the Administrator by this section shall be carried out as provided in section 708 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4558">50 U.S.C. 4558</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. Without prejudice to any action taken thereunder, Executive Order No. 10370 of <date date="1952-07-07">July 7, 1952</date> (17 F.R. 6141), is hereby revoked.</p>
<signature>
<name>Dwight D. Eisenhower.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
