<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7911448d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650"><num value="650">§ 650.</num><heading> Supervisory and enforcement authority for small business lending companies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7911448e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911448f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to supervise the safety and soundness of small business lending companies and non-Federally regulated lenders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79114490-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to small business lending companies to set capital standards to regulate, to examine, and to enforce laws governing such companies, in accordance with the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79114491-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with respect to non-Federally regulated lenders to regulate, to examine, and to enforce laws governing the lending activities of such lenders under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">section 636(a) of this title</ref> in accordance with the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79114492-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Capital directive</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79114493-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Administrator determines that a small business lending company is being operated in an imprudent manner, the Administrator may, in addition to any other action authorized by law, issue a directive to such company to increase capital to such level as the Administrator determines will result in the safe and sound operation of such company.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79114494-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator may not delegate the authority granted under paragraph (1) except to an Associate Deputy Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id79114495-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall issue regulations outlining the conditions under which the Administrator may determine the level of capital pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79114496-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a small business lending company violates this chapter, the Administrator may institute a civil action in an appropriate district court to terminate the rights, privileges, and franchises of the company under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id79114497-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation or suspension of loan authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79114498-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator may revoke or suspend the authority of a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender to make, service or liquidate business loans authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">section 636(a) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79114499-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for false statements knowingly made in any written submission required under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911449a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for omission of a material fact from any written submission required under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911449b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for willful or repeated violation of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911449c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> for willful or repeated violation of any condition imposed by the Administrator with respect to any application, request, or agreement under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911449d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> for violation of any cease and desist order of the Administrator under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id7911449e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Administrator may revoke or suspend authority under paragraph (1) only after a hearing under subsection (f). The Administrator may delegate power to revoke or suspend authority under paragraph (1) only to the Deputy Administrator and only if the Administrator is unavailable to take such action.</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7911449f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator, after finding extraordinary circumstances and in order to protect the financial or legal position of the United States, may issue a suspension order without conducting a hearing pursuant to subsection (f). If the Administrator issues a suspension under the preceding sentence, the Administrator shall within two business days follow the procedures set forth in subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id791144a0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any suspension under paragraph (1) shall remain in effect until the Administrator makes a decision pursuant to subparagraph (4) to permanently revoke the authority of the small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender, suspend the authority for a time certain, or terminate the suspension.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender must notify borrowers of a revocation and that a new entity has been appointed to service their loans. The Administrator or an employee of the Administration designated by the Administrator may provide such notice to the borrower.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any revocation or suspension under paragraph (1) shall be made by the Administrator except that the Administrator shall delegate to an administrative law judge as that term is used in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3105">section 3105 of title 5</ref> the authority to conduct any hearing required under subsection (f). The Administrator shall base the decision to revoke on the record of the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144a3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Cease and desist order</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Where a small business lending company, a non-Federally regulated lender, or other person violates this chapter or is engaging or is about to engage in any acts or practices which constitute or will constitute a violation of this chapter, the Administrator may order, after the opportunity for hearing pursuant to subsection (f), the company, lender, or other person to cease and desist from such action or failure to act. The Administrator may delegate the authority under the preceding sentence only to the Deputy Administrator and only if the Administrator is unavailable to take such action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator, after finding extraordinary circumstances and in order to protect the financial or legal position of the United States, may issue a cease and desist order without conducting a hearing pursuant to subsection (f). If the Administrator issues a cease and desist order under the preceding sentence, the Administrator shall within two business days follow the procedures set forth in subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Administrator may further order such small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender or other person to take such action or to refrain from such action as the Administrator deems necessary to insure compliance with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A cease and desist order under this subsection may also provide for the suspension of authority to lend in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144a8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure for revocation or suspension of loan authority and for cease and desist order</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144a9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before revoking or suspending authority under subsection (d) or issuing a cease and desist order under subsection (e), the Administrator shall serve an order to show cause upon the small business lending company, non-Federally regulated lender, or other person why an order revoking or suspending the authority or a cease and desist order should not be issued. The order to show cause shall contain a statement of the matters of fact and law asserted by the Administrator and the legal authority and jurisdiction under which a hearing is to be held, and shall set forth that a hearing will be held before an administrative law judge at a time and place stated in the order. Such hearing shall be conducted pursuant to the provisions of sections 554, 556, and 557 of title 5. If after hearing, or a waiver thereof, the Administrator determines that an order revoking or suspending the authority or a cease and desist order should be issued, the Administrator shall promptly issue such order, which shall include a statement of the findings of the Administrator and the grounds and reasons therefor and specify the effective date of the order, and shall cause the order to be served on the small business lending company, non-Federally regulated lender, or other person involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144aa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Witnesses summoned before the Administrator shall be paid by the party at whose instance they were called the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144ab-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A cease and desist order, suspension or revocation issued by the Administrator, after the hearing under this subsection is final agency action for purposes of chapter 7 of title 5. An adversely aggrieved party shall have 20 days from the date of issuance of the cease and desist order, suspension or revocation, to seek judicial review in an appropriate district court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144ac-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal or suspension of management official</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144ad-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this section, the term “management official” means, with respect to a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender, an officer, director, general partner, manager, employee, agent, or other participant in the management of the affairs of the company’s or lender’s activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">section 636(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144ae-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal of management official</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144af-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator may serve upon any management official a written notice of its intention to remove that management official if, in the opinion of the Administrator, the management official—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id791144b0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> willfully and knowingly commits a substantial violation of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> this chapter;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any regulation issued under this chapter;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> a final cease-and-desist order under this chapter; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> any agreement by the management official, the small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender under this chapter; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id791144b5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> willfully and knowingly commits a substantial breach of a fiduciary duty of that person as a management official and the violation or breach of fiduciary duty is one involving personal dishonesty on the part of such management official.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144b6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A notice under subparagraph (A) shall contain a statement of the facts constituting grounds therefor and shall fix a time and place at which a hearing, conducted pursuant to sections 554, 556, and 557 of title 5, will be held thereon.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144b7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id791144b8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A hearing under subparagraph (B) shall be held not earlier than 30 days and later than 60 days after the date of service of notice of the hearing, unless an earlier or a later date is set by the Administrator at the request of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144b9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the management official, and for good cause shown; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144ba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the Attorney General.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id791144bb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Unless the management official appears at a hearing under this paragraph in person or by a duly authorized representative, the management official shall be deemed to have consented to the issuance of an order of removal under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144bc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Order of removal</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id791144bd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the event of consent under subparagraph (C)(ii), or if upon the record made at a hearing under this subsection, the Administrator finds that any of the grounds specified in the notice of removal has been established, the Administrator may issue such orders of removal from office as the Administrator deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id791144be-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectiveness</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">An order under clause (i) shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144bf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> take effect 30 days after the date of service upon the subject small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender and the management official concerned (except in the case of an order issued upon consent as described in subparagraph (C)(ii), which shall become effective at the time specified in such order); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144c0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/2/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> remain effective and enforceable, except to such extent as it is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by action of the Administrator or a reviewing court in accordance with this section.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144c1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to suspend or prohibit participation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In order to protect a small business lending company, a non-Federally regulated lender or the interests of the Administration or the United States, the Administrator may suspend from office or prohibit from further participation in any manner in the management or conduct of the affairs of a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender a management official by written notice to such effect served upon the management official. Such suspension or prohibition may prohibit the management official from making, servicing, reviewing, approving, or liquidating any loan under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">section 636(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectiveness</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A suspension or prohibition under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id791144c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall take effect upon service of notice under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id791144c5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> unless stayed by a court in proceedings authorized by subparagraph (C), shall remain in effect—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144c6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to a notice of intention to remove served under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id791144c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> until such time as the Administrator dismisses the charges specified in the notice, or, if an order of removal or prohibition is issued against the management official, until the effective date of any such order.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review of suspension prior to hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 10 days after a management official is suspended or prohibited from participation under subparagraph (A), the management official may apply to an appropriate district court for a stay of the suspension or prohibition pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to a notice of intent to remove served upon the management official under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to suspend on criminal charges</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a management official is charged in any information, indictment, or complaint authorized by a United States attorney, with a felony involving dishonesty or breach of trust, the Administrator may, by written notice served upon the management official, suspend the management official from office or prohibit the management official from further participation in any manner in the management or conduct of the affairs of the small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectiveness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A suspension or prohibition under subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect until the information, indictment, or complaint is finally disposed of, or until terminated by the Administrator or upon an order of a district court.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority upon conviction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a judgment of conviction with respect to an offense described in subparagraph (A) is entered against a management official, then at such time as the judgment is not subject to further judicial review (and for purposes of this subparagraph shall not include any petition for a writ of habeas corpus), the Administrator may issue and serve upon the management official an order removing the management official, effective upon service of a copy of the order upon the small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority upon dismissal or other disposition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A finding of not guilty or other disposition of charges described in subparagraph (A) shall not preclude the Administrator from instituting proceedings under subsection (e) or (f).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification to small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Copies of each notice required to be served on a management official under this section shall also be served upon the small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id791144cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Final agency action and judicial review</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">After a hearing under this subsection, and not later than 30 days after the Administrator notifies the parties that the case has been submitted for final decision, the Administrator shall render a decision in the matter (which shall include findings of fact upon which its decision is predicated), and shall issue and cause to be served upon each party to the proceeding an order or orders consistent with this section. The decision of the Administrator shall constitute final agency action for purposes of chapter 7 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id791144d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/g/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An adversely aggrieved party shall have 20 days from the date of issuance of the order to seek judicial review in an appropriate district court.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of receiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In any proceeding under subsection (f)(4) or subsection (g)(6)(C),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002239">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002239"><num>1</num> So in original. There is no subsec. (f)(4) or (g)(6)(C) in this section.</note> the court may take exclusive jurisdiction of a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender and appoint a receiver to hold and administer the assets of the company or lender.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon request of the Administrator, the court may appoint the Administrator as a receiver under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Possession of assets</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender is not in compliance with capital requirements or is insolvent, the Administrator may take possession of the portfolio of loans guaranteed by the Administrator and sell such loans to a third party by means of a receiver appointed under subsection (h).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender is not in compliance with capital requirements or is insolvent or otherwise operating in an unsafe and unsound condition, the Administrator may take possession of servicing activities of loans that are guaranteed by the Administrator and sell such servicing rights to a third party by means of a receiver appointed under subsection (h).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144d8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties and forfeitures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender which violates any regulation or written directive issued by the Administrator regarding the filing of any regular or special report shall pay to the United States a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day of the continuance of the failure to file such report, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect. The civil penalties under this subsection may be enforced in a civil action brought by the Administrator. The penalties under this subsection shall not apply to any affiliate of a small business lending company that procures at least 10 percent of its annual purchasing requirements from small manufacturers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id791144da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s650/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator may by rules and regulations that shall be codified in the Code of Federal Regulations, after an opportunity for notice and comment, or upon application of an interested party, at any time previous to such failure, by order, after notice and opportunity for hearing which shall be conducted pursuant to sections 554, 556, and 557 of title 5, exempt in whole or in part, any small business lending company or non-Federally regulated lender from paragraph (1), upon such terms and conditions and for such period of time as it deems necessary and appropriate, if the Administrator finds that such action is not inconsistent with the public interest or the protection of the Administration. The Administrator may for the purposes of this section make any alternative requirements appropriate to the situation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id791144db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/536/s2/s23">Pub. L. 85–536, § 2[23]</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s111A/a">Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 111A(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1965">98 Stat. 1965</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dK/tI/s161">Pub. L. 108–447, div. K, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3458">118 Stat. 3458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id791144dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id791144dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id791144de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 650, acts <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-30/ch282">July 30, 1953, ch. 282</ref>, title II, § 221, <ref href="/us/stat/67/240">67 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-06-30/ch251/s4">June 30, 1955, ch. 251, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/225">69 Stat. 225</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-09/ch628/s13">Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 628, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/551">69 Stat. 551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/120/s2">Pub. L. 85–120, § 2</ref>, <date date="1957-08-03">Aug. 3, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/341">71 Stat. 341</ref>, provided for a termination date of the Small Business Act of 1953, and was omitted from the general revision by <ref href="/us/pl/85/536">Pub. L. 85–536</ref>. See Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id791144df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text related to disaster loan assistance to small business concerns in the fishing industry due to El Nino-related ocean conditions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
