<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id791144e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651"><num value="651">§ 651.</num><heading> National small business tree planting program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of grants and contracts with States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to make grants to or to enter into contracts with any State for the purpose of contracting with small businesses to plant trees on land owned or controlled by such State or local government. The Administrator shall require as a condition of any grant (or amendment or modification thereof) under this section that the applicant also contribute to the project a sum equal to at least 25 per centum of a particular project cost from sources other than the Federal Government. Such non-Federal money may include inkind contributions, including the cost or value of providing care and maintenance for a period of three years after the planting of the trees, but shall not include any value attributable to the land on which the trees are to be planted, nor may any part of any grant be used to pay for land or land charges: <i>Provided</i>, That not less than one-half of the amounts appropriated under this section shall be allocated to each State, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico on the basis of the population in each area as compared to the total population in all areas as provided by the Census Bureau of the Department of Commerce in the annual population estimate or the decennial census, whichever is most current. The Administrator may give a priority in awarding the remaining one-half of appropriated amounts to applicants who agree to contribute more than the requisite 25 per centum, and shall give priority to a proposal to restore an area determined to be a major disaster by the President on a date not more than three years prior to the fiscal year for which the application is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment by Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to accomplish the objectives of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, shall be responsible for formulating a national small business tree planting program. Based on this program, a State may submit a detailed proposal for tree planting by contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of small business concerns in implementing program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To encourage and develop the capacity of small business concerns, to utilize this important segment of our economy, and to permit rapid increases in employment opportunities in local communities, grantees are directed to utilize small business contractors or concerns in connection with the program established by this section, and shall, to the extent practicable, divide the project to allow more than one small business concern to perform the work under the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation of Federal agencies; technical services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, agencies of the Federal Government are hereby authorized to cooperate with all grantees and with State foresters or other appropriate officials by providing without charge, in furtherance of this program, technical services with respect to the planting and growing of such trees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the objectives of this section, $15,000,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1995 through 1997, and all of such sums may remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or regulation, the administration shall publish in the Federal Register proposed rules and regulations implementing this section within sixty days after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, and shall publish final rules and regulations within one hundred and twenty days of <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id791144e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “local government” includes political subdivisions of a State such as counties, parishes, cities, towns and municipalities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id791144e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “planting” includes watering, application of fertilizer and herbicides, pruning and shaping, and other subsequent care and maintenance for a period of three years after the trees are planted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id791144ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “State” includes any agency thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id791144eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s651/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report to President and Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall submit annually to the President and the Congress a report on activities within the scope of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id791144ec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/536/s2/s24">Pub. L. 85–536, § 2[24]</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/515/tV/s4">Pub. L. 101–515, title V, § 4</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2140">104 Stat. 2140</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/211/tI/s201">Pub. L. 103–211, title I, § 201</ref>, <date date="1994-02-12">Feb. 12, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/5">108 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/317/tIV">Pub. L. 103–317, title IV</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1755">108 Stat. 1755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id791144ed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id791144ee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id791144ef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 651, <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-30/ch282/s225">act July 30, 1953, ch. 282, § 225</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-09/ch628/s14">Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 628, § 14</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/551">69 Stat. 551</ref>, prohibited duplication of activities, and was omitted as superseded by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s647">section 647 of this title</ref>. See Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id791144f0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/211">Pub. L. 103–211</ref> inserted at end “, and shall give priority to a proposal to restore an area determined to be a major disaster by the President on a date not more than three years prior to the fiscal year for which the application is made”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/317">Pub. L. 103–317</ref> substituted “fiscal years 1995 through 1997” for “fiscal years 1992 through 1994”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id791144f1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id791144f2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (h) of this section relating to submitting annual report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 191 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
