<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a5cd846-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612"><num value="6612">§ 6612.</num><heading> State of mind; bystander liability; control</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd847-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Defendant’s state of mind</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In a Y2K action other than a claim for breach or repudiation of contract, and in which the defendant’s actual or constructive awareness of an actual or potential Y2K failure is an element of the claim, the defendant is not liable unless the plaintiff establishes that element of the claim by the standard of evidence under applicable State law in effect on the day before <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd848-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on bystander liability for Y2K failures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd849-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to any Y2K action for money damages in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a5cd84a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the defendant is not the manufacturer, seller, or distributor of a product, or the provider of a service, that suffers or causes the Y2K failure at issue;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a5cd84b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the plaintiff is not in substantial privity with the defendant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a5cd84c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the defendant’s actual or constructive awareness of an actual or potential Y2K failure is an element of the claim under applicable law,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the defendant shall not be liable unless the plaintiff, in addition to establishing all other requisite elements of the claim, proves, by the standard of evidence under applicable State law in effect on the day before <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, that the defendant actually knew, or recklessly disregarded a known and substantial risk, that such failure would occur.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd84d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Substantial privity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), a plaintiff and a defendant are in substantial privity when, in a Y2K action arising out of the performance of professional services, the plaintiff and the defendant either have contractual relations with one another or the plaintiff is a person who, prior to the defendant’s performance of such services, was specifically identified to and acknowledged by the defendant as a person for whose special benefit the services were being performed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd84e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain claims excluded</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(C), claims in which the defendant’s actual or constructive awareness of an actual or potential Y2K failure is an element of the claim under applicable law do not include claims for negligence but do include claims such as fraud, constructive fraud, breach of fiduciary duty, negligent misrepresentation, and interference with contract or economic advantage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd84f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Control not determinative of liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fact that a Y2K failure occurred in an entity, facility, system, product, or component that was sold, leased, rented, or otherwise within the control of the party against whom a claim is asserted in a Y2K action shall not constitute the sole basis for recovery of damages in that action. A claim in a Y2K action for breach or repudiation of contract for such a failure is governed by the terms of the contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a5cd850-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6612/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Protections of the Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act apply</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The protections for the exchanges of information provided by section 4 of the Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act (<ref href="/us/pl/105/271">Public Law 105–271</ref>) shall apply to any Y2K action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a5cd851-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/37/s13">Pub. L. 106–37, § 13</ref>, <date date="1999-07-20">July 20, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/200">113 Stat. 200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a5cd852-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a5cd853-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a5cd854-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4 of the Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/105/271/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 105–271</ref>, which was formerly set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
