<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a619333-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732"><num value="6732">§ 6732.</num><heading> Redomestication of mutual insurers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619334-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Redomestication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A mutual insurer organized under the laws of any State may transfer its domicile to a transferee domicile as a step in a reorganization in which, pursuant to the laws of the transferee domicile and consistent with the standards in subsection (f), the mutual insurer becomes a stock insurer that is a direct or indirect subsidiary of a mutual holding company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619335-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Resulting domicile</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon complying with the applicable law of the transferee domicile governing transfers of domicile and completion of a transfer pursuant to this section, the mutual insurer shall cease to be a domestic insurer in the transferor domicile and, as a continuation of its corporate existence, shall be a domestic insurer of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619336-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Licenses preserved</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The certificate of authority, agents’ appointments and licenses, rates, approvals and other items that a licensed State allows and that are in existence immediately prior to the date that a redomesticating insurer transfers its domicile pursuant to this subchapter shall continue in full force and effect upon transfer, if the insurer remains duly qualified to transact the business of insurance in such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619337-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectiveness of outstanding policies and contracts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619338-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All outstanding insurance policies and annuities contracts of a redomesticating insurer shall remain in full force and effect and need not be endorsed as to the new domicile of the insurer, unless so ordered by the State insurance regulator of a licensed State, and then only in the case of outstanding policies and contracts whose owners reside in such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619339-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Forms</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a61933a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Applicable State law may require a redomesticating insurer to file new policy forms with the State insurance regulator of a licensed State on or before the effective date of the transfer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a61933b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a redomesticating insurer may use existing policy forms with appropriate endorsements to reflect the new domicile of the redomesticating insurer until the new policy forms are approved for use by the State insurance regulator of such licensed State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a61933c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A redomesticating insurer shall give notice of the proposed transfer to the State insurance regulator of each licensed State and shall file promptly any resulting amendments to corporate documents required to be filed by a foreign licensed mutual insurer with the insurance regulator of each such licensed State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a61933d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No mutual insurer may redomesticate to another State and reorganize into a mutual holding company pursuant to this section unless the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile determines that the plan of reorganization of the insurer includes the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a61933e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval by board of directors and policyholders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The reorganization is approved by at least a majority of the board of directors of the mutual insurer and at least a majority of the policyholders who vote after notice, disclosure of the reorganization and the effects of the transaction on policyholder contractual rights, and reasonable opportunity to vote, in accordance with such notice, disclosure, and voting procedures as are approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a61933f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued voting control by policyholders; review of public stock offering</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the consummation of a reorganization, the policyholders of the reorganized insurer shall have the same voting rights with respect to the mutual holding company as they had before the reorganization with respect to the mutual insurer. With respect to an initial public offering of stock, the offering shall be conducted in compliance with applicable securities laws and in a manner approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619340-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Award of stock or grant of options to officers and directors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">During the applicable period provided for under the State law of the transferee domicile following completion of an initial public offering, or for a period of six months if no such applicable period is provided, neither a stock holding company nor the converted insurer shall award any stock options or stock grants to persons who are elected officers or directors of the mutual holding company, the stock holding company, or the converted insurer, except with respect to any such awards or options to which a person is entitled as a policyholder and as approved by the State insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619341-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Policyholder rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon reorganization into a mutual holding company, the contractual rights of the policyholders are preserved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a619342-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s6732/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Fair and equitable treatment of policyholders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The reorganization is approved as fair and equitable to the policyholders by the insurance regulator of the transferee domicile.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a619343-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 106–102, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1417">113 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
