<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id792939a2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l"><num value="687l">§ 687l.</num><heading> Issuance and guarantee of trust certificates</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939a3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance; debentures or participating securities composing trust or pool</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administration is authorized to issue trust certificates representing ownership of all or a fractional part of debentures issued by small business investment companies and guaranteed by the Administration under this chapter, or participating securities which are issued by such companies and purchased and guaranteed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s683/g">section 683(g) of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That such trust certificates shall be based on and backed by a trust or pool approved by the Administration and composed solely of guaranteed debentures or guaranteed participating securities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939a4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of guarantee; payment of principal and interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administration is authorized, upon such terms and conditions as are deemed appropriate, to guarantee the timely payment of the principal of and interest on trust certificates issued by the Administration or its agent for purposes of this section. Such guarantee shall be limited to the extent of principal and interest on the guaranteed debentures or the redemption price of and priority payments on the participating securities, which compose the trust or pool. In the event that a debenture in such trust or pool is prepaid, or participating securities are redeemed, either voluntarily or involuntarily, or in the event of default of a debenture or voluntary or involuntary redemption of a participating security, the guarantee of timely payment of principal and interest on the trust certificates shall be reduced in proportion to the amount of principal and interest such prepaid debenture or redeemed participating security and priority payments represent in the trust or pool. Interest on prepaid or defaulted debentures, or priority payments on participating securities, shall accrue and be guaranteed by the Administration only through the date of payment on the guarantee. During the term of the trust certificate, it may be called for redemption due to prepayment or default of all debentures or redemption, whether voluntary or involuntary, of all participating securities residing in the pool.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939a5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Full faith and credit of United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The full faith and credit of the United States is pledged to the payment of all amounts which may be required to be paid under any guarantee of such trust certificates issued by the Administration or its agent pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939a6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administration shall not collect a fee for any guarantee under this section: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein shall preclude any agent of the Administration from collecting a fee approved by the Administration for the functions described in subsection (f)(2) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939a7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Subrogation rights; ownership rights in debentures or participating securities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939a8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the event the Administration pays a claim under a guarantee issued under this section, it shall be subrogated fully to the rights satisfied by such payment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939a9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No State or local law, and no Federal law, shall preclude or limit the exercise by the Administration of its ownership rights in the debentures or participating securities residing in a trust or pool against which trust certificates are issued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id792939aa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Central registration requirements; regulation of brokers and dealers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939ab-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administration shall provide for a central registration of all trust certificates sold pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939ac-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator shall contract with an agent or agents to carry out on behalf of the Administration the pooling and the central registration functions of this section including, notwithstanding any other provision of law, maintenance on behalf of and under the direction of the Administration, such commercial bank accounts or investments in obligations of the United States as may be necessary to facilitate trusts or pools backed by debentures or participating securities guaranteed under this chapter, and the issuance of trust certificates to facilitate such poolings. Such agent or agents shall provide a fidelity bond or insurance in such amounts as the Administration determines to be necessary to fully protect the interests of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939ad-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Prior to any sale, the Administrator shall require the seller to disclose to a purchaser of a trust certificate issued pursuant to this section, information on the terms, conditions, and yield of such instrument.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939ae-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Administrator is authorized to regulate brokers and dealers in trust certificates sold pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id792939af-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s687l/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit the use of a book-entry or other electronic form of registration for trust certificates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id792939b0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/699/tIII/s319">Pub. L. 85–699, title III, § 319</ref>, formerly § 321, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXVIII/s18005/a">Pub. L. 99–272, title XVIII, § 18005(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/364">100 Stat. 364</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/162/tV">Pub. L. 101–162, title V</ref>, (5), <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1028">103 Stat. 1028</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/366/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 102–366, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1992-09-04">Sept. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1013">106 Stat. 1013</ref>; renumbered § 319 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dD/tII">Pub. L. 104–208, div. D, title II</ref>, §§ 205(b), 208(h)(1)(E), (F), <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-738">110 Stat. 3009–738</ref>, 3009–747.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id792939b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id792939b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id792939b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “this chapter”, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (f)(2), see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s661">section 661 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id792939b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/85/699/s319">section 319 of Pub. L. 85–699</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–18">section 80a–18 of this title</ref>, was renumbered section 317.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id792939b5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s208/h/1/F/i">Pub. L. 104–208, § 208(h)(1)(F)(i)</ref>, struck out “, including companies operating under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s681/d">section 681(d) of this title</ref>,” after “investment companies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s205/b/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 205(b)(1)</ref>, struck out at end “Such central registration shall include with respect to each sale—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) identification of each small business investment company;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the interest rate or prioritized payment rate paid by the small business investment company;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) commissions, fees, or discounts paid to brokers and dealers in trust certificates;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) identification of each purchaser of the trust certificate;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(E) the price paid by the purchaser for the trust certificate;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(F) the interest rate on the trust certificate;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(G) the fee of any agent for carrying out the functions described in paragraph (2); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(H) such other information as the Administration deems appropriate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s208/h/1/F/ii">Pub. L. 104–208, § 208(h)(1)(F)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or investments in obligations of the United States” after “accounts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s205/b/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 205(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/366">Pub. L. 102–366</ref> amended section generally, in subsec. (a) authorizing issuance of trust certificates representing ownership of participating securities, in subsec. (b) inserting provisions authorizing Administration to guarantee payment of redemption price of and priority payments on participating securities, in subsec. (e)(2) including participating securities within prohibition against preclusion or limitation of Administration’s ownership rights, and in subsec. (f) in par. (1) substituting provisions relating to small business investment company for provisions relating to development company and requiring prioritized payment rate to be included in central registration requirements, and in par. (2) inserting provisions relating to participating securities, contracts to carry out pooling, and maintenance of commercial bank accounts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/162">Pub. L. 101–162</ref> inserted “, including companies operating under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s681/d">section 681(d) of this title</ref>,” after “investment companies”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id792939b6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id792939b7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s633">section 633 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s208">section 208 of Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s208/j">section 208(j) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s634">section 634 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id792939b8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXVIII/s18005/b">Pub. L. 99–272, title XVIII, § 18005(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/365">100 Stat. 365</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tXVIII/s18005/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any law, rule, or regulation, within 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>], the Small Business Administration shall develop and promulgate final rules and regulations to implement the central registration provisions provided for in section 321(f)(1) of the Small Business Investment Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s687">15 U.S.C. 687</ref><i>l</i>(f)(1)], and shall contract with an agent for an initial period of not to exceed two years to carry out the functions provided for in sections 321(f)(2) and 321(f)(3) of such Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any law, rule, or regulation, within 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>], the Small Business Administration also shall consult with representatives of appropriate Federal and State agencies and officials, the securities industry, financial institutions and lenders, and small business persons, and shall develop and promulgate final rules and regulations to implement sections 504 and 505 [section 321; <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s687">15 U.S.C. 687</ref><i>l</i>] of the Small Business Investment Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id792939b9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of Small Business Equity Enhancement Act of 1992 on Securities Laws</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/366">Pub. L. 102–366</ref> to be construed to affect applicability of securities laws or to otherwise supersede or limit jurisdiction of Securities and Exchange Commission, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/366/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 102–366</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s661">section 661 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
