<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d430ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s68c"><num value="68c">§ 68c.</num><heading> Stamp, tag, label, or other identification</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d43100-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s68c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Affixing; retention until sale</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person manufacturing for introduction, or first introducing into commerce a wool product shall affix thereto the stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification required by this subchapter, and the same, or substitutes therefor containing identical information with respect to content of the wool product or any other products contained therein in an amount of 5 per centum or more by weight and other information required under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s68b">section 68b of this title</ref>, shall be and remain affixed to such wool product, whether it remains in its original state or is contained in garments or other articles made in whole or in part therefrom, until sold to the consumer: <i>Provided</i>, That the name of the manufacturer of the wool product need not appear on the substitute stamp, tag, or label if the name of the person who affixes the substitute appears thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d43101-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s68c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal or mutilation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who shall cause or participate in the removal or mutilation of any stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification affixed to a wood <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002008"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “wool”.</note> product with intent to violate the provisions of this subchapter, is guilty of an unfair method of competition, and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, in commerce within the meaning of the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d43102-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s68c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Packages of wool products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of this section, any package of wool products intended for sale to the ultimate consumer shall also be considered a wool product and shall have affixed to it a stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification bearing the information required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s68b">section 68b of this title</ref>, with respect to the wool products contained therein, unless such package of wool products is transparent to the extent that it allows for the clear reading of the stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification affixed to the wool product, or in the case of hosiery items this section shall not be construed as requiring the affixing of a stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification to each hosiery product contained in a package if (1) such hosiery products are intended for sale to the ultimate consumer in such package, (2) such package has affixed to it a stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification bearing, with respect to the hosiery products contained therein, the information required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s68b">section 68b of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002009"><num>2</num> See Codification note.</note> and (3) the information on the stamp, tag, label, or other means of identification affixed to such package is equally applicable with respect to each hosiery product contained therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d43103-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-10-14/ch871/s5">Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 871, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1130">54 Stat. 1130</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/417/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 98–417, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1984-09-24">Sept. 24, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1605">98 Stat. 1605</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77d43104-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77d43105-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id77d43106-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s68b">Section 68b of this title</ref>, the second time it appears in subsec. (c), was in the original “subsection (4)” and was translated as reading “section 4” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77d43107-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/417">Pub. L. 98–417</ref> designated existing first and second pars. as subsecs. (a) and (b), respectively, and added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77d43108-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77d43109-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/417">Pub. L. 98–417</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1984-09-24">Sept. 24, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/417/s307">section 307 of Pub. L. 98–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s68b">section 68b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
