<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79293ab4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a"><num value="690a">§ 690a.</num><heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of the Renewable Fuel Capital Investment Program established under this part are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79293ab5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to promote the research, development, manufacture, production, and bringing to market of goods, products, or services that generate or support the production of renewable energy by encouraging venture capital investments in smaller enterprises primarily engaged <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002263">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002263"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “in”.</note> such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id79293ab6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> to establish a venture capital program, with the mission of addressing the unmet equity investment needs of smaller enterprises engaged in researching, developing, manufacturing, producing, and bringing to market goods, products, or services that generate or support the production of renewable energy, to be administered by the Administrator—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id79293ab7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to enter into participation agreements with Renewable Fuel Capital Investment companies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id792b83a8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to guarantee debentures of Renewable Fuel Capital Investment companies to enable each such company to make venture capital investments in smaller enterprises engaged in the research, development, manufacture, production, and bringing to market of goods, products, or services that generate or support the production of renewable energy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id792b83a9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s690a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to make grants to Renewable Fuel Investment Capital companies, and to other entities, for the purpose of providing operational assistance to smaller enterprises financed, or expected to be financed, by such companies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id792b83aa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/699/tIII/s382">Pub. L. 85–699, title III, § 382</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tXII/s1207">Pub. L. 110–140, title XII, § 1207</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1775">121 Stat. 1775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
