<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d4317a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69d"><num value="69d">§ 69d.</num><heading> Fur products imported into United States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d4317b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Necessity of proper labelling; additional information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Fur products imported into the United States shall be labeled so as not to be misbranded within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s69b">section 69b of this title</ref>; and all invoices of fur products and furs required under title IV of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">19 U.S.C. 1401</ref> et seq.], shall set forth, in addition to the matters therein specified, information conforming with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s69c/b">section 69c(b) of this title</ref>, which information shall be included in the invoices prior to their certification under the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d4317c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations of Federal Trade Commission Act</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The falsification of, or failure to set forth, said information in said invoices, or the falsification or perjury of the consignee’s declaration provided for in the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.], insofar as it relates to said information, shall be an unfair method of competition, and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.]; and any person who falsifies, or fails to set forth, said information in said invoices, or who falsifies or perjures said consignee’s declaration insofar as it relates to said information, may thenceforth be prohibited by the Commission from importing, or participating in the importation of, any fur products or furs into the United States except upon filing bond with the Secretary of the Treasury in a sum double the value of said fur products and furs, and any duty thereon, conditioned upon compliance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d4317d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Verified statement of compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A verified statement from the manufacturer, producer of, or dealer in, imported fur products and furs showing information required under the provisions of this subchapter may be required under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d4317e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-08-08/ch298/s6">Aug. 8, 1951, ch. 298, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/178">65 Stat. 178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77d4317f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77d43180-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77d43181-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tariff Act of 1930, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">act June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/590">46 Stat. 590</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 4 (§ 1202 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. Title IV of the Tariff Act of 1930 is classified generally to subtitle III (§ 1401 et seq.) of chapter 4 of Title 19. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1654">section 1654 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s69">section 69 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77d43182-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77d43183-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 8 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1264">64 Stat. 1264</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
