<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d6a19b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g"><num value="69g">§ 69g.</num><heading> Condemnation and injunction proceedings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a19c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grounds for condemnation; disposition of merchandise</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77d6a19d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any fur product or fur shall be liable to be proceeded against in the district court of the United States for the district in which found, and to be seized for confiscation by process of libel for condemnation, if the Commission has reasonable cause to believe such fur product or fur is being manufactured or held for shipment, or shipped, or held for sale or exchange after shipment, in commerce, in violation of the provisions of this subchapter, and if after notice from the Commission the provisions of this subchapter with respect to such fur product or fur are not shown to be complied with. Proceedings in such libel cases shall conform as nearly as may be to suits in rem in admiralty, and may be brought by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77d6a19e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If such fur products or furs are condemned by the court, they shall be disposed of, in the discretion of the court, by destruction, by sale, by delivery to the owner or claimant thereof upon payment of legal costs and charges and upon execution of good and sufficient bond to the effect that such fur or fur products will not be disposed of until properly marked, advertised, and invoiced as required under the provisions of this subchapter; or by such charitable disposition as the court may deem proper. If such furs or fur products are disposed of by sale, the proceeds, less legal costs and charges, shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a19f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grounds for temporary injunction or restraining order; issuance without bond</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Commission has reason to believe that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1a0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any person is volating,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002010"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “violating,”.</note> or is about to violate, section 69a, 69d, or 69h(b) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1a1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s69g/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> it would be to the public interest to enjoin such violation until complaint is issued by the Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] and such complaint dismissed by the Commission or set aside by the court on review, or until order to cease and desist made thereon by the Commission has become final within the meaning of said Act,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commission may bring suit in the district court of the United States or in the United States court of any Territory, for the district or Territory in which such person resides or transacts business, to enjoin such violation, and upon proper showing a temporary injunction or restraining order shall be granted without bond.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d6a1a2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-08-08/ch298/s9">Aug. 8, 1951, ch. 298, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/180">65 Stat. 180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77d6a1a3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77d6a1a4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77d6a1a5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s69">section 69 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77d6a1a6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77d6a1a7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 8 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1264">64 Stat. 1264</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
