<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77d6a1d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a"><num value="70a">§ 70a.</num><heading> Violations of Federal Trade Commission Act</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a1d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Introduction or manufacture for introduction into commerce, sale, advertising or offering for sale in commerce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The introduction, delivery for introduction, manufacture for introduction, sale, advertising, or offering for sale, in commerce, or the transportation or causing to be transported in commerce, or the importation into the United States, of any textile fiber product which is misbranded or falsely or deceptively advertised within the meaning of this subchapter or the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, is unlawful, and shall be an unfair method of competition and an unfair and deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a1d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale, offering for sale, advertising, delivery, transportation of products advertised for sale in commerce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sale, offering for sale, advertising, delivery, transportation, or causing to be transported, of any textile fiber product which has been advertised or offered for sale in commerce, and which is misbranded or falsely or deceptively advertised, within the meaning of this subchapter or the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, is unlawful, and shall be an unfair method of competition and an unfair and deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a1d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale, offering for sale, advertising, delivery, transportation of products after shipment in commerce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sale, offering for sale, advertising, delivery, transportation, or causing to be transported, after shipment in commerce, of any textile fiber product, whether in its original state or contained in other textile fiber products, which is misbranded or falsely or deceptively advertised, within the meaning of this subchapter or the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, is unlawful, and shall be an unfair method of competition and an unfair and deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77d6a1d8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section to common carrier, freight forwarder, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to any common carrier or contract carrier or freight forwarder with respect to a textile fiber product received, shipped, delivered, or handled by it for shipment in the ordinary course of its business;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to any processor or finisher in performing a contract for the account of a person subject to the provisions of this subchapter if the processor or finisher does not change the textile fiber content of the textile fiber product contrary to the terms of such contract;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with respect to the manufacture, delivery for transportation, transportation, sale, or offering for sale of a textile fiber product for exportation from the United States to any foreign country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to any publisher or other advertising agency or medium for the dissemination of advertising or promotional material, except the manufacturer, distributor, or seller of the textile fiber product to which the false or deceptive advertisement relates, if such publisher or other advertising agency or medium furnishes to the Commission, upon request, the name and post office address of the manufacturer, distributor, seller, or other person residing in the United States, who caused the dissemination of the advertising material; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77d6a1dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s70a/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to any textile fiber product until such product has been produced by the manufacturer or processor in the form intended for sale or delivery to, or for use by, the ultimate consumer: <i>Provided</i>, That this exemption shall apply only if such textile fiber product is covered by an invoice or other paper relating to the marketing or handling of the textile fiber product and such invoice or paper correctly discloses the information with respect to the textile fiber product which would otherwise be required under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s70b">section 70b of this title</ref> to be on the stamp, tag, label, or other identification and the name and address of the person issuing the invoice or paper.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77d6a1de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/897/s3">Pub. L. 85–897, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1718">72 Stat. 1718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77d6a1df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77d6a1e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77d6a1e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
