<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id793520f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713a–9"><num value="713a–9">§ 713a–9.</num><heading> Reimbursement of corporation from funds of Government agencies for services, losses, operating costs, or commodities purchased</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Full reimbursement shall be made to the Commodity Credit Corporation for services performed, losses sustained, operating costs incurred, or commodities purchased or delivered to or on behalf of the Lend-Lease Administration, the Army or Navy, the Board of Economic Warfare, the Reconstruction Finance Corporation, or any other Government agency, from the appropriate funds of these agencies.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id793520f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1943-07-16/ch241/s4">July 16, 1943, ch. 241, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/57/566">57 Stat. 566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id793520f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id793520f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id793520fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Lend-Lease Administration and Board of Economic Warfare, referred to in text, consolidated with Foreign Economic Administration by Ex. Ord. No. 9380, <date date="1943-09-25">Sept. 25, 1943</date>. Foreign Economic Administration subsequently terminated and functions of Lend-Lease Administration and Board of Economic Warfare transferred to Department of State pursuant to Ex. Ord. No. 9630, <date date="1945-09-27">Sept. 27, 1945</date>, 10 F.R. 12245, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 9730, <date date="1946-05-27">May 27, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 5777.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793520fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For exception of functions of corporations of Department of Agriculture from transfer of functions to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, see Exceptions From Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793520fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Reconstruction Finance Corporation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6(a) of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1957, eff. <date date="1957-06-30">June 30, 1957</date>, 22 F.R. 4633, <ref href="/us/stat/71/647">71 Stat. 647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s601">section 601 of this title</ref>, abolished Reconstruction Finance Corporation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
