<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7935211c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713c"><num value="713c">§ 713c.</num><heading> Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation; continuance of existence; purchase and distribution of surplus agricultural commodities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of clause (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of title 7</ref>, the Secretary of Agriculture may transfer to the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation, which Corporation is continued, until <date date="1945-06-30">June 30, 1945</date>, as an agency of the United States under the direction of the Secretary of Agriculture, such funds, appropriated by said section, as may be necessary for the purpose of effectuating clause (2) of said section: <i>Provided</i>, That such transferred funds, together with other funds of the Corporation, may be used for purchasing, exchanging, processing, distributing, disposing, transporting, storing, and handling of agricultural commodities and products thereof and inspection costs, commissions, and other incidental costs and expenses, without regard to the provisions of existing law governing the expenditure of public funds and for administrative expenses, including rent, printing and binding, and the employment of persons and means, in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, such employment of persons to be in accordance with the provisions of law applicable to the employment of persons by the Agricultural Adjustment Administration. In carrying out clause (2) of said section, the funds appropriated by said section may be used for the purchase, without regard to the provisions of existing law governing the expenditure of public funds, of agricultural commodities and products thereof, and such commodities, as well as agricultural commodities and products thereof purchased under the preceding paragraph of this section, may be donated for relief purposes and for use in nonprofit summer camps for children.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7935211d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-06-28/ch385">June 28, 1937, ch. 385</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/323">50 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title II, § 204, <ref href="/us/stat/52/38">52 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1942-06-27/ch454">June 27, 1942, ch. 454</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/461">56 Stat. 461</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/483/s2">Pub. L. 85–483, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-07-02">July 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/287">72 Stat. 287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7935211e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7935211f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79352120-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/483">Pub. L. 85–483</ref> permitted donation of commodities for use in nonprofit summer camps for children.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1942—Act <date date="1942-06-27">June 27, 1942</date>, provided for the continuance of the Corporation from <date date="1942-06-30">June 30, 1942</date>, to <date date="1945-06-30">June 30, 1945</date>. It read as follows: “The Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation is hereby continued as an agency of the United States, under the direction of the Secretary of Agriculture, until <date date="1945-06-30">June 30, 1945</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1938—Act <date date="1938-02-16">Feb. 16, 1938</date>, substituted “until <date date="1942-06-30">June 30, 1942</date>” for “until <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79352121-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79352122-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
