<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7935212a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713c–2"><num value="713c–2">§ 713c–2.</num><heading> Purchase and distribution of surplus fishery products</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any part of the funds not to exceed $1,500,000 per year, created under and to carry out the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of title 7</ref>, may also be used by the Secretary of Agriculture for the purpose of diverting surplus fishery products (including fish, shellfish, mollusks, and crustacea) from the normal channels of trade and commerce by acquiring them and providing for their distribution through Federal, State, and private relief channels: <i>Provided</i>, That none of the funds made available to the Secretary of Agriculture under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713c–3">section 713c–3 of this title</ref> shall be used to purchase any of the commodities designated in this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713c–3">section 713c–3 of this title</ref> which may have been produced in any foreign country. The provisions of law relating to the acquisition of materials or supplies for the United States shall not apply to the acquisition of commodities under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713c–3">section 713c–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7935212b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1939-08-11/ch696/s1">Aug. 11, 1939, ch. 696, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1411">53 Stat. 1411</ref>; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. III, § 5, eff. <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2108, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1232">54 Stat. 1232</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 501, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7877, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7935212c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7935212d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7935212e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first part of this section originally read: “Any part of the funds not to exceed $1,500,000 per year, transferred by the Secretary of Agriculture to the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation created under and to carry out the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of title 7</ref> may also be used by such Corporation”, etc., and the reference in the proviso to the Secretary of Agriculture originally read: “Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation”. See Transfer of Functions note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7935212f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="similarProvisions" id="id79352130-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Similar Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Earlier provisions on this subject were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1937-03-05/ch29">act Mar. 5, 1937, ch. 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/27">50 Stat. 27</ref>, and in Joint Res. <ref href="/us/act/1937-04-12/ch73">Apr. 12, 1937, ch. 73</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/61">50 Stat. 61</ref>. The former forbade acquisition of commodities thereunder after 90 days after its enactment, but permitted distribution of commodities after such period. The latter made funds available to be used in accordance with the provisions of the former.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Joint Res. <ref href="/us/act/1937-04-12/ch73">Apr. 12, 1937, ch. 73</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/61">50 Stat. 61</ref>, provided as follows: “That not to exceed $1,000,000 of the funds available to the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation may be used by such Corporation for the purpose of diverting surplus fish (including shellfish) and the products thereof from the normal channels of trade and commerce by the acquisition and distribution thereof in accordance with the provisions of the Act entitled ‘An Act to authorize the purchase and distribution of products of the fishing industry’, approved <date date="1937-03-05">March 5, 1937</date>.”</p>
<p><ref href="/us/act/1937-03-05/ch29">Act Mar. 5, 1937, ch. 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/27">50 Stat. 27</ref>, provided as follows: <quotedContent>“That there is authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the sum of $2,000,000 for the purpose of enabling the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation to divert surplus fish (including shellfish) and the products thereof from the normal channels of trade and commerce by acquiring them and providing for their distribution through Federal, State, and private relief agencies. No commodities shall be acquired under this Act after ninety days after the date of its enactment: <i>Provided, however</i>, That distribution thereof may extend beyond said period. The provisions of law relating to the acquisition of materials or supplies for the United States shall not apply to the acquisition of commodities under this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id79352131-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id79352132-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
