<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79376aad-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1"><num value="713d–1">§ 713d–1.</num><heading> Critical shortages; recommendations by President; public hearings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376aae-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Whenever the President shall determine that there is or threatens to be a critical shortage of any raw material, commodity, or product which jeopardizes the health or safety of the people of the United States or its national security or welfare and that there is no prospect that such critical shortage may soon be remedied by an increase in the available supply without additional governmental action and that the situation cannot be solved by voluntary agreement under the provisions of this Act, he may prepare proposed measures for conserving such raw material, commodity, or product which he shall submit to the Congress in the following form:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376aaf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A statement of the circumstances which, in the President’s judgment, require the proposed conservation measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ab0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A detailed procedure for the administration of the proposed measures including the additional budget and additional personnel required for their enforcement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ab1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The proposed degree of curtailment in current and prospective use of each such raw material, commodity, or product by each processor and/or user thereof, including the specific formulae proposed for such curtailment with respect to each class or classes of processors or users and the criteria used in the establishment of such formulae.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ab2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A complete record of the factual evidence upon which his recommendations are based, including all information provided by any agency of the Federal Government which may have been made available to him in the course of his consideration of the matter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ab3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s713d–1/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Within fifteen days after the submission of such proposed conservation measures, the Joint Economic Committee shall conduct public hearings thereon and shall make such recommendations to the Congress for legislative action as in its judgment the recommendations of the President and any additional information disclosed at the public hearings may require.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id79376ab4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-12-30/ch526/s6">Dec. 30, 1947, ch. 526, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/947">61 Stat. 947</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-06-18/ch399/s2">June 18, 1956, ch. 399, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/290">70 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id79376ab5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id79376ab6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id79376ab7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/act/1947-12-30/ch526">act Dec. 30, 1947, ch. 526</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/945">61 Stat. 945</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id79376ab8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 1916 of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id79376ab9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1956-06-18">June 18, 1956</date>, changed “Joint Committee on the Economic Report” to “Joint Economic Committee”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
