<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id79376ad9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b"><num value="714b">§ 714b.</num><heading> General powers of Corporation</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ada-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Shall have succession in its corporate name.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376adb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> May adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376adc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> May sue and be sued, but no attachment, injunction, garnishment, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the Corporation or its property. The district courts of the United States, including the district courts of any Territory or possession, shall have exclusive original jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy, of all suits brought by or against the Corporation: <i>Provided</i>, That the Corporation may intervene in any court in any suit, action, or proceeding in which it has an interest. Any suit against the Corporation shall be brought in the District of Columbia, or in the district wherein the plaintiff resides or is engaged in business. No suit by or against the Corporation shall be allowed unless (1) it shall have been brought within six years after the right accrued on which suit is brought, or (2) in the event that the person bringing such suit shall have been under legal disability or beyond the seas at the time the right accrued, the suit shall have been brought within three years after the disability shall have ceased or within six years after the right accrued on which suit is brought, whichever period is longer. The defendant in any suit by or against the Corporation may plead, by way of set-off or counterclaim, any cause of action, whether arising out of the same transaction or not, which would otherwise be barred by such limitation if the claim upon which the defendant’s cause of action is based had not been barred prior to the date that the plaintiff’s cause of action arose: <i>Provided</i>, That the defendant shall not be awarded a judgment on any such set-off or counterclaim for any amount in excess of the amount of the plaintiff’s claim established in the suit. All suits against the Corporation shall be tried by the court without a jury. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Federal Tort Claims Act (Public Law 601, Seventy-ninth Congres <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002277">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002277"><num>1</num> So in original. Should be “Congress)”.</note> shall be applicable to the Corporation. Any suit by or against the United States as the real party in interest based upon any claim by or against the Corporation shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (c) to the same extent as though such suit were by or against the Corporation, except that (1) any such suit against the United States based upon any claim of the type enumerated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491">section 1491 of title 28</ref>, may be brought in the United States Court of Federal Claims, and (2) no such suit against the United States may be brought in a district court unless such suit might, without regard to the provisions of this subchapter, be brought in such court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376add-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> May adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the manner in which its business may be conducted and the powers vested in it may be exercised.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ade-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Shall have all the rights, privileges, and immunities of the United States with respect to the right to priority of payment with respect to debts due from insolvent, deceased, or bankrupt debtors. The Corporation may assert such rights, privileges, and immunities in any suit, action, or proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376adf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Shall be entitled to the use of the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as the executive departments of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> May enter into and carry out such contracts or agreements as are necessary in the conduct of its business, except that obligations under all such contracts or agreements (other than reimbursable agreements under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s714i">section 714i of this title</ref>) for equipment or services relating to automated data processing, information technologies, or related items (including telecommunications equipment and computer hardware and software) may not exceed $170,000,000 in fiscal year 1996 and not more than $188,000,000 in the 6-fiscal year period beginning on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>, unless additional amounts for such contracts and agreements are provided in advance in appropriation Acts. State and local regulatory laws or rules shall not be applicable with respect to contracts or agreements of the Corporation or the parties thereto to the extent that such contracts or agreements provide that such laws or rules shall not be applicable, or to the extent that such laws or rules are inconsistent with such contracts or agreements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> May contract for the use, in accordance with the usual customs of trade and commerce, of plants and facilities for the physical handling, storage, processing, servicing, and transportation of the agricultural commodities subject to its control. The Corporation shall not have power to acquire real property or any interest therein except that it may (a) rent or lease office space necessary for the conduct of its business and (b) acquire real property or any interest therein for the purpose of providing storage adequate to carry out effectively and efficiently any of the Corporation’s programs, or of securing or discharging obligations owing to the Corporation, or of otherwise protecting the financial interests of the Corporation: <i>Provided</i>, That the authority contained in this subsection shall not be utilized by the Corporation for the purpose of acquiring real property, or any interest therein, in order to provide storage facilities for any commodity unless the Corporation determines that existing privately owned storage facilities for such commodity in the area concerned are not adequate: <i>Provided further</i>, That no refrigerated cold storage facilities shall be constructed or purchased except with funds specifically provided by Congress for that purpose: <i>And provided further</i>, That any contract entered into by the Corporation for the use of a storage facility shall provide at least that (1) the rental rate charged for an extended term in excess of one year shall be at an annual rate less than that which is charged for a one-year contract, (2) any obligation of the Corporation to pay for the use of any space in a facility shall be relieved to the extent that the Corporation does not use the space and payment is made by another person for the use of such space, and (3) if the Corporation determines that it no longer needs the space reserved in the facility, the Corporation may be relieved, for the remaining term of the contract, of its obligations to an extent and in a manner that will provide significant savings to the Corporation while permitting the owner of the facility reasonable time to lease such space to another person: <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing contained in this subsection shall limit the duty of the Corporation, to the maximum extent practicable consistent with the fulfillment of the Corporation’s purposes and the effective and efficient conduct of its business, to utilize the usual and customary channels, facilities, and arrangements of trade and commerce in the warehousing of commodities: <i>And provided further</i>, That to encourage the storage of grain on farms, where it can be stored at the lowest cost, the Corporation may make loans to grain growers needing storage facilities when such growers shall apply to the Corporation for financing the construction or purchase of suitable storage, and these loans shall be deducted from the proceeds of price support loans or purchase agreements made between the Corporation and the growers, except that the Secretary shall make such loans in areas in which the Secretary determines that there is a deficiency of such storage. To encourage the alleviation of natural resource conservation problems that reduce the productive capacity of the Nation’s land and water resources or that cause degradation of environmental quality, the Corporation may, beginning <date date="1981-12-22">December 22, 1981</date>, make loans to any agricultural producer for those natural resource conservation and environmental enhancement measures that are recommended by the applicable county and State committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of title 16</ref> and are included in the producer’s conservation plan approved by the local soil and water conservation district; such loans shall be for a period not to exceed ten years at a rate of interest based upon the rate of interest charged the Corporation by the United States Treasury; the Corporation may make loans to any one producer in any fiscal year in an amount not to exceed $25,000; loans up to $10,000 in amount may be unsecured and loans in excess of $10,000 shall be secured; and the total of such unsecured and secured loans made in each fiscal year shall not exceed $200,000,000: <i>Provided</i>, That the authority provided by this sentence to make loans shall be effective only to the extent and in such amounts as may be provided for in prior appropriation Acts. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall, to the maximum extent practicable, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and upon terms and conditions prescribed or approved by the Secretary of Agriculture, accept strategic and critical materials produced abroad in exchange for agricultural commodities acquired by the Corporation. Insofar as practicable, in effecting such exchange of goods, the Secretary shall: (1) use normal commercial trade channels; (2) take action to avoid displacing usual marketings of United States agricultural commodities and the products thereof; (3) take reasonable precautions to prevent the resale or transshipment to other countries, or use for other than domestic use in the importing country, of agricultural commodities used for such exchange; and (4) give priority to commodities easily storable and those which serve as prime incentive goods to stimulate production of critical and strategic materials. The Corporation may solicit bids from, and utilize, private trading firms to effect such exchange of goods. The determination of the quantities and qualities of such materials which are desirable for stock piling and the determination of which materials are strategic and critical shall be made in the manner prescribed by section 3 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98b">50 U.S.C. 98b</ref>]. Strategic and critical materials acquired by Commodity Credit Corporation in exchange for agricultural commodities shall, to the extent approved by the President, be transferred to the stock pile provided for by the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98">50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.]; and in the same fiscal year such materials are transferred to the stock pile the Commodity Credit Corporation shall be reimbursed for the strategic and critical materials so transferred to the stock pile from the funds made available for the purpose of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act, in an amount equal to the fair market value, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, of the material transferred to the stock pile. If the volume of petroleum products (including crude oil) stored in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is less than the level prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6234">section 6234 of title 42</ref>, the Corporation shall, to the maximum extent practicable and with the approval of the Secretary of Agriculture, make available annually to the Secretary of Energy, upon the request of the Secretary of Energy, a quantity of agricultural products owned by the Corporation with a market value at the time of such request of at least $300,000,000 for use by the Secretary of Energy in acquiring petroleum products (including crude oil) produced abroad for placement in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve through an exchange of such agricultural products. The terms and conditions of each such exchange, including provisions for full reimbursement to the Commodity Credit Corporation, shall be determined by the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture. Nothing contained herein shall limit the authority of the Commodity Credit Corporation to acquire, hold, or dispose of such quantity of strategic and critical materials as it deems advisable in carrying out its functions and protecting its assets: <i>Provided</i>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, where a grain storage facility owned by the Corporation is not needed by the Corporation and, upon being offered for sale no person offers to pay the minimum price set by the Corporation for such facility for use in connection with storage or handling of agricultural commodities, then the Corporation may, without declaring such facility to be excess property, sell it by bids at not less than such minimum price to any public or private nonprofit agency or organization for use for the purposes of such agency or organization. This provision shall apply also to facilities which on the effective date of this Act have been declared excess to the needs of the Commodity Credit Corporation but have not been claimed by any other Government agency, or surplus to the needs of the Government but not disposed of pursuant to the provisions of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> May borrow money subject to any provision of law applicable to the Corporation: <i>Provided</i>, That the total of all money borrowed by the Corporation, other than trust deposits and advances received on sales, shall not at any time exceed in the aggregate $30,000,000,000. The Corporation shall at all times reserve a sufficient amount of its authorized borrowing power which, together with other funds available to the Corporation, will enable it to purchase, in accordance with its contracts with lending agencies, notes, or other obligations evidencing loans made by such agencies under the Corporation’s programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> Shall determine the character of and the necessity for its obligations and expenditures and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, and paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> Shall have authority to make final and conclusive settlement and adjustment of any claims by or against the Corporation or the accounts of its fiscal officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> May make such loans and advances of its funds as are necessary in the conduct of its business.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id79376ae6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714b/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content> Shall have such powers as may be necessary or appropriate for the exercise of the powers specifically vested in the Corporation, and all such incidental powers as are customary in corporations generally; but any research financed by the Corporation shall relate to the conservation or disposal of commodities owned or controlled by the Corporation and shall be conducted in collaboration with research agencies of the Department of Agriculture. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Corporation may, in the exercise of its power to remove and dispose of surplus agricultural commodities, export, or cause to be exported, not to exceed such amounts of commodities owned by the Corporation as will enable the Corporation to finance research and development of external combustion engines using fuel other than that derived from petroleum and petroleum products. The total value of commodities exported annually for the purposes of the research authorized by the preceding sentence may not exceed $30,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7939dae7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-29/ch704/s4">June 29, 1948, ch. 704, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1070">62 Stat. 1070</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-06-07/ch175">June 7, 1949, ch. 175</ref>, §§ 2, 5, <ref href="/us/stat/63/154">63 Stat. 154</ref>, 156; <ref href="/us/act/1949-08-10/ch412/s12/a">Aug. 10, 1949, ch. 412, § 12(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/591">63 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-06-28/ch381/s2">June 28, 1950, ch. 381, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/261">64 Stat. 261</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-03-20/ch102/s2">Mar. 20, 1954, ch. 102, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/30">68 Stat. 30</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1172/s2">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1172, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1047">68 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch782/s2">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 782, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/634">69 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch815/s1/a">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 815, § 1(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/783">70 Stat. 783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/758">Pub. L. 89–758</ref>, <date date="1966-11-05">Nov. 5, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1307">80 Stat. 1307</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXI/s1104">Pub. L. 95–113, title XI, § 1104</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/954">91 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/279/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–279, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-05-15">May 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/242">92 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/41/s3/b">Pub. L. 96–41, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/325">93 Stat. 325</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/234/s3">Pub. L. 96–234, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-04-11">Apr. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/333">94 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s151">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/370">95 Stat. 370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXV/s1520/a">Pub. L. 97–98, title XV, § 1520(a)</ref>, title XVI, § 1606, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1335">95 Stat. 1335</ref>, 1347; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s161/1">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 161(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/49">96 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXI/s1167/b">Pub. L. 99–198, title XI, § 1167(b)</ref>, title XVII, § 1761, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1503">99 Stat. 1503</ref>, 1651; <ref href="/us/pl/99/260/s11">Pub. L. 99–260, § 11</ref>, <date date="1986-03-20">Mar. 20, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/52">100 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/k/tI/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(k) [title I, § 101]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-322">101 Stat. 1329–322</ref>, 1329–336; <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/tIX/s902/b/1">Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4516">106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tI/s161/b/1">Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 161(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/934">110 Stat. 934</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/185/tV/s521/a">Pub. L. 105–185, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/580">112 Stat. 580</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/a/tVII/s756">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 756]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681">112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–34.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7939dae8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7939dae9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7939daea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Tort Claims Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is title IV of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753">act Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/842">60 Stat. 842</ref>, which was classified principally to chapter 20 (§§ 921, 922, 931–934, 941–946) of former Title 28, Judicial Code and Judiciary. Title IV of act <date date="1946-08-02">Aug. 2, 1946</date>, was substantially repealed and reenacted as sections 1346(b) and 2671 et seq. of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, by <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">act June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/992">62 Stat. 992</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 28. The Federal Tort Claims Act is also commonly used to refer to chapter 171 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. For complete classification of title IV to the Code, see Tables. For distribution of former sections of Title 28 into the revised Title 28, see Table at the beginning of Title 28.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act, referred to in subsec. (h), is <ref href="/us/act/1939-06-07/ch190">act June 7, 1939, ch. 190</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/96/41/s2">Pub. L. 96–41, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/319">93 Stat. 319</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 98 et seq.) of chapter 5 of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98">section 98 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this Act, referred to in subsec. (h), probably refers to the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/89/758">Pub. L. 89–758</ref>, which was approved on <date date="1966-11-05">Nov. 5, 1966</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id7939daeb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “of the District of Columbia and” in the phrase of subsec. (c) reading “including the district courts of the District of Columbia and of any Territory or possession” have been deleted as superfluous in view of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s132/a">section 132(a) of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, which states that “There shall be in each judicial district a district court which shall be a court of record known as the United States District Court for the district” and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s88">section 88 of Title 28</ref> which states that “The District of Columbia constitutes one judicial district”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (h), “chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41” substituted for “the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, which Act enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, which directed the Corporation to make secured storage facility loans of not to exceed $50,000, later increased to $100,000, to growers of dry or high moisture grain, soybeans, rice, and high moisture forage and silage during the period <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, to <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>, was omitted from the Code as terminated. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1977 Amendment note set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7939daec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> substituted “$188,000,000” for “$193,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/185">Pub. L. 105–185</ref> substituted “$193,000,000” for “$275,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s161/b/1/A">Pub. L. 104–127, § 161(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “, except that obligations under all such contracts or agreements (other than reimbursable agreements under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s714i">section 714i of this title</ref>) for equipment or services relating to automated data processing, information technologies, or related items (including telecommunications equipment and computer hardware and software) may not exceed $170,000,000 in fiscal year 1996 and not more than $275,000,000 in the 6-fiscal year period beginning on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>, unless additional amounts for such contracts and agreements are provided in advance in appropriation Acts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s161/b/1/B">Pub. L. 104–127, § 161(b)(1)(B)</ref>, in second sentence, struck out “shall have power to acquire personal property necessary to the conduct of its business but” after “The Corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/572">Pub. L. 102–572</ref> substituted “United States Court of Federal Claims” for “United States Claims Court”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> substituted “$30,000,000,000” for “$25,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/99/260">Pub. L. 99–260</ref> inserted provision authorizing the Corporation to dispose of or export surplus agricultural commodities in amounts that will enable the Corporation to finance research and development of external combustion engines using fuel other than that derived from petroleum and petroleum products and limiting the total value of the commodities exported annually to a maximum of $30,000,000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1761">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1761</ref>, inserted an additional proviso reading as follows: “That any contract entered into by the Corporation for the use of a storage facility shall provide at least that (1) the rental rate charged for an extended term in excess of one year shall be at an annual rate less than that which is charged for a one-year contract, (2) any obligation of the Corporation to pay for the use of any space in a facility shall be relieved to the extent that the Corporation does not use the space and payment is made by another person for the use of such space, and (3) if the Corporation determines that it no longer needs the space reserved in the facility, the Corporation may be relieved, for the remaining term of the contract, of its obligations to an extent and in a manner that will provide significant savings to the Corporation while permitting the owner of the facility reasonable time to lease such space to another person:”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1167/b">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1167(b)</ref>, in sentence beginning “Notwithstanding any other provision of law” substituted “Commodity Credit Corporation shall, to the maximum extent practicable, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and upon terms and conditions prescribed or approved by the Secretary of Agriculture, accept strategic and critical materials” for “Commodity Credit Corporation is authorized, upon terms and conditions prescribed or approved by the Secretary of Agriculture, to accept strategic and critical materials”; in sentence beginning “Insofar as practicable” substituted “the Secretary shall: (1) use normal commercial trade channels; (2) take action to avoid displacing usual marketings of United States agricultural commodities and the products thereof; (3) take reasonable precautions to prevent the resale or transshipment to other countries, or use for other than domestic use in the importing country, of agricultural commodities used for such exchange; and (4) give priority” for “normal commercial trade channels shall be utilized and priority shall be given”; inserted sentence reading “The Corporation may solicit bids from, and utilize, private trading firms to effect such exchange of goods.”; in sentence beginning “Strategic and critical materials” substituted “in the same fiscal year such materials are transferred” for “when transferred”; and inserted sentence beginning “If the volume of petroleum products” and sentence beginning “the terms and conditions” relating to acquisition of petroleum products for placement in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and terms and conditions of each exchange.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> substituted “Claims Court” for “Court of Claims”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> inserted “, except that the Secretary shall make such loans in areas in which the Secretary determines that there is a deficiency of such storage”, and inserted provision authorizing the Secretary to make loans to grain growers needing storage facilities for the storage of grain on farms in areas where the Secretary determines that there is a deficiency of such storage and also inserted provision that, to encourage the alleviation of natural resource conservation problems that reduce the productive capacity of the Nation’s land and water resources or that cause degradation of environmental quality, the Corporation may, beginning <date date="1981-12-22">December 22, 1981</date>, make loans to any agricultural producer for those natural resource conservation and environmental enhancement measures that are recommended by the applicable county and State committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of title 16</ref> and are included in the producer’s conservation plan approved by the local soil and water conservation district, that such loans shall be for a period not to exceed ten years at a rate of interest based upon the rate of interest charged the Corporation by the United States Treasury, that the Corporation may make loans to any one producer in any fiscal year in an amount not to exceed $25,000, that loans up to $10,000 in amount may be unsecured and loans in excess of $10,000 shall be secured, that the total of such unsecured and secured loans made in each fiscal year shall not exceed $200,000,000, and that the authority to make such loans be effective only to the extent and in such amounts as may be provided for in prior appropriation Acts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted “the Corporation may make loans” for “the Corporation shall make loans” in fourth proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/234">Pub. L. 96–234</ref> substituted “$100,000” for “$50,000” in two places, and struck out provisions respecting the size of the facility for purposes of obtaining loans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/41">Pub. L. 96–41</ref> substituted “section 3 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act” for “section 2 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref href="/us/stat/60/596">60 Stat. 596</ref>)” and “the President” for “the Munitions Board of the Department of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/279">Pub. L. 95–279</ref> substituted “$25,000,000,000” for “$14,500,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> inserted proviso directing the Corporation to make secured storage facility loans of not to exceed $50,000 to growers of dry or high moisture grain, soybeans, rice, and high moisture forage and silage during the period <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, to <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>. See Codification note set out above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/89/758">Pub. L. 89–758</ref> inserted provisions allowing for the sale of grain storage facilities by bids when no person offers to pay the minimum price set by the Commodity Credit Corporation at not less than the minimum price to any public or private nonprofit agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, substituted “$14,500,000,000” for “$12,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1955-08-11">Aug. 11, 1955</date>, substituted “$12,000,000,000” for “$10,000,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, substituted “$10,000,000,000” for “$8,500,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1954-03-20">Mar. 20, 1954</date>, substituted “$8,500,000,000” for “$6,750,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1950-06-28">June 28, 1950</date>, substituted “$6,750,000,000” for “$4,750,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1949-06-07">June 7, 1949</date>, § 5, conferred jurisdiction on the district courts “without regard to the amount in controversy”, enabled the Corporation and persons having claims against the Corporation to plead set-offs and counterclaims which are barred by the statute of limitations, if, at the time the plaintiff’s cause of action arose, the defendant’s cause of action on which the set-off or counterclaim is based was not barred by the statute of limitations, and provided that certain claims against the United States could be brought in the United States Court of Claims.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). Act <date date="1949-06-07">June 7, 1949</date>, § 2, enabled the Corporation to acquire items of personal and real property to be used in connection with the care, preservation, storage, and handling of agricultural commodities controlled by it, and enabled the Corporation to take liens on real property as security for obligations owing to it and to bid in on any execution or foreclosure sale to protect its financial interests in the matter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7939daed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7939daee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Military Establishment changed to Department of Defense by act <date date="1949-08-10">Aug. 10, 1949</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/185/tV/s521/b">Pub. L. 105–185, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/580">112 Stat. 580</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/185/tV/s521/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] takes effect on <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daf0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/572">Pub. L. 102–572</ref> effective <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s911">section 911 of Pub. L. 102–572</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daf1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daf2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daf3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/279">Pub. L. 95–279</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/279/s301/d">section 301(d) of Pub. L. 95–279</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713a–4">section 713a–4 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7939daf4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1104">Section 1104 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref> provided that the amendment made by that section is effective only with respect to the fiscal years beginning <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, and ending <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7939daf5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Storage Cost Adjustment for Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tI/s1106">Pub. L. 100–203, title I, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-5">101 Stat. 1330–5</ref>, required the Secretary of Agriculture to reduce expenditures of the Commodity Credit Corporation for commercial storage, transportation, and handling of commodities owned by the Corporation by $230,000,000 from the amount of funds otherwise projected to be expended in fiscal years 1988 and 1989 under the budget base determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s901">section 901 of title 2</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7939daf6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Increase in Borrowing Authority Effective Only to Extent Provided in Appropriation Acts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/279/tIII/s301/c">Pub. L. 95–279, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-05-15">May 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/242">92 Stat. 242</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/279/tIII/s301/c">“The increase in the borrowing authority of the Commodity Credit Corporation made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s713a–4">section 713a–4 of this title</ref>] shall be effective only to the extent provided in appropriation Acts.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7939daf7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id7939daf8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under subsec. (h) of this section delegated to Secretary of Defense, see section 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 12626, <date date="1988-02-25">Feb. 25, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 6114, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98">section 98 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7939daf9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For exception of functions of corporations of Department of Agriculture from transfer of functions to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, see Exceptions From Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
