<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7939db6c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s714n"><num value="714n">§ 714n.</num><heading> Transfer of assets of Commodity Credit Corporation, a Delaware corporation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The assets, funds, property, and records of Commodity Credit Corporation, a Delaware corporation, are transferred to the Corporation. The rights, privileges, and powers, and the duties and liabilities of Commodity Credit Corporation, a Delaware corporation, in respect to any contract, agreement, loan, account, or other obligation shall become the rights, privileges, and powers, and the duties and liabilities, respectively, of the Corporation. The enforceable claims of or against Commodity Credit Corporation, a Delaware corporation, shall become the claims of or against, and may be enforced by or against, the Corporation: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this subchapter shall limit or extend any period of limitation otherwise applicable to such claims against the Corporation.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7939db6d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-29/ch704/s16">June 29, 1948, ch. 704, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1075">62 Stat. 1075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7939db6e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7939db6f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7939db70-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For exception of functions of corporations of Department of Agriculture from transfer of functions to Secretary of Agriculture by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1953, see Exceptions From Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
