<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id793c4cc9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717"><num value="717">§ 717.</num><heading> Regulation of natural gas companies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793c4cca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Necessity of regulation in public interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As disclosed in reports of the Federal Trade Commission made pursuant to S. Res. 83 (Seventieth Congress, first session) and other reports made pursuant to the authority of Congress, it is declared that the business of transporting and selling natural gas for ultimate distribution to the public is affected with a public interest, and that Federal regulation in matters relating to the transportation of natural gas and the sale thereof in interstate and foreign commerce is necessary in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793c4ccb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transactions to which provisions of chapter applicable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the transportation of natural gas in interstate commerce, to the sale in interstate commerce of natural gas for resale for ultimate public consumption for domestic, commercial, industrial, or any other use, and to natural-gas companies engaged in such transportation or sale, and to the importation or exportation of natural gas in foreign commerce and to persons engaged in such importation or exportation, but shall not apply to any other transportation or sale of natural gas or to the local distribution of natural gas or to the facilities used for such distribution or to the production or gathering of natural gas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793c4ccc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Intrastate transactions exempt from provisions of chapter; certification from State commission as conclusive evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to any person engaged in or legally authorized to engage in the transportation in interstate commerce or the sale in interstate commerce for resale, of natural gas received by such person from another person within or at the boundary of a State if all the natural gas so received is ultimately consumed within such State, or to any facilities used by such person for such transportation or sale, provided that the rates and service of such person and facilities be subject to regulation by a State commission. The matters exempted from the provisions of this chapter by this subsection are declared to be matters primarily of local concern and subject to regulation by the several States. A certification from such State commission to the Federal Power Commission that such State commission has regulatory jurisdiction over rates and service of such person and facilities and is exercising such jurisdiction shall constitute conclusive evidence of such regulatory power or jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id793c4ccd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Vehicular natural gas jurisdiction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to any person solely by reason of, or with respect to, any sale or transportation of vehicular natural gas if such person is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793c4cce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not otherwise a natural-gas company; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id793c4ccf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> subject primarily to regulation by a State commission, whether or not such State commission has, or is exercising, jurisdiction over the sale, sale for resale, or transportation of vehicular natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id793c4cd0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-21/ch556/s1">June 21, 1938, ch. 556, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/821">52 Stat. 821</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-03-27/ch115">Mar. 27, 1954, ch. 115</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/36">68 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIV/s404/a/1">Pub. L. 102–486, title IV, § 404(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2879">106 Stat. 2879</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tIII/s311/a">Pub. L. 109–58, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/685">119 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id793c4cd1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id793c4cd2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id793c4cd3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> inserted “and to the importation or exportation of natural gas in foreign commerce and to persons engaged in such importation or exportation,” after “such transportation or sale,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1954-03-27">Mar. 27, 1954</date>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id793c4cd4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793c4cd5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Federal Power Commission; Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Commission was terminated, and its functions, personnel, property, funds, etc., were transferred to Secretary of Energy (except for certain functions which were transferred to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission) by sections 7151(b), 7171(a), 7172(a), 7291, and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793c4cd6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">State Laws and Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIV/s404/b">Pub. L. 102–486, title IV, § 404(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2879">106 Stat. 2879</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/486/tIV/s404/b">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“The transportation or sale of natural gas by any person who is not otherwise a public utility, within the meaning of State law—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in closed containers; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> otherwise to any person for use by such person as a fuel in a self-propelled vehicle,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall not be considered to be a transportation or sale of natural gas within the meaning of any State law, regulation, or order in effect before <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>. This subsection shall not apply to any provision of any State law, regulation, or order to the extent that such provision has as its primary purpose the protection of public safety.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793c4cd7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Natural Gas Act of 1977</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/2">Pub. L. 95–2</ref>, <date date="1977-02-02">Feb. 2, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/4">91 Stat. 4</ref>, authorized President to declare a natural gas emergency and to require emergency deliveries and transportation of natural gas until the earlier of <date date="1977-04-30">Apr. 30, 1977</date>, or termination of emergency by President and provided for antitrust protection, emergency purchases, adjustment in charges for local distribution companies, relationship to Natural Gas Act, effect of certain contractual obligations, administrative procedure and judicial review, enforcement, reporting to Congress, delegation of authorities, and preemption of inconsistent State or local action.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id793c4cd8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id793c4cd9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11969</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11969, <date date="1977-02-02">Feb. 2, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6791, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12038, <date date="1978-02-03">Feb. 3, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 4957, which delegated to the Secretary of Energy the authority vested in the President by the Emergency Natural Gas Act of 1977 except the authority to declare and terminate a natural gas emergency, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12553, <date date="1986-02-25">Feb. 25, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 7237.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793c4cda-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proclamation No. 4485</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 4485, <date date="1977-02-02">Feb. 2, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6789, declared that a natural gas emergency existed within the meaning of section 3 of the Emergency Natural Gas Act of 1977, set out as a note above, which emergency was terminated by Proc. No. 4495, <date date="1977-04-01">Apr. 1, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 18053, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id793c4cdb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proclamation No. 4495</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 4495, <date date="1977-04-01">Apr. 1, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 18053, terminated the natural gas emergency declared to exist by Proc. No. 4485, <date date="1977-02-02">Feb. 2, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6789, formerly set out above.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
