<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id793e9696-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s717q"><num value="717q">§ 717q.</num><heading> Appointment of officers and employees</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, examiners, and experts as may be necessary for carrying out its functions under this chapter; and the Commission may, subject to civil-service laws, appoint such other officers and employees as are necessary for carrying out such functions and fix their salaries in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id793e9697-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-21/ch556/s18">June 21, 1938, ch. 556, § 18</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/831">52 Stat. 831</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id793e9698-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id793e9699-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id793e969a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions that authorized the Commission to appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, examiners, and experts as may be necessary for carrying out its functions under this chapter “without regard to the provisions of other laws applicable to the employment and compensation of officers and employees of the United States” are omitted as obsolete and superseded.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">As to the compensation of such personnel, sections 1202 and 1204 of the Classification Act of 1949, <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>, 973, repealed the Classification Act of 1923 and all other laws or parts of laws inconsistent with the 1949 Act. The Classification Act of 1949 was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8(a), <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, and reenacted as chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5102">Section 5102 of Title 5</ref> contains the applicability provisions of the 1949 Act, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5103">section 5103 of Title 5</ref> authorizes the Office of Personnel Management to determine the applicability to specific positions and employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Such appointments are now subject to the civil service laws unless specifically excepted by those laws or by laws enacted subsequent to Executive Order 8743, <date date="1941-04-23">Apr. 23, 1941</date>, issued by the President pursuant to the <ref href="/us/act/1940-11-26/ch919/tI/s1">Act of Nov. 26, 1940, ch. 919, title I, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1211">54 Stat. 1211</ref>, which covered most excepted positions into the classified (competitive) civil service. The Order is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3301">section 3301 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted in text for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id793e969b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id793e969c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id793e969d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed (subject to a savings clause) by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, 655.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
