<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7945c220-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s719k"><num value="719k">§ 719k.</num><heading> Equal access to facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7945c221-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s719k/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Ownership in transportation system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be included in the terms of any certificate, permit, right-of-way, lease, or other authorization issued or granted pursuant to the directions contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719g">section 719g of this title</ref>, a provision that no person seeking to transport natural gas in the Alaska natural gas transportation system shall be prevented from doing so or be discriminated against in the terms and conditions of service on the basis of degree of ownership, or lack thereof, of the Alaska natural gas transportation system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7945c222-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s719k/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use within Alaska</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State of Alaska is authorized to ship its royalty gas on the approved transportation system for use within Alaska and, to the extent its contracts for the sale of royalty gas so provide, to withdraw such gas from the interstate market for use within Alaska; the Federal Power Commission shall issue all authorizations necessary to effectuate such shipment and withdrawal subject to review by the Commission only of the justness and reasonableness of the rate charged for such transportation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7945c223-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/586/s13">Pub. L. 94–586, § 13</ref>, <date date="1976-10-22">Oct. 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2915">90 Stat. 2915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7945c224-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7945c225-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7945c226-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Commission was terminated, and its functions, personnel, property, funds, etc., were transferred to the Secretary of Energy (except for certain functions which were transferred to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission) by sections 7151(b), 7171(a), 7172(a)(1), 7291, and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7945c227-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7945c228-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enforcement functions authorized by, and supplemental enforcement authority created by this chapter with respect to pre-construction, construction, and initial operation of transportation system for Canadian and Alaskan natural gas transferred to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, until first anniversary of date of initial operation of Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, see Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1979, §§ 102(h)(1), 203(a), 44 F.R. 33663, 33666, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1373">93 Stat. 1373</ref>, 1376, effective <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719e">section 719e of this title</ref>. Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System abolished and functions and authority vested in Inspector transferred to Secretary of Energy by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s3012/b">section 3012(b) of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, set out as an Abolition of Office of Federal Inspector note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719e">section 719e of this title</ref>. Functions and authority vested in Secretary of Energy subsequently transferred to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s720d/f">section 720d(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
