<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a6feacf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216"><num value="7216">§ 7216.</num><heading> Foreign public accounting firms</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability to certain foreign firms</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any foreign public accounting firm that prepares or furnishes an audit report with respect to any issuer, broker, or dealer, shall be subject to this Act and the rules of the Board and the Commission issued under this Act, in the same manner and to the same extent as a public accounting firm that is organized and operates under the laws of the United States or any State, except that registration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s7212">section 7212 of this title</ref> shall not by itself provide a basis for subjecting such a foreign public accounting firm to the jurisdiction of the Federal or State courts, other than with respect to controversies between such firms and the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Board authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board may, by rule, determine that a foreign public accounting firm (or a class of such firms) that does not issue audit reports nonetheless plays such a substantial role in the preparation and furnishing of such reports for particular issuers, brokers, or dealers, that it is necessary or appropriate, in light of the purposes of this Act and in the public interest or for the protection of investors, that such firm (or class of firms) should be treated as a public accounting firm (or firms) for purposes of registration under, and oversight by the Board in accordance with, this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Production of documents</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Production by foreign firms</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a foreign public accounting firm performs material services upon which a registered public accounting firm relies in the conduct of an audit or interim review, issues an audit report, performs audit work, or conducts interim reviews, the foreign public accounting firm shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a6fead5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> produce the audit work papers of the foreign public accounting firm and all other documents of the firm related to any such audit work or interim review to the Commission or the Board, upon request of the Commission or the Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a6fead6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States for purposes of enforcement of any request for such documents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6fead7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Other production</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any registered public accounting firm that relies, in whole or in part, on the work of a foreign public accounting firm in issuing an audit report, performing audit work, or conducting an interim review, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a6fead8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> produce the audit work papers of the foreign public accounting firm and all other documents related to any such work in response to a request for production by the Commission or the Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a6fead9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> secure the agreement of any foreign public accounting firm to such production, as a condition of the reliance by the registered public accounting firm on the work of that foreign public accounting firm.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feada-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, and the Board, subject to the approval of the Commission, may, by rule, regulation, or order, and as the Commission (or Board) determines necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, either unconditionally or upon specified terms and conditions exempt any foreign public accounting firm, or any class of such firms, from any provision of this Act or the rules of the Board or the Commission issued under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feadb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Service of requests or process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feadc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any foreign public accounting firm that performs work for a domestic registered public accounting firm shall furnish to the domestic registered public accounting firm a written irrevocable consent and power of attorney that designates the domestic registered public accounting firm as an agent upon whom may be served any request by the Commission or the Board under this section or upon whom may be served any process, pleadings, or other papers in any action brought to enforce this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feadd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific audit work</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any foreign public accounting firm that performs material services upon which a registered public accounting firm relies in the conduct of an audit or interim review, issues an audit report, performs audit work, or, performs interim reviews, shall designate to the Commission or the Board an agent in the United States upon whom may be served any request by the Commission or the Board under this section or upon whom may be served any process, pleading, or other papers in any action brought to enforce this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feade-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A willful refusal to comply, in whole in or in part, with any request by the Commission or the Board under this section, shall be deemed a violation of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feadf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Other means of satisfying production obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the staff of the Commission or the Board may allow a foreign public accounting firm that is subject to this section to meet production obligations under this section through alternate means, such as through foreign counterparts of the Commission or the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a6feae0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7216/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “foreign public accounting firm” means a public accounting firm that is organized and operates under the laws of a foreign government or political subdivision thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a6feae1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/204/tI/s106">Pub. L. 107–204, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/764">116 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX</ref>, §§ 929J, 982(g), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1859">124 Stat. 1859</ref>, 1930.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a6feae2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a6feae3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a6feae4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a), (c), and (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/204">Pub. L. 107–204</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/745">116 Stat. 745</ref>, known as the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a6feae5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s982/g/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 982(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “issuer, broker, or dealer” for “issuer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s982/g/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 982(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “issuers, brokers, or dealers” for “issuers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929J/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929J(1)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which related to deemed consent to production of audit workpapers by foreign and domestic firms.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929J/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929J(2)</ref>, (3), added subsecs. (d) to (f) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a6feae6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7a6feae7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
