<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a7960dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501"><num value="7501">§ 7501.</num><heading> National Nanotechnology Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7960dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National Nanotechnology Program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall implement a National Nanotechnology Program. Through appropriate agencies, councils, and the National Nanotechnology Coordination Office established in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s7502">section 7502 of this title</ref>, the Program shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish the goals, priorities, and metrics for evaluation for Federal nanotechnology research, development, and other activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> invest in Federal research and development programs in nanotechnology and related sciences to achieve those goals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide for interagency coordination of Federal nanotechnology research, development, and other activities undertaken pursuant to the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7960e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Program activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The activities of the Program shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> developing a fundamental understanding of matter that enables control and manipulation at the nanoscale;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960e3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing grants to individual investigators and interdisciplinary teams of investigators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960e4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establishing a network of advanced technology user facilities and centers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> establishing, on a merit-reviewed and competitive basis, interdisciplinary nanotechnology research centers, which shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> interact and collaborate to foster the exchange of technical information and best practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> involve academic institutions or national laboratories and other partners, which may include States and industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make use of existing expertise in nanotechnology in their regions and nationally;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> make use of ongoing research and development at the micrometer scale to support their work in nanotechnology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> to the greatest extent possible, be established in geographically diverse locations, encourage the participation of Historically Black Colleges and Universities that are part B institutions as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1061/2">section 1061(2) of title 20</ref> and minority institutions (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1067k/3">section 1067k(3) of title 20</ref>), and include institutions located in States participating in the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> ensuring United States global leadership in the development and application of nanotechnology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960ec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> advancing the United States productivity and industrial competitiveness through stable, consistent, and coordinated investments in long-term scientific and engineering research in nanotechnology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960ed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> accelerating the deployment and application of nanotechnology research and development in the private sector, including startup companies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960ee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> encouraging interdisciplinary research, and ensuring that processes for solicitation and evaluation of proposals under the Program encourage interdisciplinary projects and collaborations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960ef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> providing effective education and training for researchers and professionals skilled in the interdisciplinary perspectives necessary for nanotechnology so that a true interdisciplinary research culture for nanoscale science, engineering, and technology can emerge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960f0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> ensuring that ethical, legal, environmental, and other appropriate societal concerns, including the potential use of nanotechnology in enhancing human intelligence and in developing artificial intelligence which exceeds human capacity, are considered during the development of nanotechnology by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960f1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> establishing a research program to identify ethical, legal, environmental, and other appropriate societal concerns related to nanotechnology, and ensuring that the results of such research are widely disseminated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960f2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> requiring that interdisciplinary nanotechnology research centers established under paragraph (4) include activities that address societal, ethical, and environmental concerns;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960f3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> insofar as possible, integrating research on societal, ethical, and environmental concerns with nanotechnology research and development, and ensuring that advances in nanotechnology bring about improvements in quality of life for all Americans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960f4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/10/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> providing, through the National Nanotechnology Coordination Office established in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s7502">section 7502 of this title</ref>, for public input and outreach to be integrated into the Program by the convening of regular and ongoing public discussions, through mechanisms such as citizens’ panels, consensus conferences, and educational events, as appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> encouraging research on nanotechnology advances that utilize existing processes and technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7960f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Program management</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Science and Technology Council shall oversee the planning, management, and coordination of the Program. The Council, itself or through an appropriate subgroup it designates or establishes, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish goals and priorities for the Program, based on national needs for a set of broad applications of nanotechnology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> establish program component areas, with specific priorities and technical goals, that reflect the goals and priorities established for the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> oversee interagency coordination of the Program, including with the activities of the Defense Nanotechnology Research and Development Program established under section 246 of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Public Law 107–314</ref>) and the National Institutes of Health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a7960fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> develop, not later than 5 years after the date of the release of the most-recent strategic plan, and update every 5 years thereafter, a strategic plan to guide the activities described under subsection (b) that describes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the near-term and long-term objectives for the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the anticipated schedule for achieving the near-term objectives; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002577">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002577"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the metrics that will be used to assess progress toward the near-term and long-term objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> how the Program will move results out of the laboratory and into application for the benefit of society;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7960ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the Program’s support for long-term funding for interdisciplinary research and development in nanotechnology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a796100-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the allocation of funding for interagency nanotechnology projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796101-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> propose a coordinated interagency budget for the Program to the Office of Management and Budget to ensure the maintenance of a balanced nanotechnology research portfolio and an appropriate level of research effort;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796102-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> exchange information with academic, industry, State and local government (including State and regional nanotechnology programs), and other appropriate groups conducting research on and using nanotechnology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796103-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> develop a plan to utilize Federal programs, such as the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Research Program, in support of the activity stated in subsection (b)(7);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796104-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> identify research areas that are not being adequately addressed by the agencies’ current research programs and address such research areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796105-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> encourage progress on Program activities through the utilization of existing manufacturing facilities and industrial infrastructures such as, but not limited to, the employment of underutilized manufacturing facilities in areas of high unemployment as production engineering and research testbeds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796106-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> in carrying out its responsibilities under paragraphs (1) through (9), take into consideration the recommendations of the Advisory Panel, suggestions or recommendations developed pursuant to subsection (b)(10)(D), and the views of academic, State, industry, and other appropriate groups conducting research on and using nanotechnology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a796107-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Council shall prepare an annual report, to be submitted to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Science, and other appropriate committees, at the time of the President’s budget request to Congress, that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796108-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Program budget, for the current fiscal year, for each agency that participates in the Program, including a breakout of spending for the development and acquisition of research facilities and instrumentation, for each program component area, and for all activities pursuant to subsection (b)(10);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a796109-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the proposed Program budget for the next fiscal year, for each agency that participates in the Program, including a breakout of spending for the development and acquisition of research facilities and instrumentation, for each program component area, and for all activities pursuant to subsection (b)(10);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a79610a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an analysis of the progress made toward achieving the goals and priorities established for the Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a79610b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an analysis of the extent to which the Program has incorporated the recommendations of the Advisory Panel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a79610c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7501/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an assessment of how Federal agencies are implementing the plan described in subsection (c)(7), and a description of the amount of Small Business Innovative Research and Small Business Technology Transfer Research funds supporting the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a79610d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/153/s2">Pub. L. 108–153, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1923">117 Stat. 1923</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/329/tII/s204/b/1">Pub. L. 114–329, title II, § 204(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-01-06">Jan. 6, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2999">130 Stat. 2999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a79610e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a79610f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a796110-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 246 of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003, referred to in subsec. (c)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s246">section 246 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2358">section 2358 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a796111-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/329">Pub. L. 114–329</ref> amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “develop, within 12 months after <date date="2003-12-03">December 3, 2003</date>, and update every 3 years thereafter, a strategic plan to guide the activities described under subsection (b), meet the goals, priorities, and anticipated outcomes of the participating agencies, and describe—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) how the Program will move results out of the laboratory and into application for the benefit of society;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the Program’s support for long-term funding for interdisciplinary research and development in nanotechnology; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) the allocation of funding for interagency nanotechnology projects;”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7a796112-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7a796113-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Science of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Science and Technology of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Science and Technology of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Twelfth Congress, <date date="2011-01-05">Jan. 5, 2011</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id7a796114-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/153/s1">Pub. L. 108–153, § 1</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1923">117 Stat. 1923</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/153/s1">“This Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘21st Century Nanotechnology Research and Development Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
