<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id794aa4c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s770"><num value="770">§ 770.</num><heading> Appointments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794aa4c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s770/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds available to any department or agency (or any official or component thereof), and lawfully authorized for any of the specific functions which are transferred to the Administrator by this chapter, may, with the approval of the President, be used to pay the compensation and expenses of any officer appointed pursuant to this chapter until such times as funds for that purpose are otherwise available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794aa4c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s770/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim appointments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event that any officer required by this chapter to be appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate shall not have entered upon office on the effective date of this chapter, the President may designate any officer, whose appointment was required to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and who was such an officer immediately prior to the effective date of this chapter, or any officer who was performing essentially the same functions immediately prior to the effective date of this chapter to act in such office until the office is filled as provided in this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That any officer acting pursuant to the provisions of this subsection may act no longer than a period of thirty days unless during such period his appointment as such an officer is submitted to the Senate for its advice and consent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794aa4c5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s770/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Nontemporary personnel; transferee rights for one year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Transfer of nontemporary personnel pursuant to this chapter shall not cause any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation, except for cause, for one year after such transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794aa4c6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s770/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation of new position at not less than provided for in Executive Schedule for previous position in cases of appointees without break in service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who, on the effective date of this chapter, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule prescribed in chapter 53 of title 5, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the Administration to a position having duties comparable to those performed immediately preceding his appointment, shall continue to be compensated in his new position at not less than the rate provided for his previous position.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id794aa4c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/275/s11">Pub. L. 93–275, § 11</ref>, <date date="1974-05-07">May 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/105">88 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id794aa4c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id794aa4c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id794aa4ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Energy Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
