<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77ddcdc5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d"><num value="77d">§ 77d.</num><heading> Exempted transactions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77ddcdc6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77e">section 77e of this title</ref> shall not apply to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdc7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> transactions by any person other than an issuer, underwriter, or dealer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdc8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> transactions by an issuer not involving any public offering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdc9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> transactions by a dealer (including an underwriter no longer acting as an underwriter in respect of the security involved in such transaction), except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> transactions taking place prior to the expiration of forty days after the first date upon which the security was bona fide offered to the public by the issuer or by or through an underwriter,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdcb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> transactions in a security as to which a registration statement has been filed taking place prior to the expiration of forty days after the effective date of such registration statement or prior to the expiration of forty days after the first date upon which the security was bona fide offered to the public by the issuer or by or through an underwriter after such effective date, whichever is later (excluding in the computation of such forty days any time during which a stop order issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77h">section 77h of this title</ref> is in effect as to the security), or such shorter period as the Commission may specify by rules and regulations or order, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdcc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> transactions as to securities constituting the whole or a part of an unsold allotment to or subscription by such dealer as a participant in the distribution of such securities by the issuer or by or through an underwriter.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">With respect to transactions referred to in clause (B), if securities of the issuer have not previously been sold pursuant to an earlier effective registration statement the applicable period, instead of forty days, shall be ninety days, or such shorter period as the Commission may specify by rules and regulations or order.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdcd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> brokers’ transactions executed upon customers’ orders on any exchange or in the over-the-counter market but not the solicitation of such orders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> transactions involving offers or sales by an issuer solely to one or more accredited investors, if the aggregate offering price of an issue of securities offered in reliance on this paragraph does not exceed the amount allowed under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77c/b/1">section 77c(b)(1) of this title</ref>, if there is no advertising or public solicitation in connection with the transaction by the issuer or anyone acting on the issuer’s behalf, and if the issuer files such notice with the Commission as the Commission shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdcf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> transactions involving the offer or sale of securities by an issuer (including all entities controlled by or under common control with the issuer), provided that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdd0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the aggregate amount sold to all investors by the issuer, including any amount sold in reliance on the exemption provided under this paragraph during the 12-month period preceding the date of such transaction, is not more than $1,000,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdd1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the aggregate amount sold to any investor by an issuer, including any amount sold in reliance on the exemption provided under this paragraph during the 12-month period preceding the date of such transaction, does not exceed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdd2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the greater of $2,000 or 5 percent of the annual income or net worth of such investor, as applicable, if either the annual income or the net worth of the investor is less than $100,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdd3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 10 percent of the annual income or net worth of such investor, as applicable, not to exceed a maximum aggregate amount sold of $100,000, if either the annual income or net worth of the investor is equal to or more than $100,000;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdd4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the transaction is conducted through a broker or funding portal that complies with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d–1/a">section 77d–1(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdd5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the issuer complies with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d–1/b">section 77d–1(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdd6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> transactions meeting the requirements of subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77ddcdd7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Offers and sales exempt under 17 CFR 230.506</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Offers and sales exempt under section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (as revised pursuant to section 201 of the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act) shall not be deemed public offerings under the Federal securities laws as a result of general advertising or general solicitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77ddcdd8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77ddcdd9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> With respect to securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D under this subchapter, no person who meets the conditions set forth in paragraph (2) shall be subject to registration as a broker or dealer pursuant to section 78<i>o</i>(a)(1) of this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002013"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> solely because—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdda-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that person maintains a platform or mechanism that permits the offer, sale, purchase, or negotiation of or with respect to securities, or permits general solicitations, general advertisements, or similar or related activities by issuers of such securities, whether online, in person, or through any other means;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcddb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that person or any person associated with that person co-invests in such securities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcddc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that person or any person associated with that person provides ancillary services with respect to such securities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77ddcddd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The exemption provided in paragraph (1) shall apply to any person described in such paragraph if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdde-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such person and each person associated with that person receives no compensation in connection with the purchase or sale of such security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcddf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such person and each person associated with that person does not have possession of customer funds or securities in connection with the purchase or sale of such security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such person is not subject to a statutory disqualification as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c/a/39">section 78c(a)(39) of this title</ref> <sup>1</sup> and does not have any person associated with that person subject to such a statutory disqualification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77ddcde1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “ancillary services” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the provision of due diligence services, in connection with the offer, sale, purchase, or negotiation of such security, so long as such services do not include, for separate compensation, investment advice or recommendations to issuers or investors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the provision of standardized documents to the issuers and investors, so long as such person or entity does not negotiate the terms of the issuance for and on behalf of third parties and issuers are not required to use the standardized documents as a condition of using the service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77ddcde4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain accredited investor transactions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The transactions referred to in subsection (a)(7) are transactions meeting the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Accredited investor requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Each purchaser is an accredited investor, as that term is defined in section 230.501(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on general solicitation or advertising</inline>.—</heading><content>Neither the seller, nor any person acting on the seller’s behalf, offers or sells securities by any form of general solicitation or general advertising.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcde7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a transaction involving the securities of an issuer that is neither subject to section 78m or 78<i>o</i>(d) of this title, nor exempt from reporting pursuant to section 240.12g3–2(b) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, nor a foreign government (as defined in section 230.405 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations) eligible to register securities under Schedule B, the seller and a prospective purchaser designated by the seller obtain from the issuer, upon request of the seller, and the seller in all cases makes available to a prospective purchaser, the following information (which shall be reasonably current in relation to the date of resale under this section):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcde8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The exact name of the issuer and the issuer’s predecessor (if any).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcde9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The address of the issuer’s principal executive offices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The exact title and class of the security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdeb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The par or stated value of the security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The number of shares or total amount of the securities outstanding as of the end of the issuer’s most recent fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcded-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The name and address of the transfer agent, corporate secretary, or other person responsible for transferring shares and stock certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> A statement of the nature of the business of the issuer and the products and services it offers, which shall be presumed reasonably current if the statement is as of 12 months before the transaction date.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The names of the officers and directors of the issuer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdf0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The names of any persons registered as a broker, dealer, or agent that shall be paid or given, directly or indirectly, any commission or remuneration for such person’s participation in the offer or sale of the securities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdf1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><chapeau> The issuer’s most recent balance sheet and profit and loss statement and similar financial statements, which shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdf2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> be for such part of the 2 preceding fiscal years as the issuer has been in operation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdf3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or, in the case of a foreign private issuer, be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or the International Financial Reporting Standards issued by the International Accounting Standards Board;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdf4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> be presumed reasonably current if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id77ddcdf5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> with respect to the balance sheet, the balance sheet is as of a date less than 16 months before the transaction date; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id77ddcdf6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> with respect to the profit and loss statement, such statement is for the 12 months preceding the date of the issuer’s balance sheet; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77ddcdf7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/J/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> if the balance sheet is not as of a date less than 6 months before the transaction date, be accompanied by additional statements of profit and loss for the period from the date of such balance sheet to a date less than 6 months before the transaction date.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddcdf8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/3/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> To the extent that the seller is a control person with respect to the issuer, a brief statement regarding the nature of the affiliation, and a statement certified by such seller that they have no reasonable grounds to believe that the issuer is in violation of the securities laws or regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdf9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuers disqualified</inline>.—</heading><content>The transaction is not for the sale of a security where the seller is an issuer or a subsidiary, either directly or indirectly, of the issuer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdfa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bad actor prohibition</inline>.—</heading><content>Neither the seller, nor any person that has been or will be paid (directly or indirectly) remuneration or a commission for their participation in the offer or sale of the securities, including solicitation of purchasers for the seller is subject to an event that would disqualify an issuer or other covered person under Rule 506(d)(1) of Regulation D (17 CFR 230.506(d)(1)) or is subject to a statutory disqualification described under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c/a/39">section 78c(a)(39) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdfb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Business requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The issuer is engaged in business, is not in the organizational stage or in bankruptcy or receivership, and is not a blank check, blind pool, or shell company that has no specific business plan or purpose or has indicated that the issuer’s primary business plan is to engage in a merger or combination of the business with, or an acquisition of, an unidentified person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdfc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Underwriter prohibition</inline>.—</heading><content>The transaction is not with respect to a security that constitutes the whole or part of an unsold allotment to, or a subscription or participation by, a broker or dealer as an underwriter of the security or a redistribution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdfd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outstanding class requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The transaction is with respect to a security of a class that has been authorized and outstanding for at least 90 days prior to the date of the transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77ddcdfe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddcdff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to an exempted transaction described under subsection (a)(7):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddce00-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Securities acquired in such transaction shall be deemed to have been acquired in a transaction not involving any public offering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddce01-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such transaction shall be deemed not to be a distribution for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77b/a/11">section 77b(a)(11) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id77ddce02-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Securities involved in such transaction shall be deemed to be restricted securities within the meaning of Rule 144 (17 CFR 230.144).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77ddce03-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77d/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>The exemption provided by subsection (a)(7) shall not be the exclusive means for establishing an exemption from the registration requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77e">section 77e of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77ddce04-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38">May 27, 1933, ch. 38</ref>, title I, § 4, <ref href="/us/stat/48/77">48 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, title II, § 203, <ref href="/us/stat/48/906">48 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-10/ch667">Aug. 10, 1954, ch. 667</ref>, title I, § 6, <ref href="/us/stat/68/684">68 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s12">Pub. L. 88–467, § 12</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/580">78 Stat. 580</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s30">Pub. L. 94–29, § 30</ref>, <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/169">89 Stat. 169</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/477/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 96–477, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2294">94 Stat. 2294</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s944/a">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 944(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1897">124 Stat. 1897</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 112–106, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, (c), title III, § 302(a), title IV, § 401(c), <date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/314">126 Stat. 314</ref>, 315, 325; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dG/tLXXVI/s76001/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. G, title LXXVI, § 76001(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1787">129 Stat. 1787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77ddce05-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77ddce06-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77ddce07-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 201 of the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 112–106</ref>, which amended this section and enacted provisions set out as a note under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 78<i>o</i>(a)(1) of this title, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), was in the original “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s15/a/1">section 15(a)(1) of this title</ref>” and was translated as meaning section 15(a)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c/a/39">Section 78c(a)(39) of this title</ref>, referrred to in subsec. (c)(2)(C), was in the original “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3/a/39">section 3(a)(39) of this title</ref>” and was translated as meaning section 3(a)(39) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77ddce08-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s76001/a/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 76001(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s76001/a/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 76001(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) relating to securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s76001/a/3">Pub. L. 114–94, § 76001(a)(3)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 112–106, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), made identical amendments, designating existing provisions as subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s401/c">Pub. L. 112–106, § 401(c)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by substituting “section 77c(b)(1)” for “section 77c(b)” in par. (5), was executed by making the substitution in subsec. (a)(5) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 112–106, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1). See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s302/a">Pub. L. 112–106, § 302(a)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by adding par. (6) at the end, was executed by making the addition at the end of subsec. (a) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 112–106, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1). See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201/c/2">Pub. L. 112–106, § 201(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (b) relating to securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D under this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/106/s201/b/2">Pub. L. 112–106, § 201(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (b) relating to offers and sales exempt under section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Pars. (5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> redesignated par. (6) as (5) and struck out former par. (5) which related to exemption for certain transactions involving offers or sales of one or more promissory notes directly secured by a first lien on a single parcel of real estate upon which is located a dwelling or other residential or commercial structure, and exemption for certain transactions between entities involving non-assignable contracts to buy or sell the foregoing securities which are to be completed within two years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/96/477">Pub. L. 96–477</ref> added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> substituted “shall not apply to—” for “shall not apply to any of the following transactions:” in introductory text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> reenacted existing first provision of par. (1) and struck out second and third provisions, which are incorporated in pars. (2) and (3)(A) to (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> redesignated existing second provision of par. (1) as (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> redesignated existing third provision of par. (1) as (3), designated the excepted transactions as cls. (A) to (C), inserted in cl. (B) “or such shorter period as the Commission may specify by rules and regulations or order” and inserted sentence relating to the applicable period to transactions referred to in clause (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> redesignated former par. (2) as (4) and substituted “over-the-counter market” for “open or counter market”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-08-10">Aug. 10, 1954</date>, reduced from 1 year to 40 days the period during which the delivery of a prospectus is required in trading transactions as distinguished from initial distribution of the new securities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-06-06">June 6, 1934</date>, among other changes, repealed par. (3), provisions of which were replaced by section 77c(9), (10) of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77ddce09-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77ddce0a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77ddce0b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> effective <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s31/a">section 31(a) of Pub. L. 94–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78b">section 78b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77ddce0c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> effective <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s13">section 13 of Pub. L. 88–467</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c">section 78c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77ddce0d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1954 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1954-08-10">Aug. 10, 1954</date>, effective 60 days after <date date="1954-08-10">Aug. 10, 1954</date>, see note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77b">section 77b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77ddce0e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification of Exemption Rules</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/106/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 112–106, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/313">126 Stat. 313</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/106/tII/s201/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>], the Securities and Exchange Commission shall revise its rules issued in section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that the prohibition against general solicitation or general advertising contained in section 230.502(c) of such title shall not apply to offers and sales of securities made pursuant to section 230.506, provided that all purchasers of the securities are accredited investors. Such rules shall require the issuer to take reasonable steps to verify that purchasers of the securities are accredited investors, using such methods as determined by the Commission. Section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as revised pursuant to this section, shall continue to be treated as a regulation issued under section 4(2) of the Securities Act of 1933 ([now] <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d">15 U.S.C. 77d</ref>[(a)](2)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall revise subsection (d)(1) of section 230.144A of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that securities sold under such revised exemption may be offered to persons other than qualified institutional buyers, including by means of general solicitation or general advertising, provided that securities are sold only to persons that the seller and any person acting on behalf of the seller reasonably believe is a qualified institutional buyer.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77ddce0f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rulemaking</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/106/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 112–106, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/320">126 Stat. 320</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/106/tIII/s302/c">“Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>], the Securities and Exchange Commission (in this title [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d–1">section 77d–1 of this title</ref>, amending sections 77d, 77r, 78c, 78<i>l</i>, and 78<i>o</i> of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 77d, 77r, 78c, and 78<i>l</i> of this title] referred to as the ‘Commission’) shall issue such rules as the Commission determines may be necessary or appropriate for the protection of investors to carry out sections 4(6) [probably means “section 4(a)(6)”] and section 4A of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6">15 U.S.C. 77d(a)(6)</ref>, 77d–1], as added by this title. In carrying out this section, the Commission shall consult with any securities commission (or any agency or office performing like functions) of the States, any territory of the United States, and the District of Columbia, which seeks to consult with the Commission, and with any applicable national securities association.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77ddce10-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Disqualification</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/106/tIII/s302/d">Pub. L. 112–106, title III, § 302(d)</ref>, <date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/320">126 Stat. 320</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/106/tIII/s302/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>], the [Securities and Exchange] Commission shall, by rule, establish disqualification provisions under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an issuer shall not be eligible to offer securities pursuant to section 4(6) [probably means “section 4(a)(6)”] of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77d/a/6">15 U.S.C. 77d(a)(6)</ref>], as added by this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a broker or funding portal shall not be eligible to effect or participate in transactions pursuant to that section 4(6).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Disqualification provisions required by this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> be substantially similar to the provisions of section 230.262 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> disqualify any offering or sale of securities by a person that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> is subject to a final order of a State securities commission (or an agency or officer of a State performing like functions), a State authority that supervises or examines banks, savings associations, or credit unions, a State insurance commission (or an agency or officer of a State performing like functions), an appropriate Federal banking agency, or the National Credit Union Administration, that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><chapeau> bars the person from—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="aa">     “(aa)</num><content> association with an entity regulated by such commission, authority, agency, or officer;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="bb">     “(bb)</num><content> engaging in the business of securities, insurance, or banking; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="cc">     “(cc)</num><content> engaging in savings association or credit union activities; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> constitutes a final order based on a violation of any law or regulation that prohibits fraudulent, manipulative, or deceptive conduct within the 10-year period ending on the date of the filing of the offer or sale; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> has been convicted of any felony or misdemeanor in connection with the purchase or sale of any security or involving the making of any false filing with the Commission.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77ddce11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Disqualifying Felons and Other “Bad Actors” From Regulation D Offerings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s926">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 926</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1851">124 Stat. 1851</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s926">
<inline>“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>], the Commission shall issue rules for the disqualification of offerings and sales of securities made under section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> are substantially similar to the provisions of section 230.262 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> disqualify any offering or sale of securities by a person that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> is subject to a final order of a State securities commission (or an agency or officer of a State performing like functions), a State authority that supervises or examines banks, savings associations, or credit unions, a State insurance commission (or an agency or officer of a State performing like functions), an appropriate Federal banking agency, or the National Credit Union Administration, that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> bars the person from—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> association with an entity regulated by such commission, authority, agency, or officer;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> engaging in the business of securities, insurance, or banking; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> engaging in savings association or credit union activities; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> constitutes a final order based on a violation of any law or regulation that prohibits fraudulent, manipulative, or deceptive conduct within the 10-year period ending on the date of the filing of the offer or sale; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> has been convicted of any felony or misdemeanor in connection with the purchase or sale of any security or involving the making of any false filing with the Commission.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s926">section 926 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77ddce12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77ddce13-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
