<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77e288e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77i"><num value="77i">§ 77i.</num><heading> Court review of orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77e288e3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77i/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any person aggrieved by an order of the Commission may obtain a review of such order in the court of appeals of the United States, within any circuit wherein such person resides or has his principal place of business, or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia, by filing in such Court, within sixty days after the entry of such order, a written petition praying that the order of the Commission be modified or be set aside in whole or in part. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Commission, and thereupon the Commission shall file in the court the record upon which the order complained of was entered, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>. No objection to the order of the Commission shall be considered by the court unless such objection shall have been urged before the Commission. The finding of the Commission as to the facts, if supported by evidence, shall be conclusive. If either party shall apply to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence, and shall show to the satisfaction of the court that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for failure to adduce such evidence in the hearing before the Commission, the court may order such additional evidence to be taken before the Commission and to be adduced upon the hearing in such manner and upon such terms and conditions as to the court may seem proper. The Commission may modify its findings as to the facts, by reason of the additional evidence so taken, and it shall file such modified or new findings, which, if supported by evidence, shall be conclusive, and its recommendation, if any, for the modification or setting aside of the original order. The jurisdiction of the court shall be exclusive and its judgment and decree, affirming, modifying, or setting aside, in whole or in part, any order of the Commission, shall be final, subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon certiorari or certification as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id77e288e4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77i/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The commencement of proceedings under subsection (a) shall not, unless specifically ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the Commission’s order.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77e288e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38">May 27, 1933, ch. 38</ref>, title I, § 9, <ref href="/us/stat/48/80">48 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/791/s9">Pub. L. 85–791, § 9</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/945">72 Stat. 945</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/181/tII/s206">Pub. L. 100–181, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1252">101 Stat. 1252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77e288e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77e288e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77e288e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/181">Pub. L. 100–181</ref> substituted “court of appeals” for “Circuit Court of Appeals”, “United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia, by filing in such Court” for “Court of Appeals of the District of Columbia, by filing in such court”, and “<ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>” for “sections 239 and 240 of the Judicial Code, as amended (U.S.C., title 28, secs. 346 and 347)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/85/791">Pub. L. 85–791</ref>, in second sentence, substituted “transmitted by the clerk of the court to” for “served upon”, struck out “certify and” before “file in the court”, struck out “a transcript of” after “file in the court”, and inserted “as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77e288e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77e288ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
