<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77f0e12c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm"><num value="77mmm">§ 77mmm.</num><heading> Reports by indenture trustee</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f0e12d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to security holders; time; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The indenture trustee shall transmit to the indenture security holders as hereinafter provided, at stated intervals of not more than 12 months, a brief report with respect to any of the following events which may have occurred within the previous 12 months (but if no such event has occurred within such period no report need be transmitted):— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002031"><num>1</num> So in original. The colon probably should not appear.</note></chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e12e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any change to its eligibility and its qualifications under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77jjj">section 77jjj of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e12f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the creation of or any material change to a relationship specified in paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002032">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002032"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraphs”.</note> (1) through (10) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77jjj/b">section 77jjj(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e130-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the character and amount of any advances made by it, as indenture trustee, which remain unpaid on the date of such report, and for the reimbursement of which it claims or may claim a lien or charge, prior to that of the indenture securities, on the trust estate or on property or funds held or collected by it as such trustee, if such advances so remaining unpaid aggregate more than one-half of 1 per centum of the principal amount of the indenture securities outstanding on such date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e131-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any change to the amount, interest rate, and maturity date of all other indebtedness owing to it in its individual capacity, on the date of such report, by the obligor upon the indenture securities, with a brief description of any property held as collateral security therefor, except an indebtedness based upon a creditor relationship arising in any manner described in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), or (6) of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77kkk">section 77kkk of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e132-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any change to the property and funds physically in its possession as indenture trustee on the date of such report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e133-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> any release, or release and substitution, of property subject to the lien of the indenture (and the consideration therefor, if any) which it has not previously reported;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e134-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> any additional issue of indenture securities which it has not previously reported; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e135-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> any action taken by it in the performance of its duties under the indenture which it has not previously reported and which in its opinion materially affects the indenture securities or the trust estate, except action in respect of a default, notice of which has been or is to be withheld by it in accordance with an indenture provision authorized by subsection (b) of section 77<i>ooo</i> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f0e136-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional reports to security holders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The indenture trustee shall transmit to the indenture security holders as hereinafter provided, within the times hereinafter specified, a brief report with respect to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e137-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the release, or release and substitution, of property subject to the lien of the indenture (and the consideration therefor, if any) unless the fair value of such property, as set forth in the certificate or opinion required by paragraph (1) of subsection (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77nnn">section 77nnn of this title</ref>, is less than 10 per centum of the principal amount of indenture securities outstanding at the time of such release, or such release and substitution, such report to be so transmitted within 90 days after such time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e138-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the character and amount of any advances made by it as such since the date of the last report transmitted pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) (or if no such report has yet been so transmitted, since the date of execution of the indenture), for the reimbursement of which it claims or may claim a lien or charge, prior to that of the indenture securities, on the trust estate or on property or funds held or collected by it as such trustee, and which it has not previously reported pursuant to this paragraph, if such advances remaining unpaid at any time aggregate more than 10 per centum of the principal amount of indenture securities outstanding at such time, such report to be so transmitted within 90 days after such time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f0e139-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional parties to whom reports to be transmitted</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Reports pursuant to this section shall be transmitted by mail—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e13a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to all registered holders of indenture securities, as the names and addresses of such holders appear upon the registration books of the obligor upon the indenture securities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e13b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to such holders of indenture securities as have, within the two years preceding such transmission, filed their names and addresses with the indenture trustee for that purpose; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id77f0e13c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> except in the case of reports pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, to all holders of indenture securities whose names and addresses have been furnished to or received by the indenture trustee pursuant to section 77<i>lll</i> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77f0e13d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77mmm/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of report with stock exchanges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A copy of each such report shall, at the time of such transmission to indenture security holders, be filed with each stock exchange upon which the indenture securities are listed, and also with the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77f0e13e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38">May 27, 1933, ch. 38</ref>, title III, § 313, as added <ref href="/us/act/1939-08-03/ch411">Aug. 3, 1939, ch. 411</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1165">53 Stat. 1165</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/tIV">Pub. L. 101–550, title IV</ref>, §§ 411, 412, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2729">104 Stat. 2729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/tIII/s301/e/3">Pub. L. 105–353, title III, § 301(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3237">112 Stat. 3237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77f0e13f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77f0e140-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77f0e141-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s301/e/3/A">Pub. L. 105–353, § 301(e)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “any change to” before “the amount”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s301/e/3/B">Pub. L. 105–353, § 301(e)(3)(B)</ref>, struck out “any change to” before “any release”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/1">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “The indenture trustee shall” for “The indenture to be qualified shall contain provisions requiring the indenture trustee to” and inserted “any of the following events which may have occurred within the previous 12 months (but if no such event has occurred within such period no report need be transmitted):” after “a brief report with respect to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/3">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(3)</ref>, (4), inserted “any change to” before “its eligibility” and struck out “, or in lieu thereof, if to the best of its knowledge it has continued to be eligible and qualified under such section, a written statement to such effect” after “of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/5">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(5)</ref>, added par. (2) and redesignated former par. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/5/A">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated pars. (2) and (3) as (3) and (4), respectively. Former par. (4) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/5/A">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/3">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(3)</ref>, inserted “any change to” after the paragraph designation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/5/A">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (6). Former par. (6) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/3">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(3)</ref>, inserted “any change to” after the paragraph designation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s411/5/A">Pub. L. 101–550, § 411(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated pars. (6) and (7) as (7) and (8), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s412/1">Pub. L. 101–550, § 412(1)</ref>, substituted “The indenture trustee shall” for “The indenture to be qualified shall also contain provisions requiring the indenture trustee to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s412/2">Pub. L. 101–550, § 412(2)</ref>, substituted “Reports” for “The indenture to be qualified shall also provide that reports”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s412/3">Pub. L. 101–550, § 412(3)</ref>, substituted “A copy” for “The indenture to be qualified shall also provide that a copy”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id77f0e142-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id77f0e143-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
