<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id77e9b542-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1"><num value="77z–1">§ 77z–1.</num><heading> Private securities litigation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b543-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Private class actions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b544-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of this subsection shall apply to each private action arising under this subchapter that is brought as a plaintiff class action pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b545-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification filed with complaint</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b546-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each plaintiff seeking to serve as a representative party on behalf of a class shall provide a sworn certification, which shall be personally signed by such plaintiff and filed with the complaint, that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b547-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> states that the plaintiff has reviewed the complaint and authorized its filing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b548-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> states that the plaintiff did not purchase the security that is the subject of the complaint at the direction of plaintiff’s counsel or in order to participate in any private action arising under this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b549-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> states that the plaintiff is willing to serve as a representative party on behalf of a class, including providing testimony at deposition and trial, if necessary;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b54a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> sets forth all of the transactions of the plaintiff in the security that is the subject of the complaint during the class period specified in the complaint;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b54b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> identifies any other action under this subchapter, filed during the 3-year period preceding the date on which the certification is signed by the plaintiff, in which the plaintiff has sought to serve, or served, as a representative party on behalf of a class; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b54c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> states that the plaintiff will not accept any payment for serving as a representative party on behalf of a class beyond the plaintiff’s pro rata share of any recovery, except as ordered or approved by the court in accordance with paragraph (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b54d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonwaiver of attorney-client privilege</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The certification filed pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to be a waiver of the attorney-client privilege.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b54e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of lead plaintiff</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b54f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Early notice to class members</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b550-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 20 days after the date on which the complaint is filed, the plaintiff or plaintiffs shall cause to be published, in a widely circulated national business-oriented publication or wire service, a notice advising members of the purported plaintiff class—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id77e9b551-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> of the pendency of the action, the claims asserted therein, and the purported class period; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id77e9b552-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> that, not later than 60 days after the date on which the notice is published, any member of the purported class may move the court to serve as lead plaintiff of the purported class.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b553-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If more than one action on behalf of a class asserting substantially the same claim or claims arising under this subchapter is filed, only the plaintiff or plaintiffs in the first filed action shall be required to cause notice to be published in accordance with clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b554-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional notices may be required under Federal rules</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notice required under clause (i) shall be in addition to any notice required pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b555-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of lead plaintiff</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b556-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 90 days after the date on which a notice is published under subparagraph (A)(i), the court shall consider any motion made by a purported class member in response to the notice, including any motion by a class member who is not individually named as a plaintiff in the complaint or complaints, and shall appoint as lead plaintiff the member or members of the purported plaintiff class that the court determines to be most capable of adequately representing the interests of class members (hereafter in this paragraph referred to as the “most adequate plaintiff”) in accordance with this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b557-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Consolidated actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If more than one action on behalf of a class asserting substantially the same claim or claims arising under this subchapter has been filed, and any party has sought to consolidate those actions for pretrial purposes or for trial, the court shall not make the determination required by clause (i) until after the decision on the motion to consolidate is rendered. As soon as practicable after such decision is rendered, the court shall appoint the most adequate plaintiff as lead plaintiff for the consolidated actions in accordance with this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b558-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Rebuttable presumption</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b559-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Subject to subclause (II), for purposes of clause (i), the court shall adopt a presumption that the most adequate plaintiff in any private action arising under this subchapter is the person or group of persons that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id77e9b55a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> has either filed the complaint or made a motion in response to a notice under subparagraph (A)(i);</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id77e9b55b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> in the determination of the court, has the largest financial interest in the relief sought by the class; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id77e9b55c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> otherwise satisfies the requirements of Rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b55d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Rebuttal evidence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The presumption described in subclause (I) may be rebutted only upon proof by a member of the purported plaintiff class that the presumptively most adequate plaintiff—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id77e9b55e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> will not fairly and adequately protect the interests of the class; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id77e9b55f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> is subject to unique defenses that render such plaintiff incapable of adequately representing the class.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b560-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Discovery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, discovery relating to whether a member or members of the purported plaintiff class is the most adequate plaintiff may be conducted by a plaintiff only if the plaintiff first demonstrates a reasonable basis for a finding that the presumptively most adequate plaintiff is incapable of adequately representing the class.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b561-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of lead counsel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The most adequate plaintiff shall, subject to the approval of the court, select and retain counsel to represent the class.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b562-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/3/B/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on professional plaintiffs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Except as the court may otherwise permit, consistent with the purposes of this section, a person may be a lead plaintiff, or an officer, director, or fiduciary of a lead plaintiff, in no more than 5 securities class actions brought as plaintiff class actions pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure during any 3-year period.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b563-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery by plaintiffs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The share of any final judgment or of any settlement that is awarded to a representative party serving on behalf of a class shall be equal, on a per share basis, to the portion of the final judgment or settlement awarded to all other members of the class. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the award of reasonable costs and expenses (including lost wages) directly relating to the representation of the class to any representative party serving on behalf of the class.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b564-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on settlements under seal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms and provisions of any settlement agreement of a class action shall not be filed under seal, except that on motion of any party to the settlement, the court may order filing under seal for those portions of a settlement agreement as to which good cause is shown for such filing under seal. For purposes of this paragraph, good cause shall exist only if publication of a term or provision of a settlement agreement would cause direct and substantial harm to any party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b565-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on payment of attorneys’ fees and expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Total attorneys’ fees and expenses awarded by the court to counsel for the plaintiff class shall not exceed a reasonable percentage of the amount of any damages and prejudgment interest actually paid to the class.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b566-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of settlement terms to class members</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any proposed or final settlement agreement that is published or otherwise disseminated to the class shall include each of the following statements, along with a cover page summarizing the information contained in such statements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b567-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of plaintiff recovery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount of the settlement proposed to be distributed to the parties to the action, determined in the aggregate and on an average per share basis.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b568-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of potential outcome of case</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b569-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement on amount of damages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the settling parties agree on the average amount of damages per share that would be recoverable if the plaintiff prevailed on each claim alleged under this subchapter, a statement concerning the average amount of such potential damages per share.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Disagreement on amount of damages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the parties do not agree on the average amount of damages per share that would be recoverable if the plaintiff prevailed on each claim alleged under this subchapter, a statement from each settling party concerning the issue or issues on which the parties disagree.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Inadmissibility for certain purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A statement made in accordance with clause (i) or (ii) concerning the amount of damages shall not be admissible in any Federal or State judicial action or administrative proceeding, other than an action or proceeding arising out of such statement.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of attorneys’ fees or costs sought</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If any of the settling parties or their counsel intend to apply to the court for an award of attorneys’ fees or costs from any fund established as part of the settlement, a statement indicating which parties or counsel intend to make such an application, the amount of fees and costs that will be sought (including the amount of such fees and costs determined on an average per share basis), and a brief explanation supporting the fees and costs sought.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of lawyers’ representatives</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The name, telephone number, and address of one or more representatives of counsel for the plaintiff class who will be reasonably available to answer questions from class members concerning any matter contained in any notice of settlement published or otherwise disseminated to the class.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasons for settlement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A brief statement explaining the reasons why the parties are proposing the settlement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b56f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/7/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Other information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Such other information as may be required by the court.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b570-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/a/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Attorney conflict of interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a plaintiff class is represented by an attorney who directly owns or otherwise has a beneficial interest in the securities that are the subject of the litigation, the court shall make a determination of whether such ownership or other interest constitutes a conflict of interest sufficient to disqualify the attorney from representing the plaintiff class.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b571-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Stay of discovery; preservation of evidence</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b572-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any private action arising under this subchapter, all discovery and other proceedings shall be stayed during the pendency of any motion to dismiss, unless the court finds, upon the motion of any party, that particularized discovery is necessary to preserve evidence or to prevent undue prejudice to that party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b573-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Preservation of evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">During the pendency of any stay of discovery pursuant to this subsection, unless otherwise ordered by the court, any party to the action with actual notice of the allegations contained in the complaint shall treat all documents, data compilations (including electronically recorded or stored data), and tangible objects that are in the custody or control of such person and that are relevant to the allegations, as if they were the subject of a continuing request for production of documents from an opposing party under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b574-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanction for willful violation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A party aggrieved by the willful failure of an opposing party to comply with paragraph (2) may apply to the court for an order awarding appropriate sanctions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b575-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Circumvention of stay of discovery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon a proper showing, a court may stay discovery proceedings in any private action in a State court as necessary in aid of its jurisdiction, or to protect or effectuate its judgments, in an action subject to a stay of discovery pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b576-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions for abusive litigation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b577-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory review by court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any private action arising under this subchapter, upon final adjudication of the action, the court shall include in the record specific findings regarding compliance by each party and each attorney representing any party with each requirement of Rule 11(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure as to any complaint, responsive pleading, or dispositive motion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b578-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory sanctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the court makes a finding under paragraph (1) that a party or attorney violated any requirement of Rule 11(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure as to any complaint, responsive pleading, or dispositive motion, the court shall impose sanctions on such party or attorney in accordance with Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. Prior to making a finding that any party or attorney has violated Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, the court shall give such party or attorney notice and an opportunity to respond.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b579-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Presumption in favor of attorneys’ fees and costs</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b57a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), for purposes of paragraph (2), the court shall adopt a presumption that the appropriate sanction—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b57b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for failure of any responsive pleading or dispositive motion to comply with any requirement of Rule 11(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure is an award to the opposing party of the reasonable attorneys’ fees and other expenses incurred as a direct result of the violation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b57c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for substantial failure of any complaint to comply with any requirement of Rule 11(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure is an award to the opposing party of the reasonable attorneys’ fees and other expenses incurred in the action.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b57d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rebuttal evidence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The presumption described in subparagraph (A) may be rebutted only upon proof by the party or attorney against whom sanctions are to be imposed that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b57e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the award of attorneys’ fees and other expenses will impose an unreasonable burden on that party or attorney and would be unjust, and the failure to make such an award would not impose a greater burden on the party in whose favor sanctions are to be imposed; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id77e9b57f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the violation of Rule 11(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure was de minimis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b580-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the party or attorney against whom sanctions are to be imposed meets its burden under subparagraph (B), the court shall award the sanctions that the court deems appropriate pursuant to Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id77e9b581-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s77z–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Defendant’s right to written interrogatories</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any private action arising under this subchapter in which the plaintiff may recover money damages only on proof that a defendant acted with a particular state of mind, the court shall, when requested by a defendant, submit to the jury a written interrogatory on the issue of each such defendant’s state of mind at the time the alleged violation occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id77e9b582-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38">May 27, 1933, ch. 38</ref>, title I, § 27, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/67/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 104–67, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-22">Dec. 22, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/737">109 Stat. 737</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/tI/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 105–353, title I, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, title III, § 301(a)(5), <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3230">112 Stat. 3230</ref>, 3235.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id77e9b583-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id77e9b584-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id77e9b585-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (3)(A)(iii), (B)(iii)(I)(cc), (vi), (b)(2), and (c), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id77e9b586-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s301/a/5">Pub. L. 105–353, § 301(a)(5)</ref>, made technical correction relating to placement of section in subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 105–353, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id77e9b587-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id77e9b588-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s101/a/2">section 101(a)(2) of Pub. L. 105–353</ref> not to affect or apply to any action commenced before and pending on <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 105–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77p">section 77p of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id77e9b589-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not to affect or apply to any private action arising under this subchapter or title I of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.), commenced before and pending on <date date="1995-12-22">Dec. 22, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/67/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 104–67</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1995 Amendment note under section 77<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id77e9b58a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in section to be deemed to create or ratify any implied right of action, or to prevent Commission, by rule or regulation, from restricting or otherwise regulating private actions under Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/67/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 104–67</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78j–1">section 78j–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
