<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id794cee6c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s784"><num value="784">§ 784.</num><heading> Exports of coal and refined petroleum products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794cee6d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s784/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> File concerning export transactions, sales, exchanges or shipments: establishment and maintenance; scope of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized and directed to establish and maintain a file which shall contain information concerning every transaction, sale, exchange or shipment involving the export from the United States to a foreign nation of coal, crude oil, residual oil or any refined petroleum product. Information to be included in the file shall be current and shall include, but shall not be limited to, the name of the exporter (including the name or names of the holders of any beneficial interests), the volume and type of product involved in the export transaction, the manner of shipment and identification of the vessel or carrier, the destination, the name of the purchaser if a sale, exchange or other transaction is involved, and a statement of reasons justifying the export.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794cee6e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s784/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information and report to committee of Congress or head of Federal agency from Administrator; exception: disclosure detrimental to national security</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of any committee of Congress or the head of any Federal agency, the Administrator shall promptly provide any information maintained in the file and a report thereon to such committee, or agency head, except where the President finds such disclosure to be detrimental to national security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794cee6f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s784/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to Administrator from Federal agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any Federal agency which collects or has information relevant to the functions required by this section shall make such information available to the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794cee70-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s784/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of independent information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall not be required to collect independently information described in subsection (a) if he can secure the information described in subsection (a) from other Federal agencies and the information secured from such agencies is available to the Congress pursuant to a request under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id794cee71-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/275/s25">Pub. L. 93–275, § 25</ref>, <date date="1974-05-07">May 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/114">88 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/385/tI/s111">Pub. L. 94–385, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1132">90 Stat. 1132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id794cee72-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id794cee73-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id794cee74-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/385">Pub. L. 94–385</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id794cee75-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id794cee76-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Energy Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
