<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7803f3c1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d"><num value="78d">§ 78d.</num><heading> Securities and Exchange Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition; limitations on commissioners; terms of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established a Securities and Exchange Commission (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”) to be composed of five commissioners to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Not more than three of such commissioners shall be members of the same political party, and in making appointments members of different political parties shall be appointed alternately as nearly as may be practicable. No commissioner shall engage in any other business, vocation, or employment than that of serving as commissioner, nor shall any commissioner participate, directly or indirectly, in any stock-market operations or transactions of a character subject to regulation by the Commission pursuant to this chapter. Each commissioner shall hold office for a term of five years and until his successor is appointed and has qualified, except that he shall not so continue to serve beyond the expiration of the next session of Congress subsequent to the expiration of said fixed term of office, and except (1) any commissioner appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term, and (2) the terms of office of the commissioners first taking office after <date date="1934-06-06">June 6, 1934</date>, shall expire as designated by the President at the time of nomination, one at the end of one year, one at the end of two years, one at the end of three years, one at the end of four years, and one at the end of five years, after <date date="1934-06-06">June 6, 1934</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of staff and leasing authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall appoint and compensate officers, attorneys, economists, examiners, and other employees in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s4802">section 4802 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In establishing and adjusting schedules of compensation and benefits for officers, attorneys, economists, examiners, and other employees of the Commission under applicable provisions of law, the Commission shall inform the heads of the agencies referred to under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1833b">section 1833b of title 12</ref> and Congress of such compensation and benefits and shall seek to maintain comparability with such agencies regarding compensation and benefits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Leasing authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothwithstanding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002045"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Notwithstanding”.</note> any other provision of law, the Commission is authorized to enter directly into leases for real property for office, meeting, storage, and such other space as is necessary to carry out its functions, and shall be exempt from any General Services Administration space management regulations or directives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of travel support for Commission activities from non-Federal sources; regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in accordance with regulations which the Commission shall prescribe to prevent conflicts of interest, the Commission may accept payment and reimbursement, in cash or in kind, from non-Federal agencies, organizations, and individuals for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by Commission members and employees in attending meetings and conferences concerning the functions or activities of the Commission. Any payment or reimbursement accepted shall be credited to the appropriated funds of the Commission. The amount of travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses for members and employees paid or reimbursed under this subsection may exceed per diem amounts established in official travel regulations, but the Commission may include in its regulations under this subsection a limitation on such amounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of relocation expenses from former employers by professional fellows program participants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, former employers of participants in the Commission’s professional fellows programs may pay such participants their actual expenses for relocation to Washington, District of Columbia, to facilitate their participation in such programs, and program participants may accept such payments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever any fee is required to be paid to the Commission pursuant to any provision of the securities laws or any other law, the Commission may provide by rule that such fee shall be paid in a manner other than in cash and the Commission may also specify the time that such fee shall be determined and paid relative to the filing of any statement or document with the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of expenses for assisting foreign securities authorities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commission may accept payment and reimbursement, in cash or in kind, from a foreign securities authority, or made on behalf of such authority, for necessary expenses incurred by the Commission, its members, and employees in carrying out any investigation pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78u/a/2">section 78u(a)(2) of this title</ref> or in providing any other assistance to a foreign securities authority. Any payment or reimbursement accepted shall be considered a reimbursement to the appropriated funds of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Office of the Investor Advocate</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Office established</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established within the Commission the Office of the Investor Advocate (in this subsection referred to as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Investor Advocate</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The head of the Office shall be the Investor Advocate, who shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> report directly to the Chairman; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be appointed by the Chairman, in consultation with the Commission, from among individuals having experience in advocating for the interests of investors in securities and investor protection issues, from the perspective of investors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The annual rate of pay for the Investor Advocate shall be equal to the highest rate of annual pay for other senior executives who report to the Chairman of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on service</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An individual who serves as the Investor Advocate may not be employed by the Commission—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> during the 2-year period ending on the date of appointment as Investor Advocate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the person ceases to serve as the Investor Advocate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff of Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Investor Advocate, after consultation with the Chairman of the Commission, may retain or employ independent counsel, research staff, and service staff, as the Investor Advocate deems necessary to carry out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of the Investor Advocate</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Investor Advocate shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> assist retail investors in resolving significant problems such investors may have with the Commission or with self-regulatory organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3d8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identify areas in which investors would benefit from changes in the regulations of the Commission or the rules of self-regulatory organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identify problems that investors have with financial service providers and investment products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> analyze the potential impact on investors of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> proposed regulations of the Commission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> proposed rules of self-regulatory organizations registered under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> to the extent practicable, propose to the Commission changes in the regulations or orders of the Commission and to Congress any legislative, administrative, or personnel changes that may be appropriate to mitigate problems identified under this paragraph and to promote the interests of investors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to documents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall ensure that the Investor Advocate has full access to the documents of the Commission and any self-regulatory organization, as necessary to carry out the functions of the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on objectives</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than June 30 of each year after 2010, the Investor Advocate shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the objectives of the Investor Advocate for the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Each report required under clause (i) shall contain full and substantive analysis and explanation.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on activities</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than December 31 of each year after 2010, the Investor Advocate shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the activities of the Investor Advocate during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3e5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Each report required under clause (i) shall include—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3e6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> appropriate statistical information and full and substantive analysis;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3e7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> information on steps that the Investor Advocate has taken during the reporting period to improve investor services and the responsiveness of the Commission and self-regulatory organizations to investor concerns;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3e8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> a summary of the most serious problems encountered by investors during the reporting period;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3e9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> an inventory of the items described in subclause (III) that includes—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id7803f3ea-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> identification of any action taken by the Commission or the self-regulatory organization and the result of such action;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id7803f3eb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the length of time that each item has remained on such inventory; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id7803f3ec-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/IV/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> for items on which no action has been taken, the reasons for inaction, and an identification of any official who is responsible for such action;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3ed-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> recommendations for such administrative and legislative actions as may be appropriate to resolve problems encountered by investors; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f3ee-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> any other information, as determined appropriate by the Investor Advocate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3ef-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Independence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Each report required under this paragraph shall be provided directly to the Committees listed in clause (i) without any prior review or comment from the Commission, any commissioner, any other officer or employee of the Commission, or the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/6/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">No report required under clause (i) may contain confidential information.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall, by regulation, establish procedures requiring a formal response to all recommendations submitted to the Commission by the Investor Advocate, not later than 3 months after the date of such submission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Ombudsman</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the first Investor Advocate is appointed under paragraph (2)(A)(i),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002046"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “(2)(A)(ii),”.</note> the Investor Advocate shall appoint an Ombudsman, who shall report directly to the Investor Advocate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Ombudsman appointed under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3f5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> act as a liaison between the Commission and any retail investor in resolving problems that retail investors may have with the Commission or with self-regulatory organizations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3f6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> review and make recommendations regarding policies and procedures to encourage persons to present questions to the Investor Advocate regarding compliance with the securities laws; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f3f7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> establish safeguards to maintain the confidentiality of communications between the persons described in clause (ii) and the Ombudsman.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out the duties of the Ombudsman under subparagraph (B), the Ombudsman shall utilize personnel of the Commission to the extent practicable. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as replacing, altering, or diminishing the activities of any ombudsman or similar office of any other agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3f9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/g/8/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Ombudsman shall submit a semiannual report to the Investor Advocate that describes the activities and evaluates the effectiveness of the Ombudsman during the preceding year. The Investor Advocate shall include the reports required under this section in the reports required to be submitted by the Inspector Advocate under paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3fa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Examiners</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Division of Trading and Markets</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Division of Trading and Markets of the Commission, or any successor organizational unit, shall have a staff of examiners who shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> perform compliance inspections and examinations of entities under the jurisdiction of that Division; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> report to the Director of that Division.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f3fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Division of Investment Management</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Division of Investment Management of the Commission, or any successor organizational unit, shall have a staff of examiners who shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f3ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> perform compliance inspections and examinations of entities under the jurisdiction of that Division; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f400-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> report to the Director of that Division.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f401-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f402-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Office established</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established within the Commission the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f403-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f404-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The head of the Office shall be the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation, who shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f405-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> report directly to the Commission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f406-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> be appointed by the Commission, from among individuals having experience in advocating for the interests of small businesses and encouraging small business capital formation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f407-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The annual rate of pay for the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall be equal to the highest rate of annual pay for other senior executives who report directly to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f408-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> No current employee of the Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An individual may not be appointed as the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation if the individual is currently employed by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f409-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff of Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation, after consultation with the Commission, may retain or employ independent counsel, research staff, and service staff, as the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation determines to be necessary to carry out the functions of the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f40a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f40b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> assist small businesses and small business investors in resolving significant problems such businesses and investors may have with the Commission or with self-regulatory organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f40c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identify areas in which small businesses and small business investors would benefit from changes in the regulations of the Commission or the rules of self-regulatory organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f40d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identify problems that small businesses have with securing access to capital, including any unique challenges to minority-owned small businesses, women-owned small businesses, and small businesses affected by hurricanes or other natural disasters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f40e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> analyze the potential impact on small businesses and small business investors of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f40f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> proposed regulations of the Commission that are likely to have a significant economic impact on small businesses and small business capital formation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f410-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> proposed rules that are likely to have a significant economic impact on small businesses and small business capital formation of self-regulatory organizations registered under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f411-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> conduct outreach to small businesses and small business investors, including through regional roundtables, in order to solicit views on relevant capital formation issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f412-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> to the extent practicable, propose to the Commission changes in the regulations or orders of the Commission and to Congress any legislative, administrative, or personnel changes that may be appropriate to mitigate problems identified under this paragraph and to promote the interests of small businesses and small business investors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f413-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> consult with the Investor Advocate on proposed recommendations made under subparagraph (F); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7803f414-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/4/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> advise the Investor Advocate on issues related to small businesses and small business investors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f415-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to documents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall ensure that the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation has full access to the documents and information of the Commission and any self-regulatory organization, as necessary to carry out the functions of the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f416-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report on activities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f417-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than December 31 of each year after 2015, the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the activities of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f418-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f419-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> appropriate statistical information and full and substantive analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f41a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> information on steps that the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation has taken during the reporting period to improve small business services and the responsiveness of the Commission and self-regulatory organizations to small business and small business investor concerns;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f41b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a summary of the most serious issues encountered by small businesses and small business investors, including any unique issues encountered by minority-owned small businesses, women-owned small businesses, and small businesses affected by hurricanes or other natural disasters and their investors, during the reporting period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f41c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> an inventory of the items summarized under clause (iii) (including items summarized under such clause for any prior reporting period on which no action has been taken or that have not been resolved to the satisfaction of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation as of the beginning of the reporting period covered by the report) that includes—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f41d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identification of any action taken by the Commission or the self-regulatory organization and the result of such action;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f41e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the length of time that each item has remained on such inventory; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7803f41f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> for items on which no action has been taken, the reasons for inaction, and an identification of any official who is responsible for such action;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f420-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> recommendations for such changes to the regulations, guidance and orders of the Commission and such legislative actions as may be appropriate to resolve problems with the Commission and self-regulatory organizations encountered by small businesses and small business investors and to encourage small business capital formation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7803f421-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> any other information, as determined appropriate by the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f422-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No report required by subparagraph (A) may contain confidential information.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f423-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Independence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall be provided directly to the committees of Congress listed in such subparagraph without any prior review or comment from the Commission, any commissioner, any other officer or employee of the Commission, or the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f424-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall establish procedures requiring a formal response to all recommendations submitted to the Commission by the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation, not later than 3 months after the date of such submission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f425-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation shall be responsible for planning, organizing, and executing the annual Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80c–1">section 80c–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f426-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/i/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection may be construed as replacing or reducing the responsibilities of the Investor Advocate with respect to small business investors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7803f427-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Open data publication</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All public data assets published by the Commission under the securities laws and the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/124/1376">124 Stat. 1376</ref>) shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7803f428-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> made available as an open Government data asset (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3502">section 3502 of title 44</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7803f429-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> freely available for download;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7803f42a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> rendered in a human-readable format; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7803f42b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78d/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> accessible via application programming interface where appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7803f42c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, title I, § 4, <ref href="/us/stat/48/885">48 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/619/s3">Pub. L. 86–619, § 3</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/408">74 Stat. 408</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/771">Pub. L. 86–771</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/913">74 Stat. 913</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/tIII/s305/20">Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 305(20)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/425">78 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/38/s1">Pub. L. 98–38, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-06-06">June 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/205">97 Stat. 205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/181/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 100–181, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1254">101 Stat. 1254</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/tI/s103">Pub. L. 101–550, title I, § 103</ref>, title II, § 207, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2713">104 Stat. 2713</ref>, 2721; <ref href="/us/pl/104/290/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 104–290, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3444">110 Stat. 3444</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/tII/s203">Pub. L. 105–353, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3234">112 Stat. 3234</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s8/d/2">Pub. L. 107–123, § 8(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2399">115 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX</ref>, §§ 915, 919D, 965, 991(e)(1), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1830">124 Stat. 1830</ref>, 1840, 1911, 1954; <ref href="/us/pl/114/284/s2/a">Pub. L. 114–284, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1447">130 Stat. 1447</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dS/tIX/s902">Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1143">132 Stat. 1143</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLVIII/s5822">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LVIII, § 5822</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3427">136 Stat. 3427</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tIII/s30003/a">Pub. L. 119–21, title III, § 30003(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/126">139 Stat. 126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7803f42d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7803f42e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7803f42f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (g)(4)(D)(ii), and (i)(4)(D)(ii), was in the original “this title”. See References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, referred to in subsec. (j), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1376">124 Stat. 1376</ref>, which enacted chapter 53 (§ 5301 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking, and chapters 108 (§ 8201 et seq.) and 109 (§ 8301 et seq.) of this title, and enacted, amended, and repealed numerous other sections and notes in the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7803f430-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsecs. (i) to (k). <ref href="/us/pl/119/21">Pub. L. 119–21</ref> redesignated subsecs. (j) and (k) as (i) and (j), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (i) which related to the establishment of the Securities and Exchange Commission Reserve Fund and amounts therein.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (j)(4)(C), (6)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted “minority-owned small businesses, women-owned small businesses, and small businesses affected by hurricanes or other natural disasters” for “minority-owned and women-owned small businesses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/114/284">Pub. L. 114–284</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s915">Pub. L. 111–203, § 915</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s919D">Pub. L. 111–203, § 919D</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s965">Pub. L. 111–203, § 965</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/e/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(e)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123">Pub. L. 107–123</ref> added pars. (1) and (2) and struck out former pars. (1) and (2), which authorized the Commission to appoint and compensate officers, attorneys, examiners, and other experts as needed, and to select, appoint, and compensate professional economists.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/353">Pub. L. 105–353</ref> added par. (2) and redesignated former par. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/290">Pub. L. 104–290</ref> inserted before period at end “and the Commission may also specify the time that such fee shall be determined and paid relative to the filing of any statement or document with the Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s103">Pub. L. 101–550, § 103</ref>, inserted heading, designated existing provision as par. (1) and inserted heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/550/s207">Pub. L. 101–550, § 207</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/181">Pub. L. 100–181</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/38">Pub. L. 98–38</ref> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/88/426">Pub. L. 88–426</ref> repealed provisions which prescribed the compensation of the Chairman and the Commissioners.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/771">Pub. L. 86–771</ref> authorized the chairman to receive an additional $500 a year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/619">Pub. L. 86–619</ref> increased the salary of each commissioner from $15,000 to $20,000 a year, and provided for continuation in office of a commissioner upon termination of his term until a successor is appointed and has qualified, not beyond expiration of next session of Congress subsequent to the expiration of said fixed term of office.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7803f431-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7803f432-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 915, 919D, and 965 of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/e/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 991(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1955">124 Stat. 1955</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/e/2">“The amendment made by this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7803f433-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/123">Pub. L. 107–123</ref> effective <date date="2001-10-01">Oct. 1, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 107–123</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78ee">section 78ee of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7803f434-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/426">Pub. L. 88–426</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/s501">section 501 of Pub. L. 88–426</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id7803f435-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, set out in the credit of this section, was repealed (subject to a savings clause) by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, 655.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f436-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction—No New Disclosure Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> not to be construed to require certain additional information to be collected or disclosed, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5826">section 5826 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77g">section 77g of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f437-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expenditure of Funds in and Closure of the Securities and Exchange Commission Reserve Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tIII/s30003/c">Pub. L. 119–21, title III, § 30003(c)</ref>–(e), <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/126">139 Stat. 126</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/21/tIII/s30003/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition Provision</inline>.—</heading><content>During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>] and ending on <date date="2025-10-01">October 1, 2025</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission may expend amounts in the Securities and Exchange Commission Reserve Fund that were obligated before the date of enactment of this Act for any program, project, or activity that is ongoing (as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act) in accordance with [former] subsection (i) of section 4 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">15 U.S.C. 78d</ref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Remaining Amounts</inline>.—</heading><content>Effective on <date date="2025-10-01">October 1, 2025</date>, the obligated and unobligated balances of amounts in the Securities and Exchange Commission Reserve Fund shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Closing of Account</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1555">section 1555 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Securities and Exchange Commission Reserve Fund shall be considered closed, and thereafter shall not be available for obligation or expenditure for any purpose, upon execution of the transfer required under subsection (d).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f438-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Outreach by the Commission</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/106/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 112–106, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2012-04-05">Apr. 5, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/327">126 Stat. 327</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/106/tVII/s701">“The Securities and Exchange Commission shall provide online information and conduct outreach to inform small and medium sized businesses, women owned businesses, veteran owned businesses, and minority owned businesses of the changes made by this Act [see Short Title of 2012 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f439-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pay Authority for Employment of Experts and Consultants</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s929G/c">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 929G(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1856">124 Stat. 1856</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s929G/c">“The [Securities and Exchange] Commission may set the rate of pay for experts and consultants appointed under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, in the same manner in which it sets the rate of pay for employees of the Commission.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7803f43a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7803f43b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f43c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>1950 REORGANIZATION PLAN NO. 10</b><br />15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">Prepared by the President and transmitted to the Senate and the House of Representatives in Congress assembled, <date date="1950-03-13">March 13, 1950</date>, pursuant to the provisions of the Reorganization Act of 1949, approved <date date="1949-06-20">June 20, 1949</date> [see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s901">5 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f43d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered">SECURITIES AND EXCHANGE COMMISSION</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7803f43e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Section 1. Transfer of Functions to the Chairman</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section there are hereby transferred from the Securities and Exchange Commission, hereinafter referred to as the Commission, to the Chairman of the Commission, hereinafter referred to as the Chairman, the executive and administrative functions of the Commission, including functions of the Commission with respect to (1) the appointment and supervision of personnel employed under the Commission, (2) the distribution of business among such personnel and among administrative units of the Commission, and (3) the use and expenditure of funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b)(1) In carrying out any of his functions under the provisions of this section the Chairman shall be governed by general policies of the Commission and by such regulatory decisions, findings, and determinations as the Commission may by law be authorized to make.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) The appointment by the Chairman of the heads of major administrative units under the Commission shall be subject to the approval of the Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Personnel employed regularly and full time in the immediate offices of Commissioners other than the Chairman shall not be affected by the provisions of this reorganization plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) There are hereby reserved to the Commission its functions with respect to revising budget estimates and with respect to determining upon the distribution of appropriated funds according to major programs and purposes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78063d2f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sec. 2. Performance of Transferred Functions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Chairman may from time to time make such provisions as he shall deem appropriate authorizing the performance by any officer, employee, or administrative unit under his jurisdiction of any function transferred to the Chairman by the provisions of section 1 of this reorganization plan.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78063d30-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sec. 3. Designation of Chairman</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The functions of the Commission with respect to choosing a Chairman from among the Commissioners composing the Commission are hereby transferred to the President.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78063d31-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Message of the President</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">To the Congress of the United States:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I transmit herewith Reorganization Plan No. 10 of 1950, prepared in accordance with the Reorganization Act of 1949 and providing for reorganizations in the Securities and Exchange Commission. My reasons for transmitting this plan are stated in an accompanying general message.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">After investigation I have found and hereby declare that each reorganization included in Reorganization Plan No. 10 of 1950 is necessary to accomplish one or more of the purposes set forth in section 2(a) of the Reorganization Act of 1949.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The taking effect of the reorganizations included in this plan may not in itself result in substantial immediate savings. However, many benefits in improved operations are probable during the next years which will result in a reduction in expenditures as compared with those that would be otherwise necessary. An itemization of these reductions in advance of actual experience under this plan is not practicable.</p>
<signature>
<name>Harry S. Truman.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
