<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78503f6b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee"><num value="78ee">§ 78ee.</num><heading> Transaction fees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f6c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery of costs of annual appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall, in accordance with this section, collect transaction fees and assessments that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the annual appropriation to the Commission by Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f6d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exchange-traded securities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subsection (j), each national securities exchange shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002113"><num>1</num> See Adjustment of Transaction Fee Rate notes below.</note> per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) transacted on such national securities exchange.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f6e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Off-exchange trades of exchange registered and last-sale-reported securities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subsection (j), each national securities association shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 <sup>1</sup> per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) registered on a national securities exchange or subject to prompt last sale reporting pursuant to the rules of the Commission or a registered national securities association.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f6f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessments on security futures transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each national securities exchange and national securities association shall pay to the Commission an assessment equal to $0.009 for each round turn transaction (treated as including one purchase and one sale of a contract of sale for future delivery) on a security future traded on such national securities exchange or by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange, except that for fiscal year 2007 and each succeeding fiscal year such assessment shall be equal to $0.0042 for each such transaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f70-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Dates for payments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fees and assessments required by subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section shall be paid—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78503f71-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> on or before March 15, with respect to transactions and sales occurring during the period beginning on the preceding September 1 and ending at the close of the preceding December 31; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78503f72-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> on or before September 25, with respect to transactions and sales occurring during the period beginning on the preceding January 1 and ending at the close of the preceding August 31.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f73-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, by rule, may exempt any sale of securities or any class of sales of securities from any fee or assessment imposed by this section, if the Commission finds that such exemption is consistent with the public interest, the equal regulation of markets and brokers and dealers, and the development of a national market system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f74-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall publish in the Federal Register notices of the fee and assessment rates applicable under this section for each fiscal year not later than 30 days after the date on which an Act making a regular appropriation to the Commission for such fiscal year is enacted, together with any estimates or projections on which such fees are based.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f75-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Pro rata application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The rates per $1,000,000 required by this section shall be applied pro rata to amounts and balances of less than $1,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f76-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit of fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f77-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Offsetting collections</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Fees collected pursuant to subsections (b), (c), and (d) for any fiscal year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78503f78-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections to the account providing appropriations to the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78503f79-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (k), shall not be collected for any fiscal year except to the extent provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> General revenues prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No fees collected pursuant to subsections (b), (c), and (d) for fiscal year 2002 or any succeeding fiscal year shall be deposited and credited as general revenue of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments to fee rates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to subsections (i)(1)(B) and (k), for each fiscal year, the Commission shall by order adjust each of the rates applicable under subsections (b) and (c) for such fiscal year to a uniform adjusted rate that, when applied to the baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales for such fiscal year, is reasonably likely to produce aggregate fee collections under this section (including assessments collected under subsection (d) of this section) that are equal to the regular appropriation to the Commission by Congress for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Mid-year adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to subsections (i)(1)(B) and (k), for each fiscal year, the Commission shall determine, by March 1 of such fiscal year, whether, based on the actual aggregate dollar volume of sales during the first 5 months of such fiscal year, the baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar volume of sales used under paragraph (1) for such fiscal year is reasonably likely to be 10 percent (or more) greater or less than the actual aggregate dollar volume of sales for such fiscal year. If the Commission so determines, the Commission shall by order, no later than March 1, adjust each of the rates applicable under subsections (b) and (c) for such fiscal year to a uniform adjusted rate that, when applied to the revised estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales for the remainder of such fiscal year, is reasonably likely to produce aggregate fee collections under this section (including fees collected during such five-month period and assessments collected under subsection (d) of this section) that are equal to the regular appropriation to the Commission by Congress for such fiscal year. In making such revised estimate, the Commission shall, after consultation with the Congressional Budget Office and the Office of Management and Budget, use the same methodology required by subsection (<i>l</i>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In exercising its authority under this subsection, the Commission shall not be required to comply with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>. An adjusted rate prescribed under paragraph (1) or (2) and published under subsection (g) shall not be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f7f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f80-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual adjustment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subsections (i)(1)(B) and (k), an adjusted rate prescribed under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the later of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78503f81-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the first day of the fiscal year to which such rate applies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id78503f82-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 60 days after the date on which an Act making a regular appropriation to the Commission for such fiscal year is enacted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f83-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Mid-year adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An adjusted rate prescribed under paragraph (2) shall take effect on April 1 of the fiscal year to which such rate applies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f84-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Lapse of appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If on the first day of a fiscal year a regular appropriation to the Commission has not been enacted, the Commission shall continue to collect (as offsetting collections) the fees and assessments under subsections (b), (c), and (d) at the rate in effect during the preceding fiscal year, until 60 days after the date such a regular appropriation is enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f85-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales for any fiscal year is the baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) to be transacted on each national securities exchange and by or through any member of each national securities association (otherwise than on a national securities exchange) during such fiscal year as determined by the Commission, after consultation with the Congressional Budget Office and the Office of Management and Budget, using the methodology required for making projections pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s907">section 907 of title 2</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f86-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal of Commission budget requests</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f87-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For fiscal year 2012, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Commission shall prepare and submit a budget to the President. Whenever the Commission submits a budget estimate or request to the President or the Office of Management and Budget, the Commission shall concurrently transmit copies of the estimate or request to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f88-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall submit each budget submitted under paragraph (1) to Congress, in unaltered form, together with the annual budget for the Administration submitted by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78503f89-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall include in each budget submitted under paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78503f8a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an itemization of the amount of funds necessary to carry out the functions of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78503f8b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an amount to be designated as contingency funding to be used by the Commission to address unanticipated needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78503f8c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/m/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a designation of any activities of the Commission for which multi-year budget authority would be suitable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78503f8d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, title I, § 31, <ref href="/us/stat/48/904">48 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1944-03-17/ch101">Mar. 17, 1944, ch. 101</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/117">58 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s22">Pub. L. 94–29, § 22</ref>, <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/162">89 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/290/tIV/s405/a">Pub. L. 104–290, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3442">110 Stat. 3442</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/353/tIII/s301/b/14">Pub. L. 105–353, title III, § 301(b)(14)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-03">Nov. 3, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3236">112 Stat. 3236</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–432; <ref href="/us/pl/107/123">Pub. L. 107–123</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2390">115 Stat. 2390</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/a/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 991(a)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1950">124 Stat. 1950</ref>, 1954.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7852887e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7852887f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78528880-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(A)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Commission shall, in accordance with this section, collect transaction fees and assessments that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the supervision and regulation of securities markets and securities professionals, and costs related to such supervision and regulation, including enforcement activities, policy and rulemaking activities, administration, legal services, and international regulatory activities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “September 25” for “September 30”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/C">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “30 days after the date on which an Act making a regular appropriation to the Commission for such fiscal year is enacted” for “April 30 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year to which such rate applies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/D">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(D)</ref>, added subsec. (j) and struck out former subsec. (j) which related to recapture of projection windfalls for further rate reductions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/E">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(E)</ref>, substituted “60 days” for “30 days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/a/1/F">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(a)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “Baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales” for “Definitions” in heading and struck out introductory provisions “For purposes of this section:”, par. (2) designation and heading “Baseline estimate of the aggregate dollar amount of sales”, and par. (1) which provided table of target offsetting collection amounts for fiscal years 2002 through 2011.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/d/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 991(d)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Subject to subsection (j), each” for “Every” and struck out at end “Fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited and collected as general revenue of the Treasury.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s2/1">Pub. L. 107–123, § 2(1)</ref>–(3), substituted “$15 per $1,000,000” for “<sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>300</sub> of one percent” and “security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)” for “and security futures products” and struck out “, except that for fiscal year 2007 or any succeeding fiscal year such rate shall be equal to <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>800</sub> of one percent of such aggregate dollar amount of sales” before period at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c), substituted “Off-exchange trades of exchange registered and last-sale-reported securities” for “Off-exchange trades of last-sale-reported securities” in subsec. heading, struck out par. (1) heading, substituted “Subject to subsection (j), each national securities” for “Each national securities”, inserted “registered on a national securities exchange or” after “narrow-based security index))”, struck out “, excluding any sales for which a fee is paid under subsection (c) of this section” after “national securities association”, and struck out pars. (2) and (3), which related to deposit of fees and lapse of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “Each national securities association shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>300</sub> of one percent of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities registered on such an exchange (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, and security futures products), except that for fiscal year 2007 or any succeeding fiscal year such rate shall be equal to <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>800</sub> of one percent of such aggregate dollar amount of sales. Fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited and collected as general revenue of the Treasury.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s2/1">Pub. L. 107–123, § 2(1)</ref>,(2), (4), which directed that subsec. (d) be amended by substituting “$15 per $1,000,000” for “<sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>300</sub> of one percent” and “security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)” for “and security futures products”, and striking out “, except that for fiscal year 2007, or any succeeding fiscal year, such rate shall be equal to <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>800</sub> of one percent of such aggregate dollar amount of sale” before period at end of par. (1), was executed by making the amendment in subsec. (c), to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, which redesignated subsec. (d) as (c). See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, (6), redesignated subsec. (e) as (d) and substituted “except that for fiscal year 2007 and each succeeding fiscal year such assessment shall be equal to $0.0042 for each such transaction” for “except that for fiscal year 2007 or any succeeding fiscal year such assessment shall be equal to $0.0075 for each such transaction. Assessments collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited and collected as general revenue of the Treasury”. Former subsec. (d) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s2/5">Pub. L. 107–123, § 2(5)</ref>, which directed that subsec. (e) be amended by substituting “$0.009” for “$0.02”, was executed by making the amendment in subsec. (d), to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, (6) which redesignated subsec. (e) as (d). See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/5">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(5)</ref>, (6), redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and substituted “Dates for payments” for “Dates for payment of fees” in heading and “The fees and assessments required” for “The fees required” in introductory provisions. Former subsec. (e) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/6">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/6">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, (b)(2), redesignated subsec. (h) as (g) and inserted before period at end “not later than April 30 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year to which such rate applies, together with any estimates or projections on which such fees are based”. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/6">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i), as enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s2/6">Pub. L. 107–123, § 2(6)</ref>, as (h). See below. Former subsec. (h) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/a/7">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(a)(7)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s2/6">Pub. L. 107–123, § 2(6)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 107–123, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/1">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(1)]</ref>, inserted “and assessments” after “fees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c), (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/2">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(2)]</ref>, substituted “other evidences of indebtedness, and security futures products” for “and other evidences of indebtedness”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/6">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(6)]</ref>, added subsec. (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/5">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(5)]</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/3">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(3)]</ref>, inserted “or assessment” after “fee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/5">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(5)]</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/4">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(4)]</ref>, inserted “and assessment” after “fee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s206/f/5">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 206(f)(5)]</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/353">Pub. L. 105–353</ref> substituted “this section” for “this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/290">Pub. L. 104–290</ref> reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Every national securities exchange shall pay to the Commission on or before March 15 of each calendar year a fee in an amount equal to one three-hundredths of 1 per centum of the aggregate dollar amount of the sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness) transacted on such national securities exchange during each preceding calendar year to which this section applies. Every registered broker and dealer shall pay to the Commission on or before March 15 of each calendar year a fee in an amount equal to one three-hundredths of 1 per centum of the aggregate dollar amount of the sales of securities registered on a national securities exchange (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness) transacted by such broker or dealer otherwise than on such an exchange during each preceding calendar year: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no payment shall be required for any calendar year in which such payment would be less than one hundred dollars. The Commission, by rule, may exempt any sale of securities or any class of sales of securities from any fee imposed by this section, if the Commission finds that such exemption is consistent with the public interest, the equal regulation of markets and brokers and dealers, and the development of a national market system.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> amended section generally, extending provisions requiring the payment of fees to include transactions in listed securities which occur in the over-the-counter market.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1944—Act <date date="1944-03-17">Mar. 17, 1944</date>, amended section generally, inserting provisions exempting from the payment of the fee securities designated for exemption by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78528881-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78528882-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s991/d/1">section 991(d)(1) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/a/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 991(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1951">124 Stat. 1951</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/a/2">
<inline>“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect on the later of—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date of enactment of an Act making a regular appropriation to the [Securities and Exchange] Commission for fiscal year 2012 [Div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/112/74">Pub. L. 112–74</ref>, approved <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>].”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78528883-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s11">Pub. L. 107–123, § 11</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2401">115 Stat. 2401</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/123/s11">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), the amendments made by this Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Immediate Transaction Fee Reductions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by section 2 [amending this section] shall take effect on the later of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the first day of fiscal year 2002; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> thirty days after the date on which a regular appropriation to the Commission for such fiscal year is enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorities provided by section 6(b)(9) of the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77f/b/9">15 U.S.C. 77f(b)(9)</ref>] and sections 13(e)(9), 14(g)(9), and 31(k) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78m/e/9">15 U.S.C. 78m(e)(9)</ref>, 78n(g)(9), and 78ee(k)], as so designated by this Act, shall not apply until <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78528884-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/290/tIV/s405/b">Pub. L. 104–290, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3443">110 Stat. 3443</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/290/tIV/s405/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to transactions in securities that occur on or after <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Off-exchange trades of last sale reported transactions</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to transactions described in section 31(d)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [subsec. (d)(1) of this section] (as amended by subsection (a) of this section) that occur on or after <date date="1997-09-01">September 1, 1997</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78528885-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> effective <date date="1976-01-01">Jan. 1, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s31/a">section 31(a) of Pub. L. 94–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78b">section 78b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78528886-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Securities and Exchange Commission Overpayment Credit</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/174/tV/s505">Pub. L. 115–174, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1362">132 Stat. 1362</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/174/tV/s505">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Commission’ means the Securities and Exchange Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘national securities association’ means an association that is registered under section 15A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78">15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>o</i>–3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘national securities exchange’ means an exchange that is registered as a national securities exchange under section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Credit for Overpayment of Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 31(j) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78ee/j">15 U.S.C. 78ee(j)</ref>), and subject to subsection (c) of this section, if a national securities exchange or a national securities association has paid fees and assessments to the Commission in an amount that is more than the amount that the exchange or association was required to pay under section 31 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78ee">15 U.S.C. 78ee</ref>) and, not later than 10 years after the date of such payment, the exchange or association informs the Commission about the payment of such excess amount, the Commission shall offset future fees and assessments due by that exchange or association in an amount that is equal to the difference between the amount that the exchange or association paid and the amount that the exchange or association was required to pay under such section 31.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (b) shall apply only to fees and assessments that a national securities exchange or a national securities association was required to pay to the Commission before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78528887-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Budget of the President</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/d/2">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 991(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1954">124 Stat. 1954</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s991/d/2">“For fiscal year 2012, and each fiscal year thereafter, the annual budget for the Administration submitted by the President to Congress shall reflect the amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 77f, 78d, 78m, 78n, and 78kk of this title].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78528888-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of the Effect of Fee Reductions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/123/s9">Pub. L. 107–123, § 9</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2400">115 Stat. 2400</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/123/s9">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Office of Economic Analysis of the Securities and Exchange Commission (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Office’) shall conduct a study of the extent to which the benefits of reductions in fees effected as a result of this Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of this title</ref>] are passed on to investors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors for Consideration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Office shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> consider the various elements of the securities industry directly and indirectly benefiting from the fee reductions, including purchasers and sellers of securities, members of national securities exchanges, issuers, broker-dealers, underwriters, participants in investment companies, retirement programs, and others;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> consider the impact on different types of investors, such as individual equity holders, individual investment company shareholders, businesses, and other types of investors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> include in the interpretation of the term ‘investor’ shareholders of entities subject to the fee reductions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> consider the economic benefits to investors flowing from the fee reductions to include such factors as market efficiency, expansion of investment opportunities, and enhanced liquidity and capital formation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>], the Securities and Exchange Commission shall submit to the Congress the report prepared by the Office on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78528889-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fees From National Securities Associations for Member Transactions Other Than on National Securities Exchanges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tV">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title V]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–61, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tV">“That effective <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, every national securities association shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate of one-three-hundredth of one percentum of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange (other than bonds, debentures, and other evidences of indebtedness) subject to prompt last sale reporting pursuant to the rules of the Commission or a registered national securities association, excluding any sales for which a fee is paid under section 31 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78ee">15 U.S.C. 78ee</ref>), and such increase shall be deposited as an offsetting collection to this appropriation, to remain available until expended, to recover the costs to the Government of the supervision and regulation of securities markets and securities professionals: <i>Provided further</i>, That the fee due from every national securities association shall be paid on or before <date date="1997-09-30">September 30, 1997</date>, with respect to transactions and sales occurring during the period beginning on <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, and ending at the close of <date date="1997-08-31">August 31, 1997</date>”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id7852888a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Adjustment of Transaction Fee Rate</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2023-01-26">Jan. 26, 2023</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $8.00 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2023-02-27">Feb. 27, 2023</date>, see 88 F.R. 5051.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2022-04-08">Apr. 8, 2022</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $22.90 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2022-05-14">May 14, 2022</date>, see 87 F.R. 21931.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2021-01-15">Jan. 15, 2021</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $5.10 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2021-02-25">Feb. 25, 2021</date>, see 86 F.R. 6694.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2020-01-09">Jan. 9, 2020</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $22.10 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2020-02-18">Feb. 18, 2020</date>, see 85 F.R. 2218.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2019-03-15">Mar. 15, 2019</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $20.70 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2019-04-16">Apr. 16, 2019</date>, see 84 F.R. 9576.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2018-04-17">Apr. 17, 2018</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $13.00 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2018-05-22">May 22, 2018</date>, see 83 F.R. 17577.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2017-05-31">May 31, 2017</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $23.10 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2017-07-04">July 4, 2017</date>, see 82 F.R. 25895.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2016-01-07">Jan. 7, 2016</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $21.80 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2016-02-16">Feb. 16, 2016</date>, see 81 F.R. 1458.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2015-01-15">Jan. 15, 2015</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $18.40 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2015-02-14">Feb. 14, 2015</date>, see 80 F.R. 2978.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2014-02-12">Feb. 12, 2014</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $22.10 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2014-03-18">Mar. 18, 2014</date>, see 79 F.R. 9504.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2013-04-25">Apr. 25, 2013</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $17.40 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2013-05-25">May 25, 2013</date>, see 78 F.R. 25515.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2012-03-01">Mar. 1, 2012</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $22.40 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2012-04-01">Apr. 1, 2012</date>, see 77 F.R. 13663.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By order dated <date date="2012-01-20">Jan. 20, 2012</date>, the Securities and Exchange Commission adjusted the fee rates applicable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section to $18.00 per $1,000,000, effective <date date="2012-02-21">Feb. 21, 2012</date>, see 77 F.R. 3818.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7852888b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7852888c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
