<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78576b26-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff"><num value="78fff">§ 78fff.</num><heading> General provisions of a liquidation proceeding</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78576b27-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of a liquidation proceeding under this chapter shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78576b28-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> as promptly as possible after the appointment of a trustee in such liquidation proceeding, and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78576b29-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to deliver customer name securities to or on behalf of the customers of the debtor entitled thereto as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/c/2">section 78fff–2(c)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78576b2a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to distribute customer property and (in advance thereof or concurrently therewith) otherwise satisfy net equity claims of customers to the extent provided in this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78576b2b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to sell or transfer offices and other productive units of the business of the debtor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78576b2c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to enforce rights of subrogation as provided in this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78576b2d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to liquidate the business of the debtor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78576b2e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of title 11</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent consistent with the provisions of this chapter, a liquidation proceeding shall be conducted in accordance with, and as though it were being conducted under chapters 1, 3, and 5 and subchapters I and II of chapter 7 of title 11. For the purposes of applying such title in carrying out this section, a reference in such title to the date of the filing of the petition shall be deemed to be a reference to the filing date under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78576b2f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of customer status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In a liquidation proceeding under this chapter, whenever a person has acted with respect to cash or securities with the debtor after the filing date and in a manner which would have given him the status of a customer with respect to such cash or securities had the action occurred prior to the filing date, and the trustee is satisfied that such action was taken by the customer in good faith and prior to the appointment of the trustee, the date on which such action was taken shall be deemed to be the filing date for purposes of determining the net equity of such customer with respect to such cash or securities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78576b30-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Apportionment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In a liquidation proceeding under this chapter, any cash or securities remaining after the liquidation of a lien or pledge made by a debtor shall be apportioned between his general estate and customer property in the proportion in which the general property of the debtor and the cash and securities of the customers of such debtor contributed to such lien or pledge. Securities apportioned to the general estate under this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of section 78<i>lll</i>(5)(A) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78576b31-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78fff/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs and expenses of administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All costs and expenses of administration of the estate of the debtor and of the liquidation proceeding shall be borne by the general estate of the debtor to the extent it is sufficient therefor, and the priorities of distribution from the general estate shall be as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s726">section 726 of title 11</ref>. Costs and expenses of administration shall include payments pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/e">section 78fff–2(e) of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–3/c/1">section 78fff–3(c)(1) of this title</ref> (to the extent such payments recovered securities which were apportioned to the general estate pursuant to subsection (d)) and costs and expenses of SIPC employees utilized by the trustee pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–1/a/2">section 78fff–1(a)(2) of this title</ref>. All funds advanced by SIPC to a trustee for such costs and expenses of administration shall be recouped from the general estate under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s507/a/2">section 507(a)(2) of title 11</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7859b422-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/598/s6">Pub. L. 91–598, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-30">Dec. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1646">84 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/283/s8">Pub. L. 95–283, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-05-21">May 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/259">92 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/tIII/s308/g">Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 308(g)</ref>, (h), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2675">92 Stat. 2675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/tXV/s1502/b">Pub. L. 109–8, title XV, § 1502(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/217">119 Stat. 217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7859b423-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7859b424-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7859b425-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (3), (b), (c), and (d), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/598">Pub. L. 91–598</ref>, <date date="1970-12-30">Dec. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1636">84 Stat. 1636</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7859b426-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> substituted “507(a)(2)” for “507(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> substituted “General provisions of a liquidation proceeding” for “Liquidation proceedings” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> in heading substituted “Purposes” for “General purposes of liquidation proceeding”, in introductory text substituted provisions relating to purposes of liquidation proceedings under this chapter, for provisions relating to purposes of any proceeding in which a trustee has been appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78eee/b/3">section 78eee(b)(3) of this title</ref>, in par. (1) substituted provisions requiring execution of authorities to deliver customer name securities and distribute customer property in accordance with this chapter, for provisions requiring execution of authorities to return specifically identifiable property and distribute the single and separate fund in accordance with this section, and in par. (2) substituted provisions authorizing sale, etc., of productive units of the debtor, for provisions authorizing operation of the business of the debtor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s308/g">Pub. L. 95–598, § 308(g)</ref>, in heading substituted “title 11” for “Bankruptcy Act” and in text “under chapters 1, 3, and 5 and subchapters I and II of chapter 7 of title 11. For the purposes of applying such title in carrying out this section, a reference in such title to the date of the filing of the petition shall be deemed to be a reference to the filing date under this chapter.” for “under, the Bankruptcy Act. For purposes of applying the Bankruptcy Act to this chapter, any reference in the Bankruptcy Act to the date of commencement of proceedings under the Bankruptcy Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the filing date under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> in heading substituted “Application of Bankruptcy Act” for “Powers and Duties of Trustee”, and in text substituted provisions relating to applicability of Bankruptcy Act to liquidation proceedings, for provisions relating to the powers and duties of trustees. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–1">section 78fff–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> in heading substituted “Determination of customer status” for “Application of Bankruptcy Act”, and in text substituted provisions relating to determination of status of a customer with respect to cash or securities, for provisions setting forth general and special provisions of the Bankruptcy Act applicable to liquidation proceedings, and defining terms for purposes of such applicability and the provisions of this section. See subsec. (b) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/c">section 78fff–2(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> in heading substituted “Apportionment” for “Completion of open contractual commitments”, and in text substituted provisions relating to apportionment of cash or securities remaining after the liquidation of a lien or pledge made by a debtor, for provisions relating to completion by the trustee of open contractual commitments, which were made in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business and which were outstanding on the filing date. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/e">section 78fff–2(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s308/h">Pub. L. 95–598, § 308(h)</ref>, substituted in first sentence “<ref href="/us/usc/t11/s726">section 726 of title 11</ref>” for “the Bankruptcy Act” and in last sentence “under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s507/a/1">section 507(a)(1) of title 11</ref>” for “as a first priority under the Bankruptcy Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> in heading substituted “Costs and expense of administration” for “Notice”, and in text substituted provisions relating to costs and expenses of administration of the estate of the debtor and of the liquidation proceeding, for provisions relating to notice requirements for the trustee subsequent to appointment as trustee. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/a/l">section 78fff–2(a)(l) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> struck out subsec. (f) requiring advances by the SIPC to the trustee for customers’ claims and completion of open contractual commitments, and authorizing discretionary advances to the trustee for compensation of personnel deemed necessary for the liquidation proceeding. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–3">section 78fff–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> struck out subsec. (g) setting forth provisions relating to payments to customers by the trustee, and provisions respecting the quantum of proof of claim required for such payment. See section 78fff–2(a)(2) and (b) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> struck out subsec. (h) relating to nonapplicability of provisions to proof of claim by associates and others connected in some way with the debtor. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/a/2">section 78fff–2(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> struck out subsec. (i) setting forth provisions relating to reports by the trustee to the court. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–1/c">section 78fff–1(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref> struck out subsec. (j) which related to nonapplicability of provisions to rights of persons to establish by formal proof such claims as they may have to payment or delivery of specific securities. See <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78fff–2/a/4">section 78fff–2(a)(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7859b427-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7859b428-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/8">Pub. L. 109–8</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, and not applicable with respect to cases commenced under Title 11, Bankruptcy, before such effective date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/8/s1501">section 1501 of Pub. L. 109–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of Title 11</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id7859b429-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s402/a">section 402(a) of Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of Title 11</ref>, Bankruptcy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
