<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id785c25c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj"><num value="78jjj">§ 78jjj.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to pay assessment, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a member of SIPC shall fail to file any report or information required pursuant to this chapter, or shall fail to pay when due all or any part of an assessment made upon such member pursuant to this chapter, and such failure shall not have been cured, by the filing of such report or information or by the making of such payment, together with interest and penalty thereon, within five days after receipt by such member of written notice of such failure given by or on behalf of SIPC, it shall be unlawful for such member, unless specifically authorized by the Commission, to engage in business as a broker or dealer. If such member denies that it owes all or any part of the amount specified in such notice, it may after payment of the full amount so specified commence an action against SIPC in the appropriate United States district court to recover the amount it denies owing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Engaging in business after appointment of trustee or initiation of direct payment procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any broker or dealer for whom a trustee has been appointed pursuant to this chapter or for whom a direct payment procedure has been initiated to engage thereafter in business as a broker or dealer, unless the Commission otherwise determines in the public interest. The Commission may by order bar or suspend for any period, any officer, director, general partner, owner of 10 per centum or more of the voting securities, or controlling person of any broker or dealer for whom a trustee has been appointed pursuant to this chapter or for whom a direct payment procedure has been initiated from being or becoming associated with a broker or dealer, if after appropriate notice and opportunity for hearing, the Commission shall determine such bar or suspension to be in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Concealment of assets; false statements or claims</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific prohibited acts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person who, directly or indirectly, in connection with or in contemplation of any liquidation proceeding or direct payment procedure—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785c25cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> employs any device, scheme, or artifice to defraud;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785c25cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> engages in any act, practice, or course of business which operates or would operate as a fraud or deceit upon any person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id785c25ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> fraudulently or with intent to defeat this chapter—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> conceals or transfers any property belonging to the estate of a debtor;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> makes a false statement or account;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> presents or uses any false claim for proof against the estate of a debtor;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> receives any material amount of property from a debtor;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> gives, offers, receives, transfers, or obtains any money or property, remuneration, compensation, reward, advantage, other consideration, or promise thereof, for acting or forebearing to act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> conceals, destroys, mutilates, falsifies, makes a false entry in, or otherwise falsifies any document affecting or relating to the property or affairs of a debtor; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id785c25d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/1/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> withholds, from any person entitled to its possession, any document affecting or relating to the property or affairs of a debtor,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be fined not more than $250,000 or imprisoned for not more than five years, or both.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Fraudulent conversion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person who, directly or indirectly steals, embezzles, or fraudulently, or with intent to defeat this chapter, abstracts or converts to his own use or to the use of another any of the moneys, securities, or other assets of SIPC, or otherwise defrauds or attempts to defraud SIPC or a trustee by any means, shall be fined not more than $250,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Misrepresentation of SIPC membership or protection</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25d8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person who falsely represents by any means (including, without limitation, through the Internet or any other medium of mass communication), with actual knowledge of the falsity of the representation and with an intent to deceive or cause injury to another, that such person, or another person, is a member of SIPC or that any person or account is protected or is eligible for protection under this chapter or by SIPC, shall be liable for any damages caused thereby and shall be fined not more than $250,000 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id785c25d9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78jjj/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Injunctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any court having jurisdiction of a civil action arising under this chapter may grant temporary injunctions and final injunctions on such terms as the court deems reasonable to prevent or restrain any violation of paragraph (1). Any such injunction may be served anywhere in the United States on the person enjoined, shall be operative throughout the United States, and shall be enforceable, by proceedings in contempt or otherwise, by any United States court having jurisdiction over that person. The clerk of the court granting the injunction shall, when requested by any other court in which enforcement of the injunction is sought, transmit promptly to the other court a certified copy of all papers in the case on file in such clerk’s office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id785c25da-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/598/s14">Pub. L. 91–598, § 14</ref>, formerly § 10, <date date="1970-12-30">Dec. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1655">84 Stat. 1655</ref>; renumbered § 14 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/283">Pub. L. 95–283</ref>, §§ 9, 13, <date date="1978-05-21">May 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/260">92 Stat. 260</ref>, 269; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIX/s929V/b">Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 929V(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1868">124 Stat. 1868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id785c25db-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id785c25dc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id785c25dd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/598">Pub. L. 91–598</ref>, <date date="1970-12-30">Dec. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1636">84 Stat. 1636</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id785c25de-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929V/b/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929V(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “$250,000” for “$50,000” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929V/b/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929V(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “$250,000” for “$50,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929V/c">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929V(c)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283/s13/a">Pub. L. 95–283, § 13(a)</ref>, inserted “and penalty” after “interest”, and substituted “it” for “he” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283/s13/b">Pub. L. 95–283, § 13(b)</ref>, in heading inserted “or initiation of direct payment procedure” after “trustee”, and in text inserted references to initiation of direct payment procedure in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/283/s13/c">Pub. L. 95–283, § 13(c)</ref>, in heading substituted “Concealment of assets; false statements or claims” for “Embezzlement, etc., of assets of SIPC”, added par. (1), and designated existing provisions as par. (2) and, as so designated, inserted references to direct or indirect acts, and provisions covering defrauding or attempts to defraud SIPC or a trustee, and substituted provisions covering activities constituting fraudulent, or with intent to defeat this chapter, abstracts or conversions, for provisions covering activities constituting unlawfully abstracting or unlawfully and willfully converting moneys, etc.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id785c25df-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id785c25e0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
