<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78360018-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p"><num value="78p">§ 78p.</num><heading> Directors, officers, and principal stockholders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78360019-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosures required</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7836001a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Directors, officers, and principal stockholders required to file</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Every person who is directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10 percent of any class of any equity security (other than an exempted security) which is registered pursuant to section 78<i>l</i> of this title, or who is a director or an officer of the issuer of such security (including, solely for the purposes of this subsection, every person who is a director or an officer of a foreign private issuer, as that term is defined in section 240.3b–4 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation), shall file the statements required by this subsection with the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7836001b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Time of filing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The statements required by this subsection shall be filed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7836001c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> at the time of the registration of such security on a national securities exchange or by the effective date of a registration statement filed pursuant to section 78<i>l</i>(g) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7836001d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> within 10 days after he or she becomes such beneficial owner, director, or officer, or within such shorter time as the Commission may establish by rule;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7836001e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if there has been a change in such ownership, or if such person shall have purchased or sold a security-based swap agreement involving such equity security, before the end of the second business day following the day on which the subject transaction has been executed, or at such other time as the Commission shall establish, by rule, in any case in which the Commission determines that such 2-day period is not feasible; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7836001f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> with respect to a foreign private issuer, the securities of which are, as of <date date="2025-12-18">December 18, 2025</date>, registered pursuant to subsection (b) or (g) of section 78<i>l</i> of this title, on the date that is 90 days after <date date="2025-12-18">December 18, 2025</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78360020-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of statements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A statement filed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78360021-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) shall contain a statement of the amount of all equity securities of such issuer of which the filing person is the beneficial owner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78360022-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph shall indicate ownership by the filing person at the date of filing, any such changes in such ownership, and such purchases and sales of the security-based swap agreements or security-based swaps as have occurred since the most recent such filing under such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78360023-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Electronic filing and availability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Beginning not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78360024-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a statement filed under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (2) shall be filed electronically and in English;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78360025-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Commission shall provide each such statement on a publicly accessible Internet site not later than the end of the business day following that filing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id78360026-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the issuer (if the issuer maintains a corporate website) shall provide that statement on that corporate website, not later than the end of the business day following that filing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id78360027-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to exempt</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission by rule, regulation, or order, may conditionally or unconditionally exempt any person, security, or transaction, or any class or classes of persons, securities, or transactions, from the requirements of this section if the Commission determines that the laws of a foreign jurisdiction apply substantially similar requirements to such person, security, or transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78360028-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Profits from purchase and sale of security within six months</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of preventing the unfair use of information which may have been obtained by such beneficial owner, director, or officer by reason of his relationship to the issuer, any profit realized by him from any purchase and sale, or any sale and purchase, of any equity security of such issuer (other than an exempted security) or a security-based swap agreement involving any such equity security within any period of less than six months, unless such security or security-based swap agreement was acquired in good faith in connection with a debt previously contracted, shall inure to and be recoverable by the issuer, irrespective of any intention on the part of such beneficial owner, director, or officer in entering into such transaction of holding the security or security-based swap agreement purchased or of not repurchasing the security or security-based swap agreement sold for a period exceeding six months. Suit to recover such profit may be instituted at law or in equity in any court of competent jurisdiction by the issuer, or by the owner of any security of the issuer in the name and in behalf of the issuer if the issuer shall fail or refuse to bring such suit within sixty days after request or shall fail diligently to prosecute the same thereafter; but no such suit shall be brought more than two years after the date such profit was realized. This subsection shall not be construed to cover any transaction where such beneficial owner was not such both at the time of the purchase and sale, or the sale and purchase, of the security or security-based swap agreement or a security-based swap involved, or any transaction or transactions which the Commission by rules and regulations may exempt as not comprehended within the purpose of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78360029-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions for sale of security by beneficial owner, director, or officer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any such beneficial owner, director, or officer, directly or indirectly, to sell any equity security of such issuer (other than an exempted security), if the person selling the security or his principal (1) does not own the security sold, or (2) if owning the security, does not deliver it against such sale within twenty days thereafter, or does not within five days after such sale deposit it in the mails or other usual channels of transportation; but no person shall be deemed to have violated this subsection if he proves that notwithstanding the exercise of good faith he was unable to make such delivery or deposit within such time, or that to do so would cause undue inconven­ience or expense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7836002a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Securities held in investment account, transactions in ordinary course of business, and establishment of primary or secondary market</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall not apply to any purchase and sale, or sale and purchase, and the provisions of subsection (c) of this section shall not apply to any sale, of an equity security not then or theretofore held by him in an investment account, by a dealer in the ordinary course of his business and incident to the establishment or maintenance by him of a primary or secondary market (otherwise than on a national securities exchange or an exchange exempted from registration under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78e">section 78e of this title</ref>) for such security. The Commission may, by such rules and regulations as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest, define and prescribe terms and conditions with respect to securities held in an investment account and transactions made in the ordinary course of business and incident to the establishment or maintenance of a primary or secondary market.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7836002b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section to foreign or domestic arbitrage transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to foreign or domestic arbitrage transactions unless made in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission may adopt in order to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7836002c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of transactions in security futures products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall apply to ownership of and transactions in security futures products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7836002d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s78p/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on Commission authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority of the Commission under this section with respect to security-based swap agreements shall be subject to the restrictions and limitations of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c–1/b">section 78c–1(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7836002e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, title I, § 16, <ref href="/us/stat/48/896">48 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s8">Pub. L. 88–467, § 8</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/579">78 Stat. 579</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/tIII/s303/g">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 208(b)(3), title III, § 303(g), (h)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–435, 2763A–455, 2763A–456; <ref href="/us/pl/107/204/tIV/s403/a">Pub. L. 107–204, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/788">116 Stat. 788</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVII/s762/d/5">Pub. L. 111–203, title VII, § 762(d)(5)</ref>, title IX, § 929R(b), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1761">124 Stat. 1761</ref>, 1867; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXI/s8103/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8103(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1838">139 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7836002f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78360030-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78360031-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8103/b/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8103(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “(including, solely for the purposes of this subsection, every person who is a director or an officer of a foreign private issuer, as that term is defined in section 240.3b–4 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation)” after “an officer of the issuer of such security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8103/b/1/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8103(b)(1)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8103/b/1/C">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8103(b)(1)(C)</ref>, inserted “and in English” after “electronically”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8103/b/1/D">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8103(b)(1)(D)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929R/b/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929R(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “(and, if such security is registered on a national securities exchange, also with the exchange)” after “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929R/b/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 929R(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “, or within such shorter time as the Commission may establish by rule” after “officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5/A">Pub. L. 111–203, § 762(d)(5)(A)</ref>, struck out “(as defined in section 206(b) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</ref> note))” after “security-based swap agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 762(d)(5)(B)</ref>, which directed amendment of subpar. (B) by inserting “or security-based swaps” after “security-based swap agreement”, was executed by making the insertion after “security-based swap agreements”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5/D">Pub. L. 111–203, § 762(d)(5)(D)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (b) by substituting “or a security-based swap” for “(as defined in section 206B of the Gramm-Leach Bliley Act)” in third sentence, was executed by making the substitution for “(as defined in section 206B of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act)” in third sentence, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5/C">Pub. L. 111–203, § 762(d)(5)(C)</ref>, struck out “(as defined in section 206B of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act)” after “security-based swap agreement” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5/E">Pub. L. 111–203, § 762(d)(5)(E)</ref>, struck out “(as defined in section 206B of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act)” after “security-based swap agreements”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/204">Pub. L. 107–204</ref> reenacted section catchline without change, added heading and text of subsec. (a), and struck out former subsec. (a) which read as follows: “Every person who is directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10 per centum of any class of any equity security (other than an exempted security) which is registered pursuant to section 78<i>l</i> of this title, or who is a director or an officer of the issuer of such security, shall file, at the time of the registration of such security on a national securities exchange or by the effective date of a registration statement filed pursuant to section 78<i>l</i>(g) of this title, or within ten days after he becomes such beneficial owner, director, or officer, a statement with the Commission (and, if such security is registered on a national securities exchange, also with the exchange) of the amount of all equity securities of such issuer of which he is the beneficial owner, and within ten days after the close of each calendar month thereafter, if there has been a change in such ownership or if such person shall have purchased or sold a security-based swap agreement (as defined in section 206B of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act) involving such equity security during such month, shall file with the Commission (and if such security is registered on a national securities exchange, shall also file with the exchange), a statement indicating his ownership at the close of the calendar month and such changes in his ownership and such purchases and sales of such security-based swap agreements as have occurred during such calendar month.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tIII/s303/g">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title III, § 303(g)]</ref>, amended subsecs. (a) and (b) generally, revising provisions to extend application to security-based swap agreements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s208/b/3">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 208(b)(3)]</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tIII/s303/h">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title III, § 303(h)]</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s8/a">Pub. L. 88–467, § 8(a)</ref>, substituted “registered pursuant to section 78<i>l</i> of this title” for “registered on a national securities exchange”, “Commission (and, if such security is registered on a national securities exchange, also with the exchange)” for “exchange (and a duplicate original thereof with the Commission)”, “a change” for “any change”, and “Commission (and if such security is registered on a national securities exchange, shall also file with the exchange) a statement” for “exchange a statement (and a duplicate original thereof with the Commission)”, and inserted “on a national securities exchange or by the effective date of a registration statement filed pursuant to section 78<i>l</i>(g) of this title” after “registration of such security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s8/b">Pub. L. 88–467, § 8(b)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78360032-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78360033-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXI/s8103/b/2">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8103(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1839">139 Stat. 1839</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXI/s8103/b/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78360034-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s929R/b">section 929R(b) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s762/d/5">section 762(d)(5) of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the later of 360 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, or, to the extent a provision of subtitle B (§§ 761–774) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> requires a rulemaking, not less than 60 days after publication of the final rule or regulation implementing such provision of subtitle B, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s774">section 774 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77b">section 77b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78360035-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/204/tIV/s403/b">Pub. L. 107–204, title IV, § 403(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/789">116 Stat. 789</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/204/tIV/s403/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall be effective 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-07-30">July 30, 2002</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78360036-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/467">Pub. L. 88–467</ref> effective <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/467/s13">section 13 of Pub. L. 88–467</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c">section 78c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id78360037-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Regulation; Issuance or Amendment of Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXI/s8103/c">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8103(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1839">139 Stat. 1839</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXI/s8103/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on Regulation</inline>.—</heading><content>If any provision of section 240.3a12–3(b) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, is inconsistent with the amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section], that provision of such section 240.3a12–3(b) (or such successor) shall have no force or effect beginning on the effective date described in subsection (b)(2) [see Effective Date of 2025 Amendment note above].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance or Amendment of Regulations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Securities and Exchange Commission shall issue final regulations (or amend or rescind, in whole or in part, existing regulations of the Commission) to carry out the amendments made by subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><content>The Securities and Exchange Commission may issue such additional regulations (or amend or rescind, in whole or in part, existing regulations of the Commission) as necessary to implement the intent of this section.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78360038-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78360039-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
