<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a7e1ba9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903"><num value="7903">§ 7903.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1baa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Engaged in the business</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “engaged in the business” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s921/a/21">section 921(a)(21) of title 18</ref>, and, as applied to a seller of ammunition, means a person who devotes time, attention, and labor to the sale of ammunition as a regular course of trade or business with the principal objective of livelihood and profit through the sale or distribution of ammunition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bab-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Manufacturer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “manufacturer” means, with respect to a qualified product, a person who is engaged in the business of manufacturing the product in interstate or foreign commerce and who is licensed to engage in business as such a manufacturer under chapter 44 of title 18.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bac-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Person</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “person” means any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, or any other entity, including any governmental entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bad-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified product</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “qualified product” means a firearm (as defined in subparagraph (A) or (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s921/a/3">section 921(a)(3) of title 18</ref>), including any antique firearm (as defined in section 921(a)(16) of such title), or ammunition (as defined in section 921(a)(17)(A) of such title), or a component part of a firearm or ammunition, that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bae-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified civil liability action</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1baf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “qualified civil liability action” means a civil action or proceeding or an administrative proceeding brought by any person against a manufacturer or seller of a qualified product, or a trade association, for damages, punitive damages, injunctive or declaratory relief, abatement, restitution, fines, or penalties, or other relief, resulting from the criminal or unlawful misuse of a qualified product by the person or a third party, but shall not include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an action brought against a transferor convicted under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s924/h">section 924(h) of title 18</ref>, or a comparable or identical State felony law, by a party directly harmed by the conduct of which the transferee is so convicted;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an action brought against a seller for negligent entrustment or negligence per se;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> an action in which a manufacturer or seller of a qualified product knowingly violated a State or Federal statute applicable to the sale or marketing of the product, and the violation was a proximate cause of the harm for which relief is sought, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7a7e1bb3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any case in which the manufacturer or seller knowingly made any false entry in, or failed to make appropriate entry in, any record required to be kept under Federal or State law with respect to the qualified product, or aided, abetted, or conspired with any person in making any false or fictitious oral or written statement with respect to any fact material to the lawfulness of the sale or other disposition of a qualified product; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id7a7e1bb4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any case in which the manufacturer or seller aided, abetted, or conspired with any other person to sell or otherwise dispose of a qualified product, knowing, or having reasonable cause to believe, that the actual buyer of the qualified product was prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm or ammunition under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s922">section 922 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> an action for breach of contract or warranty in connection with the purchase of the product;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> an action for death, physical injuries or property damage resulting directly from a defect in design or manufacture of the product, when used as intended or in a reasonably foreseeable manner, except that where the discharge of the product was caused by a volitional act that constituted a criminal offense, then such act shall be considered the sole proximate cause of any resulting death, personal injuries or property damage; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id7a7e1bb7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> an action or proceeding commenced by the Attorney General to enforce the provisions of chapter 44 of title 18 or chapter 53 of title 26.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bb8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Negligent entrustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">As used in subparagraph (A)(ii), the term “negligent entrustment” means the supplying of a qualified product by a seller for use by another person when the seller knows, or reasonably should know, the person to whom the product is supplied is likely to, and does, use the product in a manner involving unreasonable risk of physical injury to the person or others.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bb9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The exceptions enumerated under clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A) shall be construed so as not to be in conflict, and no provision of this chapter shall be construed to create a public or private cause of action or remedy.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Minor child exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the right of a person under 17 years of age to recover damages authorized under Federal or State law in a civil action that meets 1 of the requirements under clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bbb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Seller</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “seller” means, with respect to a qualified product—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7e1bbc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an importer (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s921/a/9">section 921(a)(9) of title 18</ref>) who is engaged in the business as such an importer in interstate or foreign commerce and who is licensed to engage in business as such an importer under chapter 44 of title 18;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7e1bbd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a dealer (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s921/a/11">section 921(a)(11) of title 18</ref>) who is engaged in the business as such a dealer in interstate or foreign commerce and who is licensed to engage in business as such a dealer under chapter 44 of title 18; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7e1bbe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a person engaged in the business of selling ammunition (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s921/a/17/A">section 921(a)(17)(A) of title 18</ref>) in interstate or foreign commerce at the wholesale or retail level.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bbf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State” includes each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States, and any political subdivision of any such place.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a7e1bc0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Trade association</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “trade association” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a7e1bc1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any corporation, unincorporated association, federation, business league, professional or business organization not organized or operated for profit and no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a808bc2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that is an organization described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/6">section 501(c)(6) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7a808bc3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 2 or more members of which are manufacturers or sellers of a qualified product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7a808bc4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s7903/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Unlawful misuse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “unlawful misuse” means conduct that violates a statute, ordinance, or regulation as it relates to the use of a qualified product.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7a808bc5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/92/s4">Pub. L. 109–92, § 4</ref>, <date date="2005-10-26">Oct. 26, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2097">119 Stat. 2097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a808bc6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a808bc7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7a808bc8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/109/92">Pub. L. 109–92</ref>, <date date="2005-10-26">Oct. 26, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2095">119 Stat. 2095</ref>, known as the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s7901">section 7901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
