<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id794f5f4d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794"><num value="794">§ 794.</num><heading> Energy conservation study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794f5f4e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study of conservation methods</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administrator shall conduct a study on potential methods of energy conservation and, not later than six months after <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, shall submit to Congress a report on the results of such study. The study shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f4f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the energy conservation potential of restricting exports of fuels or energy-intensive products, or goods, including an analysis of balance-of-payments and foreign relations implications of any such restrictions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f50-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> alternative requirements, incentives, or disincentives for increasing industrial recycling and resource recovery in order to reduce energy demand, including the economic costs and fuel consumption tradeoff which may be associated with such recycling and resource recovery in lieu of transportation and use of virgin materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f51-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> means for incentives or disincentives to increase efficiency of industrial use of energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794f5f52-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency mass transportation assistance plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within ninety days of <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, the Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Federal Energy Administrator, shall submit to the Congress for appropriate action an “Emergency Mass Transportation Assistance Plan” for the purpose of conserving energy by expanding and improving public mass transportation systems and encouraging increased ridership as alternatives to automobile travel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id794f5f53-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations in plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such plan shall include, but shall not be limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f54-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> recommendations for emergency temporary grants to assist States and local public bodies and agencies thereof in the payment of operating expenses incurred in connection with the provision of expanded mass transportation service in urban areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f55-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> recommendations for additional emergency assistance for the purchase of buses and rolling stock for fixed rail, including the feasibility of accelerating the timetable for such assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s142/a/2">section 142(a)(2) of title 23</ref> for the purpose of providing additional capacity for and encouraging increased use of public mass transportation systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f56-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> recommendations for a program of demonstration projects to determine the feasibility of fare-free and low-fare urban mass transportation systems, including reduced rates for elderly and handicapped persons during nonpeak hours of transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f57-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> recommendations for additional emergency assistance for the construction of fringe and transportation corridor parking facilities to serve bus and other mass transportation passengers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id794f5f58-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s794/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> recommendations on the feasibility of providing tax incentives for persons who use public mass transportation systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id794f5f59-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/319/s8">Pub. L. 93–319, § 8</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/260">88 Stat. 260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id794f5f5a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id794f5f5b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id794f5f5c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Energy Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
