<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id78659bf5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10"><num value="80a–10">§ 80a–10.</num><heading> Affiliations or interest of directors, officers, and employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659bf6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Interested persons of company who may serve on board of directors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No registered investment company shall have a board of directors more than 60 per centum of the members of which are persons who are interested persons of such registered company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659bf7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment and use of directors, officers, etc., as regular broker, principal underwriter, or investment banker</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No registered investment company shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bf8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> employ as regular broker any director, officer, or employee of such registered company, or any person of which any such director, officer, or employee is an affiliated person, unless a majority of the board of directors of such registered company shall be persons who are not such brokers or affiliated persons of any of such brokers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bf9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> use as a principal underwriter of securities issued by it any director, officer, or employee of such registered company or any person of which any such director, officer, or employee is an interested person, unless a majority of the board of directors of such registered company shall be persons who are not such principal underwriters or interested persons of any of such principal underwriters; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bfa-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> have as director, officer, or employee any investment banker, or any affiliated person of an investment banker, unless a majority of the board of directors of such registered company shall be persons who are not investment bankers or affiliated persons of any investment banker. For the purposes of this paragraph, a person shall not be deemed an affiliated person of an investment banker solely by reason of the fact that he is an affiliated person of a company of the character described in section 80a–12(d)(3)(A) and (B) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659bfb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Officers, directors, or employees of one bank or bank holding company as majority of board of directors of company; exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No registered investment company shall have a majority of its board of directors consisting of persons who are officers, directors, or employees of any one bank (together with its affiliates and subsidiaries) or any one bank holding company (together with its affiliates and subsidiaries) (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841">section 1841 of title 12</ref>) or any one savings and loan holding company, together with its affiliates and subsidiaries (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1467a">section 1467a of title 12</ref>),,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002121">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002121"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> except that, if on <date date="1940-03-15">March 15, 1940</date>, any registered investment company had a majority of its directors consisting of persons who are directors, officers, or employees of any one bank, such company may continue to have the same percentage of its board of directors consisting of persons who are directors, officers, or employees of such bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659bfc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception to limitation of number of interested persons who may serve on board of directors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b)(2) of this section, a registered investment company may have a board of directors all the members of which, except one, are interested persons of the investment adviser of such company, or are officers or employees of such company, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bfd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such investment company is an open-end company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bfe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such investment adviser is registered under subchapter II of this chapter and is engaged principally in the business of rendering investment supervisory services as defined in subchapter II;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659bff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> no sales load is charged on securities issued by such investment company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c00-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any premium over net asset value charged by such company upon the issuance of any such security, plus any discount from net asset value charged on redemption thereof, shall not in the aggregate exceed 2 per centum;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c01-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> no sales or promotion expenses are incurred by such registered company; but expenses incurred in complying with laws regulating the issue or sale of securities shall not be deemed sales or promotion expenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c02-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> such investment adviser is the only investment adviser to such investment company, and such investment adviser does not receive a management fee exceeding 1 per centum per annum of the value of such company’s net assets averaged over the year or taken as of a definite date or dates within the year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c03-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> all executive salaries and executive expenses and office rent of such investment company are paid by such investment adviser; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c04-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> such investment company has only one class of securities outstanding, each unit of which has equal voting rights with every other unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659c05-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Death, disqualification, or resignation of directors as suspension of limitation provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If by reason of the death, disqualification, or bona fide resignation of any director or directors, the requirements of the foregoing provisions of this section or of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–15/f/1">section 80a–15(f)(1) of this title</ref> in respect of directors shall not be met by a registered investment company, the operation of such provision shall be suspended as to such registered company—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c06-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for a period of thirty days if the vacancy or vacancies may be filled by action of the board of directors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c07-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for a period of sixty days if a vote of stockholders is required to fill the vacancy or vacancies; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c08-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> for such longer period as the Commission may prescribe, by rules and regulations upon its own motion or by order upon application, as not inconsistent with the protection of investors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659c09-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Officer, director, etc., of company acting as principal underwriter of security acquired by company</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No registered investment company shall knowingly purchase or otherwise acquire, during the existence of any underwriting or selling syndicate, any security (except a security of which such company is the issuer) a principal underwriter of which is an officer, director, member of an advisory board, investment adviser, or employee of such registered company, or is a person (other than a company of the character described in section 80a–12(d)(3)(A) and (B) of this title) of which any such officer, director, member of an advisory board, investment adviser, or employee is an affiliated person, unless in acquiring such security such registered company is itself acting as a principal underwriter for the issuer. The Commission, by rules and regulations upon its own motion or by order upon application, may conditionally or unconditionally exempt any transaction or classes of transactions from any of the provisions of this subsection, if and to the extent that such exemption is consistent with the protection of investors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659c0a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory boards; restrictions on membership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a registered investment company which has an advisory board, such board, as a distinct entity, shall be subject to the same restrictions as to its membership as are imposed upon a board of directors by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78659c0b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section to unincorporated registered management companies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a registered management company which is an unincorporated company not having a board of directors, the provisions of this section shall apply as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c0c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the provisions of subsection (a), as modified by subsection (e), shall apply to the board of directors of the depositor of such company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c0d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the provisions of subsections (b) and (c), as modified by subsection (e), shall apply to the board of directors of the depositor and of every investment adviser of such company; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78659c0e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–10/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the provisions of subsection (f) shall apply to purchases and other acquisitions for the account of such company of securities a principal underwriter of which is the depositor or an investment adviser of such company, or an affiliated person of such depositor or investment adviser.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78659c0f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, title I, § 10, <ref href="/us/stat/54/806">54 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1416">84 Stat. 1416</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s28/5">Pub. L. 94–29, § 28(5)</ref>, <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/165">89 Stat. 165</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/tII/s213/c">Pub. L. 106–102, title II, § 213(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1398">113 Stat. 1398</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/351/tIV/s401/c">Pub. L. 109–351, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1973">120 Stat. 1973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78659c10-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78659c11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78659c12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/351">Pub. L. 109–351</ref> inserted “or any one savings and loan holding company, together with its affiliates and subsidiaries (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1467a">section 1467a of title 12</ref>),” after “1841 of title 12)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> substituted “bank (together with its affiliates and subsidiaries) or any one bank holding company (together with its affiliates and subsidiaries) (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841">section 1841 of title 12</ref>), except” for “bank, except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> inserted reference to provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–15/f/1">section 80a–15(f)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5/a">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5(a)</ref>, struck out introductory text “After one year from the effective date of this subchapter” and substituted “interested persons of such registered company” for “investment advisers of, affiliated persons of an investment adviser of, or officers or employees of, such registered company”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5/b/1">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, struck out introductory text “After one year from the effective date of this subchapter,” and substituted “No” for “no”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5/b/2">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “interested” for “affiliated” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5/c">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5(c)</ref>, struck out introductory text “After the effective date of this subchapter”, substituted “No”, “, except that”, “had a majority”, and “such company” for “no”, “: <i>Provided</i>, That”, “shall have had a majority”, and “such company”, respectively, and inserted reference to employees where first appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s5/d">Pub. L. 91–547, § 5(d)</ref>, reenacted provisions except for substitution of “interested persons” for “affiliated persons” in introductory text, deletion of “such investment adviser” before “is engaged” in item (2), and substitution of “class of securities” for “class of stock” and “unit” for “share” in two places in item (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78659c13-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78659c14-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Pub. L. 106–102</ref> effective 18 months after <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/102/s225">section 225 of Pub. L. 106–102</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77c">section 77c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78659c15-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> effective <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s31/a">section 31(a) of Pub. L. 94–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78b">section 78b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78659c16-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref>, see section 30 (introductory text and pars. (1) and (2)) of <ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–52">section 80a–52 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id78659c17-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id78659c18-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
