<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id787181fb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31"><num value="80a–31">§ 80a–31.</num><heading> Accountants and auditors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787181fc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of accountant</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any registered management company or registered face-amount certificate company to file with the Commission any financial statement signed or certified by an independent public accountant, unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787181fd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such accountant shall have been selected at a meeting held within thirty days before or after the beginning of the fiscal year or before the annual meeting of stockholders in that year by the vote, cast in person, of a majority of those members of the board of directors who are not interested persons of such registered company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787181fe-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such selection shall have been submitted for ratification or rejection at the next succeeding annual meeting of stockholders if such meeting be held, except that any vacancy occurring between annual meetings, due to the death or resignation of the accountant, may be filled by the vote of a majority of those members of the board of directors who are not interested persons of such registered company, cast in person at a meeting called for the purpose of voting on such action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787181ff-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the employment of such accountant shall have been conditioned upon the right of the company by vote of a majority of the outstanding voting securities at any meeting called for the purpose to terminate such employment forthwith without any penalty; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id78718200-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> such certificate or report of such accountant shall be addressed both to the board of directors of such registered company and to the security holders thereof.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the selection of an accountant has been rejected pursuant to paragraph (2) or his employment terminated pursuant to paragraph (3), the vacancy so occurring may be filled by a vote of a majority of the outstanding voting securities, either at the meeting at which the rejection or termination occurred or, if not so filled, at a subsequent meeting which shall be called for the purpose. In the case of a common-law trust of the character described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–16/c">section 80a–16(c) of this title</ref>, no ratification of the employment of such accountant shall be required but such employment may be terminated and such accountant removed by action of the holders of record of a majority of the outstanding shares of beneficial interest in such trust in the same manner as is provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–16/c">section 80a–16(c) of this title</ref> in respect of the removal of a trustee, and all the provisions therein contained as to the calling of a meeting shall be applicable. In the event of such termination and removal, the vacancy so occurring may be filled by action of the holders of record of a majority of the shares of beneficial interest either at the meeting, if any, at which such termination and removal occurs, or by instruments in writing filed with the custodian, or if not so filed within a reasonable time then at a subsequent meeting which shall be called by the trustees for the purpose. The provisions of paragraph (42) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–2/a">section 80a–2(a) of this title</ref> as to a majority shall be applicable to the vote cast at any meeting of the shareholders of such a trust held pursuant to this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78718201-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of controller or other principal accounting officer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No registered management company or registered face-amount certificate company shall file with the Commission any financial statement in the preparation of which the controller or other principal accounting officer or employee of such company participated, unless such controller, officer or employee was selected, either by vote of the holders of such company’s voting securities at the last annual meeting of such security holders, or by the board of directors of such company.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id78718202-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80a–31/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports of accountants and auditors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized, by rules and regulations or order in the public interest or for the protection of investors, to require accountants and auditors to keep reports, work sheets, and other documents and papers relating to registered investment companies for such period or periods as the Commission may prescribe, and to make the same available for inspection by the Commission or any member or representative thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id78718203-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, title I, § 32, <ref href="/us/stat/54/838">54 Stat. 838</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s18">Pub. L. 91–547, § 18</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1427">84 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s28/4">Pub. L. 94–29, § 28(4)</ref>, <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/165">89 Stat. 165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id78718204-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id78718205-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id78718206-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–16/c">section 80a–16(c) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–16/b">section 80a–16(b) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref> struck out introductory text “After one year from the effective date of this subchapter,” and substituted “It” for “it”; inserted “the vote, cast in person, of” before “a majority” and substituted “interested persons of” for “investment advisers of, or affiliated persons of an investment adviser of, or officers or employees of,” in par. (1); inserted “the vote of a majority of those members of” before “the board of directors” and “who are not interested persons of such registered company, cast in person at a meeting called for the purpose of voting on such action” after “the board of directors” in par. (2); substituted period for colon in par. (4); and in text after par. (4), substituted “if not so filled,” for “if not so filled then” and “if not so filed” for “if not so filled”, and substituted reference to par. (42) for par. (40) of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–2/a">section 80a–2(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id78718207-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78718208-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/29">Pub. L. 94–29</ref> effective <date date="1975-06-04">June 4, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/29/s31/a">section 31(a) of Pub. L. 94–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78b">section 78b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id78718209-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref> effective on expiration of one year after <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s30/1">section 30(1) of Pub. L. 91–547</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–52">section 80a–52 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7871820a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id7871820b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
