<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id787d90ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5"><num value="80b–5">§ 80b–5.</num><heading> Investment advisory contracts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787d90cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation, assignment, and partnership-membership provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No investment adviser registered or required to be registered with the Commission shall enter into, extend, or renew any investment advisory contract, or in any way perform any investment advisory contract entered into, extended, or renewed on or after <date date="1940-11-01">November 1, 1940</date>, if such contract—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provides for compensation to the investment adviser on the basis of a share of capital gains upon or capital appreciation of the funds or any portion of the funds of the client;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> fails to provide, in substance, that no assignment of such contract shall be made by the investment adviser without the consent of the other party to the contract; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> fails to provide, in substance, that the investment adviser, if a partnership, will notify the other party to the contract of any change in the membership of such partnership within a reasonable time after such change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787d90cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation prohibition inapplicable to certain compensation computations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be construed to prohibit an investment advisory contract which provides for compensation based upon the total value of a fund averaged over a definite period, or as of definite dates, or taken as of a definite date;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> apply to an investment advisory contract with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id787d90d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an investment company registered under subchapter I of this chapter, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id787d90d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any other person (except a trust, governmental plan, collective trust fund, or separate account referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–3/c/11">section 80a–3(c)(11) of this title</ref>), provided that the contract relates to the investment of assets in excess of $1 million,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">if the contract provides for compensation based on the asset value of the company or fund under management averaged over a specified period and increasing and decreasing proportionately with the investment performance of the company or fund over a specified period in relation to the investment record of an appropriate index of securities prices or such other measure of investment performance as the Commission by rule, regulation, or order may specify;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> apply with respect to any investment advisory contract between an investment adviser and a business development company, as defined in this subchapter, if (A) the compensation provided for in such contract does not exceed 20 per centum of the realized capital gains upon the funds of the business development company over a specified period or as of definite dates, computed net of all realized capital losses and unrealized capital depreciation, and the condition of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/4/B/iii">section 80a–60(a)(4)(B)(iii) of this title</ref> is satisfied, and (B) the business development company does not have outstanding any option, warrant, or right issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/4/B">section 80a–60(a)(4)(B) of this title</ref> and does not have a profit-sharing plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–56/n">section 80a–56(n) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> apply to an investment advisory contract with a company excepted from the definition of an investment company under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–3/c/7">section 80a–3(c)(7) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id787d90d6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> apply to an investment advisory contract with a person who is not a resident of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787d90d7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Measurement of changes in compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of paragraph (2) of subsection (b), the point from which increases and decreases in compensation are measured shall be the fee which is paid or earned when the investment performance of such company or fund is equivalent to that of the index or other measure of performance, and an index of securities prices shall be deemed appropriate unless the Commission by order shall determine otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787fd9c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “Investment advisory contract” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a), “investment advisory contract” means any contract or agreement whereby a person agrees to act as investment adviser to or to manage any investment or trading account of another person other than an investment company registered under subchapter I of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787fd9c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Exempt persons and transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, by rule or regulation, upon its own motion, or by order upon application, may conditionally or unconditionally exempt any person or transaction, or any class or classes of persons or transactions, from subsection (a)(1), if and to the extent that the exemption relates to an investment advisory contract with any person that the Commission determines does not need the protections of subsection (a)(1), on the basis of such factors as financial sophistication, net worth, knowledge of and experience in financial matters, amount of assets under management, relationship with a registered investment adviser, and such other factors as the Commission determines are consistent with this section. With respect to any factor used in any rule or regulation by the Commission in making a determination under this subsection, if the Commission uses a dollar amount test in connection with such factor, such as a net asset threshold, the Commission shall, by order, not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, adjust for the effects of inflation on such test. Any such adjustment that is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id787fd9ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s80b–5/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to restrict mandatory pre-dispute arbitration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, by rule, may prohibit, or impose conditions or limitations on the use of, agreements that require customers or clients of any investment adviser to arbitrate any future dispute between them arising under the Federal securities laws, the rules and regulations thereunder, or the rules of a self-regulatory organization if it finds that such prohibition, imposition of conditions, or limitations are in the public interest and for the protection of investors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id787fd9cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, title II, § 205, <ref href="/us/stat/54/852">54 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/750/s7">Pub. L. 86–750, § 7</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/887">74 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s25">Pub. L. 91–547, § 25</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1432">84 Stat. 1432</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/477/tII/s203">Pub. L. 96–477, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2290">94 Stat. 2290</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/181/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 100–181, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1263">101 Stat. 1263</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/290/tII/s210">Pub. L. 104–290, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3436">110 Stat. 3436</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tIV/s418">Pub. L. 111–203, title IV, § 418</ref>, title IX, §§ 921(b), 928, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1579">124 Stat. 1579</ref>, 1841, 1852; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dS/tVIII/s802/b/1">Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title VIII, § 802(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1140">132 Stat. 1140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id787fd9cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id787fd9cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id787fd9ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/4/B/iii">section 80a–60(a)(4)(B)(iii) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/3/B/iii">section 80a–60(a)(3)(B)(iii) of this title</ref>” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/4/B">section 80a–60(a)(4)(B) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/3/B">section 80a–60(a)(3)(B) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s928">Pub. L. 111–203, § 928</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “registered or required to be registered with the Commission” for “, unless exempt from registration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–3/b">section 80b–3(b) of this title</ref>,” and struck out “make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce, directly or indirectly, to” after “shall” and “to” after “in any way”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s418">Pub. L. 111–203, § 418</ref>, inserted at end “With respect to any factor used in any rule or regulation by the Commission in making a determination under this subsection, if the Commission uses a dollar amount test in connection with such factor, such as a net asset threshold, the Commission shall, by order, not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, adjust for the effects of inflation on such test. Any such adjustment that is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s921/b">Pub. L. 111–203, § 921(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/290/s210/1">Pub. L. 104–290, § 210(1)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/290/s210/2">Pub. L. 104–290, § 210(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/181">Pub. L. 100–181</ref> completely revised and expanded provisions on investment advisory contracts, changing structure of section from a single unlettered paragraph to one consisting of four subsections lettered (a) to (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/477">Pub. L. 96–477</ref> provided that par. (1) of this section was not to apply with respect to any investment advisory contract between an investment adviser and a business development company so long as the compensation provided for in such contract did not exceed 20 per cent of the realized capital gains upon the funds of the business development company and such business development company did not have outstanding any option, warrant, or right issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–60/a/3/B">section 80a–60(a)(3)(B) of this title</ref> and did not have a profit-sharing plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref> substituted reference to section “80b–3(b)” for “80b–3” of this title in first sentence, redesignated as second sentence former third sentence, designating existing provisions as cl. (A) and adding cl. (B) and items (i) and (ii) and provision respecting compensation based on asset value of company or fund under management averaged over a specified period in relation to investment record of an index of securities or such other measure of investment performance specified by Commission rules, regulations, or orders, inserted third sentence provision respecting point from which compensation is to be measured, substituted in fourth, formerly third, sentence “paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section” for “this section” and in definition of “investment advisory contract” the words “account of another person other than an investment company registered under subchapter I of this chapter” for “account for a person other than an investment company”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/750">Pub. L. 86–750</ref> substituted “unless exempt from registration pursuant to” for “registered under”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id787fd9cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id787fd9d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 921(b) and 928 of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 day after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective 1 year after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, except that any investment adviser may, at the discretion of the investment adviser, register with the Commission under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 during that 1-year period, subject to the rules of the Commission, and except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s419">section 419 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–2">section 80b–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id787fd9d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/547">Pub. L. 91–547</ref> effective on expiration of one year after <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/547/s30/1">section 30(1) of Pub. L. 91–547</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–52">section 80a–52 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id787fd9d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id787fd9d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of Securities and Exchange Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 10 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1265">64 Stat. 1265</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78d">section 78d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
