<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a87b840-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8515"><num value="8515">§ 8515.</num><heading> Weather research and development planning</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2017-04-18">April 18, 2017</date>, and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Under Secretary, acting through the Assistant Administrator for Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and in coordination with the Director of the National Weather Service and the Assistant Administrator for Satellite and Information Services, shall issue a research and development and research to operations plan to restore and maintain United States leadership in numerical weather prediction and forecasting that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a87b841-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8515/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describes the forecasting skill and technology goals, objectives, and progress of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in carrying out the program conducted under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8512">section 8512 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a87b842-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8515/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identifies and prioritizes specific research and development activities, and performance metrics, weighted to meet the operational weather and flood-event mission of the National Weather Service to achieve a weather-ready Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a87b843-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8515/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> describes how the program will collaborate with stakeholders, including the United States weather industry and academic partners; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7a87b844-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8515/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identifies, through consultation with the National Science Foundation, the United States weather industry, and academic partners, research necessary to enhance the integration of social science knowledge into weather forecast and warning processes, including to improve the communication of threat information necessary to enable improved severe weather planning and decisionmaking on the part of individuals and communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7a87b845-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/25/tI/s105">Pub. L. 115–25, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2017-04-18">Apr. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/95">131 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/316/s10">Pub. L. 117–316, § 10</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4413">136 Stat. 4413</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7a87b846-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7a87b847-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id7a87b848-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/316">Pub. L. 117–316</ref> inserted “and flood-event” after “operational weather”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
