<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7a8a297c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8543"><num value="8543">§ 8543.</num><heading> Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and National Weather Service exchange program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a8a297d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8543/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Assistant Administrator for Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and the Director of National <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002604">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002604"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”.</note> Weather Service may establish a program to detail Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research personnel to the National Weather Service and National Weather Service personnel to the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a8a297e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8543/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Goal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The goal of this program is to enhance forecasting innovation through regular, direct interaction between the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research’s world-class scientists and the National Weather Service’s operational staff.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a8a297f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8543/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The program shall allow up to 10 Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research staff and National Weather Service staff to spend up to 1 year on detail. Candidates shall be jointly selected by the Assistant Administrator for Oceanic and Atmospheric Research and the Director of the National Weather Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7a8a2980-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s8543/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not less frequently than once each year, the Under Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on participation in such program and shall highlight any innovations that come from this interaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7a8a2981-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/25/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 115–25, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2017-04-18">Apr. 18, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/107">131 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
