<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7aa9238f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202"><num value="9202">§ 9202.</num><heading> NSF support of research on manipulated or synthesized content and information security</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies, shall support merit-reviewed and competitively awarded research on manipulated or synthesized content and information authenticity, which may include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa92390-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> fundamental research on digital forensic tools or other technologies for verifying the authenticity of information and detection of manipulated or synthesized content, including content generated by generative adversarial networks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa92391-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> fundamental research on technical tools for identifying manipulated or synthesized content, such as watermarking systems for generated media;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa92392-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> social and behavioral research related to manipulated or synthesized content, including human engagement with the content;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa92393-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> research on public understanding and awareness of manipulated and synthesized content, including research on best practices for educating the public to discern authenticity of digital content; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa92394-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9202/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> research awards coordinated with other federal agencies and programs, including the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Agency,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002653">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002653"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Activity,”.</note> with coordination enabled by the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7aa92395-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/258/s3">Pub. L. 116–258, § 3</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1151">134 Stat. 1151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
