<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7aa9239c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9204"><num value="9204">§ 9204.</num><heading> Generative adversarial network defined</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “generative adversarial network” means, with respect to artificial intelligence, the machine learning process of attempting to cause a generator artificial neural network (referred to in this section as the “generator” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002654">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002654"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a closing parenthesis.</note> and a discriminator artificial neural network (referred to in this section as a “discriminator”) to compete against each other to become more accurate in their function and outputs, through which the generator and discriminator create a feedback loop, causing the generator to produce increasingly higher-quality artificial outputs and the discriminator to increasingly improve in detecting such artificial outputs.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id7aa9239d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/258/s6">Pub. L. 116–258, § 6</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1152">134 Stat. 1152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7aa9239e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7aa9239f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7aa923a0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/116/258">Pub. L. 116–258</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1150">134 Stat. 1150</ref>, known as the Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act and also as the IOGAN Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9201">section 9201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section, referred to in text, was in the original “this paragraph”, and was translated as reading “this section”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/116/258/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 116–258</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
