<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7aa923b1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302"><num value="9302">§ 9302.</num><heading> Strategic plan for sustainable chemistry</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923b2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Entity shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consult with relevant stakeholders, including representatives from industry, academia, national labs, the Federal Government, and international entities, to develop and update, as needed, a consensus definition of “sustainable chemistry” to guide the activities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop a working framework of attributes characterizing, and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry, as described in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assess the state of sustainable chemistry in the United States as a key benchmark from which progress under the activities described in this chapter can be measured, including assessing key sectors of the United States economy, key technology platforms, commercial priorities, and barriers to innovation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> coordinate and support Federal research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training efforts in sustainable chemistry, including budget coordination and support for public-private partnerships, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> identify any Federal regulatory barriers to, and opportunities for, Federal agencies facilitating the development of incentives for development, consideration, and use of sustainable chemistry processes and products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> identify major scientific challenges, roadblocks, and hurdles to transformational progress in improving the sustainability of the chemical sciences; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923b9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> review, identify, and make effort to eliminate duplicative Federal funding and duplicative Federal research in sustainable chemistry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923ba-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Characterizing and assessing sustainable chemistry</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Entity shall develop a working framework of attributes characterizing, and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry for the purposes of carrying out this chapter. In developing this framework, the Entity shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923bb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> seek advice and input from stakeholders as described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923bc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> consider existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry already in use at Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923bd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> consider existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry already in use by international organizations of which the United States is a member, such as the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923be-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> consider any other appropriate existing definitions of, or frameworks characterizing and metrics for assessing, sustainable chemistry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923bf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the duties described in subsections (a) and (b), the Entity shall consult with stakeholders qualified to provide advice and information to guide Federal activities related to sustainable chemistry through workshops, requests for information, or other mechanisms as necessary. The stakeholders shall include representatives from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> business and industry, including trade associations and small- and medium-sized enterprises from across the value chain;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the scientific community, including the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, scientific professional societies, national labs, and academia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the defense community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> State, tribal, and local governments, including nonregulatory State or regional sustainable chemistry programs, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> nongovernmental organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id7aa923c5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> other appropriate organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923c6-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923c7-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Entity shall submit a report to the Committee on Environment and Public Works, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Education and Labor, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. In addition to the elements described in subsections (a) and (b), the report shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923c8-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a summary of federally funded sustainable chemistry research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923c9-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a summary of the financial resources allocated to sustainable chemistry initiatives by each participating agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923ca-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an assessment of the current state of sustainable chemistry in the United States, including the role that Federal agencies are playing in supporting it;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923cb-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an analysis of the progress made toward achieving the goals and priorities of this chapter, and recommendations for future program activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923cc-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> an evaluation of steps taken and future strategies to avoid duplication of efforts, streamline interagency coordination, facilitate information sharing, and spread best practices among participating agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa923cd-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> an evaluation of duplicative Federal funding and duplicative Federal research in sustainable chemistry, efforts undertaken by the Entity to eliminate duplicative funding and research, and recommendations on how to achieve these goals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923ce-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to GAO</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Entity shall also submit the report described in paragraph (1) to the Comptroller General of the United States for consideration in future Congressional inquiries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa923cf-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9302/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Entity shall submit a report to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States that incorporates the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (D), (E), and (F) of paragraph (1) every 3 years, commencing after the initial report is submitted until the Entity terminates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id7aa923d0-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s262">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 262</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3498">134 Stat. 3498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7aa923d1-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7aa923d2-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7aa923d3-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (b), and (d)(1)(D), was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle E (§§ 261–267) of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3497">134 Stat. 3497</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of subtitle E to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), was in the original “this title”, which was translated as meaning this subtitle, which is classified principally to this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7aa923d4-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id7aa923d5-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Education and Labor of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Education and the Workforce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
