<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id7aa92406-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401"><num value="9401">§ 9401.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92407-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Advisory Committee” means the National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9414/a">section 9414(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92408-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency head</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “agency head” means the head of any Executive agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92409-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Artificial intelligence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “artificial intelligence” means a machine-based system that can, for a given set of human-defined objectives, make predictions, recommendations or decisions influencing real or virtual environments. Artificial intelligence systems use machine and human-based inputs to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa9240a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> perceive real and virtual environments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa9240b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> abstract such perceptions into models through analysis in an automated manner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id7aa9240c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> use model inference to formulate options for information or action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa9240d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Community college</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “community college” means a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year Tribal Colleges or Universities under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1059c">section 1059c of title 20</ref> and public 2-year State institutions of higher education.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa9240e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiative</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Initiative” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9411/a">section 9411(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa9240f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiative Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Initiative Office” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Office established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9412/a">section 9412(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92410-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Institute</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Institute” means an Artificial Intelligence Research Institute described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9431/b/2">section 9431(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92411-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001 and <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1002/c">section 1002(c) of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92412-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency Committee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Interagency Committee” means the interagency committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9413/a">section 9413(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92413-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> K-12 education</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “K-12 education” means elementary school and secondary school education provided by local educational agencies, as such agencies are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id7aa92414-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0" identifier="/us/usc/t15/s9401/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Machine learning</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “machine learning” means an application of artificial intelligence that is characterized by providing systems the ability to automatically learn and improve on the basis of data or experience, without being explicitly programmed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id7aa92415-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dE/s5002">Pub. L. 116–283, div. E, § 5002</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4523">134 Stat. 4523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id7aa92416-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id7aa92417-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id7aa92418-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this division”, meaning div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4523">134 Stat. 4523</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of div. E to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id7aa92419-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id7aa9241a-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dE/s5001">Pub. L. 116–283, div. E, § 5001</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4523">134 Stat. 4523</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dE/s5001">“This division [enacting this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s278h–1">section 278h–1 of this title</ref> and amending sections 1862i and 1862n–1 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare] may be cited as the ‘National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id7aa9241b-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aa9241c-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14110</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14110, <date date="2023-10-30">Oct. 30, 2023</date>, 88 F.R. 75191, which related to safe, secure, and trustworthy development and use of artificial intelligence, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(ggg), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8240.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d0d-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14141</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14141, <date date="2025-01-14">Jan. 14, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 5469, which related to the development and operation of infrastructure necessary to establishing United States’ economic competitiveness in artificial intelligence, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14318, § 4, <date date="2025-07-23">July 23, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 35386, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d0e-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14179. Removing Barriers to American Leadership in Artificial Intelligence</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14179, <date date="2025-01-23">Jan. 23, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8741, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. The United States has long been at the forefront of artificial intelligence (AI) innovation, driven by the strength of our free markets, world-class research institutions, and entrepreneurial spirit. To maintain this leadership, we must develop AI systems that are free from ideological bias or engineered social agendas. With the right Government policies, we can solidify our position as the global leader in AI and secure a brighter future for all Americans. This order revokes certain existing AI policies and directives that act as barriers to American AI innovation, clearing a path for the United States to act decisively to retain global leadership in artificial intelligence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to sustain and enhance America’s global AI dominance in order to promote human flourishing, economic competitiveness, and national security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Definition</i>. For the purposes of this order, “artificial intelligence” or “AI” has the meaning set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9401/3">15 U.S.C. 9401(3)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Developing an Artificial Intelligence Action Plan</i>. (a) Within 180 days of this order [<date date="2025-01-23">Jan. 23, 2025</date>], the Assistant to the President for Science and Technology (APST), the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), in coordination with the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy, the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB Director), and the heads of such executive departments and agencies (agencies) as the APST and APNSA deem relevant, shall develop and submit to the President an action plan to achieve the policy set forth in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Implementation of Order Revocation</i>. (a) The APST, the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, and the APNSA shall immediately review, in coordination with the heads of all agencies as they deem relevant, all policies, directives, regulations, orders, and other actions taken pursuant to the revoked Executive Order 14110 of <date date="2023-10-30">October 30, 2023</date> (Safe, Secure, and Trustworthy Development and Use of Artificial Intelligence) [formerly set out above]. The APST, the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, and the APNSA shall, in coordination with the heads of relevant agencies, identify any actions taken pursuant to Executive Order 14110 that are or may be inconsistent with, or present obstacles to, the policy set forth in section 2 of this order. For any such agency actions identified, the heads of agencies shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, suspend, revise, or rescind such actions, or propose suspending, revising, or rescinding such actions. If in any case such suspension, revision, or rescission cannot be finalized immediately, the APST and the heads of agencies shall promptly take steps to provide all available exemptions authorized by any such orders, rules, regulations, guidelines, or policies, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, until such action can be finalized.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 60 days of this order, the OMB Director, in coordination with the APST, shall revise OMB Memoranda M–24–10 and M–24–18 as necessary to make them consistent with the policy set forth in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d0f-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14318. Accelerating Federal Permitting of Data Center Infrastructure</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14318, <date date="2025-07-23">July 23, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 35385, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy and Purpose</i>. My Administration has inaugurated a golden age for American manufacturing and technological dominance. We will pursue bold, large-scale industrial plans to vault the United States further into the lead on critical manufacturing processes and technologies that are essential to national security, economic prosperity, and scientific leadership. These plans include artificial intelligence (AI) data centers and infrastructure that powers them, including high-voltage transmission lines and other equipment. It will be a priority of my Administration to facilitate the rapid and efficient buildout of this infrastructure by easing Federal regulatory burdens.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In addition, my Administration will utilize federally owned land and resources for the expeditious and orderly development of data centers. This usage will be done in a manner consistent with the land’s intended purpose—to be used in service of the prosperity and security of the American people.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Definitions</i>. For purposes of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) “Data Center Project” means a facility that requires greater than 100 megawatts (MW) of new load dedicated to AI inference, training, simulation, or synthetic data generation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) “Covered Components” means materials, products, and infrastructure that are required to build Data Center Projects or otherwise upon which Data Center Projects depend, including:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) energy infrastructure, such as transmission lines, natural gas pipelines or laterals, substations, switchyards, transformers, switchgear, and system protective facilities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) natural gas turbines, coal power equipment, nuclear power equipment, geothermal power equipment, and any other dispatchable baseload energy sources, including electrical infrastructure (including backup power supply) constructed or otherwise used principally to serve a Data Center Project;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iii) semiconductors and semiconductor materials, such as wafers, dies, and packaged integrated circuits;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iv) networking equipment, such as switches and routers; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(v) data storage, such as hardware storage systems, software for data management and protection, and integrated services that work with public cloud providers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) “Covered Component Project” means infrastructure comprising Covered Components, or a facility with the primary purposes of manufacturing or otherwise producing Covered Components.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) “Qualifying Project” means:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) a Data Center Project or Covered Component Project for which the Project Sponsor has committed at least $500 million in capital expenditures as determined by the Secretary of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) a Data Center Project or Covered Component Project involving an incremental electric load addition of greater than 100 MW;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iii) a Data Center Project or Covered Component Project that protects national security; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iv) a Data Center Project or Covered Component Project that has otherwise been designated by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary of Energy as a “Qualifying Project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) “Project Sponsor” means the lead sponsor providing financial and other support for a Data Center Project or Covered Component Project, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) “Superfund Site” means any site where action is being taken pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">42 U.S.C. 9604</ref>, 9606, or 9620 [sections 104, 106, or 120 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) “Brownfield Site” means a site as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/39">42 U.S.C. 9601(39)</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/s101/39">section 101(39) of Pub. L. 96–510</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Encouraging Qualifying Projects</i>. The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) and other relevant executive departments and agencies (agencies), shall launch an initiative to provide financial support for Qualifying Projects, which could include loans and loan guarantees, grants, tax incentives, and offtake agreements. All relevant agencies shall identify and submit to the Director of OSTP any such relevant existing financial support that can be used to assist Qualifying Projects, consistent with the protection of national security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Revocation of Executive Order 14141</i>. Executive Order 14141 of <date date="2025-01-14">January 14, 2025</date> (Advancing United States Leadership in Artificial Intelligence Infrastructure) [formerly set out above], is hereby revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Efficient Environmental Reviews</i>. (a) Within 10 days of the date of this order, each relevant agency shall identify to the Council on Environmental Quality any categorical exclusions already established or adopted by such agency pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act [of 1969, <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>] (NEPA), reliance on and adoption of which by agencies (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4336">42 U.S.C. 4336</ref> and 4336c [sections 106 and 109 of <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>]) could facilitate the construction of Qualifying Projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Council on Environmental Quality shall coordinate with relevant agencies on the establishment of new categorical exclusions to cover actions related to Qualifying Projects that normally do not have a significant effect on the human environment. Agencies shall, for purposes of establishing these categorical exclusions, rely on any sufficient basis to do so as each such agency determines.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4336e/10/B/iii">42 U.S.C. 4336e(10)(B)(iii)</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/91/190/s111/10/B/iii">section 111(10)(B)(iii) of Pub. L. 91–190</ref>], loans, loan guarantees, grants, tax incentives, or other forms of Federal financial assistance for which an agency lacks substantial project-specific control and responsibility over the subsequent use of such financial assistance shall not be considered a “major Federal action” under NEPA. For purposes of this order, Federal financial assistance representing less than 50 percent of total project costs shall be presumed not to constitute substantial Federal control and responsibility.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>Efficiency and Transparency Through FAST-41</i>. (a) The Executive Director (Executive Director) of the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council (FPISC) may, within 30 days of the date that a project is identified to FPISC by a relevant agency, designate a Qualifying Project as a transparency project pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4370m–2/b/2/A/iii">42 U.S.C. 4370m–2(b)(2)(A)(iii)</ref> [section 41003(b)(2)(A)(iii) of Pub. L. 114—94] and section 41003 of the Fixing America’s Surface Transportation Act (<ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Public Law 114–94</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1312">129 Stat. 1312</ref>, 1747) (FAST-41) [sic]. Within 30 days of receiving such agency notification, the Executive Director may publish Qualifying Projects on the Permitting Dashboard established under section 41003(b) of FAST-41, including schedules for expedited review.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In consultation with Project Sponsors, the Executive Director shall expedite the transition of eligible Qualifying Projects from transparency projects to FAST-41 “covered projects” as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4370m/6/A">42 U.S.C. 4370m(6)(A)</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s41001/6/A">section 41001(6)(A) of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>]. To the extent that a Qualifying Project does not meet the criteria set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4370m/6/A/i">42 U.S.C. 4370m(6)(A)(i)</ref> or (iii), FPISC may consider all other available options to designate the project a covered project under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4370m/6/A/iv">42 U.S.C. 4370m(6)(A)(iv)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. <i>Streamlining of Permitting Review</i>. (a) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assist in expediting permitting on Federal and non-Federal lands by developing or modifying regulations promulgated under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.); the Clean Water Act [Federal Water Pollution Control Act] (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1251">33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.); the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act [of 1980] (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.); the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">15 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.); and other relevant applicable laws, in each case, that impact the development of Qualifying Projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall, consistent with the Environmental Protection Agency’s statutory authorities, expeditiously identify Brownfield Sites and Superfund Sites for use by Qualifying Projects. As part of this effort, within 180 days of the date of this order, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall develop guidance to help expedite environmental reviews for qualified reuse and assist State governments and private parties to return such Brownfield Sites and Superfund Sites to productive use as expeditiously as possible.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 8. <i>Biological and Water Permitting Efficiencies</i>. (a) Upon identification of sites by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Energy as described in section 9 of this order, the action agency, as identified through the process described in the Endangered Species Act [of 1973] (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531–154">16 U.S.C. 1531–154</ref>4) (ESA), shall initiate consultation under section 7 of the ESA with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, or both with respect to common construction activities for Qualifying Projects that will occur over the next 10 years at a programmatic level. The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce shall utilize programmatic consultation to ensure timely and efficient completion of such consultation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, shall review the nationwide permits issued under section 404 of the Clean Water Act of 1972 [Federal Water Pollution Control Act] (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</ref>) and section 10 of the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s403">33 U.S.C. 403</ref>) to determine whether an activity-specific nationwide permit is needed to facilitate the efficient permitting of activities related to Qualifying Projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 9. <i>Federal Lands Availability</i>. (a) The Department of the Interior and the Department of Energy shall, after consultation with industry and further in consultation with the Department of Commerce as to the Project Sponsors to which relevant authorizations shall be granted, offer appropriate authorizations for sites identified by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Energy, as applicable and appropriate for the relevant uses, consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201">42 U.S.C. 2201</ref> [section 161 of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>], <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7256">42 U.S.C. 7256</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/s646">section 646 of Pub. L. 95–91</ref>], <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq. [<ref href="/us/pl/94/579">Pub. L. 94–579</ref>], and all other applicable law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Defense shall, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2667">10 U.S.C. 2667</ref> or other applicable law and as and when the Secretary of Defense deems it necessary or desirable, identify suitable sites on military installations for Covered Component infrastructure uses and competitively lease available lands for Qualifying Projects to support the Department of Defense’s energy, workforce, and mission needs, subject to security and force protection considerations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 10. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The costs for publication of this order shall be borne by the Department of Energy.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d10-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14320. Promoting the Export of the American AI Technology Stack</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14320, <date date="2025-07-23">July 23, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 35393, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. Artificial intelligence (AI) is a foundational technology that will define the future of economic growth, national security, and global competitiveness for decades to come. The United States must not only lead in developing general-purpose and frontier AI capabilities, but also ensure that American AI technologies, standards, and governance models are adopted worldwide to strengthen relationships with our allies and secure our continued technological dominance. This order establishes a coordinated national effort to support the American AI industry by promoting the export of full-stack American AI technology packages.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to preserve and extend American leadership in AI and decrease international dependence on AI technologies developed by our adversaries by supporting the global deployment of United States-origin AI technologies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Establishment of the American AI Exports Program</i>. (a) Within 90 days of the date of this order [<date date="2025-07-23">July 23, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Commerce shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), establish and implement the American AI Exports Program (Program) to support the development and deployment of United States full-stack AI export packages.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Commerce shall issue a public call for proposals from industry-led consortia for inclusion in the Program. The public call shall require that each proposal must:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) include a full-stack AI technology package, which encompasses:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(A) AI-optimized computer hardware (e.g., chips, servers, and accelerators), data center storage, cloud services, and networking, as well as a description of whether and to what extent such items are manufactured in the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(B) data pipelines and labeling systems;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(C) AI models and systems;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(D) measures to ensure the security and cybersecurity of AI models and systems; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(E) AI applications for specific use cases (e.g., software engineering, education, healthcare, agriculture, or transportation);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) identify specific target countries or regional blocs for export engagement;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) describe a business and operational model to explain, at a high level, which entities will build, own, and operate data centers and associated infrastructure;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) detail requested Federal incentives and support mechanisms; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) comply with all relevant United States export control regimes, outbound investment regulations, and end-user policies, including chapter 58 of title 50 [subtitle B (§§ 1741–1781) of title XVII of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref>], United States Code, and relevant guidance from the Bureau of Industry and Security within the Department of Commerce.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Department of Commerce shall require proposals to be submitted no later than 90 days after the public call for proposals is issued, and shall consider proposals on a rolling basis for inclusion in the Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of Commerce shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the Director of OSTP, evaluate submitted proposals for inclusion under the Program. Proposals selected by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the Director of OSTP, will be designated as priority AI export packages and will be supported through priority access to the tools identified in section 4 of this order, as consistent with applicable law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Mobilization of Federal Financing Tools</i>. (a) The Economic Diplomacy Action Group (EDAG), established in the Presidential Memorandum of <date date="2024-06-21">June 21, 2024</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904">22 U.S.C. 9904</ref> note], chaired by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the United States Trade Representative, and as described in section 708 of the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019 (Title VII of Division J of <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</ref>) (CABDA) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904">22 U.S.C. 9904</ref>], shall coordinate mobilization of Federal financing tools in support of priority AI export packages.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) I delegate to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the Director of OSTP the authority under section 708(c)(3) of CABDA to appoint senior officials from their respective executive departments and agencies to serve as members of the EDAG.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary of State, in consultation with the EDAG, shall be responsible for:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) developing and executing a unified Federal Government strategy to promote the export of American AI technologies and standards;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) aligning technical, financial, and diplomatic resources to accelerate deployment of priority AI export packages under the Program;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) coordinating United States participation in multilateral initiatives and country-specific partnerships for AI deployment and export promotion;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) supporting partner countries in fostering pro-innovation regulatory, data, and infrastructure environments conducive to the deployment of American AI systems;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) analyzing market access, including technical barriers to trade and regulatory measures that may impede the competitiveness of United States offerings; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) coordinating with the Small Business Administration’s Office of Investment and Innovation to facilitate, to the extent permitted under applicable law, investment in United States small businesses to the development of American AI technologies and the manufacture of AI infrastructure, hardware, and systems.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Members of the EDAG shall deploy, to the maximum extent permitted by law, available Federal tools to support the priority export packages selected for participation in the Program, including direct loans and loan guarantees (12 U.S.C.[ ]635) [section 2 of act <date date="1945-07-31">July 31, 1945</date>]; equity investments, co-financing, political risk insurance, and credit guarantees (22 U.S.C.[ ]9621) [<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1421">section 1421 of Pub. L. 115–254</ref>]; and technical assistance and feasibility studies (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2421/b">22 U.S.C. 2421(b)</ref>) [<ref href="/us/pl/87/195/s661">section 661 of Pub. L. 87–195</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The costs for publication of this order shall be borne by the Department of Commerce.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d11-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14363. Launching the Genesis Mission</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14363, <date date="2025-11-24">Nov. 24, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 55035, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. From the founding of our Republic, scientific discovery and technological innovation have driven American progress and prosperity. Today, America is in a race for global technology dominance in the development of artificial intelligence (AI), an important frontier of scientific discovery and economic growth. To that end, my Administration has taken a number of actions to win that race, including issuing multiple Executive Orders and implementing America’s AI Action Plan, which recognizes the need to invest in AI-enabled science to accelerate scientific advancement. In this pivotal moment, the challenges we face require a historic national effort, comparable in urgency and ambition to the Manhattan Project that was instrumental to our victory in World War II and was a critical basis for the foundation of the Department of Energy (DOE) and its national laboratories.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This order launches the “Genesis Mission” as a dedicated, coordinated national effort to unleash a new age of AI-accelerated innovation and discovery that can solve the most challenging problems of this century. The Genesis Mission will build an integrated AI platform to harness Federal scientific datasets—the world’s largest collection of such datasets, developed over decades of Federal investments—to train scientific foundation models and create AI agents to test new hypotheses, automate research workflows, and accelerate scientific breakthroughs. The Genesis Mission will bring together our Nation’s research and development resources—combining the efforts of brilliant American scientists, including those at our national laboratories, with pioneering American businesses; world-renowned universities; and existing research infrastructure, data repositories, production plants, and national security sites—to achieve dramatic acceleration in AI development and utilization. We will harness for the benefit of our Nation the revolution underway in computing, and build on decades of innovation in semiconductors and high-performance computing. The Genesis Mission will dramatically accelerate scientific discovery, strengthen national security, secure energy dominance, enhance workforce productivity, and multiply the return on taxpayer investment into research and development, thereby furthering America’s technological dominance and global strategic leadership.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Establishment of the Genesis Mission</i>. (a) There is hereby established the Genesis Mission (Mission), a national effort to accelerate the application of AI for transformative scientific discovery focused on pressing national challenges.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Energy (Secretary) shall be responsible for implementing the Mission within DOE, consistent with the provisions of this order, including, as appropriate and authorized by law, setting priorities and ensuring that all DOE resources used for elements of the Mission are integrated into a secure, unified platform. The Secretary may designate a senior political appointee to oversee day-to-day operations of the Mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Assistant to the President for Science and Technology (APST) shall provide general leadership of the Mission, including coordination of participating executive departments and agencies (agencies) through the National Science and Technology Council (NSTC) and the issuance of guidance to ensure that the Mission is aligned with national objectives.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>Operation of the American Science and Security Platform</i>. (a) The Secretary shall establish and operate the American Science and Security Platform (Platform) to serve as the infrastructure for the Mission with the purpose of providing, in an integrated manner and to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with law:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) high-performance computing resources, including DOE national laboratory supercomputers and secure cloud-based AI computing environments, capable of supporting large-scale model training, simulation, and inference;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) AI modeling and analysis frameworks, including AI agents to explore design spaces, evaluate experimental outcomes, and automate workflows;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) computational tools, including AI-enabled predictive models, simulation models, and design optimization tools;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) domain-specific foundation models across the range of scientific domains covered;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) secure access to appropriate datasets, including proprietary, federally curated, and open scientific datasets, in addition to synthetic data generated through DOE computing resources, consistent with applicable law; applicable classification, privacy, and intellectual property protections; and Federal data-access and data-management standards; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) experimental and production tools to enable autonomous and AI-augmented experimentation and manufacturing in high-impact domains.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary shall take necessary steps to ensure that the Platform is operated in a manner that meets security requirements consistent with its national security and competitiveness mission, including applicable classification, supply chain security, and Federal cybersecurity standards and best practices.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Within 90 days of the date of this order [<date date="2025-11-24">Nov. 24, 2025</date>], the Secretary shall identify Federal computing, storage, and networking resources available to support the Mission, including both DOE on-premises and cloud-based high-performance computing systems, and resources available through industry partners. The Secretary shall also identify any additional partnerships or infrastructure enhancements that could support the computational foundation for the Platform.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Within 120 days of the date of this order, the Secretary shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) identify a set of initial data and model assets for use in the Mission, including digitization, standardization, metadata, and provenance tracking; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) develop a plan, with appropriate risk-based cybersecurity measures, for incorporating datasets from federally funded research, other agencies, academic institutions, and approved private-sector partners, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Within 240 days of the date of this order, the Secretary shall review capabilities across the DOE national laboratories and other participating Federal research facilities for robotic laboratories and production facilities with the ability to engage in AI-directed experimentation and manufacturing, including automated and AI-augmented workflows and the related technical and operational standards needed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Within 270 days of the date of this order, the Secretary shall, consistent with applicable law and subject to available appropriations, seek to demonstrate an initial operating capability of the Platform for at least one of the national science and technology challenges identified pursuant to section 4 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Identification of National Science and Technology Challenges</i>. (a) Within 60 days of the date of this order, the Secretary shall identify and submit to the APST a detailed list of at least 20 science and technology challenges of national importance that the Secretary assesses to have potential to be addressed through the Mission and that span priority domains consistent with National Science and Technology Memorandum 2 of <date date="2025-09-23">September 23, 2025</date>, including:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) advanced manufacturing;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) biotechnology;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) critical materials;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) nuclear fission and fusion energy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) quantum information science; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) semiconductors and microelectronics.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 30 days of submission of the list described in subsection (a) of this section, the APST shall review the proposed list and, working with participating agency members of the NSTC, coordinate the development of an expanded list that can serve as the initial set of national science and technology challenges to be addressed by the Mission, including additional challenges proposed by participating agencies through the NSTC, subject to available appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Following development of the expanded list described in subsection (b) of this section, agencies participating in the Mission shall use the Platform to advance research and development aligned with the national science and technology challenges identified in the expanded list, consistent with applicable law and their respective missions, and subject to available appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) On an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall review and update the list of challenges in consultation with the APST and the NSTC to reflect progress achieved, emerging national needs, and alignment with my Administration’s research and development priorities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Interagency Coordination and External Engagement</i>. (a) The APST, through the NSTC, and with support from the Federal Chief Data Officer Council and the Chief AI Officer Council, shall convene relevant and interested agencies to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) assist participating agencies in aligning, to the extent permitted by law, their AI-related programs, datasets, and research and development activities with the objectives of the Mission in their respective areas of expertise, while avoiding duplication of effort across the Federal Government and promoting interoperability;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) identify data sources that may support the Mission’s aim;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) develop a process and resourcing plan in coordination with participating agencies for integrating appropriate and available agency data and infrastructure into the Mission, to the extent permitted by law and subject to available appropriations, including methods under which all agencies contributing to the Mission are encouraged to implement appropriate risk-based security measures that reflect cybersecurity best practices;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) launch coordinated funding opportunities or prize competitions across participating agencies, to the extent permitted by law and subject to available appropriations, to incentivize private-sector participation in AI-driven scientific research aligned with Mission objectives; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) establish mechanisms to coordinate research and development funding opportunities and experimental resources across participating agencies, ensuring agencies can participate effectively in the Mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The APST shall coordinate with relevant agencies in establishing, consistent with existing authorizing statutes and subject to available appropriations, competitive programs for research fellowships, internships, and apprenticeships focused on the application of AI to scientific domains identified as national challenges for the Mission, to include placement of program participants at DOE national laboratories and other participating Federal research facilities, with the purpose of providing access to the Platform and training in AI-enabled scientific discovery.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary, in coordination with the APST and the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, shall establish mechanisms for agency collaboration with external partners possessing advanced AI, data, or computing capabilities or scientific domain expertise, including through cooperative research and development agreements, user facility partnerships, or other appropriate arrangements with external entities to support and enhance the activities of the Mission, and shall ensure that such partnerships are structured to preserve the security of Federal research assets and maximize public benefit. To facilitate these collaborations, the Secretary shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) develop standardized partnership frameworks, including cooperative research and development or other appropriate agreements, and data-use and model-sharing agreements;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) establish clear policies for ownership, licensing, trade-secret protections, and commercialization of intellectual property developed under the Mission, including innovations arising from AI-directed experiments;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) implement uniform and stringent data access and management processes and cybersecurity standards for non-Federal collaborators accessing datasets, models, and computing environments, including measures requiring compliance with classification, privacy, and export-control requirements, as well as other applicable laws; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) establish procedures to ensure the highest standards of vetting and authorization of users and collaborators seeking access to the resources of the Mission and associated research activities, including the Platform and associated Federal research resources.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The APST, through the NSTC, shall, to the extent appropriate, identify opportunities for international scientific collaboration to support activities under the Mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>Evaluation and Reporting</i>. (a) Within 1 year of the date of this order, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the President, through the APST and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, describing:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the Platform’s operational status and capabilities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) progress toward integration across DOE national laboratories and other participating Federal research partners, including shared access to computing resources, data infrastructure, and research facilities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) the status of user engagement, including participation of student researchers and any related training;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) updates on research efforts and outcomes achieved, including measurable scientific advances, publications, and prototype technologies;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) the scope and outcomes of public-private partnerships, including collaborative research projects and any technology transitions or commercialization activities; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) any identified needs or recommendations for authorities or interagency support to achieve the Mission’s objectives.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The costs for publication of this order shall be borne by the Department of Energy.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id7aab6d12-552d-11f1-9071-ff305b7c3ff0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14365. Ensuring a National Policy Framework for Artificial Intelligence</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14365, <date date="2025-12-11">Dec. 11, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 58499, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. United States leadership in Artificial Intelligence (AI) will promote United States national and economic security and dominance across many domains. Pursuant to Executive Order 14179 of <date date="2025-01-23">January 23, 2025</date> (Removing Barriers to American Leadership in Artificial Intelligence) [set out above], I revoked my predecessor’s attempt to paralyze this industry and directed my Administration to remove barriers to United States AI leadership. My Administration has already done tremendous work to advance that objective, including by updating existing Federal regulatory frameworks to remove barriers to and encourage adoption of AI applications across sectors. These efforts have already delivered tremendous benefits to the American people and led to trillions of dollars of investments across the country. But we remain in the earliest days of this technological revolution and are in a race with adversaries for supremacy within it.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">To win, United States AI companies must be free to innovate without cumbersome regulation. But excessive State regulation thwarts this imperative. First, State-by-State regulation by definition creates a patchwork of 50 different regulatory regimes that makes compliance more challenging, particularly for start-ups. Second, State laws are increasingly responsible for requiring entities to embed ideological bias within models. For example, a new Colorado law banning “algorithmic discrimination” may even force AI models to produce false results in order to avoid a “differential treatment or impact” on protected groups. Third, State laws sometimes impermissibly regulate beyond State borders, impinging on interstate commerce.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">My Administration must act with the Congress to ensure that there is a minimally burdensome national standard—not 50 discordant State ones. The resulting framework must forbid State laws that conflict with the policy set forth in this order. That framework should also ensure that children are protected, censorship is prevented, copyrights are respected, and communities are safeguarded. A carefully crafted national framework can ensure that the United States wins the AI race, as we must.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Until such a national standard exists, however, it is imperative that my Administration takes action to check the most onerous and excessive laws emerging from the States that threaten to stymie innovation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to sustain and enhance the United States’ global AI dominance through a minimally burdensome national policy framework for AI.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>AI Litigation Task Force</i>. Within 30 days of the date of this order [<date date="2025-12-11">Dec. 11, 2025</date>], the Attorney General shall establish an AI Litigation Task Force (Task Force) whose sole responsibility shall be to challenge State AI laws inconsistent with the policy set forth in section 2 of this order, including on grounds that such laws unconstitutionally regulate interstate commerce, are preempted by existing Federal regulations, or are otherwise unlawful in the Attorney General’s judgment, including, if appropriate, those laws identified pursuant to section 4 of this order. The Task Force shall consult from time to time with the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, the Assistant to the President for Science and Technology, the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy, and the Assistant to the President and Counsel to the President regarding the emergence of specific State AI laws that warrant challenge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>Evaluation of State AI Laws</i>. Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, consistent with the Secretary’s authorities under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s902/b">47 U.S.C. 902(b)</ref> [<ref href="/us/pl/102/538/s103/b">section 103(b) of Pub. L. 102–538</ref>], shall, in consultation with the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy, the Assistant to the President for Science and Technology, and the Assistant to the President and Counsel to the President, publish an evaluation of existing State AI laws that identifies onerous laws that conflict with the policy set forth in section 2 of this order, as well as laws that should be referred to the Task Force established pursuant to section 3 of this order. That evaluation of State AI laws shall, at a minimum, identify laws that require AI models to alter their truthful outputs, or that may compel AI developers or deployers to disclose or report information in a manner that would violate the First Amendment or any other provision of the Constitution. The evaluation may additionally identify State laws that promote AI innovation consistent with the policy set forth in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. <i>Restrictions on State Funding</i>. (a) Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information, shall issue a Policy Notice specifying the conditions under which States may be eligible for remaining funding under the Broadband Equity Access and Deployment (BEAD) Program that was saved through my Administration’s “Benefit of the Bargain” reforms, consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1702/e">47 U.S.C. 1702(e)</ref>–(f) [section 60102(e), (f) of <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref>]. That Policy Notice must provide that States with onerous AI laws identified pursuant to section 4 of this order are ineligible for non-deployment funds, to the maximum extent allowed by Federal law. The Policy Notice must also describe how a fragmented State regulatory landscape for AI threatens to undermine BEAD-funded deployments, the growth of AI applications reliant on high-speed networks, and BEAD’s mission of delivering universal, high-speed connectivity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Executive departments and agencies (agencies) shall assess their discretionary grant programs in consultation with the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto and determine whether agencies may condition such grants on States either not enacting an AI law that conflicts with the policy of this order, including any AI law identified pursuant to section 4 or challenged pursuant to section 3 of this order, or, for those States that have enacted such laws, on those States entering into a binding agreement with the relevant agency not to enforce any such laws during the performance period in which it receives the discretionary funding.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. <i>Federal Reporting and Disclosure Standard</i>. Within 90 days of the publication of the identification specified in section 4 of this order, the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission shall, in consultation with the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, initiate a proceeding to determine whether to adopt a Federal reporting and disclosure standard for AI models that preempts conflicting State laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. <i>Preemption of State Laws Mandating Deceptive Conduct in AI Models</i>. Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission shall, in consultation with the Special Advisor for AI and Crypto, issue a policy statement on the application of the Federal Trade Commission Act’s prohibition on unfair and deceptive acts or practices under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s45">15 U.S.C. 45</ref> [section 5 of act <date date="1914-09-26">Sept. 26, 1914</date>] to AI models. That policy statement must explain the circumstances under which State laws that require alterations to the truthful outputs of AI models are preempted by the Federal Trade Commission Act’s prohibition on engaging in deceptive acts or practices affecting commerce.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 8. <i>Legislation</i>. (a) The Special Advisor for AI and Crypto and the Assistant to the President for Science and Technology shall jointly prepare a legislative recommendation establishing a uniform Federal policy framework for AI that preempts State AI laws that conflict with the policy set forth in this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The legislative recommendation called for in subsection (a) of this section shall not propose preempting otherwise lawful State AI laws relating to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) child safety protections;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) AI compute and data center infrastructure, other than generally applicable permitting reforms;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) State government procurement and use of AI; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) other topics as shall be determined.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 9. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The costs for publication of this order shall be borne by the Department of Commerce.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
